<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397590990024621</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/caloundra-sharks-in-top-three/3206802/</url>
  <title>Caloundra Sharks in top three</title>
  <content>
RUGBY LEAGUE: A win against Noosa has gifted Caloundra some breathing space, but the run to the finish is still a close contest according to coach Glenn Irwin.
The Sharks defeated the Pirates 34-24 on Saturday night to claim third spot on the six-team division one ladder.
"We got off to a good lead but they kind of kept coming back at us and we probably only kicked away in the last 10 minutes," he said.
"It was a pretty important game for us because who ever won took third spot."
Holding on to third spot is integral for Caloundra according to Irwin, with a home ground advantage up for grabs in the finals.
"It's a home semi-final if you get third so we had plenty to play for," he said.
"You just rather play on your home ground and you get better support and you certainly put it out there when your playing at home.
"It makes a big difference in any level of sport really."
Irwin said second-rower Blair Howard, who travels from Maleny each week, was vital in the win.
"He brought a lot of energy to the team and every time we ran the ball he seemed to make good metres and was very positive in everything he did," he said.
Caloundra needs to win their final two games to stay in the top three but Irwin was confident it could be done.
"We've just about got everyone back on deck now," he said.
"We've had a few injuries but we are very close now to being back at full strength so that's a positive at this time of the year.
"Barring injuries and if we can keep everyone on the field, I'd like to think we'd be in pretty good shape."
In other games, Maroochydore beat Nambour 42-10 and Kawana toppled Caboolture 56-0.
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
Why environmentalists want to see shark nets pulled out
Noosa student Nina Burkardt has secured her aerobatics licence
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
There's something for everyone in our 10 Things To Do guide
Don't miss your chance to head out on the town with our Gig Guide
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
You wouldn't guess who's back
There some places even these celebs can't get into
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nina Burkardt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Sharks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irwin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blair Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUGBY LEAGUE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Irwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
