<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397801443424490</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/driver-on-ice-crashes-into-port-pirie-playground-during-police-chase-narrowly-misses-child-and-man/news-story/e576caed63cc01f471a8e2c7c1525ded</url>
  <title>Driver on ice crashes into playground, misses child</title>
  <content>
A MOTORIST on ice allegedly fleeing police has been arrested after he crashed his car into a Port Pirie playground and narrowly avoided hitting a small child.
The man was driving a defected and unregistered car along The Terrace when he was spotted by a patrol at about 5.15pm on Sunday, prompting police to signal the car to pull over.
Instead, it sped off.
The car crashed through a nearby fence and continued along Gordon St where it smashed through another fence into Woodward Park.
A child and a man were at the playground when the car crashed but narrowly avoided being hit, SA Police say.
The 23-year-old man ran from the playground and was found by officers in a nearby backyard.
He was arrested and charged with multiple driving offences, including drive unregistered, disqualified, contrary to defect, to escape police pursuit, in a manner dangerous and unlawfully on premises and resist arrest.
The Port Pirie man also tested positive to methamphetamine.
He was refused police bail and will appear in the Port Pirie Magistrates Court on Monday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodward Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Pirie Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Pirie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
