<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397792853489796</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/music/dr-luke-subpoenas-lady-gaga-in-kesha-case-20170730-gxlxo6.html</url>
  <title>Dr. Luke subpoenas Lady Gaga in Kesha case</title>
  <content>
Dr. Luke is continuing his defamation lawsuit against Kesha. The music producer has now subpoenaed Lady Gaga for a deposition for her involvement in the case.
"Dr. Luke's counsel served a subpoena on Lady Gaga because she has relevant information regarding, among other things, false statements about Dr. Luke made to her by Kesha," said Dr. Luke's lawyer in a statement on Saturday.

Up Next

Private Sydney: Packer parts ways with Scientologist

02:14

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Entertainment news highlights

Thor and Stranger Things release trailers at Comic Con, Sam Newman keeps quiet, Delta gets pulled and Rhys Nicholson gets cut off.

"This motion has become necessary because Dr. Luke's counsel has not been able to obtain, despite repeated request, a deposition date from Lady Gaga."
According to a TMZ report, Lady Gaga did submit a written statement, but redacted too much of the content to prove useful. She will now be required to attend a three-hour, sit-down interview instead.Photo: Jason LaVeris
Lady Gaga has publicly supported Kesha throughout her sexual assault case against Dr. Luke - including tweeting "#FreeKesha" - and is said to have exchanged text messages with the pop star.
"In connection with Dr. Luke's defamation claims against Kesha, various third parties are being deposed by both sides, including celebrities," his lawyer's statement also confirmed.

It's worth noting the usage of "celebrities" - plural - meaning other A-listers may find themselves on the stand.

A post shared by xoxo, Gaga (@ladygaga) on

A representative for Lady Gaga released a statement saying the pop star "has provided all of the relevant information in her possession and is at most an ancillary witness in this process."
"Dr. Luke's team is attempting to manipulate the truth and draw press attention to their case by exaggerating Lady Gaga's role and falsely accusing her of dodging reasonable requests," said the statement.
Dr. Luke previously sued Kesha's mother Pebe Sebert for defamation in 2014 and 2016, but dropped the suits in June.
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comic Con</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FreeKesha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stranger Things</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scientologist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TMZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason LaVeris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Gaga</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pebe Sebert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kesha</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhys Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. Luke</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
