<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397848688065445</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/life-sex-dolls-game-changer/3206819/</url>
  <title>Life-like sex dolls a 'game changer'</title>
  <content>
THE latest generation of sex dolls are being touted as the most lifelike yet - able to listen and answer questions using sophisticated voice recognition software and move like a real person.

Developed by Doll Sweet Dolls and EX Doll, the dolls can be controlled via a smartphone and a PlayStation controller.

Luxury silicone sex doll specialist Paul Lumb labelled the prototype the "Bugatti Veyron of VR" - and comes at a cost of $A7500 price tag.

"They will have an element of natural conversation, so they won't sound too robotic, but they will take time - languages are massive," he told The Sun.

"The voice recognition is no different to a smart phone, but this model also has facial expressions, unlike standard silicone heads.

"Over the last two years we've been moving towards real touch, real feel silicon dolls, enhancing the skeleton to make it lighter - these adult-sized dolls have a combined head and body weight of 32 kilograms."

Mr Lumb said sex robots have been quietly developed behind the scenes for ten to 15 years and were now getting to the point where they will walk, talk and feel human.

And while this model is not at that point, the prototype is introducing the next level of doll development.

"This is revolutionary, it's a game-changer - from a gamer's perspective, it'd be like a new console being released," he said.

The news comes as Australia's largest health, sexuality and lifestyle exhibition Sexpo prepares to showcase the latest advancements in technology within the adult industry.

Sexpo event director Bentleigh Gibson said the theme of this year's show in Brisbane was "feel the future" - fitting given the developments of naughty tech.

"From the latest developments of toys and gadgets to sex robots to virtual reality, never before has sex and technology been so intertwined," he told news.com.au.

Mr Gibson said apart from the obvious appeal of sex robots, the innovation of sex toys was one of the biggest trends in the adult industry.

"While there is still a market for regular toys, over time these products will be phased out to make room for smart and wireless devices," he said.

"With faster internet speeds and smartphones, it has never been easier to be intimate with someone - regardless of where in the world they live."

The event director said being able to take more control over sex devices was a good thing for those looking to spice up their love life.

"It might seem a little scary, but overtime it will be adopted and seen in most relationships," he said.

Mr Gibson said the evolution of the tech industry has seen DVDs becoming less popular, while VR has been attracting a lot of attention.

"VR has widespread applications and has been widely adopted in the adult industry," he said.

"The technology allows people to fully immerse themselves in the world, so it's hard not to see the appeal."

What do you think of sex robots? Continue the conversation in the comments below or with Matthew Dunn on Facebook and Twitter.

How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
Why environmentalists want to see shark nets pulled out
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
There's something for everyone in our 10 Things To Do guide
Don't miss your chance to head out on the town with our Gig Guide
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
You wouldn't guess who's back
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVDs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gibson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bugatti Veyron of VR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexpo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doll Sweet Dolls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EX Doll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleigh Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Lumb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lumb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PlayStation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
