<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397633939698168</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/motorsport/hungarian-grand-prix-daniel-ricciardo-hits-out-at-sore-loser-max-verstappen-20170730-gxlwv8.html</url>
  <title>Daniel Ricciardo hits out at 'sore loser' Max Verstappen after Hungarian Grand Prix</title>
  <content>
Budapest: Daniel Ricciardo had his Hungarian Grand Prix ended on the opening lap when Red Bull teammate Max Verstappen drove into the side of the Australian's RB13 racer.
The pair made good starts from sixth and fifth respectively, both jumping the Mercedes of Lewis Hamilton on the first turn.

Up Next

AFL plays of round 19

02:18

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Hungarian GP: Sebastian Vettel extends lead

Ferrari's Formula One championship leader Sebastian Vettel took pole position at the Hungarian Grand Prix on Saturday.

Ricciardo then passed his Dutch teammate into turn two to move into fourth before Verstappen hit him as they came through the corner.
The incident did irreparable damage to Ricciardo's Red Bull, which went off the circuit and was spilling a lot of oil.

It also sparked an angry reaction from Ricciardo over the team radio.
"Someone hit me. Is that who I think it was?" Ricciardo asked his race engineer.

"Yes," came the reply from Red Bull, and then Ricciardo did not mince his words.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"F---ing sore loser," Ricciardo added.Photo: Getty Images
While the incident ended Ricciardo's race, Verstappen was given a 10 second penalty but still managed to finish fifth as he barrelled down on the Mercedes of Hamilton at the death.
The race was won by Ferrari's Sebastian Vettel, who overcame steering difficulties to extend his championship lead over rival Hamilton to 14 points heading into the summer break.Photo: Getty Images
The four-time Formula One champion made a decent start from pole position, crucially holding off teammate Kimi Raikkonen on the long straight into turn one. On a Hungaroring track where overtaking is notoriously hard, there were limited chances to catch him after that.
"I'm over the moon. It was a really difficult race. I had my hands full," Vettel said.Photo: Getty Images
"The steering started to go sideways and it got worse. I really had to stay focused the whole race."
Ricciardo, however, was fuming when asked by reporters at the circuit about the collision between the two Red Bulls.Photo: Getty Images
"That was amateur to say the least," Ricciardo said.
"It's not like he was trying to pass. He doesn't like people passing him. I didn't really know what happened. It's just frustrating - it was not even an overtaking move.Photo: AP
"It was an emotional response."
Ricciardo called for his 19-year-old teammate to take full responsibility for the error.
"In that moment the team said sorry and they will speak to Max," Ricciardo said. "Let's see if he acts his age or like a man about it and admits the error. 
"I could go and call him names after the accident but if he starts bringing in other excuses in then we will have a problem."
Verstappen offered up an apology immediately after the race.
"It is of course not what you want," Verstappen said of the incident.
"The start was actually quite good but then we were both fighting for position into turn two. I had a car in front of me and I locked up and then I was a passenger.
"It was never my intention to hit anyone and especially my teammate, who I have a good relationship with.
"I apologise to Daniel and I will speak to him in private. We will sort it out."
It was Vettel's 46th career win, coming in ahead of teammate Raikkonen for a Ferrari 1-2.
"Grazie! Forza Ferrari!" a jubilant Vettel shouted on the team radio after crossing the line for his fourth win of the season.
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian's RB13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes of Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricciardo's Red Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Ricciardo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Vettel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raikkonen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verstappen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Verstappen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vettel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari's Sebastian Vettel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forza Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bulls.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vettel's 46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungaroring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari's Formula One</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes of Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Formula One</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimi Raikkonen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricciardo</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
