<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397840098130740</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/voters-in-scott-morrisons-own-electorate-believe-hes-wrong-on-inequality-20170729-gxlk82.html</url>
  <title>Voters in Scott Morrison's own electorate believe he's wrong on inequality</title>
  <content>
Voters in Treasurer Scott Morrison's own electorate overwhelmingly believe inequality is a worsening problem in Australia and the government must do more to address it.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

How Labor plans to close family trust loopholes

Shadow treasurer Chris Bowen outlines Labor's plan to curb high income earners legally using trusts to slash their tax bills.

Polling of voters in Mr Morrison's southern Sydney seat of Cook has found nearly 85 per cent believe it is important for the government's policies to reduce inequality.
The ReachTEL poll was conducted last Thursday, three days after Mr Morrison claimed inequality was reducing in Australia and accused Labor of prosecuting a dishonest "politics of envy" campaign on the issue.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
But just 8 per cent of Mr Morrison's constituents agree that inequality has improved.
Sixty-three per cent believe it is worsening, while about 25 per cent believe it has remained about the same.

Almost half of voters - 48 per cent - say they are less likely to vote for Mr Morrison as a result of his comments, including 60 per cent of undecided voters and half of One Nation supporters.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Sixty-six per cent of voters believe Mr Morrison should reconsider his position, including 45 per cent of Liberal voters. Nearly 70 per cent believe Mr Morrison should do more to understand how inequality is affecting ordinary Australians.Photo: AAP
The poll of 726 people across the electorate was commissioned by activist group GetUp.
National director Paul Oosting said rising inequality should not be a partisan issue, with the vast majority of Australians concerned about issues such as stagnating wages.
"If the nation's Treasurer won't take these issues seriously, then voters are going to look for someone else who will. Mr Morrison's views of inequality are painfully at odds with those of his own electorate - including his own voting base," he said.
The debate about inequality has ramped up after Opposition Leader Bill Shorten declared it would be Labor's defining mission going into the next election.
But Mr Morrison last week said Mr Shorten's claim that inequality had reached a 75-year high was a "lie".
"This idea that people and inequality and incomes have been going in the wrong direction, that's not borne out by the facts," he said
"The last census showed that on the global measure of inequality - which is the Gini coefficient, the accepted global measure of income inequality around the word - that figure shows that it hasn't got worse, inequality.
"It's actually got better."
The Gini coefficient is a number between 0 and 1 that represents a nation's equality, with 0 being perfect equality and 1 being total inequality.
In the early 1980s Australia's number was about 0.2. It grew to 0.309 in 1995 and peaked around 0.334 in 2008-9 before falling in the wake of the global financial crisis. The Australian Bureau of Statistics has not published figures since the 2013-14 financial year.
The OECD's most recent economic survey of Australia said inequality was worsening.
"The Gini coefficient has been drifting up and households in upper income brackets have benefited disproportionately from Australia's long period of economic growth," it said. 
"Real incomes for the top quintile of households grew by more than 40 per cent between 2004 and 2014 while those for the lowest quintile only grew by about 25 per cent."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OECD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Oosting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sixty-three</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrison</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gini</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ReachTEL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GetUp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sixty-six</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
