<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397792853489787</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:58</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/settling-12000-refugees-syria-iraq/8757812</url>
  <title>The last of the 12,000 refugees: Syrians and Iraqis build new lives in Australia</title>
  <content>
Nader Hamouch is about to literally plant the seeds of his new life in Australia.
The Syrian flower farmer is part of an intake of 12,000 displaced Syrians and Iraqis given refuge in Australia, a deal .
But like many of his fellow travellers, it's been difficult for him to find his feet.
The 44-year-old from Latakia City carries photos of his old flower farm on his phone. But says it was no longer safe for him, his wife and four children.
He's just bought his first batch of seeds to help him start the business all over again - this time at Tahmoor on Sydney's outskirts.
"When you see the flowers growing and blooming a little bit every day, it gives you joy and happiness," he says.
He's coming across flowers he's never seen before - and learning the English names for the ones he is already familiar with.

While learning English, he has also had to get his head around Australian regulations and the local environment.
"There was too many barriers, I couldn't take all of them in one package because otherwise I get disappointed, I wouldn't do anything," he says.
These are challenges shared by many of those arriving as part of this special intake.
"Families, adults and even children have experienced and witness horrible things before they arrive," settlement services manager Yamamah Agha says.
"Losing loved ones, losing friends, losing their jobs, losing their homes and everything they liked to be resettled in a new country.
"It's not something easy to do and it's not something of their choice."

Ms Agha's workplace, Settlement Services International, meets refugees at the airport with a welcome banner.
But after that, it's hard work.
Many need medical attention before they can even think about looking for a job.
"Mental health, torture, trauma - all these things are challenges they have," Ms Agha says.
Serg, an Armenian tradesman from Aleppo, arrived in Australia three months ago with his wife and two daughters.
His son is still overseas, and we can't use his full name or show his face.
But his dream is to unite his family in Sydney.
"I would love my family to settle here quickly, find jobs, settle here and get married here," he says.

He's learning English, and says it's a slow adjustment to the safety and security Australia offers.
"We came from the Middle East, we are there a bit different from here, we are a bit quick, nervous maybe," he says.
"But here we are learning how to be calm, how to follow the rules, follow the system in a perfect way."
His daughter Lucy is trained as a dentist and speaks English, but is yet to have her qualifications recognised here.
"It's my dream," she says.
"Dentistry is the first to treat the people; it's communication with people."

For many younger refugees, their schooling has been interrupted at best.
Patrician Brothers' College Fairfield has specifically created a program to help boys aged 12 to 19 learn English and catch up on their education.
"They're coming sometimes from two years, three years, four years' break in their learning," principal Peter Wade says.
"It's a big break in anyone's learning to do that, catch up, and acquire a new language."
Today, some are studying mathematics and some are learning about cooking.
Both subjects are taught in English, with assistance from specialist teachers.

"It's early days, but I'm finding that the boys are really settling in with the other students in the school and have already started integrating in some sports," Mr Wade says.
One of the boys put his prized soccer boots on his desk every day until someone recognised he wanted to play soccer, and helped him join one of the school teams.
But there's also been challenges - with school routines such as evacuation drills bringing back memories of past trauma for some students.
"I think having the students here in our intensive English centre heightens our awareness of things we take for granted," Mr Wade says.

The school is in Fairfield - one of the most popular spots for the new arrivals to make home.
But that's caused alarm for Fairfield Council, with Mayor Frank Carbone saying the area doesn't have the resources to accommodate them.
He compares it to establishing a whole new suburb, but one where most people are unable to work.
"Our unemployment rate in Fairfield has gone up above 9 per cent, while the state average has gone below 5 per cent," he says.
The Federal Government says refugees, once in Australia, are largely free to live where they choose.

But Mr Carbone says if more infrastructure isn't provided for western Sydney, the refugees should be encouraged to move elsewhere.
"I'll have to have a discussion with my council and my community about encouraging refugees to places where there are more opportunities -where there are more jobs, where there are more services, where the government is putting money into infrastructure," he says.
"Places like Manly, Penrith, Campbelltown and Camden."
The special intake of Syrian and Iraqi refugees is now drawing to a close - with just a handful of families expected to arrive over coming days.
Mr Hamouch acknowledges not everyone will be able to start a business within a year of arrival, like he's doing.
But he says the keys to his success can also help others - he's now safe; and Australians have made him feel welcome.
"They don't ask you where you're from, they treat you as a human, and this is very important for me," he says.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armenian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Frank Carbone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraqis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latakia City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wade</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aleppo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Agha</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tahmoor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Settlement Services International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Carbone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hamouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brothers' College Fairfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yamamah Agha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nader Hamouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
