<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397706954143037</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/golf/karrie-webb-blows-winning-position-at-scottish-open-as-bunker-helps-contribute-to-late-double-bogey/news-story/aa00ae0e39c1fdd429ea89af66eb864d</url>
  <title>The 'perfect drive' that turned into a nightmare</title>
  <content>
MI Hyang Lee took advantage of Karrie Webb's late double bogey to win the Ladies Scottish Open for her second LPGA Tour title.
A stroke ahead of Lee with two holes left at a chilly Dundonald Links, Webb dropped a shot back with the double bogey on the par-five 17th after driving into a bunker and having to play out backwards.
"I bent down, picked my tee up - thought I hit a perfect drive there," Webb said.
"When I stood up, I went to tell (my caddie) Jonny (Scott) that I absolutely knotted my 3-wood exactly how I wanted and he said it kicked into the bunker. I have no idea how it did that."
Lee, playing in the group ahead of Webb, increased the margin to two with a birdie on the par-five 18th.
Needing an eagle to force a playoff, Webb closed with a birdie to tie for second with Mi Jung Hur.
Webb didn't know she was two strokes behind because of the lack of a leaderboard on the final hole in the tune-up event for the Women's British Open next week at Kingsbarns.
"It's pretty bad to not have a leaderboard on the last," Webb said.
"That's the first time I've ever been (at a tour event) that hasn't had a leaderboard on 18. ... We didn't know if Mi Hyang had birdied or not, because there wasn't like a loud cheer like she had."
The 42-year-old Aussie reached the green-side bunker in two shots.
"Well, my bunker shot, I said to Jonny, 'I don't know if I need to hole this or get it up-and-down,'" she said.
"Imagine if you went for it and overplayed it and you only had to get it up-and-down. I was trying to make it but also not being overly aggressive."
Webb had earlier chipped in for eagle on the par-five 14th and bogeyed the par-four 16th before losing the lead on 17.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladies Scottish Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LPGA Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webb</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingsbarns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MI Hyang Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dundonald Links</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mi Hyang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mi Jung Hur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karrie Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's British Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
