<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397801443424504</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/why-block-wont-come-back-sydney/3206815/</url>
  <title>Why The Block won't come back to Sydney</title>
  <content>
SYDNEY'S famous Bondi might have been the setting for the first season of reality TV show The Block but strict and unaccommodating councils means the show might never return to the beach, or any other Sydney suburb.

The show - and the structures the couples renovate - have been mostly Melbourne based since Series 4 and, 13 seasons later it's unlikely to change said host Scott Cam.

"At this stage, no ... we need to get the council on board with us. That's our biggest problem," Cam said, adding that the councils didn't deem what the show was doing to be a full construction zone.

The production was fined $2000 at least 10 times the last time they shot in Sydney for a one off season in 2013.

"The Victorian Government realise that we bring about $20 million into the economy ... we don't have catering, so the 150 tradies all go off site to buy their food," said Cam, who lives in Sydney but relocated to Melbourne during filming.

Co-host Shelley Craft claimed that if the show, which premiered last night, returned to Sydney it would not be as enjoyable to watch.

"There is not a lot of excitement watching someone get stuck in traffic for six hours," she joked.

"Councils are great to us [in Melbourne], most of our production team and crew have relocated, real estate is obtainable in Melbourne and so for so many reasons we are here," Craft said.

"We have amazing support from the city of Melbourne."

This season of The Block will see the five teams renovating a street of dilapidated houses that were set for demolition in the leafy suburb of Elsternwick.

Cam added that contrary to reports of unease from local residents, the production was welcomed into the area.

"We don't have many dramas with residents because we really look after them. And the fact is, the alternative was going to be 45 town houses on this block ... instead we are putting five beautiful houses that blend in with their street and raise the value of the house across the road."

Originally published as Why The Block won't return to Sydney

How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
Why environmentalists want to see shark nets pulled out
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
There's something for everyone in our 10 Things To Do guide
Don't miss your chance to head out on the town with our Gig Guide
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
You wouldn't guess who's back
There some places even these celebs can't get into
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-host Shelley Craft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Cam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Series 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elsternwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
