<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397801443424492</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/andrew-forrest-to-fund-own-the-force-campaign-20170730-gxlxsi.html</url>
  <title>Andrew Forrest to fund 'Own the Force' campaign</title>
  <content>
Billionaire mining magnate Andrew Forrest will pour millions of dollars into the 'Own the Force' campaign if the Perth-based franchise survives the axe.
RugbyWA and the ARU begin arbitration in Sydney on Monday, with the fate of the Western Force hanging in the balance.Photo: AAP
If the ARU win the arbitration hearing, they will axe the Force from the Super Rugby competition.
If the Force win, the ARU will have no other choice but to try to axe the Melbourne Rebels, or negotiate a merger between two Australian franchises.
The Force will argue the 'alignment' deal they signed with the ARU last year guarantees their future until the end of the current broadcast deal in 2020.
But the ARU will counter that argument by saying the broadcast landscape has now changed given the Super Rugby competition will be reduced from 18 to 15 teams next season.

Forrest, who is valued at $4.8 billion, has pledged to do whatever it takes to save the Force.
The 55-year-old West Australian has renewed calls for the ARU to help facilitate a Brumbies takeover of the Rebels.
He is also open to the idea of the Force merging with the Rebels.
Forrest is prepared to put his money where his mouth is to ensure the Force not only survive, but thrive long into the future.
The Force are currently owned by the ARU under the bailout 'alignment' deal they signed last year.
But once their future became threatened, the franchise launched an 'Own the Force' campaign in a bid to become Australia's premier publicly-owned sporting club.
The franchise has been selling shares at $1000 a pop in a bid to raise enough revenue to buy back the license, and have enough funds left over to set up their future.
So far, about 4700 people have either bought - or have pledged to buy - a share. Some people have bought multiple shares.
Forrest has no interest in owning the Force himself.
But he has devised a plan to give the 'Own the Force' campaign a massive financial boost.
Forrest is offering people interest-free loans to buy shares in the Force.
And more importantly, the money lent to them will be paid back to RugbyWA - not Forrest.
It effectively means the Force will now receive $2000 for each share sold - potentially pumping millions of extra dollars into the franchise.
Forrest's commitment isn't expected to end there, but for now he is keeping his cards close to his chest regarding any potential future funding of the franchise.
The Fortescue Metals chairman believes a Brumbies takeover of the Rebels would be the best outcome for Australian rugby.
Forrest said the option would allow the Brumbies to expand their sponsorship base.
He also wants a rugby academy in Melbourne to be set up for a player pathway to the Brumbies.
"It will bolster the rugby culture in Victoria, giving players there access to one of the best teams in the country," Forrest said.
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Forrest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Rebels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RugbyWA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue Metals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forrest</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
