<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397844393098108</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/8ateight/8eight-oil-to-give-asx-tailwind-20170730-gxlxl4.html</url>
  <title>8@eight: Oil to give ASX tailwind</title>
  <content>
While Apple reports earnings at 6.30am AEST on Wednesday, as a whole US earnings will become less of an issue for investors and the focus here largely turns back to economic data trends and specifically the inflationary readings.
Let's recap though, because 57 per cent of S&P 500 corporate have reported earnings, and we find 78 per cent have beaten the Street's forecast on earnings, by an average of 5.2 per cent, while 72 per cent have beaten on sales. Great number, but that's not going to surprise as this level of beats are only modestly above the average we've seen over past quarters. What is positive though is aggregate EPS growth thus far is an impressive 10.6 per cent, with top line growth at 6 per cent. Both numbers are nicely higher than what was expected going into reporting season. With valuations getting quite a bit of focus, this is the sort of earnings growth that will keep the bulls happy. But far more needs to happen going forward if we are to avoid a correction of sorts when we step back from liquidity-driven markets to one where we go back to our roots and look at return on equity and earnings growth. How many companies are trading at a discount to intrinsic value? Not many.

The earnings batten though is handed to Japan, where we see over 350 companies reporting today alone. It's also a busy reporting calendar in Europe, so European equity markets should be well traded. Specifically, I will be watching the German DAX, where price action is looking very interesting. A move through Friday's high today and I would be looking for a rally in the DAX, potentially into 12,500. Of course, Aussie earning season officially kicks off tomorrow with Navitas and then Rio being the biggy. Again, the focus for me is not so much about whether corporates can beat the street's forecasts or earnings, but whether the outlooks are sufficient and inspirational enough for the market to break the 5850 to 5675 range it's been in since mid-May.

The key focus for so many macro traders and investors is around inflation and inflation expectations. US data then hogs the limelight, although tomorrow's RBA meeting and Friday's Statement on Monetary Policy will be a key focal point locally too. On Friday, we saw US Q2 GDP print 2.6 per cent, which was a touch below expectations, while the ECI (Employee Cost Index), which is a compensation measure the Federal Reserve look at closely, came in at 0.5 per cent, falling 30 basis points on the quarter. Neither were great numbers and it was not a surprise to see the US 10-year treasury yield fall three basis points (bp) to 2.28 per cent. Inflation expectations remain firm there though, and one suspects that will happen with the US dollar having fallen 10.2 per cent since January. So with inflation expectations staying firm, we have seen 'real' yields falling across the curve and this is great for gold, terrible for the USD.

Absolute calamities in the Trump administration are not helping either and what an amazing few days of news flow. We have seen with key personnel changes, in-fighting in key divisions, all amid a backdrop where despite holding both the Senate and House, the Republicans can't get anything passed. Healthcare was supposed to be well and truly passed by now, allowing the fiscal offset to push through sweeping tax reform. Clearly, that's a 2018 story now! As mentioned, it's all about economics now, with US core PCE, personal income, vehicle sales, manufacturing and services ISM and US non-farm payrolls in the mix. Will we see further lows in the USD this week? Watch the US 10-year treasury for a break of 2.33 per cent or 2.22 per cent as a guide for USD flows, while a shorter-term rates markets will be interesting with Fed funds future now pricing a 40 per cent chance of a hike by the December meeting.

I mention the US dollar as a central theme for traders, but for FX traders there has been a huge shift to sell the Swiss franc (CHF) and sentiment towards the 'Swissy' has deteriorated significantly. GBP/CHF rallied 3.5 per cent last week, which is a huge move when we adjust for leverage. AUD/CHF has flown too and is eyeing a break of the February highs, so put that on the radar, with the Australian event risk in play this week.

So an eventful week ahead, but the Asia market open looks quite constructive at this stage and while the S&P 500 fell 0.1 per cent on Friday, SPI futures closed 24 points higher. Our call for the ASX 200 currently sits at 5718, with BHP eyeing a solid open, 1.7 per cent higher, and the fact US crude rallied 8.6 per cent last week has been a strong tailwind. The futures open at 8am AEST shouldn't see too many fireworks judging by the unchanged reads we have seen in the FX open this morning, and although the US oil rig count gained by two rigs, I suspect pullbacks in the oil price should be supported and we will be watching for a move into $US50. The S&P 500 energy sector closed 0.19 per cent lower on Friday, by way of a guide here.

We can also see spot iron ore falling 2.1 per cent, however, futures markets have been strong, with iron ore and steel futures gaining 3.1 per cent and 1.2 per cent respectively. Copper closed unchanged at $US2.875, although the trend remains higher. 

Market highlights

Up Next

How Labor plans to close family trust loopholes

05:11

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Can earnings shake life back into the ASX 200?

What to expect this week as the corporate reporting calendar starts. This video was produced in commercial partnership between Fairfax Media and IG Markets.

SPI futures up 24 points or 0.4% to 5658

AUD +0.2% to 79.88 US cents (Session range: 0.7937 - 0.8007)

On Wall St, Dow +0.2%, S&P 500 -0.1%, Nasdaq -0.1%

In New York, BHP +0.8%, Rio +1.6%

In Europe, Stoxx 50 -0.7%, FTSE -1%, CAC -1.1%, DAX -0.4%

Spot gold +0.8% to $US1269.74 an ounce

Brent crude +2.2% to $US52.61 a barrel

US oil +1.5% to $US49.76 a barrel

Iron ore -2.1% to $US68.73 a tonne

Dalian iron ore +3% to 545 yuan

LME aluminium -1.6% to $US1907 a tonne

LME copper -0.1% to $US6325 a tonne

10-year bond yield: US 2.29%, Germany 0.54%, Australia 2.68%

  This column was produced in commercial partnership
   between Fairfax Media and
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE -1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LME</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GBP/CHF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1269.74</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US52.61</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD/CHF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US68.73</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500 -0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX -0.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IG Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP +0.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 50 -0.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Employee Cost Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio +1.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 2.68</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday's Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swissy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq -0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navitas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Q2 GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US49.76</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany 0.54</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US 2.29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.875</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC -1.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6325</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>German DAX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX 200</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1907</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
