<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397749903816411</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:48</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/analysts-predict-cba-shares-to-fall-questions-about-narev-future-20170729-gxlkn3</url>
  <title>Analysts predict CBA shares to fall; questions about Narev future</title>
  <content>
Ian Narev will mark six years as Commonwealth Bank of Australia's chief executive in December. It's the same amount of time his predecessor, Ralph Norris, was in the role.
Running what is one the country's largest employers and company by market capitalisation is an incredibly taxing job. So it's not surprising there's been speculation as to whether Narev will step down towards the end of the year.
Business people who bump into Narev outside the office say his body language hints at someone who may be wearying of the role but it's merely conjecture. Fifty-year-old Narev's made no statement that he has any intention to depart the bank which has already seen change at the top.
Last month, group chief financial officer David Craig retired to be replaced by Rob Jesudason. Chairman Catherine Livingstone has only had her feet under the table as the bank's chairman since January. And the bank's chief risk officer Alden Toevs was replaced by David Cohen in July 2016.

Wayne Taylor

Internally, the market favourite to replace Narev when he does step down is Matt Comyn, the bank's impressive group executive of retail banking services, who's in his early 40s. Externally, the former CBA executive Ross McEwan, who now runs Royal Bank of Scotland, has been mentioned as a wildcard contender. McEwan, 60, denied earlier this year rumours that he intended to depart RBS.

Reputation

Every board of a major listed Australian company should have an orderly succession plan in place. And it would be expected that boards would review succession regularly not only of the CEO but the top executive team. A board needs to as part of constantly assessing the future position of the organisation and whether the executive team in place is taking it there.
So how has CBA performed under Narev? There are many measures of a CEO and a company's performance. Share price is typically the first starting point. When Narev began as CEO, CBA shares were trading near $50. Recently they were just shy of $84. But now some analysts are predicting its shares will fall towards $70.
Reputation is another metric that people might point to review performance of both a CEO and company. Reputation for the banks became an issue after the global financial crisis when a variety of scandals emerged and banks were perceived as not only slow in responding to public concerns but also arrogant. These scandals ranged from traders allegedly rigging the bank bill swap rate to scandals in the financial planning arms of National Australia Bank, Macquarie Private Wealth and CBA, and the CommInsure scandal.

There was a perception that the big banks guaranteed by the Australian taxpayer during the GFC - and since - had favoured themselves above the public, and Narev and CBA, in particular, were singled out for what was perceived to be a poor response to its financial planning and insurance problems.
But such perceptions are not reflected in customer satisfaction surveys. Successive Roy Morgan surveys reveal that customer satisfaction with the CBA remains over 80 per cent - the highest of the four major banks - and among the highest ranking in surveys dating back to the mid-2000s. Still, only half of CBA's customers are "highly likely" to recommend the bank.
Such customer satisfaction survey results haven't got in the way of politicians' preferred sport of bank bashing. The federal government this year introduced a bank levy. Last year, the Prime Minister warned banks they operated under a social licence that was underwritten by public confidence and trust. The federal opposition, if elected, has promised a royal commission into the banking sector.
Performance measures

If CBA under Narev has had strong performance in both its share price, customer satisfaction and profitability - the latter has increased by nearly a quarter during his time - then what of market share?
In home loans, CBA's market share has been almost static, around 25-26 per cent of the Australian market under Narev, and business lending has remained around 18-19 per cent.
A company the size of CBA finds it harder and harder to move the dial in a small market such as Australia, where the so-called four pillars policy ensures a cosy oligopoly. It raises the question about future growth prospects for all banks particularly if home lending moderates from its solid growth of recent years. UBS bank analysts note that "Aussie banks are becoming more utility-like".
Morgan Stanley analyst Richard Wiles, who released a substantial report on the Australian banking sector last Thursday, has an underweight rating on CBA arguing that Australia is decoupling from the global economic recovery and that Australia consumers are facing a cash-flow and credit crunch. Higher electricity prices and low or no wages growth will continue to impinge on household incomes.

Louie Douvis

Wiles also noted that CBA had been the biggest beneficiary of growth in Australian housing loans over the past 25 years - a period during which the country has experienced uninterrupted economic growth - but he believes the outlook for the mortgage market has changed and that CBA's loan growth will slow more than expected.
Wiles expects housing loan growth for the sector to slow from 6 per cent in financial year 2017 to 4 per cent the year after.
He argues that the major banks are currently trading on an average forward earnings per share multiple of 13.4 times, which is above the long run average, and also implies 5 per cent loan growth.
Slower loan growth is one reason why he has a target on CBA's shares of $72. Meanwhile, Citi analysts have a share price forecast of $75 and a sell on the stock; CLSA rates CBA underperform and UBS is neutral.

Future headwinds

Wiles is also concerned about CBA's collective provision coverage for potential loan losses which he argues is at its lowest since financial year 2008. He no longer believes that CBA has a different risk profile from the other majors and that a risk to the bank is higher impairment chargers triggered by a weaker economy.
Another risk to Morgan Stanley's forecasts is if CBA were to do an "expensive offshore acquisition" but this seems highly unlikely given the poor record of Australian banks investing offshore, such as ANZ and NAB, and the lack of investor appetite for such a strategy, even if growth in the domestic market will be harder to find.
Since Narev took over as CEO global and domestic regulatory changes have imposed greater capital requirements on all banks, which has had in turn affected on return on equity.
In the financial year 2011, CBA's ROE was 19.5 per cent and in financial year 2016 it had declined to 16.5 per cent. Expectations are that this trend will continue. Morgan Stanley sees it sitting around 15 per cent by financial year 2019 and Citi says 13.7 per cent by 2020. While CBA's ROE has been higher than the other three major banks the point is the gap is narrowing.
The declining ROE for CBA is another reason why some of the analysts' have underweight or sell recommendations on CBA. They also see it as the bank with the greatest need of the four majors to raise capital in the next few years, possibly around $3 billion to meet its common equity Tier 1 requirements.
Citi analysts believe that CBA management may need to accelerate strategic change in order to maintain its valuation premium relative to its peers. This may or may not be Narev's problem depending on how much longer he's at the helm.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Private Wealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman Catherine Livingstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CLSA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Jesudason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross McEwan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Bank of Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Comyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Narev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alden Toevs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tier 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ralph Norris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Wiles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narev</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA's ROE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McEwan, 60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommInsure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>22</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
