<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397797148457127</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/daniel-ricciardo-taken-out-of-hungarian-grand-prix-by-teammate-max-verstappen/news-story/167b08e3176bda57f8c68f1945276a60</url>
  <title>'F***ing sore loser': Dan rages</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN F1 star Daniel Ricciardo has blown up at his Red Bull teammate Max Verstappen after the 19-year-old's "amateur" mistake sent him crashing out of the Hungarian Grand Prix.
, with Verstappen coming in fifth. But for Australian fans, the race was over after the very first lap.
Ricciardo started the race in sixth, one place behind his Dutch teammate. He passed Verstappen on the second corner, but as both cars reached the next turn, Verstappen collided with Ricciardo, sending him off the track and irreparably damaging his car.
"Someone hit me. Is that who I think it was?" a furious Ricciardo asked over the team radio.
"Yes," the team replied.
"F***ing sore loser," Ricciardo said.
He hadn't calmed down much when he spoke to reporters a short time later.
"That was amateur to say the least. It's not like he was trying to pass. He doesn't like people passing him," Ricciardo said.
"I didn't really know what happened. It's just frustrating, it was not even an overtaking move. It was an emotional response.
"I don't think there is an excuse for it."
Verstappen, for his part, was apologetic after the race.
"This is not nice and I apologise to Daniel for that, and also to the team, because we could have scored some good points here. I'll speak with Daniel in private and we'll sort it out," the Dutch teenager said.
"It is never my intention to his anyone, but especially not your teammate, and especially with the relationship I have with Daniel. It's always really good and we can always have a laugh."
There probably wasn't much laughing today.
VETTEL'S TRIUMPH, HAMILTON'S CLASS
Sebastian Vettel, meanwhile, increased his drivers' world championship lead to 14 points when he led Kimi Raikkonen home in a dominant Ferrari one-two finish.
In his 50th race for Ferrari, the four-time champion German controlled the contest from pole position in stifling heat to reel off his first win in five races since the Monaco Grand Prix. His main title rival, Lewis Hamilton of Mercedes, finished fourth.
Hamilton showed his worth as a team player when he let Valtteri Bottas through to take third place on the podium.
"I respect Lewis for that, it really proves he is a team player," Sky Sports' Anthony Davidson said after the race.
"He's still got a shot at this championship and there he has really played the team game."

I really don't like Hamilton that much but today he's shown that he's a team player. Brilliant of him to let Bottas through. Respect.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports' Anthony Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Ricciardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Vettel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valtteri Bottas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verstappen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Verstappen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VETTEL'S TRIUMPH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HAMILTON'S CLASS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRALIAN F1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco Grand Prix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Hamilton of Mercedes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bottas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimi Raikkonen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricciardo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
