<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397844393098066</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/adelaide/mitch-mcgoverns-steel-is-a-credit-to-him-says-adelaide-crows-teammate-josh-jenkins/news-story/234e2bbe3c199af97fceca3ab55fa478</url>
  <title>Jenkins hails iceman McGovern</title>
  <content>
CROWS forward Josh Jenkins described team-mate Mitch McGovern™s game-saving mark and goal as oeclutch™™ and said the club™s sensational fightback would stand it in good stead in the finals.

While Adelaide produced a dreadful first half, Jenkins said the biggest story out of the day was its grand comeback from 50 points down to salvage a draw - and the lessons the players would learn from it.

"That's what we should take out of it, that's perhaps the story for us,'' he said.

"Yes, we didn't turn up or play to our level in the first half and, as we've seen all year, when you don't play to the level, it doesn't matter where you are ranked, you'll get beaten.

McGovern's manic game saver

"That's what happened to us early - we didn't play to the level and Collingwood played extraordinarily well against us.

"But in quarters three and four we got back to our style and played with a little bit of bravado, just got the ball moving, won contests a little bit more and we know what we can do when we play to our standard.

"We probably just need to do it from the start next week (in the Showdown).

"But there's a lot we can take out of this.''

Jenkins admitted he was one of "about 15 players who did nothing in the first half'' as the Crows were blown out of the water, falling 38 points behind at the long break and 50 points early in the third quarter.

Crows press conference

"It takes a while, but what you do learn is that you can have a shocking quarter, shocking half or a shocking three quarters and still have an impact on a game,'' said Jenkins, who had just one disposal in the first half and finished with 13 touches, three crucial goals and two score assists.

"It was very pleasing to impact the game because often, particularly when I was younger, I would have maybe, not thrown in the towel, but just floated through and done stuff all and really leaned on my team-mates too much.

"So it was great to contribute because, like probably 15 of my team-mates at half-time, I'd done nothing.''

McGovern was one of the first-half stinkers but he bagged three goals in an 11-minute spell in the third quarter before standing tall at the death.

"To take that big grab and kick that goal says a lot about him,'' Jenkins said.

"I could only imagine how nervous he would have been going back for that kick, and to kick it straight was really clutch and a credit to him, because he does a lot of work on his goalkicking routine.''

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenkins</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
