<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397590990024643</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/motor-sport/survivor-dick-johnson-still-tasting-success-in-motor-racing/news-story/c455b7d5263197c426314eccc246cf78</url>
  <title>Revved-up Johnson still breaks mould</title>
  <content>
THERE is a difference between being broke and broken. Dick Johnson knows it. He's lived it.
Queensland's motorsport legend has been broke three times, turned inside out and upside down emotionally, financially and physically.
But broken? Old Dick? Never.
On Sunday at Queensland Raceway, the Johnson racing team's main man Scott McLaughlin finished second to Chaz Mostert but still has a 129-point lead in the Supercar championship.
Should McLaughlin take the title, the Johnson team would complete one of the great comeback stories of Queensland sport.
If the State of Origin side are Queensland's benchmark for sporting toughness then surely the silver medal goes to the man with the silver hair.
Just four years ago Johnson had debts of $9.1 million and had lost his house, factory and health with his very dignity hanging by a withering thread.
But enter American billionaire Roger Penske, who at 80 is seven years Johnson's senior, who bought 51 per cent of Johnson's team and is so enjoying the ride that wherever he is in the world he tunes in to the races.
Penske's buy-in and the ensuing success has enhanced Johnson's financial position to the point where it is believed he could retire if he wanted to but the only "r'' word that interests him is racing.
"I sort of could retire but I keep going because I want to do something,'' Johnson said in pit lane, watching like the old pro who was there if they needed him but didn't want to butt in.
"And what the hell else am I going to do? I don't know anything else.
"I suppose the tough times just show you what sort of family you have when it counts. Without the support of my family I would have been screwed many times and would have chucked the towel in.''
Johnson at a motor racing venue is a bit like Father Christmas in a shopping centre. Fans just quietly gravitate.
Asked what is the strangest autograph request he has had, he smiles and shakes his head.
"When I come up here I still get asked to sign tits,'' he said.
"The difference was in the old days they used to be up here (chest high) now they are down here (knee high). I guess that's longevity for you.''
Many men his age loathe digital media but he is enjoys it.
"What has given me the longest lease of life was You Tube,'' he said.
"I like it because the young kids can see what life was. There is good and bad but from my point of view it's good.''
Johnson has been around so long he remembers the days when teammates like John French used to carry a cut lunch hidden in their console during Bathurst.
"He used to have these vegemite sandwiches but we would forget they were there until a few weeks after the race when you would pick up the smell.''

Supercars: Chaz Mostert has claimed the victory in Ipswich today but states there is still work for him and his team to do.

'There's always work to do'
Johnson's life is an interesting amalgam of the past, present and future.
Occasionally he drops grandchildren Jett and Lacey to school but last week in Noosa the sepia-tainted memories flared when he took his famous True Blue Ford for an exhibition spin.
"It felt every bit as good as it used to 35 years ago but the difference was my arse used to be small enough to easily fit in.''
No matter what the result yesterday Johnson was planning to finish the day with his favourite drop - Jim Beam and diet coke.
"I never used to drink - even when I did two years in national service - but then I got involved in motor tracing ...''
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bathurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penske</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lacey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Beam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John French</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>True Blue Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Raceway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Father Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Penske</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott McLaughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLaughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chaz Mostert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
