<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397749903816420</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/western-bulldogs-back-in-form-but-finals-task-still-tough-says-coach-luke-beveridge-20170730-gxlubd.html</url>
  <title>Western Bulldogs back in form but finals task still 'tough', says coach Luke Beveridge</title>
  <content>
Western Bulldogs coach Luke Beveridge says his team's task in making the top eight remains "tough" despite three consecutive victories giving the reigning premiers a fighting chance of figuring in the September action.
The Dogs bumped Essendon out of eighth spot with a 30-point win in a frenetic game at a packed Etihad Stadium on Sunday, and look to be heading towards their top form as the home and away season enters its final month.

Up Next

AFL plays of round 19

02:18

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Dogs back in finals hunt

The Western Bulldogs defeat Essendon to put themselves well and truly in the mix for September football.

Several of the Dogs' premiership heroes played important roles in the win, but arguably the standout was half-back flanker Jason Johannisen, who booted four goals after being shifted forward for periods of the game. After a difficult stretch mid-season in which he struggled to deal with close-checking and rough tactics from opposition sides, Johannisen, having recently signed a new five-year contract with the Dogs, is again having a major impact, impressing his coach in the process. "Some teams are going to him, and going hard," Beveridge said.
"We're finding out as a team how to capitalise on his play when teams are trying to negate him. We sent him to one of the wings, where we knew he'd be a bit freer, and then he did sneak forward. But then we felt it was probably time to play him out of that back end in that second half. It's amazing what accurate, long kicking can do. He was just brilliant with those set shots.

"He's been terrific. He's had a couple of games where it's been hard for him because teams have brought that confrontational aspect to defending him. He was brilliant today."
Having dealt with mental health issues recently, veteran forward Travis Cloke also earned Beveridge's praise for a serviceable showing in what was his first senior game since round 12. The coach agreed it posed a dilemma as to whether Cloke would hold his spot for next Saturday's game away to lowly Brisbane, with fellow forward Jack Redpath due to return from suspension.Photo: AAP/Tracey Nearmy
Following the game against the Lions, the Dogs face Greater Western Sydney (Etihad), Port Adelaide (Ballarat) and Hawthorn (Etihad). Beveridge said the Bulldogs still had a lot of work to do to secure their spot in the finals. "If you've got your eyes on the eight, you can't afford to slip up. We've had to just really focus on the next week to remind ourselves the type of footy we need to play to establish ourselves as a recognisable and threatening team. It's great that in the recent three weeks we've been able to do that, but I think we play some very very good sides on the run home, so it's going to be tough."

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Essendon coach John Worsfold bemoaned the way his side had used the ball at times on Sunday, but with Carlton (MCG), Adelaide (Etihad), Gold Coast (Metricon Stadium) and Fremantle (Etihad) to come, the Dons' remain in the finals hunt. "We need to show that we're good enough now, by winning what's ahead of us," Worsfold said.Photo: Quinn Rooney
Worsfold also wouldn't single out veteran Jobe Watson for criticism, despite the midfielder's underwhelming performance, which included several blunders in the last quarter, instead apportioning blame to his entire on-ball unit.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Worsfold</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballarat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinn Rooney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Redpath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beveridge</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/Tracey Nearmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metricon Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Worsfold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
