<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397754198783761</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4821584/nba-guard-matthew-dellavedova-wows-warrnambool/?cs=310</url>
  <title>NBA guard Matthew Dellavedova wows Warrnambool</title>
  <content>
NBA guard Matthew Dellavedova wows Warrnambool

Warrnambool's Rylan Miller, 10, and Massimo Da Ros, 11, compete with NBA star Matthew Dellavedova during a skills session. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' under player Massimo Da Ros, 11, had Matthew Dellavedova sign his chest, as well as a ball. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 player Harry Annett, 10, is all smiles as he takes on NBA star Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Matthew Dellavedova stands with the Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 team which won a competition to bring the NBA star to Warrnambool. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Matthew Dellavedova signs a jersey for Warrnambool Seahawks' Finn O'Sullivan, 11. Picture: Rob Gunstone

NBA star Matthew Dellavedova having fun playing basketball with the Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 team. Picture: Rob Gunstone

NBA star Matthew Dellavedova having fun playing basketball with the Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 team. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Matthew Dellavedova signs a basketball for Warrnambool Seahawks' Logan Barby, 10. Picture: Rob Gunstone

NBA star Matthew Dellavedova having fun playing basketball with the Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 team. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Finn O'Sullivan, 11, gets up high to block the shot of Will Rantall, 10, during a drill with Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone

NBA star Matthew Dellavedova having fun playing basketball with the Warrnambool Seahawks' under team. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Matthew Dellavedova with Warrnambool Seahawks' under team helper Alex Annett, 14. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 player Will Rantall, 10, looks for an option as he takes on NBA star Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' under player Harry Annett, 10, is all smiles as he takes on NBA star Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone

NBA star Matthew Dellavedova having fun playing basketball with the Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 team. Picture: Rob Gunstone

NBA star Matthew Dellavedova having fun playing basketball with the Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 team. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' under player Harry Annett, 10, is all smiles as he takes on NBA star Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' under player Harry Annett, 10, is all smiles as he takes on NBA star Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 player Harry Annett, 10, is all smiles as he takes on NBA star Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' under player Will Rantall, 10,  looks for an option as he takes on NBA star Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 player Will Rantall, 10, looks for an option as he takes on NBA star Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Matthew Dellavedova looks for a way past Warrnambool Seahawks' player Rylan Miller, 10. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Matthew Dellavedova and Warrnambool under 12 player Massimo Da Ros, 11, watch as the team runs through a drill. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Warrnambool Seahawks' Nick Unwin, 10, Massimo Da Ros, 11, and Rylan Miller, 10, all wearing their Dellavedova tops, compete during a drill. Picture: Rob Gunstone

BA star Matthew Dellavedova talks to fans during a visit to Warrnambool. Picture: Rob Gunstone

SNBA star Matthew Dellavedova talks to fans during a visit to Warrnambool. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Matthew Dellavedova stands with the Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 team which won a competition to bring the NBA star to Warrnambool. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Matthew Dellavedova signs a jersey for Warrnambool Seahawks' Will Rantall, 10. Picture: Rob Gunstone

Matthew Dellavedova chats to the Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 team which won a competition to bring the NBA star to Warrnambool. Picture: Rob Gunstone

exit

NBA championship-winner Matthew Dellavedova wowed them in Victoria's south-west on Sunday.

Dellavedova, 26, spent one-on-one time with Warrnambool Seahawks' under 12 basketball team following its win in a 'Team Up With Delly' competition run by his apparel sponsor Peak.
Each player received a signed Dellavedova Australian Boomers' jersey and had their photo taken with the Olympian.

He then took ran a Q&A session and clinics with hundreds of aspiring south-west players at the Arc.
It was not his first visit to Warrnambool.
"My sister had a jamboree here once so I helped out," Dellavedova said. 

"I think I was the demonstrator when I was probably 14 at the coaches' clinics and we (my family) used to come down here on the summer holidays."
Seahawks players Finn O'Sullivan and Nicholas Unwin said the visit was "a dream come true".
"We did this Delly contest and we took a lot of photos around Warrnambool and Koroit," Finn said.
The pair said they asked Dellavedova "how he felt meeting LeBron and Kyrie (Irving)", about his first minutes in the NBA and who his basketball idol was.

Warrnambool Seahawks' under player Will Rantall, 10, looks for an option as he takes on NBA star Matthew Dellavedova. Picture: Rob Gunstone
Finn said his young Seahawks team had enjoyed a successful representative season.
"We were close in the Bendigo championship," he said.

"We just got knocked off against Sale but we still fought out hard and won the division two final."
Dellavedova, who played alongside Lebron James in Cleveland Cavaliers' historic 2016 championship before being traded to the Bucks on a four-year $38 million deal, said the depth of Australian basketball was increasing.
"I think it's the strongest it's probably been in a little while," he said.

"We've got eight Aussies in the NBA and a lot of Aussie girls in the WNBA and the NBL and WNBL are going in the right direction.
"The Boomers and Opals are going pretty strong as well, so I think it's a pretty exciting time for Australian basketball."

Warrnambool Standard
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irving</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>24</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland Cavaliers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas Unwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool Seahawks' Nick Unwin, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massimo Da Ros</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rylan Miller, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massimo Da Ros, 11</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dellavedova</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool's Rylan Miller, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool Seahawks' Will Rantall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool Standard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LeBron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Dellavedova</name>
    <count>32</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebron James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SNBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Up With Delly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seahawks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Gunstone</name>
    <count>30</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finn O'Sullivan, 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koroit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bendigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dellavedova, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Annett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rylan Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Annett</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Rantall</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dellavedova Australian Boomers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool Seahawks</name>
    <count>22</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool Seahawks' Finn O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrnambool Seahawks' Logan Barby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finn O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
