<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397625349763488</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/melbourne-storm-legend-cameron-smith-says-he-wants-to-play-400-matches-hes-selling-himself-short-20170730-gxlunx.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne Storm legend Cameron Smith says he wants to play 400 matches. He's selling himself short</title>
  <content>
When Cameron Smith does finally decide to retire, probably in his late 40s and still setting up tries and making tackles and wrapping referees around his little finger, how will he be judged?
He admitted after making his 350th appearance - a 40-6 hatchet job on Manly at AAMI Park on Sunday - that he had one eye on becoming the first player to reach the magical 400-game mark.

Up Next

Tigers trump disappointing Titans

01:30

More Rugby League Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Smith has blinder in 350th

Cameron Smith celebrated his 350th game and was on fire in Melbourne.

"But that's two more seasons and that equals two more pre-seasons," Smith said with coach Craig Bellamy sitting next to him at the post-match media conference. "He doesn't have them anymore," Bellamy smiled, referring to Smith getting most of the pre-season off because of his late finish to the year because he plays for Australia. 
Smith joined Bulldogs legend Terry Lamb on 350 matches and only a Mack Truck will stop him from surpassing Darren Lockyer's all-time mark of 355 by the time the finals roll around.

A strained pec muscle suffered last weekend against Canberra couldn't sideline him for even a week. Since joining Melbourne in 2002, he has missed just 34 Storm games and only 11 of those have been through injury. Bellamy rested him twice this year during Origin.
Smith is contracted next season and he's 34 but there's a feeling he has another season in him beyond that. When he danced down the left side late against the Sea Eagles, dropped the ball onto his left foot and perfectly grubber kicked into the in-goal for halfback Cooper Cronk to swoop and score, you sensed this bloke could just play forever. The only other player you felt this about was Steve Menzies, the Manly warhorse who was squeezed out to England at the end of his career.

Indeed, there seems to be more certainty around Smith's playing future than that of Cronk, who will leave Melbourne next year for love in Sydney but is still without a contract in 2018.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Smith has nothing left to prove. It's all done: Origin wins for Queensland, Test matches for Australia, Dally Ms, personal accolades, milestones, records.Photo: AAP
They're just waiting for him to retire so they can plonk him in about five or six hall of fames and then make him an Immortal. Only a very special player can have his place in history assured well before his career is over. And yet he keeps playing, keeps working hard, keeps doing whatever pre-season Bellamy wants him to do.
Perhaps of greater significance is that Smith was critical in putting the Storm back together following the salary cap scandal apocalypse that saw the club stripped in 2010 of all their silverware.Photo: AAP
They won the title in 2012 but have not been able to clinch one since. A side of this calibre, a club of this culture, a player of Smith's standing, surely deserves another premiership given their dominance of the past decade.
Some in the game will tell you that you don't necessarily judge success in terms of titles won. They're usually the ones who have never won anything.
With Cronk leaving and Smith and fullback Billy Slater in the twilight of their careers, securing one last premiership would nail down their respective legends.
Against Manly, the Storm machine was at its ruthless best. Put his durability aside for a moment. When it's all said and done and people are weighing up Smith's contribution, they will count him as one of the smartest players of all time.
He came to Melbourne from Brisbane as a halfback or five-eighth but ended up revolutionising the role of hooker with dummy half play that will one day be framed and hung in a museum.
Smith just has so much time.
With the Storm pressing the Manly try line early on, he took them on, ran to the defence and shovelled a flick pass back for rookie Jahrome Hughes to score the home side's first of the afternoon.
A try to Manly winger Matthew Wright in the 30th minute after he latched onto a beautiful cut-out pass from fullback Tom Trbojevic gave the visitors a sniff at 8-6.
But in reality it was always going to be the Storm's afternoon.
With Cronk's laser-sharp kicking game also telling, Melbourne scored just before halftime through winger Suliasi Vunivalu, and then ran wild with four more tries after the break.
It was always going to be Smith's afternoon. He finished with four try assists, landed five goals from seven attempts and topped the tackle count.
The player who never stops, playing out a career that seemingly will never end.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mack Truck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Menzies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Trbojevic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suliasi Vunivalu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Lockyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jahrome Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dally Ms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
