<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397676889371633</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/falcons-secure-finals-berth-in-state-league/3206804/</url>
  <title>Falcons secure finals berth in state league</title>
  <content>
RUGBY LEAGUE: The Falcons have secured a berth in the finals following a dominant victory, but there's still plenty of room for improvement according to coach Craig Ingebrigtsen.
The Sunshine Coast took on the Central Queensland Capras at Browne Park for the Intrust Super Cup clash on Saturday night and ran home victorious 44-26.
Ingebrigtsen said he was pleased with the result, but was frustrated his side started the game in a deficit.
"I'm getting a bit sick of it to be honest," he said.
"We were down 12-nil and they (Capras) had all the running and then we scored 26 points in about 15 minutes.
"That's really frustrating from a coaching perspective and it's something we want to solve before we get to the finals."
Ingebrigtsen said the Falcons were guaranteed a spot in the finals following the win but second place on the 14-team ladder was still up for grabs.
"It might make the players comfortable, but it doesn't make me comfortable as a coach," he said.
"But, I'm really happy that we're in the finals for the second year in a row and  what we do with that opportunity that's been presented is how we will be remembered.
"We've just got to make sure that we take it on and we embrace it."
Despite starting slow, the Falcons entered half-time in front 26-12. The side followed through with a further four tries in the second half to finish strong.
Ingebrigtsen said Lachlan Timm played well on his return, with Tui Kamikamica and Harrison Muller also putting in solid performances.
Alex Bishop's performance at hooker was a highlight for the coach.
"It was Bishop's best game of the year at nine," he said.
"He was really good and he played 80 minutes at nine and was just durable and got the job done."
The Falcons will hit the road for a third away game in a row this Saturday against the Mackay Cutters.
"It's a real big game next week and they're a really good footy team and we're looking forward to that contest," Ingebrigtsen said.
"They've had a bye this week so they'll be nice and fresh."
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
Why environmentalists want to see shark nets pulled out
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
There's something for everyone in our 10 Things To Do guide
Don't miss your chance to head out on the town with our Gig Guide
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
You wouldn't guess who's back
There some places even these celebs can't get into
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Ingebrigtsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Queensland Capras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Cutters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingebrigtsen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tui Kamikamica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrison Muller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intrust Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Browne Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Timm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falcons</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUGBY LEAGUE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
