<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397668299436955</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/rush-hour/rush-hour-stories-you-need-to-know-today/news-story/4f563989091c439a16670e8081f68ef3</url>
  <title>RUSH HOUR: Stories you need to know today</title>
  <content>
Passengers are warned to expect delays at airports around the country today. Picture: Tom Huntley

Share

6:55am
Royals had no sex for "seven years"
Prince Charles and Princess Diana didn't have sex for seven years, according to a new program on Britain's Channel 4, which lays bear the couple's marital dysfunction.
The program draws on taped sessions between Diana and her voice coach, claiming Charles was "all over Diana like a bad rash" when they first started dating, but it wasn't long before their sex life fizzled out altogether.
The Princess worked with Peter Settelen for two years in the early nineties to help improve her public speaking voice, and their appointments became a safe place for her to vent her anxieties and frustrations.
The show "Diana: In Her Own Words", reveals Charles told her he had a right to a mistress, that when Diana begged the Queen for marriage advice she was simply told "Charles is hopeless", and that she fantasised about running away with her bodyguard.

A new British TV show has laid bare Diana's anxieties and frustrations. Picture: Ken GoffSource:Supplied

Share on Facebook
Share on Twitter
Share on Google+
Share on Reddit
Email

6:30am
Passengers face nationwide delays
Airport security has been drastically ramped up following terror raids in Sydney over the weekend, with passengers are warned to expect long delays.
Thousands across the country have been hit with enhanced screening processes, including more ID checks and increased cabin and checked baggage inspections.
Teams of sniffer dogs will also be on hand.
Domestic travellers have been warned to arrive two hours before their flight; international three hours early.
"(Passengers) should limit the amount of carry-on and checked baggage so far as possible, as this will help to ensure that security screening is efficient," Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull said when he announced the enhanced security.

Security has been ramped up in Brisbane following terror raids at the weekend. Picture: Adam HeadSource:News Corp Australia

Adelaide passengers had lengthy delays at security, which will continue today. Picture: Tom HuntleySource:News Corp Australia

Share on Facebook
Share on Twitter
Share on Google+
Share on Reddit
Email

6:05am
Crash on Melbourne's EastLink
Melbourne drivers are warning to allow extra time on their commute this morning, following a crash on EastLink.
Southbound traffic has been affected, with two trucks and a car blocking the ramps onto the Monash Freeway at Dandenong North.
Drivers are advised to take the earlier exit onto Wellington Road.
EASTLINK Frankston bound - Bad smash, no access to the MONASH in either direction

Share on Facebook
Share on Twitter
Share on Google+
Share on Reddit
Email

5:45am
Sydney meat mincer bomb plan
Two father-and-son teams are allegedly behind a plot to blow up an international flight out of Sydney with a homemade bomb disguised as a meat mincer.
Until last week the four men were totally unknown to the nation's counter-terrorism authorities, with only one conviction for negligent driving between them.
But that all changed when police picked up a "small piece of intelligence" about the possible "Islamist-inspired" plot to use a crude explosive device.
It is believed the plot involved smuggling the bomb onto a flight bound for the Middle East, possibly Dubai, hidden in carry-on luggage.
Police arrested them Saturday due to the risk to public safety.
Five homes were raided across the city.
- to read more

Police foil plot to 'bring down plane': PM
1:59

Arrests in Sydney after anti-terror raids foiled a plot that reportedly involved blowing up an aircraft.

July 30th 2017
16 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Share on Facebook
Share on Twitter
Share on Google+
Share on Reddit
Email

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam HeadSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Settelen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Huntley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom HuntleySource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken GoffSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EASTLINK Frankston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MONASH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
