<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397706954143041</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/calls-for-auditor-general-to-probe-child-protection-system/8758578</url>
  <title>Calls for auditor-general to probe Tasmania's child protection system</title>
  <content>
There are calls for Tasmania's auditor-general to launch an investigation into the state's troubled child protection system.
The system has been plagued by controversy in recent months with strong criticism of residential care provider Safe Pathways, which had children removed from its care amid claims of neglect.
It has raised questions about the checks and balances that are in place.
In a letter obtained by the ABC earlier this month, the head of
It said
"The provider must submit monthly reports identifying the activities undertaken and their effectiveness, as well as progress towards KPIs (key performance indicators) and the outcomes identified in each child's therapeutic plan. Providers are also required to participate in fortnightly care team meetings with the child safety officers."
The ABC requested specific information from the department regarding whether those checks were adhered to.
Q. How many reports "identifying the activities undertaken and their effectiveness etc" were received by the department and how many should there have been?
A: "The care provider was monitored on an ongoing basis throughout the life of the contract."
Q: At any time were concerns about child safety or quality of care raised in any of these reports?
A. "Yes. As has been stated previously, concerns were first raised several months before . These were investigated and the organisation was placed under notice and a formal review commenced in October."
Q. How many "fortnightly care team meetings with child safety officer etc" took place while Safe Pathways were contracted and how many should there have been?
A. "Regular meetings were held."
The response did not satisfy Tasmanian Upper-House MP Ruth Forrest.
"I think there does need to be some way of checking on that," she said.
'I'll be contacting the auditor-general'

Ms Forrest said she would be approaching Tasmania's auditor-general about conducting an audit of all external providers operating in the state.
"The terms of reference of such an inquiry or an audit would be important to ensure that you're not just saying, 'Yes the checks have occurred' but what the outcomes of those checks [were] and when problems were identified, what actions were taken," she said.
"I will certainly be communicating with the auditor-general to see what his view is on this."
Privately there is growing support for the probe with several key child protection groups telling the ABC the auditor-general was well placed to undertake such a review.
The ABC requested an interview with the head of the Department of Health and Human Services Michael Pervan, but he declined.
A similar investigation was undertaken in 2011, on the former state government's watch.
The .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Forrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Services Michael Pervan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Upper-House MP Ruth Forrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Safe Pathways</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q. How</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
