<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397968947151000</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/art-and-design/melbourne-arts/sigur-ros-bring-own-brand-of-equality-to-margaret-court-arena-20170728-gxkq0z.html</url>
  <title>Sigur Ros bring own brand of equality to Margaret Court Arena </title>
  <content>
MUSIC
SIGUR ROS ★★★ 1/2
Margaret Court Arena, July 27
Reviewed by Michael Dwyer

Here it comes, out of the calm: the shimmer and build, the keening and hammering, the tempest and the supernova. Immense computer projections escalate into molten eruptions and galactic implosions. Jonsi bends from the waist, sawing his electric guitar with a cellist's bow as decibels hit the red.Photo: Mark Metcalfe
This, of course, is how Sigur Ros rolls. But the mood has turned darker; more violent for the Icelandic storm-bringers. The remaining trio - bassist Georg Holm and drummer Orri Dyrason flank singer Jonsi Birgisson in the audio-visual maelstrom - seems determined to atone with force for the loss of keyboard player Kjartan Sveinsson.
The stage is dark, too, for much of act one. As neon lights creep up and along a forest of encircling poles, it begins in the gravel-crunching, metal-shearing present, then circles back to their ecstatic/ dramatic 1999 origins. It finishes with a couple of new pieces, ironically among the sweetest in Thursday's epic panorama.
A wordless departure signals the intermission we had to have. The cycle of grandeur and exhilaration is exhausting. Jonsi's flawless, airborne falsetto surely needs a gargle.
They return, behind the screen now, in a billow of pink smoke and lasers for the grim sojourn of Ovedur, which climaxes with white lights shooting from a pistol-shot snare sample. No, really.
It's impossible to guess what's making all that noise behind the simple tools of bass, drums, and bowed guitar. Sigur Ros is much, much bigger than three guys. It ends up combusting in the heart of a blinding red sun during a brain-melting stroboscopic storm. Naturally.
Jonsi says one thing to a mesmerised capacity crowd that dares, finally, to stand. It might be "Suck on that, Margaret Court," but alas, it's in Icelandic. During final bows, the show's only literal image occupies the screen: a rainbow map of Australia stamped with the word, "Equality."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonsi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonsi Birgisson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georg Holm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ovedur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIGUR ROS ★★★ 1/2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Metcalfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sigur Ros</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kjartan Sveinsson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orri Dyrason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Court Arena</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Icelandic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
