<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398011896824453</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/opinion/belle-taylor-the-facebook-failures-being-ignored/news-story/c4aa958942880a2e175972562665ddc5</url>
  <title>The Facebook failures being ignored</title>
  <content>
IMAGINE this: 200,000 Australian's get together in a giant arena and share naked photos of people taken without their consent, tell jokes about terrorism and discuss acts of violence. 
There are complaints, but when the police go to investigate they are stopped at the door of the arena by Mark Zuckerburg.
"I'm sorry," the Facebook founder tells police. "In America we call this freedom of speech. And even though the people in there are Australian, Facebook owns this land. We decide what goes on in there."
It would be absurd, right? But is this happening already?
Last week, the hidden Facebook group Bad Girls Advice was finally shut down after multiple complaints about the group. Some of the offensive content included pictures posted of naked men, seemingly without their knowledge. There were discussions of violence and even posts making fun of the Manchester bombing tragedy.

But it was not that content that led to Facebook removing the group. It wasn't until administrators approved a post that seemed to condone bestiality that there were enough complaints for the internet giant to take action.
But just days later, Facebook reinstated the group, telling a news.com.au journalist: "Our community operations team reviews millions of pieces of content per week and from time-to-time we make mistakes. In that instance, we restore the content and apologise to the people impacted by our error."
If bestiality falls within the boundaries of acceptable content, what doesn't?
If you think Bad Girls Advice is some sort of outlier fringe group, think again. The female-only Australian group had more than 200,000 members. Its brother group, the male-only Blokes Advice had a similar number of members when it was shut down in August last year after posts that seemed to support domestic violence.
Gable Tostee, the man acquitted of the murder of Warriena Wright, a woman he met on Tinder who died after falling from the balcony of his Gold Coast apartment, was a member of Blokes Advice. He offered up dating tips.
I have previously written about online groups that post sickening content. Some groups exist as "joke" groups, sharing memes that poke fun at topics such as the Holocaust and terrorism. Other groups are committed hate groups that target a single person, usually a blogger.
These groups are handy when members decide they want to "dox" someone, using their combined power to trawl the internet looking for personal information about a person to harass them with.

The members are not, as many people seem to believe, teenagers, or "the kind of people I don't associate with".
The members represent a range of age groups, professions and spheres of social influence.
I have seen women boast about having fake online profiles, called "alts", which they use purely to anonymously troll and bully people online. Their own profile, under their real name, will be full of inspirational quotes and details of the next (private) school fundraiser.
Shocking? Yes. Morally dubious? Definitely. So what can be done about it? Not a lot.
Under the Criminal Code Act 1995 (Cth) it is an offence to use the internet, social media or a telephone to menace, harass or cause offence. It is a Federal offence with a maximum penalty of three years in prison or a fine of up to $30,000, but it seems this is a law that is difficult to prosecute and rarely enforced.
It also doesn't assist when it comes to actually getting offensive content removed from the internet.
"There is no real softer legislation related to cyber bullying as such in WA under State legislation and this is what I'm trying to change," Paul Litherland of Surf Online Safe told me last week.
Litherland is a former officer with the WA Police technology crime investigation unit. He now has a business which sees him tour schools teaching kids about the dangers of the online world.
He says parents may be horrified when bullying content is posted about their child online, but there is surprisingly little the authorities can do.
Last week a Perth mother, Rosie, spoke out about her shock over a video of her 13-year-old daughter's friend Lara being beaten up after school. The video was posted on Facebook, and while the people filmed committing violent acts can be pursued by police, the act of uploading the video is not criminal.
"What are the authorities going to do about videos about kids being physically harmed and put out on social media?" Rosie asked a Perth journalist. "What is the penalty for that?"
There is none. But even if there was, getting content taken off Facebook is extremely difficult.
Facebook is a US organisation, and though it has 17 million active Australian users, our authorities have almost no control over the content on the popular site.
"We're talking WA Police and the fact that Facebook is in the US, so actually making physical contact with someone at Facebook is difficult, most of the reporting process happens via email and online," Litherland said.
"In the US with freedom of speech and all of that, they will say, 'Wait a minute, why do we need to remove it? Is it breaching law?' Well no, it's not. And they will consider that argument as well. Not that it is condoned in any way, but they will consider that aspect.
"That's the biggest hurdle for a lot of WA policing agencies that this is a US organisation you can ask them to remove it but getting them to be compelled by law internationally to remove it is extremely difficult."
The internet gives us an incredible power to connect.
But when our most popular social media networks are controlled in a foreign country, how much authority are we handing over to a company that we have no control over, with values that may not always gel with Australian ideas of right and wrong?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holocaust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Criminal Code Act 1995</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Litherland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Zuckerburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gable Tostee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Online Safe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Litherland of Surf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blokes Advice</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warriena Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bad Girls Advice</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
