<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398106386106129</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/ricciardo-taken-out-of-hungarian-gp-by-teammate-ve/3206838/</url>
  <title>Ricciardo taken out of Hungarian GP by teammate Verstappen</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN F1 star Daniel Ricciardo has blown up at his Red Bull teammate Max Verstappen after the 19-year-old's "amateur" mistake sent him crashing out of the Hungarian Grand Prix.
Sebastian Vettel eventually won the race, with Verstappen coming in fifth. But for Australian fans, the race was over after the very first lap.
Ricciardo started the race in sixth, one place behind his Dutch teammate. He passed Verstappen on the second corner, but as both cars reached the next turn, Verstappen collided with Ricciardo, sending him off the track and irreparably damaging his car.
"Someone hit me. Is that who I think it was?" a furious Ricciardo asked over the team radio.
"Yes," the team replied.
"F***ing sore loser," Ricciardo said.
He hadn't calmed down much when he spoke to reporters a short time later.
"That was amateur to say the least. It's not like he was trying to pass. He doesn't like people passing him," Ricciardo said.
"I didn't really know what happened. It's just frustrating, it was not even an overtaking move. It was an emotional response.
"I don't think there is an excuse for it."
Verstappen, for his part, was apologetic after the race.
"This is not nice and I apologise to Daniel for that, and also to the team, because we could have scored some good points here. I'll speak with Daniel in private and we'll sort it out," the Dutch teenager said.
"It is never my intention to his anyone, but especially not your teammate, and especially with the relationship I have with Daniel. It's always really good and we can always have a laugh."
There probably wasn't much laughing today.
Sebastian Vettel, meanwhile, increased his drivers' world championship lead to 14 points when he led Kimi Raikkonen home in a dominant Ferrari one-two finish.
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
There's something for everyone in our 10 Things To Do guide
Don't miss your chance to head out on the town with our Gig Guide
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
You wouldn't guess who's back
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Ricciardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Vettel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verstappen</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Verstappen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRALIAN F1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimi Raikkonen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricciardo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
