<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398097796171385</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/us-sports/kyrie-irving-laps-up-steph-currys-impersonation-of-lebron-james/news-story/2df176b13fa5d09b9d0292da1d8dca6c</url>
  <title>Kyrie laps up Curry</title>
  <content>
LeBron James And Tony Romo Humiliated By Director Judd Apatow

NEVER would™ve happened if they just stuck with the Chicken Dance.

A wedding for ex-Golden State Warrior and current Dallas Maverick Harrison Barnes became a LeBron James mock-session when one of James' jam-out songs was played, with Steph Curry imitating a dance the Cavaliers superstar posted on Instagram last month.

More relevant, though: That other Cavaliers superstar - the one who wants out, reportedly because he no longer wants to play second fiddle to James - couldn't stop laughing at his supposed arch-nemesis teasing his supposed teammate.

And the Kyrie Irving saga adds a petty, high school flare to it.

During Barnes' reception on the weekend, Tee Grizzley's First Day Out came on, the same song James used to pump himself up during an Instagram video on June 15. Curry has seen it, apparently enough to do his own version of James' intense dance, poking fun at the NBA's best player in the comfort of privacy and friends.

Except others - and James - now can see behind the curtain because an Instagram user uploaded the clip (and then deleted it, but not before others had captured it). And what stands out is that in the crowd, which Curry is amusing with a joke at James' expense, is Irving, egging on his supposed enemy.

The video adds another exceedingly trivial twist to the Cavaliers' hectic off-season, in which they are now trying to ship Irving away and trying to gear up for another NBA Finals run. All eyes though, for now, are on James' Instagram account for a response.

Irving wants to join the New York Knicks "very badly" after telling the Cavs he wants out of Cleveland.

who informed him of all the teams on Irving's list of desired destinations, the Knicks are at the top.

"I got a phone call, and the voice on the other end of that phone call is a trustworthy person," Torre said. "And he was saying to me that Kyrie Irving very badly wants to be a New York Knick. Kyrie Irving wants to come home."

When it was first reported Irving wanted out of Cleveland, it was speculated the All-Star point guard would be too expensive for the Knicks.

While the Knicks obviously would love to have the star point guard on the team, they do not want to part ways with rising star Kristaps Porzingis or big man Willy Hernangomez.

On the other hand, Carmelo Anthony (plus future picks) for Irving would be a deal the Knicks would take without hesitation. That scenario remains unlikely, however, because Anthony does not want it to happen.

Melo previously expressed interest in going to the Cavaliers, but that was before Irving's trade request went public.

Knicks fans still can hope newly hired general manager Scott Perry will figure out a way to bring the four-time All-Star to the Garden.

- with Thomas Lipe

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irving</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Star</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Lipe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willy Hernangomez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristaps Porzingis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmelo Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Knicks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA Finals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Maverick Harrison Barnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebron James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grizzley's First Day Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicken Dance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrie Irving</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knicks</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James' Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steph Curry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cavs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LeBron James And Tony Romo Humiliated By Director Judd Apatow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden State Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
