<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397964652183629</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/shocking-number-of-sexual-assaults-at-anu-to-be-exposed/8758638</url>
  <title>'Shocking' number of sexual assaults at ANU to be exposed as 'ugly truth' revealed by national survey</title>
  <content>
More sexual assault victims are expected to come forward when the "shocking" and "ugly" picture of the problem at the Australian National University (ANU) Canberra campus is revealed as part of a national survey.
The results of the largest student survey of sexual assaults and sexual harassment at Australia's 39 universities will be made public tomorrow.
Individual universities have been informed of their figures and are tightly guarding them before they publish their results after the national report by the Human Rights Commission, commissioned by Universities Australia, is released.
The ANU has the country's highest population of students living on campus and those close to the issue expect that to be reflected in the figures.
ANU vice chancellor Brian Schmidt warned the results would be confronting for those who had experienced sexual assault and he expected it to be the catalyst for many others to disclose their experience for the first time.
"The results will be shocking, and we should be shocked," he said.
"They will tell us an ugly truth about how young people in particular are affected by sexual violence."
Professor Schmidt said it was important to remind people who had experienced sexual assault that confidential help was available.
He promised to be personally involved in the ANU's response to the report.
"It is not an issue that we can simply acknowledge then move onto the next thing. It is an issue that we must deal with," Professor Schmidt said.
Earlier this month, the  in a pre-emptive move before the national survey was released.
That counsellor will be on campus full time from today and additional counsellors will also be available to students and staff over the coming weeks, to deal with an expected increase in the number of people seeking help and support.
ANU has also hired an independent consulting company to review all of its policies and procedures for dealing with sexual assaults and harassment, as well as appointing an external chair for a steering committee to oversee its response.
Online consent course rolled out to residential students

More than 2,000 ANU students from residential colleges have now completed an online consent education course that is being rolled out to all students.
The ANU said staff were also undertaking training in how to handle disclosures of sexual assault and harassment.
Ahead of the figures being released, the peak representative body for students, Universities Australia, has also arranged for a national 24-hour phone support line to operate until the end of November.
The service is run by specialist trauma counsellors from Rape and Domestic Violence Services Australia.
"We know the survey is likely to see a greater number of students seeking counselling support," Universities Australia chief executive Belinda Robinsonn said.
If you or anyone else you know has experienced sexual assault, there is help available:
Rape and Domestic Violence Services Australia: 1800 572 224 (24 hours from 9:00am today)
ANU Counselling Centre: (02) 6125 2442 (9:00am - 1:00pm and 2:00pm - 4:40pm)

Canberra Rape Crisis Centre: (02) 6247 2525 (7:00am - 11:00pm)

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's 39</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Schmidt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domestic Violence Services Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Rape Crisis Centre: (02) 6247 2525 (7:00</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Robinsonn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU Counselling Centre: (02) 6125 2442 (9:00</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
