<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398016191791798</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/four-police-divisions-dog-squad-take-aim-at-coast-/3206833/</url>
  <title>Four police divisions, dog squad take aim at Coast nightlife</title>
  <content>
A POLICE sting targeting the Sunshine Coast's busiest nightclub district has caught nearly 50 people driving on drugs and alcohol in 48 hours.
Sunshine Coast police detected 46 drivers with alcohol or drugs in their system during a two-night traffic operation over the weekend, targeting drivers leaving the Mooloolaba Safe Night Out precinct on Friday and Saturday night.
The Brisbane Dog Squad were called in to help during Operation Lockdown, which officers from Mooloolaba Police Beat, Nambour Road Policing Unit, the Sunshine Coast Criminal and the Roadside Drug Testing Unit.
In total 6243 roadside breath tests were conducted with 24 drivers returning a blood alcohol content over the legal limit, including one driver who allegedly had a positive BAC of 0.130%.
Officers also conducted 128 saliva tests with 22 drivers allegedly testing positive to driving with methylamphetamine or cannabis present in their system.
Police also charged seven people with 14 dangerous drug offences and three vehicles were immobilised during the operation.
Sunshine Coast District Officer Darryl Johnson said the results indicated some members of the community continue to risk their own lives and the lives of others by driving under the influence of drugs and alcohol.
"From a community perspective, these statistics are disappointing but the Queensland Police Service will continue to focus on road safety, using preventative strategies and operations like this to make Sunshine Coast roads safer," Superintendent Johnson said.
Police distributed 800 Are you about to Drink and Drive? leaflets onto vehicles parked in Mooloolaba prior to the commencement of the operation on Friday night.
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
There's something for everyone in our 10 Things To Do guide
Don't miss your chance to head out on the town with our Gig Guide
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
You wouldn't guess who's back
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast District Officer Darryl Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Safe Night Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Police Beat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Criminal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operation Lockdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roadside Drug Testing Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Road Policing Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Dog Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
