<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397840098130749</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/security-fears-at-australian-airports-lead-to-delays/news-story/09c0f21e25b6c0693e4a49f24cd0dc97</url>
  <title>'Crazy lines' at our tense airports</title>
  <content>
PASSENGERS are reporting "crazy lines" at Australia's largest airport on what is the first weekday morning since news broke of the Sydney-based terror plot to blow up a plane.
The Federal Government, airport management and airlines have been warning passengers to arrive much earlier than usual as security was beefed up at the country's biggest airports.
Travellers have been warned to arrive two hours before their domestic flight because of "additional scrutiny". Those flying internationally will need to arrive three hours before their flight is scheduled, with security experts expecting the arrangements will be in place for the foreseeable future.
Travellers are also being urged to limit the amount of baggage they take on flights to help speed up the screening process.
There are no changes to what can and cannot be carried on-board an aircraft.
Passengers in Sydney this morning took to social media to comment on the delays.
Few were caught unaware of the extra time needed after massive publicity since Saturday's terror raids, and after airlines began texting passengers directly advising them of the new measures.
Two would-be father and son terror teams linked by marriage are allegedlyout of Sydney using a homemade bomb disguised as a kitchen mincer.
Qantas, Virgin and Jetstar were alerting their passengers to arrive early - but then told them they would have to wait to check in their bags once they arrived.
However, one person pointed out Sydney Airport itself may have been caught short by the number of people arriving early.
3AW in Melbourne is reporting there are big delays at the Qantas check in at Tullamarine. One Twitter user said there were Federal police cars back to back at the drop off zones and "police everywhere" but queues looked OK.
The Herald Sun reported AFP and Victoria Police officers were patrolling the airport terminals in Melbourne as long queues formed outside security gates.
Immigration Minister Peter Dutton acknowledged the measures were causing "a disruption" to travel arrangements.
"If people don't need to be going to airports, if you can bid farewell to loved ones at the kerbside, if you don't need to go inside the security section, please don't," he told the Nine Network on Monday morning.
Sydney Airport tweeted this morning it appreciated the support and patience of passengers who had arrived early. However, some passengers have reported the "jam packed" T2 was being complicated by a broken down baggage
A Twitter user said the airport was "stuffed".
"There's no chance of catching this flight."
Police have said there was indication the integrity of airport security having been compromised, and began quietly introducing the increased security on Thursday.
They were forced to act on Saturday after determining the risk to public safety was too great if they waited any longer.
On Saturday afternoon, NSW and Federal Police in the Sydney suburbs of Surry Hills, Lakemba, Wiley Park and Punchbowl and arrested four men.
They are being held for an extended period under special legal conditions while investigators comb through evidence.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tullamarine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
