<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397964652183627</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:38</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/nsw-act/news/sydney-terror-plot-to-blow-up-flight-with-meat-mincer-bomb-foiled/news-story/1fc8b0ef610c68cd75a3b12ee396a8f7</url>
  <title>Sydney terror plot to blow up flight with 'meat mincer bomb' foiled</title>
  <content>
Alleged terror conspiracy suspects in custody
1:36

Four men arrested over an alleged terrorist conspiracy can be detained for a week, a magistrate has ruled.

July 31st 2017
3 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Where the raids took place.

Liz Burke and AAP

Share

A PAIR of father and son would-be terror teams will remain in detention for up to a week over a "very sophisticated plot" to bring down a plane departing Australia with a meat mincer.
The four Sydney men, arrested on Saturday afternoon over the alleged terror plot, have not yet been charged and police are combing through evidence.
The group's plan was thwarted when authorities picked up a "small piece of intelligence" about the possible plot to smuggle an improvised explosive device onto an international flight bound for the Middle East. Authorities say the plot was "Islamist inspired".
has reported the bomb may have been disguised as a kitchen meat grinder, that was to be carried in hand luggage onto a flight departing Sydney.
Other media reports suggested it could have been a "non-traditional" device that would have distributed poisonous gas within the plane.

Counter-terrorism officers lead a man from the Surry Hills house that was raided. Four properties across the city were raided by police. Picture: 9 NEWSSource:Channel 9

Police lead a woman from the raided home, while detectives searched inside. Picture: Damian ShawSource:News Corp Australia

The property at Lakemba on Sunday morning.Source:News Corp Australia
A kitchen device used to make sausages was among items seized in raids in five separate homes across Sydney over the weekend. Mobile phones and documents were also taken from the properties.
Police decided to arrest the men on Saturday after a period of surveillance, deciding the risk to public safety was high.
NSW Police and AFP officers swooped on five properties in the suburbs of Surry Hills, Lakemba, Wiley Park and Punchbowl on Saturday afternoon.
The four arrested, believed to be two groups of father and son, linked by marriage, are being held by AFP for an additional period of detention.

The men had previously been unknown to police and security agencies.
Speaking with ABC radio on Monday, Justice Minister Michael Keenan said authorities had uncovered what appeared to be a "very sophisticated plot" and would have undertaken "extensive planning".

Police shut down Cleveland St in Surry Hills as part of the operation. Picture: Damian ShawSource:News Corp Australia
A magistrate granted the extension, allowing authorities to hold the men for up to seven days while a complex investigation continues.
The thwarted plan has , with authorities enforcing extra security measures following the threat.
Travellers have been warned to arrive two hours before their domestic flight because of "additional scrutiny".
Those flying internationally will need to arrive three hours before their flight is scheduled, with security experts expecting the arrangements will be in place for the foreseeable future.

Forensic officers at the Surry Hills property on Sunday. Picture: Jeremy PiperSource:News Corp Australia
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull said the threat of terror in Australia was "very real".
NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller said police had to act when they did.
"With terrorism you can't wait, you can't wait to put the whole puzzle together, you do have to go early because if you get it wrong the consequences are severe," he said.
"You need to make the decision at some stage, when is the right time to go. Both (Australian Federal Police) and NSW Police agreed last night was the right time to go."
AFP Commissioner Andrew Colvin confirmed the threat involved an improvised device and was Islamist inspired.
"We're taken this threat very seriously," he said on Sunday.
"You should infer that we think this was credible and there was an intention, and there was quite possibly a capability as well."

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull addresses the media following counter terror raids. Picture: Sam Mooy/AAPSource:AAP
Prime Minister Turnbull said airport security measures had been increased for public safety.
"The tight co-operation and collaboration between our intelligence and security agencies is the key to keeping Australians safe from terrorism," he said.
Travellers were warned to expect delays and increased scrutiny at all Australian departure points after security measures were "intensified". "Some of that will be visible, some of it will not be visible, but it will take more time," Mr Turnbull said.
In Surry Hills and Lakemba, where the men were arrested, neighbours have expressed shock.
"Never in my life would I have expected this ... they're a very nice family," one Surry Hills neighbour said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP Commissioner Andrew Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy PiperSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Minister Michael Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Commissioner Mick Fuller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damian ShawSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEWSSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mooy/AAPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
