<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397883047804209</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/national/carrara-children-left-petrified-after-taxi-rank-punch-up/news-story/ac80f44bbc791bca2db70cbcf63c9fa9</url>
  <title>Young fans</title>
  <content>
YOUNG AFL fans were left oepetrified" after witnessing a brawl while waiting for taxis outside Metricon Stadium on Saturday night.

Three people were taken to hospital after being injured in the melee believed to have involved about 10 people.

Witnesses said the fight broke out when two men began arguing during a long wait for a cab outside the Carrara stadium about 10.30pm.

Police confirmed they are investigating the incident that saw a 21-year-old man with a broken nose and a 45-year-old woman with back pain taken to the Gold Coast University Hospital about 11pm after Richmond's 33-point win over the Gold Coast Suns

A third man, believed to have been punched in the face, was also transferred to the hospital.

A Gold Coast woman, who claimed she alerted security to the altercation, said a man was knocked unconscious during the fight.

"The response time for the police was at least 15 minutes. By this time, one of the assailants had gone absolutely psychotic and was further up the road bashing his head into a barrier," she said.

"At least five police vehicles and motorbikes, eventually turned up and began a search for that assailant.

"Kids were petrified. Barriers at the taxi rank were pushed down. One more barrier knocked down would have meant the kids in front line ... would have fallen into oncoming traffic."

The woman said the fight had left her "shaken" because so many families were in the area.

"I do know that at least ten children have had their innocence taken away from them and shall have it instilled in their minds now that going to the football is a bad and frightful experience," she said.

Gold Coast Suns CEO Mark Evans said the behaviour during the night was overall "very good".

"There was an altercation somewhere about an hour post-game at a taxi rank between two groups of supporters," he said.

"Our stadium staff attended quickly and I believe then police may have followed that up with further action."

A club spokesman encouraged fans to use "free transport and park and ride solutions" to and from the stadium.

"Clearly taxis and other ride share companies are options fans use to get to and from the game, however at peak periods like Saturday night, these options can be stretched," he said.

"We will review the weekend's incident with all the stakeholders involved to ensure appropriate levels of resources are in place for every event at Metricon Stadium."

Two people were questioned by police on Saturday evening but released without charge.

Anyone with information is encouraged to phone Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metricon Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns CEO Mark Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
