<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398054846497760</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/08/42/worker-who-sued-coworkers-for-powerball-millions-moves-to-the-us</url>
  <title>Worker who sued co-workers for Powerball millions moves to the US</title>
  <content>
A Sydney factory worker who unsuccessfully took his workmates to court after he was left out of a winning $40 million Powerball syndicate has reportedly moved to the US after being left with a $1 million legal bill.

Brendan King, a father-of-five, left Australia two weeks ago after being given a transfer from his role at electricity factory Prysmian Group's Cromer plant on the northern beaches to one in South Carolina, The Daily Telegraph reports.

"It got too much for Brendan, he's a good guy, he transferred with the company to Lexington two weeks ago and will be there for two years," Fahad Saleem, a co-worker from the Cromer plant, was quoted by The Daily Telegraph as saying.

"It's a fresh start in life for him and his family."

Mr King's move was confirmed by his solicitor, Simon Morrison, who described the change in his role as "a promotion".

Speaking to The Daily Telegraph earlier this month, Mr King admitted the legal battle - which resulted in him being ordered to pay the courts costs of the 14 colleagues he worked with in May last year - had taken a harsh toll on him and his family.

"I've got too many bills," he said from his Yarramalong home on the Central Coast.

"Whatever happens, my family remains my biggest treasure. But I can't pretend this hasn't been a stress on us."

Mr King, 44, maintains that he was the 15th member of the syndicate and that he is entitled to his $2.7m share of the winnings. It is understood that he has lodged an appeal against the court's decision.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prysmian Group's Cromer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr King</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr King, 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Powerball</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fahad Saleem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Carolina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lexington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarramalong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cromer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
