<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398054846497741</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/cricket/michael-clarke-takes-a-swing-at-steve-smith/news-story/8f55c0d5490f22972a9924e3971817c3</url>
  <title>Michael Clarke takes a swing at Steve Smith</title>
  <content>
Hussey:'Just get a deal done'
1:47

Cricket: Former Australian batsman David Hussey has stated firmly that a deal needs to get done now.

July 29th 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Cricket news and galleries/

Steve Smith and Michael Clarke together in their playing days.

Share

MICHAEL Clarke has criticised former teammate Steve Smith for his level of involvement in the ongoing pay war threatening to derail Australian cricket.
Cricket Australia (CA) and the Australian Cricketers' Association (ACA) have been at loggerheads as the two parties try to come to an agreement on a new Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) for all professional cricketers in Australia. Players have been unemployed since June 30, when the previous MOU lapsed.
If a deal can't be struck, crisis talks will likely go to arbitration where an independent party will make a ruling on the matter.
Smith has been largely quiet as his vice-captain David Warner has led the way in making players' concerns public. When asked several weeks ago why he was the face of the players' movement rather than Smith, Warner said his skipper has enough on his plate so he was trying to ease Smith's burden.
While Clarke acknowledges Smith is in a tough position, he believes he needs to play a much greater role in helping a pay deal come to fruition.
"It's a tough one because I guess a lot of the criticism I copped as captain was being involved in too many things,'' Clarke said on Channel Nine's Sports Sunday.
"There are other people in the pecking order that need to take care of that - your job is to concentrate on what is on the field.
"That wasn't my style as captain-. My style was to be involved- with everything because on the field. Off the field, it's exactly the same. The team is the priority and, as captain, it's your job to look after that.
"Steve Smith is probably in a tough situation. He probably feels, 'I want to leave it to the ACA - that is their job and I want to concentrate on making sure we are prepared.' If the players are going to be involved, like they have been on social media, it needs to be led from Steve Smith the captain, definitely."

Clarke and Smith in their playing days.Source:News Limited
Earlier this month Smith posted a lengthy message on Instagram saying the players are not prepared to give up the revenue sharing model that has served Australian cricket for two decades. This is at the heart of the ugly pay war because CA wants to move away from this scheme, believing alternative models are better suited to providing resources and funding for grassroots cricket.
Smith was included in a video released by the ACA in June explaining its position, and there's been no shortage of Australian players making their positions clear on Twitter (Shane Watson, Mitchell Starc, Glenn Maxwell, Peter Handscomb and Meg Lanning are just a few of those who have been active in pushing their message on social media).
Clarke said the ongoing dispute was a "horrible look for our game" and is adamant Australia's chances of winning the Ashes are being harmed with every day the conflict wears on.
"As a (former) player, I'm saying if a deal's not done by Monday afternoon allow it go to arbitration because we need this finalised," Clarke said.
"I believe this is definitely going to arbitration, and I think the ACA would be silly to say no to it. The players can't say no, the players have got to say yes because they've got to play.
"This (Australia men's) team cannot afford to miss one game of cricket if we want to beat England in the Ashes.
"We need to go to Bangladesh (next month), we need to go to India for the ODIs (in October), and then we need to play our best cricket to beat England in Australia, which I believe we will if we've played some cricket together as a team.
"This needs to be done between CA and the players' association, and the players need to do what (they) know best and that's to play this game we love."

ACA CEO Alistair Nicholson is determined to fight to keep the revenue sharing model.Source:AFP

CA CEO James Sutherland has been critical of the ACA for not showing enough of a commitment to getting a deal.Source:AAP
But despite Clarke's advice for Smith, the 28-year-old has been involved behind the scenes.
Smith has had held productive conversations with the ACA and CA over the past few days in the hope of helping to find a way through the mire.
, but in recent days he has also taken calls from and met in person with CA head of team performance Pat Howard. The skipper is eager for information and keen to provide feedback on behalf of the players.
There is no suggestion Smith is the magic mediator to broker one of the most bitter fights in the game's history, however, it's clear as cricket's spiritual leader in this country, the 28-year-old has taken on an active role in expressing his desire for the war to be ended.
The ACA sent a letter to players on Saturday detailing how CA's plan for arbitration could drag on past the start of the Ashes series and cost hundreds of thousands of dollars. CA responded by emphasising players would be contracted throughout any arbitration process and therefore the Ashes wouldn't be impeded in that scenario.
- with Ben Horne, News Corp Australia

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Handscomb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarke</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA CEO Alistair Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.25</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memorandum of Understanding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ODIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CA CEO James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine's Sports Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Horne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Starc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hussey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg Lanning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Hussey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Former Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Clarke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
