<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398097796171445</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/garry-lyon-says-daniel-wells-failure-to-arrive-at-collingwood-in-good-shape-has-contributed-to-pressure-on-nathan-buckley/news-story/436755a722d8691ba6564022a4743fae</url>
  <title>'He may have cost Nathan Buckley his job'</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE great Garry Lyon says high-profile recruit Daniel Wells could have cost Nathan Buckley his job, due to his failure to arrive at the club's pre-season in good shape.
Wells didn't make his club debut for Collingwood until Round 5 and also spent time on the sidelines midway through the year with calf issues.
Off the back of Wells' sublime 34-disposal, three-goal showing against Adelaide, Lyon said the Pies could easily have secured enough wins to relieve the pressure on Buckley, had the former Kangaroo been fit to feature more frequently.
"If I was Nathan Buckley, I would be that disappointed in him. He may have cost Nathan Buckley his job," Lyon said on SEN Breakfast.
"It could have been the best game he's ever played, but the fact of the matter remains - due to the fact he turned up in an unfit state to execute the contract - what's in his contract may have cost Nathan Buckley his coaching career."
Wells joined Collingwood as a free agent on a big-money, three-year deal at the end of last season.
But the Pies have since drawn criticism for recruiting the silky-skilled midfielder - especially when Nathan Buckley admitted Wells "wasn't in match condition" when he arrived at the club.
Wells has played just nine games for the Pies, winning six and drawing one - showcasing his importance when fully fit.
That said, Wells has added a touch of class to a workmanlike Collingwood midfield - making them a more threatening and dangerous outfit going forward.
"His performance yesterday was off the charts. 30 (touches) and three (goals) - these days that's the century in cricket parlance," Lyon said.
"We've spoken all year about the midfield and forwards at Collingwood, winning inside-50s and not converting.
"How different is it when you get the balls in the hands of the bloke that can put it on a featherbed?"
Lyon said Wells' quality made his failure to get fit even more disappointing.
"Bucks might have only needed one or two more wins to end the (contract) speculation," he said.
"He may keep his job, but we may have put this to bed in Round 12, or Round 10, had Daniel Wells fulfilled the part of his contract.
"I'm sure he gets the cheque and puts it in the bank pretty well, but getting back in a fit state would've been a better start.
"I'm really disappointed, I can't accept that, and I will take issue with anyone that tries to defend him on that."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Wells</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEN Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
