<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398059141465140</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/huge-queues-at-sydney-airports-t2-terminal-as-terrorism-security-increased-20170730-gxly5g.html</url>
  <title>Huge queues at Sydney Airport's T2 terminal as terrorism security increased</title>
  <content>
Huge queues of people snaked out Sydney Airport's domestic terminal T2 on Monday morning as passengers experienced lengthy delays to check in to their flights.
Crowds also gathered in the baggage claim area with the wait attributed to extra security after an alleged  was uncovered.Photo: Getty Images
Domestic terminal T2 - which handles Jetstar, Virgin and Tiger flights - was the worst affected with a long line of passengers going out the door and on to the footpath.
Confusion reigned as passengers were unsure of which line to join.

Passengers for domestic flights have been advised to check in two hours before take-off due to heightened security at the airport but those who arrived early had to be prepared to queue.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Passenger Sally Rugg tweeted that the check-in process would take at least an hour, with staff handing out water bottles to travellers.

They're handing out water bottles to people queuing to check in their baggage at Sydney airport - reckon the wait is at least an hour

Sydney Airport is understood to have put on extra staff to manage the increase in security measures. Security was beefed up late last week after authorities became aware of an alleged plot to blow up a flight bound from Sydney to the Middle East.
Four men were taken into custody in a series of arrests across Sydney on Saturday.
Air travellers have been warned they will need to be patient and limit both carry-on and checked-in luggage due to extra screening measures. 

This is the new normal

Most flights were leaving on time despite the length of time it was taking to check passengers in.
Sydney Airport has been contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T2</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Rugg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport's T2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
