<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398020486759114</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/man-charged-over-brutal-coast-assault/3206831/</url>
  <title>Man charged over brutal Coast assault</title>
  <content>
POLICE have charged a man following a serious assault on the Sunshine Coast.
Police allege that three men argued in a Mooloolaba carpark on Parkyn Parade in the early hours of Sunday morning.
The argument turned violent when one of the men punched a 19-year-old Pelican Waters man, causing him to lose consciousness and fall to the ground.
The man who punched the teen fled, before being caught by police on Parkyn Parade.
The 19-year-old received serious but non life-threatening injuries.
A 22-year-old Shailer Park man has been charged with assault occasioning bodily harm and police obstruction.
He will appear in the Maroochydore Magistrates Court on August 23.
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
There's something for everyone in our 10 Things To Do guide
Don't miss your chance to head out on the town with our Gig Guide
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
You wouldn't guess who's back
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things To Do</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pelican Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shailer Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gig Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkyn Parade</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
