<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398097796171381</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4814014/ready-or-not-newcastle-vegan-culture-comes-of-age/?cs=316</url>
  <title>Ready or not, Newcastle vegan culture comes of age</title>
  <content>
Passionate: Kate Parker says, "It's about not wanting cows and chickens to die."

About three years ago, a teacher and social media manager named Kate Parker started listing places on her art-teaching website where you could find good vegan food in Newcastle. Since then, not only has her little list turned into a full blown website, but also she's created a strong social media following for folks in the Hunter region with a hunger to learn about vegan food.
Growing trend

Parker said vegan food is a growing trend.
"When I first went vegan, it was the Natural Tucker shop; you could get one dahl and one pasta at Goldbergs", Parker says. "Now it's gone off in Newcastle."
The 30-year-old has been vegan for almost 10 years. She's also a casual teacher of art, photography, digital media, film and animation. Her artistic background is an asset for her social media work, particularly on Instagram.
"I think it's a fun way to communicate," Parker says of Instagram. "I started putting up my own photos, it just went from there. I used a medium for what it was for. There weren't too many businesses and non-personal accounts at the time [I started], and it grew up pretty quickly."
Currently her Instagram account, @NewcastleVeganGuideAU has nearly 13,000 followers.
"I think it's people who like good food, I don't think there's 12,000 vegans in Newcastle," Parker says. "I think there are more people thinking about the ethics of food and exploring veganism."
The Instagram account and website describes itself as "everything vegan in the Hunter Region". It features beautiful vegan dishes from restaurants and cafes, and people submit photos of their meal to the account. Newcastle Vegan Guide is a community effort, it doesn't make any money and is monitored by Parker and her friends.
FAVOURITES

Though the account has over 1600 photos of local vegan options, there are a few specific vegan dishes Parker recommends above the rest.
"There's the burger at Bonta Vera; get the tofu steak at Nagisa. Go and get the vegan banquet at Warners Bay Sephardim; it's Middle Eastern and Mediterranean. Also Masa Madre's vegan pizza," Parker says.
Her journey from vegetarian to veganism was a logical one.
"I was 18 when I went vego I found myself getting into lots of pro and anti vegetarian arguments. I started to realise through those debates that the logical conclusion for every argument for vegetarianism is veganism." Parker says.
She's never been able to work out why people are so aggressive towards people who are trying to do the right thing. For herself the decision to be a vegan is for animal rights and environmental reasons, particularly the environmental costs of the egg and dairy industry.
"It's about not wanting cows and chickens to die and male chicks to just be killed when they are only a few days old," Parker says.

"Do you really think there's millions of roosters on a happy farm somewhere?

"Female chickens make eggs, so they're kept alive. Once they're sexed, male chicks can be suffocated or electrocuted in mass.

"Laying hens are kept alive 18 months to two years, but when they become menopausal and aren't laying eggs anymore they are considered too old to be bothered with. They are killed for fertilizers and dog food."
She added that chickens killed for food are only allowed 12 weeks to live.
Parker is also an activist in more ways than just her diet.

She's a cook and she's catered many events for Newcastle Greens including anti-coal campaigns.

Using a shoestring budget, she has put together vegan feasts, which she feels is a better alternative than the chicken wings that used to be served.

She said vegan food seems more in line with the Greens' ethos.

She doesn't tie herself to train tracks but she does provide a necessary service.

Because her teaching job is tied to the state government, she can't do anything too "arresty."  
"I've always been a behinds-the-scenes person," Parker says. "Other people are out at the polling booths on election day, I always catered the election night party."

SPREADING THE WORD

In early July, Parker moved to Hobart to live with some friends, but she plans to keep close ties with Newcastle as her family is here.

Despite the distance, she'll continue managing her social media accounts. She's still involved with Newcastle Vegan Guide although her friends are doing more of the maintenance work.
With a friend, she's helped start Sydney Vegan Guide which has over 16,000 followers.

She's obviously been busy since she arrived in Hobart because her Hobart Green Guide website and Instagram is already flourishing with photos and information.  
"I like to show people it's delicious and easy, and you don't miss out anything," Parker says of her vegan initiatives.
She's clearly driven to encourage everyone to learn more about veganism.

Though she's passionate about the environmental and ethical benefits, Parker has never been too interested in its health advantages.
"My favourite food is chips," she says.

From Sephardim's vegan banquet.

Nagisa's tofu steak.

Bonta Vera burger.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parker</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natural Tucker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Parker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonta Vera</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Greens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nagisa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sephardim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Vegan Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masa Madre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warners Bay Sephardim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart Green Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldbergs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Vegan Guide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Region</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NewcastleVeganGuideAU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
