<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397973242118317</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/markets/australian-markets/hopes-rise-for-upbeat-profit-season/news-story/83b7ef7321f6e7555f208fc28759d52f</url>
  <title>Hopes rise for upbeat profit season</title>
  <content>
CommSec: US Close 31 July 17
2:53

US sharemarkets were mixed on Friday. Blue-chip shares rose but technology shares eased modestly. Shares in Amazon lost 2.5% in response to its earnings result. Amongst other large decliners on the day were Altria (-9.5%), Mattel (-7.8%) and Starbucks (-9.2%). The Dow Jones rose by almost 34 points or 0.2% to a record high.

July 31st 2017
an hour ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Finance - syndicated/

Earnings reports begin rolling in this week. Picture: Mick Tsikas/AAP

Trevor ChappellAAP

Share

EXPECTATIONS are upbeat ahead of the looming company reporting season with analysts expecting a reasonably good set of results from Australia's listed companies when earnings reports start rolling in this week.
The consensus estimate of overall earnings growth in 2016/17 is 13 per cent, with the strongest results in the resources sector.
Citi analysts Tony Brennan and Mark Tomlins say results will be varied but balanced, with as many sectors likely to have experienced improved business conditions over the past financial year as those that have experienced deteriorating conditions.
Although consumer spending has been subdued and housing activity may be slowing, the fall in mining investment is levelling off and infrastructure spending has increased.
Also, fewer companies have issued profit warnings than is usual in the so-called "confession season" that precedes each reporting season, with downgrades mostly limited to consumer stocks and small-cap companies.
"FY17 appears to have been stronger than usual for market earnings growth, underpinned by the recovery in resources earnings, and modest growth in industrial earnings," the Citi analysts said in a research note. The resources sector has benefited from a recovery in commodity prices, and energy utilities have benefited from higher power prices.
High levels of residential housing construction and more infrastructure projects are expected to boost the profits of companies supplying building materials. Infrastructure projects are also expected to have benefited engineering firms. Also, firmer premium rates have been positive for insurance companies. But retailers and companies in the leisure and gambling sectors are likely to have been impacted by subdued consumer spending.
Strong competition and low price inflation is expected to weigh on the supermarket operators.
Sales into China will be a bright spot for food and beverage suppliers but domestic sales less so.

Stronger regulation and competition are expected to mute the revenue growth of banks.
Perpetual Private head of direct equities Stephen Kench predicts that the upcoming earnings season will be reasonably positive and reflective of what came out of February's round of reports.
Mr Kench said the first half of 2016/17 had produced the best reporting season since February, 2010, in terms of positive earnings revisions. Also, companies had generally exhibited an improved level of confidence not seen since the global financial crisis.
"I think more of the same is what we see coming through (in the second half)," he said.
Mr Kench said investors would focus on company outlooks, including any potential impact from the erratic political environment of the last three to six months, the federal budget's tax on banks, and affordability issues for consumers arising from higher healthcare, energy and mortgage costs.
"So, do management still have a level of confidence that we've seen in business surveys over the last six months, or are they starting to put caveats on their outlook?" Mr Kench said.
UBS strategists David Cassidy and Dean Dusanic say it will be interesting to see the extent to which expected gains and losses are already reflected in existing stock prices.
Reporting season a year ago was notable for investor disappointment with highly- priced companies, the UBS duo said.
"Areas where growth is available have been bid up aggressively this year - for example, healthcare," they said in a research note.
"This raises risks of stock-specific disappointment as we move into reporting season."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CommSec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue-chip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Tomlins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Finance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Altria (-9.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February, 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Brennan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Dusanic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kench</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor ChappellAAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mattel (-7.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Close 31 July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FY17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Tsikas/AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Cassidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Kench</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starbucks (-9.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
