<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397925997477573</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/kate-beckinsales-terrifying-comic-con-close-call-with-stalker/news-story/e9f5f37577f1eb351f515cadf8d78601</url>
  <title>Kate Beckinsale's terrifying Comic Con close call with stalker</title>
  <content>
Kate Beckinsale Has Never Had a Full Glass of Alcohol
0:53

Kate Beckinsale says she's never had a full glass of alcohol because it affects her very quickly.

December 29th 2016
7 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Kate Beckinsale had to delay her Comic Con appearance when a stalker turned up to the festival. Picture: Jeff Spicer/Getty

Lauren FranklinThe Sun

Share

KATE Beckinsale was forced to postpone her Comic Con appearance yesterday following an incident with an "overzealous fan" who has been following her across America for the past year and even threatened to stab her.
According to, police arrested the man named Terry Lee Repp, 45, at the Tampa Bay convention after they were instructed to look out for him due to his sinister history with the British star.
An officer recognised him before Kate, 44, was due to appear on her 11am Q&A panel,  reports.

Kate Beckinsale's Comic Con appearance included a close encounter with a crazed fan. Picture: GettySource:Getty Images
They arrested him on the spot before taking him to jail and booking him for stalking.
In documents obtained by the website, cops say he appears to "have an irrational obsession with the victim and has travelled across the country in an effort to harass her."
The harassment has gone on for at least a year, and in 2016 made physical contact with her at an event in Salt Lake City where he touched her back and threatened to stab her.
He saw her at another event in Houston at which he was detained by police.

Kate Beckinsale's stalker, Terry Repp. Picture: Hillsborough County SheriffSource:Supplied
While Terry Lee Repp didn't make contact with Kate this time she did file a report at Hillsborough County Jail, she also did the panel later in the day, as a delighted fan shared on social media.

A post shared by RB (@alphaextreme85) on

While Kate may be enduring the ordeal of a stalker, her personal life is going from strength to strength.

She has recently found love with .
A source told Entertainment Tonight Kate met Matt through a mutual friend and they are "officially boyfriend and girlfriend".
They added: "They quickly started flirting, went on their first date and it's continued since.
"Everyone in Kate's circle loves Matt and are so supportive of this relationship."
This story originally appeared on and is republished here with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comic Con</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Lee Repp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Full Glass of Alcohol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Tonight Kate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KATE Beckinsale</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salt Lake City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren FranklinThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillsborough County SheriffSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GettySource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Repp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillsborough County Jail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tampa Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Spicer/Getty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Beckinsale Has Never Had</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Beckinsale's Comic Con</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
