<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397921702510229</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/national/refusal-to-resolve-samesex-marriage-political-suicide-says-liberal-senator-20170729-gxlkji</url>
  <title>Refusal to resolve same-sex marriage political suicide says Liberal senator </title>
  <content>
Western Australian Liberal Senator Dean Smith says the Turnbull government will be committing political suicide if is does not resolve the issue of same-sex marriage with a parliamentary vote before the next federal election.
In a clear signal Senator Smith and Coalition moderates intend to push the issue internally when Parliament resumes next week, he argues younger voters are already deserting the Coalition in droves.
He says the Liberal party vote among 18-24 year olds has fallen from 50 per cent to 26.9 per cent over the past four federal elections and, at last year's election, Labor was 25 percentage points ahead of the Coalition among this age group.
"The most compelling argument for dealing with this matter now is its importance to younger voters," he writes in today's The Australian Financial Review.

"Bill Shorten and Labor are delighting in the massive political advantage this gives them among young adult voters who comprise 35 per cent of the enrolled population.

"The government should not feel obligated to commit political suicide by handing its opponents a massive political cudgel by allowing the question of marriage equality to remain unresolved and fester over the next two years."
The government went to the the last election promising no change to same-sex marriage without a plebiscite first. A plebiscite was scheduled for February this year but Labor, the Greens and the Nick Xenophon Team argued a plebiscite was unnecessary, expensive and harmful and voted in the Senate to block it.
Subsequently, Mr Turnbull and his predecessor Tony Abbott  in which the Liberals would be given a free vote because it would break an election promise. Any policy change must be first be put to the people at the next election. In addition, the conservative wing of the Liberal Party, already ranged against Mr Turnbull, would start a civil war if the issue were brought forward now.
Private members bill

But Senator Smith, who is preparing a private members bill, contends the government upheld its end of the bargain by trying to hold a plebiscite and should now just get on with it.
"While it's true the government has an election commitment to pursue a plebiscite, it is also true that despite its best endeavours the Parliament will not support it because of its $170 million price tag, $15 million in public funding for 'yes' and 'no' campaigns and most importantly the admission by some Coalition parliamentarians they would not be bound by its result," he says.
"Far too much time and energy has already been consumed by this debate. It is time to resolve the matter, in Parliament, as our Constitution provides."
Senator Smith notes that given the political argument is primarily about process, not the pros and cons of same-sex marriage, "it signals a profound shift in the momentum of the public discussion," he says.

"The politics of the marriage debate have evolved and continued inaction is becoming harder to defend."
Two years ago, the moderates forced a party room discussion on same-sex marriage. Mr Abbott had underestimated the level of support in his ranks and that meeting was a key factor in ending his leadership just two months later. He nominated a plebiscite as a fall-back policy to hold the party together and Mr Turnbull, who opposed a plebiscite, agreed to one as policy as a condition of taking the leadership from Mr Abbott.
In the past week, Labor leader  but says a same-sex marriage plebiscite is not warranted because it involves no constitutional change.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
