<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397968947150981</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Tech Guide</source>
  <url>http://www.techguide.com.au/reviews/laser-4k-smart-tv-player-review-bring-world-content-tv/</url>
  <title>Laser 4K Smart TV Player review - bring a world of content to any TV - Tech Guide</title>
  <content>
Related Articles

If you're after an easy and affordable way to turn your existing television into a smart TV then you'll find the answer with the new Laser MMC-X40 4K Smart TV Media Player.

The small device - about the size of an Apple TV or Telstra TV unit - connects to your TV via HDMI and to the internet with a cable or Wi-Fi.

There is no set up involved, you just connect the Laser 4K Smart TV Media Player to your TV or computer and you can get started.

Users can access streaming services like Netflix, Stan and YouTube and play 4K content.

The device is running Android so it is also possible to install apps from the Google Play Store to run on your TV including all the catch-up TV apps like SBS On Demand, Tenplay and ABC iView as well as use the built-in browser to surf the web.

And because you have access to the Google Play Store, you can also install apps like Foxtel Now and stream your content even though there is no native Foxtel App on your television.

But the fun doesn't end there.

There is also a microSD card slot so you can view your own videos and photos through the Laser 4K Smart Media Player on TV.

Three USB ports can also be used to transfer content or to connect a Bluetooth dongle for a mouse or keyboard.

It even has Miracast so you can mirror content from your smartphone or tablet on your TV screen.

The Laser device is also DLNA compatible so it's possible to access content that is stored on connected hard drives and computers on your network.

It can play high compression files from H.265 and 4H UHD at 60fps (frames per second).

The Laser 4K Smart TV Media Player comes with a two-sided controller that can act as a remote, a mouse and a keyboard.

The controller was frustrating to use at times with the on-screen mouse hard to control.

The directional controls were also a little temperamental but we still managed to navigate the system.

For our review, we connected the Laser 4K Smart TV Player to a computer monitor and to our TV.

When it was connected to the monitor, we paired a Bluetooth mouse and keyboard to the device and were able to easily navigate the system.

Connected to the TV, we had to rely on the Laser controller which wasn't always as intuitive as we hoped for.

But despite that, there is no denying the fact that the Laser 4K Smart TV Player offers plenty of bang for your buck and helps deliver a huge amount of content that you may not have been able to otherwise access.

VERDICT

The Laser MMC-X40 4K Smart TV Player is a gateway to an amazing amount of content and convenience so you can turn any TV into a smart TV.

Rating - 75%

75
%

PROS: Easy to connect and set up, turn any TV into a smart TV, offers access to a huge amount of content, works with a TV or computer.

CONS: Remote not as responsive and easy to use.

VERDICT: The Laser MMC-X40 4K Smart TV Player is a gateway to an amazing amount of content and convenience so you can turn any TV into a smart TV.

User Rating:   Be the first one !

Related Posts

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laser 4K Smart Media Player</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HDMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H UHD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K Smart TV Player</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H.265</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laser 4K Smart TV Player</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laser 4K Smart TV Media Player</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS On Demand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Play Store</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tenplay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel App</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laser MMC-X40 4K Smart TV Player</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>microSD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluetooth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC iView</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laser MMC-X40 4K Smart TV Media Player</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miracast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DLNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CONS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
