<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398278184800725</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/07/heres-what-everyone-says-about-how-the-tesla-model-3-drives/</url>
  <title>Here's What Everyone Says About How The Tesla Model 3 Drives</title>
  <content>
Now that the  is finally here in production form with the earliest deliveries going out last night, it's time for the wave of driving impressions. Here's what people are saying about how the Model 3 looks, feels and performs in the real world.

AU Editor's Note: Most of the performance figures in this article are still in MPH. Tesla hasn't released 0-100km/h figures for the Model 3 yet, which is actually 0-62mph and can take a tiny bit longer. Nonetheless, enjoy. - Cam

On paper, the $US35,000 ($44,000 directly converted into Australian dollars - Cam) Tesla Model 3 has a claimed 0-60mph time of 5.6 seconds with the standard 350km range battery trim and a 210km/h top speed, or 0-60mph in 5.1 seconds with the longer range 500km battery that tops out at 225km/h. Its platform is similar to that of the Model S and Model X, with a low center of gravity thanks to the low-slung, sled-like battery positioning.

It's obviously the smallest car in Tesla's current lineup, but still offers seating for five, enough storage up front for a carry-on bag, and a revised trunk opening from the concept model shown off last year. So what is like to drive the Model 3?

You can check out a brief video drive over on MotorTrend, who described the ride as sporty, with almost no body roll, decent steering feedback and sharp handling. From MotorTrend's write-up:

Electrek's first impressions detail the interior, revealing that the Autopilot activation is now clearly labelled on the stalk on the right of the steering wheel with the other drive options. Also notable is mention that the regenerative braking on the Model 3 feels substantially weaker in the driving dynamics than on the Model S and Model X.

Electrek also noted that they weren't too comfortable looking at the center screen for driving information, and that it would take time to get used to, from the write-up:

For those curious about the build quality on the new Model 3, USA Today reported that the fit and finish was good, but of course this is a demonstration model that was probably carefully screened before issued for test drives. From USA Today:

As for interior volume, the best word came from Tim Stevens over at Roadshow, who said there isn't much concern over fitting whatever you might need in the Model 3:

Other than that, Top Gear had the only initial impression that mentioned an actual demonstration of Autopilot while in the Model 3, and the experience sounds on par with what we've come to expect with the semi-autonomous system in Tesla's other cars.

All of these initial impressions were in the Long Range trim Model 3, which is priced higher at $US44,000 ($55,000 directly converted to Australian dollars - Cam), and many of the test cars were apparently owned by Tesla staff and had been option well beyond that price point.

Overall, things look good for Tesla's revolutionary new electric car, but of course nothing compares to long-term testing and the revelations of actual ownership. Still, this is a strong start, and if Tesla can deliver a sporty, reliable driving experience with a tight finish to all of its claimed half-million deposit holders, the Model 3 just might live up to its hype.

WATCH MORE: Car News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Car News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everyone Says About How</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Electrek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla Model 3 Drives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model 3</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model X</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model S</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US44,000 ($55,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MotorTrend</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top Gear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA TODAY</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US35,000 ($44,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AU Editor's Note</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roadshow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla Model 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
