<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398230940159881</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/boss/how-maseratis-glen-sealey-learned-to-sell-luxury-cars-20170707-gx6iuw</url>
  <title>The secret to selling luxury cars</title>
  <content>
by
Glen Sealey

Glen Sealey is managing director of luxury car brand Maserati ANZ. He was born and raised in Condobolin in the far west of NSW. He is a third-generation car dealer.
After school I would go home via the [family's Ford] dealership. Hanging around, you soon see what's going on but you also participate in the conversation at the dinner table over debtors,parts stock, new cars and the like.
Being a small dealership, the whole family worked in it. My father ran the business as dealer principal, mum ran the office, my brother was a mechanic and my sister worked in the office with my mother.
If there was one thing I learnt early in life, it's that I would never be a good car detailer.

Supplied

These Ford Courier utes would come in from the farmers and had to be cleaned and reconditioned ready for sale. You could do the outside and the engine, and everything would be going well. Then you'd get to the interior. You'd be running a rag along the base of the seat and think you've got everything out but there would still be thistles down there and you'd cut your hand.

I always wanted to work at the dealership, but my father said, "Before you come back here, you have to go off and earn your keep somewhere else first."
So after I graduated from university I thought, "Let's go out and have a look at this big bad world before I go back." Unfortunately, I've never gone back.
My first job out of university was with [computer company] Compac. But I'd be talking to my family and friends in the automotive industry and I thought, "You know what? I really, really enjoy that industry. I really see a future for myself in the car industry."
So I put my hand up for a job, my first job in the motoring industry, as a marketing co-ordinator for Suzuki.

People look at this industry in many ways but I can tell you it's a very dynamic, structured business. It's also colourful: you meet some colourful characters. It's a lot of fun.
Dealing with the top end of the markets is like selling in the country. In a country town you sell more at the golf clubs, at the rugby and social events than you ever will sitting in a dealership.
At the bottom end of the market in the city, you can sit there and wait for people to come in and buy their car. But at the top end of the market, it's about relationships.
Glen Sealey spoke to Theo Chapman.

Like Leadership with the Financial Review on . Follow us on . Join the  conversation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzuki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Compac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theo Chapman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Sealey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Condobolin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Courier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maserati ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
