<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398183695518945</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/duchess-of-cambridge-stuns-in-paper-plate-hat-on-royal-tour-of-belgium/news-story/28c00899e57f695964183c16b920ca20</url>
  <title>Kate stuns in 'paper plate' hat</title>
  <content>
THE Duchess of Cambridge has again showed off her thrifty side, re-wearing an outfit while in Belgium ... and she turned heads with her striking headwear.
Kate accompanied her husband, the Duke of Cambridge, to Belgium to commemorate the centenary of the Battle of Passchendaele.
The Duchess, 35, first wore the white coat-dress to her daughter Princess Charlotte's christening. She teamed the Alexander McQueen outfit with a white John Lock and Company hat, which resembled a paper plate or satellite dish, and Balenciaga pearls.
The Duke and Duchess of Cambridge are accompanying Prince Charles to Belgium on the request of the Queen, where they paid tribute to the tens of thousands killed in one of the First World War's bloodiest conflicts.
The couple stood in solemn silence as the Last Post sounded and more than 54,000 poppy petals - one for every man who died - cascaded down at an emotional service to mark 100 years since the Battle of Passchendaele began.
Prince William and Kate were in Belgium for a two-day commemoration of the battle, fought near Ypres between July 31 and November 10, 1917. In all, 325,000 Allied soldiers and 260,000 Germans were killed or wounded.
William and the king of Belgium laid wreaths at the Menin Gate memorial in Ypres, which bears the names of more than 54,000 fallen soldiers aged between 15 and 60 who have no known grave.
William, wearing a poppy and his medals, told the commemoration crowd: "During the First World War, Britain and Belgium stood shoulder to shoulder".
"One hundred years on, we still stand together, gathering as so many do every night, in remembrance of that sacrifice," he said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ypres</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duchess, 35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battle of Passchendaele</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Last Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First World War</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menin Gate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 10, 1917</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Lock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duchess of Cambridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke of Cambridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgium</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander McQueen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Charlotte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balenciaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
