<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398239530094565</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/07/irobot-says-your-data-is-safe-but-always-read-the-eula/</url>
  <title>iRobot Says Your Data Is Safe - But Always Read The EULA</title>
  <content>
Last week, we reported that iRobot, the company famous for bringing the Roomba into our homes was looking at  pertaining to the internal maps of customers' home. The company's CEO has sent us a statement clarifying iRobot's position.

Colin Angle, Chairman, CEO and Founder of iRobot says

"iRobot does not sell data as our customers always come first. We will never violate their trust by selling or misusing customer-related data, including data collected by our connected products. Right now, the data Roomba collects enables it to effectively clean the home and provides customers with information about cleaning performance. iRobot believes that in the future, this information could provide even more value for our customers by enabling the smart home and the devices within it to work better, but always with their explicit consent.

This is good news but it's a good reminder to read the user agreement of any device or application that collects data about you, your home or business.

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iRobot Says Your Data Is Safe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iRobot</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Founder of iRobot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roomba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Always Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Angle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
