<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398226645192560</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/whats-on-tv-wednesday-august-9-20170728-gxl2b6.html</url>
  <title>What's on TV: Wednesday, August 9</title>
  <content>
Hijacked
SBS, 8.30pm
A series that won't be playing on any airline in-flight entertainment systems this millennium, Hijacked tells the stories of famous real-life terrorist incidents, kicking off with the 1970 effort by the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine, in which they commandeered five planes in a matter of days. Sticking to the tried and true formula of recreations intercut with modern-day reflections from key players, it tells the story well enough, although from our fearful 2017 perspective it seems positively surreal to see people pulling out guns on planes. LDUtopiaPhoto: Hwa Goh
pay Stars of the Silver Screen
Fox Arts, 8.30pm
This pleasant British series has veteran film critics provide fascinating insights into the lives and work of some of the biggest names from the golden years of Hollywood. Tonight's subject is Joan Fontaine, and the program does a good job of charting her story from her birth in Tokyo in 1917 through her famously difficult relationship with her sister, Olivia de Havilland; her Oscar-winning triumph in Alfred Hitchcock's Suspicion; and the uproar that greeted the interracial romance between her character and Harry Belafonte's in 1957's Island in the Sun. It quickly becomes clear that nothing came easy - the pre-war movies that might have made Fontaine a star invariably flopped; Cary Grant and other stars took an instant dislike to her; and Hitchcock treated her dreadfully. Other actors profiled in coming weeks include Richard Harris, James Coburn and Dean Martin. BN
movie Pitch Perfect 2 (2015)
Nine, 8.45pm
As with most Hollywood sequels, the second of what will soon be three Pitch Perfect movies rounded off the rough edges of the original's plot about a misfit female a capella singing group triumphing against the odds and doubled down on the audience's favourites; that means a lot of quips from Rebel Wilson's Fat Amy. Anna Kendrick, whose formidable enthusiasm flags here occasionally, returns as Bella Bardens lynchpin Beca, with the former college group reuniting for a tilt at a world title after they're banned from performing in America in a Fat Amy-related disaster. Producer and co-star Elizabeth Banks takes on directing duties, and although she eventually runs out of ways to shoot the many zesty performances of pop hits, she does sharpen the focus on assertive female unity in the face of career setbacks and dismissive Germans. This only just avoids falling short on inspiration. CM
Utopia
ABC, 9pm
Anyone who has suffered through the purgatory of working in an office run by management apparatchiks will recognise the various human tropes who make Utopia such a bite-sized pleasure, from the office leader with a never-ending "vision" for the future, to the clueless chief executive with his heart sort of in the right place. This week the National Building Authority team gets involved with the sale of a port, and Tony (Rob Sitch) has to spend the night sleeping rough for charity, but line honours go to the absurdity of the office's digital upgrade in which they telecommunicate with people sitting metres away. LD
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stars of the Silver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Building Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Popular Front</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberation of Palestine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Belafonte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utopia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred Hitchcock's Suspicion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cary Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar-winning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hwa Goh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bella Bardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fat Amy-related</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC, 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fontaine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Kendrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebel Wilson's Fat Amy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Sitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pitch Perfect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Coburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LDUtopiaPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pitch Perfect 2 (2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havilland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan Fontaine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Banks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Arts, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hitchcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
