<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398269594865956</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/whats-on-tv-tuesday-august-8-20170728-gxl27c.html</url>
  <title>What's on TV: Tuesday, August 8</title>
  <content>
The House with Annabel Crabb (premiere)
ABC, 8pmPhoto: Josh Flavell
Writer, political journalist and accomplished baker Annabel Crabb introduces her six-part exploration of Parliament House by explaining that the Canberra institution is "the most scrutinised structure on the continent and yet, paradoxically, it's also one of the most secret". She then sets off on an upstairs-downstairs tour, taking in the new arrivals to the 45th Parliament in 2016 and its official opening, as well as activities in the basement loading dock and a glimpse of the Midwinter Ball. Crabb is a good guide: vivacious and articulate, she makes the stream of information about the building and its history, rules and rituals lively and illuminating. Her collection of fab frocks appears to have been toned down to a more subdued basic black for this production, but there's no absence of colour as it's shot with an artful eye. DE
Adam Ruins Everything
SBS Viceland, 8pm
Writer and comedian Adam Conover continues his investigations, which combine a light-hearted tone with serious debunking. In this episode, the target is weight-loss myths. Poor Sam is desperate to get in shape for his high-school reunion - a pool party, ugh - in order to impress the girl who once captured his heart. So he's initiated a concerted weight-loss campaign. Adam pops out of his fridge to demonstrate to him why his strategy - calorie counting, obsessive exercising, low-fat foods - is doomed to failure. Aided by a barrage of impressive statistics, the findings of a range of studies, and some snazzy graphics and animation, Adam details moves by the sugar industry over decades to demonise fats. He also manages to provide some more helpful strategies for happier, healthier living. Entertaining and informative. DE

movie Fantastic Four (2015)
Eleven, 8.30pm
Few critics liked this attempt to reboot the Marvel Comics title about a quartet of scientists and sidekicks whose experiments accidentally turn them into exotic superheroes. There are flaws, including the awkward insert of reshoots (you can spot them by the poor quality of Kate Mara's wig), but what I saw was an origin story where youthful connections endured and the thrill of discovery came with the cost of failure. Mara, Miles Teller (who has moments of soulful openness), Michael B. Jordan and Jamie Bell play the wayward four-piece, with Toby Kebbell as their colleague turned nemesis; his turn for the bad isn't entirely unexpected given that his character is named Victor Von Doom. Director Josh Trank hasn't worked since, but even if this fades out to merely set up sequels (that will never be made), it's a solemn, sometimes touching, superhero tale. CM
pay Thronecast
​Showcase, 10.30pm
With Game of Thrones stars and British celebrity super-fans queueing up to join host Sue Perkins on the couch, Thronecast remains essential viewing for the serious Thrones fan. Each week Perkins and her guests pick the bones of the latest episode clean - "Like a Dothraki at Nando's", as Perkins once put it - making sure that nothing of potential significance goes unexamined. Perkins' own blend of dry and risque humour sets the tone, which is quite different to that of more fanboyish American after-shows like Talking Dead. She's enthusiastic and well informed, and each week her offsider, Jamie East, takes a useful dive into the backstory of one particular character or institution. It's great to see the show's stars in their civvies, though Perkins could perhaps do better in drawing some of the younger ones out of their shells and keeping them involved. BN
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Flavell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perkins</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Comics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midwinter Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Trank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Perkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael B. Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Mara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Conover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS Viceland, 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fantastic Four (2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC, 8pmPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miles Teller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thronecast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crabb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleven, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dothraki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Von Doom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annabel Crabb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Ruins Everything</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Kebbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talking Dead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
