<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398226645192565</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/entertainment/australian-survivor-escape-room-owner-joan-caballero-the-first-to-be-eliminated/news-story/dc3194535999f179e64347084f9426bb</url>
  <title>First Australian Survivor eliminated</title>
  <content>
IN the end not being able to solve a challenge puzzle probably cost Joan Caballero her place in Australian Survivor.
The Sydney mother of three, who owns an Escape Room business, was voted out in a dramatic and close tribal council, after she and South Australian Kent Nelson couldn't solve the puzzle for them Asaga tribe.
The first vote was split - six for Caballero and six for Nelson.
The tribe voted again, and West Australian Ben Morgan and Victorian Jericho Malabonga switched their vote, and Caballero was gone.
"It's one of those things," Caballero said.
"Obviously first I was really upset, a little embarrassed and quite shocked about it, because my tribe, we were doing so well together and we were great mates.
"I really didn't think they would use the challenge as a reason to vote someone out.
"If I could do it over again, maybe I would have talked to more people, but I felt really safe."
It was obvious during the first episode that this year's cast of Australian Survivor are playing are harder game, which producers set out to achieve.

Caballero was lied to a number of times after her tribe lost the immunity challenge, to the Samatau tribe.
This included a direct lie to her face by Perth model Sarah Tilleke, who is going in with a clear strategy to play a big game.
Caballero said she has no ill feelings towards Tilleke, who she thought was one of her biggest supporters.
"She told me I was safe, and I feel she did that so that I would feel comfortable, which is kind of good game play," she said.
"When you speak to her, Sarah has this almost hypnotising sense to her.
Her tone is very calming, she is very articulate and she is very careful with what she says.
"I think she is definitely a very good game player.
"She knew exactly what she needed to do."
The Asaga tribe has some strong leaders, including Victorian endurance runner Samantha Gash and former special operations soldier, West Australian Mark Wales.
But Caballero's favourite player and some to watch was West Australian mining technician Luke Toki.
"I loved Luke," she said.
"I think he has this charisma that will get him far.
"He just makes everyone laugh.
"In that situation, in Survivor, and in Samoa, the weather conditions were terrible and I just feel like having his character, his personality, just lightened up the mood."
Back in Sydney, Caballero has settled back into normal life, running her Escape Room business.
She said at the end of the day, she is philosophical about getting voted out.
"Of course I wanted to get further, but at the end of the day, everyone gets voted out unless you are in the final two," she said.
"So I guess it's a good thing I got voted out early on, and wasn't the second last person going."
AUSTRALIAN SURVIVOR WILL AIR ON MONDAY AND TUESDAY THIS WEEK, AT 7.30PM.

Meet the guys and gals from Australian Survivor 2017.

See Australian Survivor contestants series 2
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asaga</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Toki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Jericho Malabonga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Mark Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan Caballero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Gash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Ben Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Tilleke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tilleke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Kent Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Escape Room</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRALIAN SURVIVOR WILL AIR ON MONDAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caballero</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TUESDAY THIS WEEK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samatau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
