<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397844393098101</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/national/paul-pisasale-exdriver-claims-former-mayor-visited-brothels-with-developers/news-story/5a88a3a7fba53a555a55ea8cbaf00221</url>
  <title>Driver claims ex-mayor visited brothels</title>
  <content>
The recent times of Paul Pisasale

FORMER Ipswich mayor Paul Pisasale was driven in his council car to brothels and massage parlours with developers, according to explosive claims his former driver says have been handed to corruption investigators.

Pisasale is also accused of occasionally staying at accommodation owned by one developer.

Stephen Potts, who said he worked for Pisasale from September 2014 to midway through last year, told The Courier-Mail he had detailed the allegations to the Crime and Corruption Commission.

Pisasale was a wildly popular mayor whose career crashed spectacularly in May this year when he was. A month later he.

and other charges unrelated to these allegations, which the former politician plans to defend.

Mr Potts said he would drive Pisasale in a Holden Statesmen Caprice to venues including an unapproved massage parlour in Brisbane and a legal one on the Gold Coast.

"On one occasion we went down for a funeral to Tweed Heads and he called into one prior to the funeral service. What went on in there, I don't know. But I'm just saying, we got there early," Mr Potts said.

Mr Potts said Pisasale never discussed what went on inside. "He might say he felt better or whatever after whatever happened there," Mr Potts said.

Some of the venues were designated as massage parlours.

"For a long time I thought it was just to do with getting therapy for his multiple sclerosis," he said.

In about the second half of 2015, Mr Potts said he had driven Pisasale behind a car belonging to developer Chris Zenonos to the massage parlour Cloud 9, in East Brisbane.

Mr Zenonos last night told The Courier-Mail he had shown Mr Pisasale's driver to the massage parlour but then left.

"In regards to Mr Potts following me to Cloud 9 massage place, I was with Paul and he told me his MS was playing up and he wanted a massage," Mr Zenonos said.

"He followed me there and ... then I left.

"It is not a brothel and nor did I know the fact that it was raided for prostitution as there is a big sign at the front that say's massage, haircuts and waxing."

"If I was to take Paul to Cloud 9 massage why would Paul get his driver to follow me there instead of me just taking him in my car?," Mr Zenonos said.

Mr Potts also said he believed Pisasale had stayed at accommodation in Kangaroo Point linked to Mr Zenonos, who had had property interests in Ipswich.

Mr Potts alleged he dropped Pisasale there on several occasions and "picked him up the next morning".

Mr Zenonos said the apartments were owned by his parents, who are friends with Pisasale.

"Paul asked me if he could get changed or shower at the Holiday apartments if he was in Brisbane so I confirmed this with my dad and he said: 'no problem'," Mr Zenonos said, adding that there was "definitely no conflict of interest".

Mr Potts also said he had driven Pisasale with another developer who also has interests in Ipswich, to a legal brothel on the Gold Coast.

Mr Potts said he did not keep log books, and did not raise an issue with the mayor because as an employee he was not in a position to challenge the politician. But he  approached investigators after news broke of the CCC probe.

Mr Potts said he resigned after tensions with the mayor, the alleged driving experiences and seeing some arguments with a person close to the mayor.

The CCC declined to comment on the allegations. Requests for comment were left with Pisasale's lawyer and the other developer.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloud 9</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Potts</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pisasale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Potts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pisasale</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corruption Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pisasale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Zenonos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tweed Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Statesmen Caprice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Zenonos</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
