<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398145040812511</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>ABN Newswire</source>
  <url>http://www.abnnewswire.net/press/en/89337/Havilah-Resources-Ltd-(ASX-HAV)-Moves-to-New-Office-to-Prepare-for-Growth-89337.html</url>
  <title>Havilah Resources Ltd (ASX:HAV) Moves to New Office to Prepare for Growth</title>
  <content>
Adelaide, July 31, 2017 AEST (ABN Newswire) - Havilah Resources Limited (ASX:HAV) (Havilah) is pleased to announce that it has relocated its Adelaide office to a new office located in Dulwich, from neighbouring Glenside. The move is designed to facilitate continued future growth, while also reducing the cost of occupancy.
Highlights
- More flexible office allowing for growth while reducing cost.
- Upgrade of IT infrastructure.
- Green credentials with 25% reduction in energy consumption.
Background
The new office provides an opportunity to increase productivity through a modern open plan working environment and will also add space to accommodate expected needs of the next stages of business-critical projects such as Kalkaroo and Mutooroo. Havilah's IT infrastructure will also be upgraded at the same time to move to a cloud-based system. The new building has strong green credentials including a solar facade consisting of solar panels and translucent PV cells reducing the building's overall energy consumption by approximately 25%.
The new office address in Adelaide is: 164 Fullarton Road, Dulwich, South Australia, 5065.
The new office phone number is: +61-8-8155-4500.
Commenting on the office move, Havilah Managing Director, Dr Chris Giles said: "The new location was chosen following an extensive review process for its high-profile location and open plan layout, designed to maximise communication and collaborative team work.
"This location also allows for the ability to expand very quickly to add room for Kalkaroo and Mutooroo project teams that are expected to increase as activity ramps up.
"Havilah has also seized the opportunity to upgrade its IT infrastructure including remote working and data management capabilities.
"We are fortunate to be able to achieve this whilst, at the same time reducing our annual office rental cost" he said.
To view the release, please visit:

About Havilah Resources Ltd
() is a debt free South Australian gold producer having recently financed and developed its first gold mine at Portia in north-eastern South Australia. It plans to follow on with three copper-gold-cobalt mining developments at North Portia, Kalkaroo and Mutooroo, which are underpinned by a JORC resources mineral inventory of over 1.4 million tonnes of copper, 3.6 million ounces of gold, and 18,000 tonnes of cobalt.

     

Related Companies
            

Social Media
Share this Article

ABN Newswire
This Page Viewed:  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havilah Resources Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalkaroo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JORC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN Newswire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havilah Managing Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dulwich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havilah's IT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Chris Giles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havilah Resources Ltd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31, 2017 AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia, 5065</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havilah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fullarton Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Portia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Page Viewed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mutooroo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
