<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398140745845068</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/whats-on-tv-monday-august-7-20170728-gxl1z0.html</url>
  <title>What's on TV: Monday, August 7</title>
  <content>
movie American History X (1998)
Masterpiece Movies (pay TV), 6.30pm
Directed by English television commercial virtuoso Tony Kaye, who subsequently asked to be credited on screen as Humpty Dumpty because the producers let lead actor Edward Norton re-edit the film, American History X is the story of Derek Vinyard (Norton), a former white supremacist just released from jail for the brutal murder of a young black man who tried to steal his car. Interspersed with black-and-white flashbacks, the narrative follows a reformed Derek's attempts to persuade his impressionable young skinhead brother (Edward Furlong) not to make the same mistakes. The shooting style swings wildly between handheld dynamics and artful impressionism, while the plot is often cliched and schematic. That said, Norton is close to astounding. And not just as the incendiary young man preaching hate: his contemporary bitterness and regret are just as keenly felt as his rage. Norton almost saves the movie. CMAmerican History X
Mario Batali's Moltissimo
SBS Viceland, 8pm
Mario Batali is far from a household name here in Australia, but in the US, the Italian-American chef and owner-operator of some 25 restaurants there is big business. On Moltissimo, he cooks for two celebrity guests per episode at Munchies, Vice's relaxed on-site kitchen in Brooklyn. Tonight's guests might not mean much to Australian audiences - ex-NFL star Ray Lewis and his former Miami Hurricanes teammate, Rohan Marley, son of Bob Marley - but they're fine dinner companions, particularly Marley, who talks about the coffee company he founded to support Jamaican farmers. Batali, in his trademark fleece vest and with what appears to be a scrunchie holding back his ginger ponytail, cuts an unusual figure, but most importantly, the man can cook. AR
pay Street Science
Discovery Science, 8.30pm
A surprisingly spectacular little series in which mad chemist Kevin Delaney travels the US, showing how common household and industrial chemicals can react to produce startling effects. His first stop is a Florida hair salon, which has a ready supply of hydrogen peroxide. Suitably attired in safety gear, Delaney shows how dumping peroxide and a catalyst into flasks of liquid soap produces enormous eruptions of a thick, gooey foam known as "elephant's toothpaste". Not content with that impressive little spectacle, he decides to super-size it, seeing how far such an eruption will spray out of the windows and sunroof of a Volkswagen Beetle. Infra-red and high-speed cameras capture what happens in marvellous detail. Later Delaney shows how they make fake snow for the movies and does remarkable things with sugar at a sweet shop and liquid nitrogen at a brewery. Don't try any of it at home. BN
Brainwashing Stacey: Anti-Abortion Camp
ABC2, 9.30pm
That Stacey Dooley gets around, doesn't she? From Magaluf to Bulgaria, she's there shining a light on some of the world's more unsavoury situations, but she's never been quite as embedded as this. Brainwashing Stacey sees her challenged to live and breathe the reality of the people she's profiling - in this case a bunch of teenagers at a Christian anti-abortion camp called Survivors in California. It's confronting stuff, particularly when they're taken to a memorial site for aborted fetuses that were dumped at the side of the road 19 years ago to avoid the expense of a medical waste facility, and told of how "if one of those children might have escaped that horrible death, they might be standing right here with you today." Founder Jeff White likens the "abortion epidemic" to the Holocaust. But his charges come across as highly sensitive young people merely passionate about their chosen cause. Dooley struggles when tasked with holding a placard, and can't help but try to distance her opinion from that of the Survivors in public. But there's unexpected food for thought here, particularly when we're introduced to a young couple and their baby - adopted as a means to save the child from abortion. AR
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Marley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holocaust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen Beetle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward Furlong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delaney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Abortion Camp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stacey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS Viceland, 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOKLYN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stacey Dooley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mario Batali's Moltissimo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Science, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American History X (1998</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miami Hurricanes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Science</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Delaney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulgaria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CMAmerican History X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magaluf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV), 6.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Kaye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dooley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derek Vinyard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Humpty Dumpty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American History X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterpiece Movies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mario Batali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Marley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moltissimo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC2, 9.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward Norton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
