<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398187990486309</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/chanticleer/costs-dreamliners-key-to-qantass-smooth-flight-path-20170728-gxkpz1</url>
  <title>Costs, Dreamliners key to Qantas's smooth flight path </title>
  <content>
It took two years to rebuild trust with investors after running into financial turbulence and Qantas chief executive Alan Joyce now has to show that the airline's miraculous turnaround is sustainable. This is difficult in aviation where institutional shareholders have an inherent distrust of airlines and for good reason.
Qantas will post its second-highest annual profit on record next month as the airline hits cruising altitude, with net earnings to remain around the $1 billion mark in coming years. Strategically, it will be a significant year for chief executive Alan Joyce who is in his eighth term as the airline, the game-changing aircraft which will allow it to fly direct between Australia and Europe for the first time.
There is ongoing speculation that chairman Leigh Clifford will make a decision around stepping down later in the year, with  However, it is worth noting there has been talk of Clifford - who has been in the job 10 years - departing for years but it has turned out to be incorrect.
This does not necessarily mean Qantas has a trouble-free future ahead, particularly as international competition shows no sign of slowing down.

Aviation is one of the most volatile industries around where everything from higher oil prices to wars, terrorist attacks, economic downturns and volcanic eruptions keep the sector in a constant cycle of feast and famine. Some fund managers say they still see Qantas as a trading stock, which is why the register is dominated by index funds like BlackRock Group, with a stake of 5.2 per cent.

Buffett investment

However, even long-time airline bears like Warren Buffett are warming to the industry. Buffett, who famously avoided investing in airlines for decades, has thrown $US10 billion ($12.5 billion) at the industry, with Berkshire Hathaway buying stakes in United, American, Delta and Southwest Airlines. US airlines are enjoying a revival while Middle Eastern operators Emirates and Etihad are making losses after years of rapid expansion. Asia remains the most promising aviation market, which Qantas wants to capitalise on.
The message Joyce, who has been running Qantas for eight years, will give when the airline delivers its big profit next month, is that the turnaround is sustainable and the days of unexpected turbulence are over.  compared to $1.5 billion last year. Consensus analyst forecasts point to pre-tax earnings of $1.38 billion and a net profit of $1.1 billion.
These are impressive numbers compared to other global carriers and domestic rival Virgin Australia, which is expected to post a loss next month, considering Qantas was in the red three years earlier. The 60 per cent jump in Qantas's share price so far this calendar year suggests the market is buying the story that it can now remain profitable throughout the cycle. Analysts expect core earnings to remain steady at around $1.2 billion per annum in coming years.

Joyce closed a challenging chapter in the airline's history on June 30 this year when a three-and-a-half year $2 billion cost-cutting program formally ended. The deep cuts, including job losses, may have finished but it is now targeting further cost reductions of $400 million a year for the next three years to 2020.
Joyce will provide more detail around how he expects to achieve that target at the full-year results in August but has already said it will come from a combination of lower costs and revenue increases. New technology and more modern aircraft are the key to these targets but there will also be changes to its supplier relationships, ground operations and the way aircraft are utilised.
Most of Joyce's tenure as chief executive has been spent putting out fires, turning the ship around and fighting old battles. It is unclear how long the 51-year-old will stay on, given he is still relatively young for a chief executive, but his narrative over the next 12 months will be different than it has been in previous years.
Emphasis on costs

While the emphasis on costs will remain, he will be focused on the arrival of the airline's first 787-9 Dreamliner aircraft in October. The Qantas marketing department will be working overtime when the Boeing aircraft touches down from Seattle ahead of the launch of the 17-hour direct Perth-London flights in March.
Despite the hype, it is true the lightweight Boeing aircraft is a game-changer and will enable Australia to connect directly with Europe for the first time in history. Qantas has ordered eight of the long-haul aircraft as it retires its older Boeing 747 aircraft. One of the airline's oldest 747s will be retired this week, leaving it with 10.
The new-generation jets are expected to be flying non-stop between Sydney and London or New York by as early as 2022 as the airline prepares for a shake-up to its international network. For now, they will be deployed on Perth-London and Melbourne-Los Angeles. Qantas has been expanding its international network, adding flights to Osaka in Japan last week.
Citi analysts say international earnings before interest and tax (EBIT) will increase by more than $100 million given the higher proportion of premium seats on the 787-9s. Citi says the eight 787-9s will have 5 per cent more seats compared to the older 747s, and the majority of those seat increases would be in the premium segment. Replacing the Airbus A380 with 787-9s on Melbourne to Los Angeles will reduce capacity and make it more profitable because there are fewer empty seats.

Qantas says the Dreamliner will have 42 business seats, 28 premium class and 166 economy, which means premium seat offerings account for 30 per cent of total seats compared to 23.3 per cent and 26.6 per cent on the A380s and 747s respectively.
The other possible big event for Qantas this year is an announcement around the possible retirement of Clifford. The annual general meeting in October would be the obvious time to do this but do not hold your breath as many have incorrectly predicted Clifford was going years ago. Goyder joins the Qantas board in November, which is when Clifford celebrates his 10-year anniversary.
Exciting corporate job

Whether or not a change in chairman would trigger a change in chief executive remains to be seen. No-one is complaining about the job Joyce is doing at the moment, but eight years is above the average CEO term. It would also be a good time to go out on a high, although it would be hard to find a more exciting corporate job in Australia.

Macquarie analysts are tipping a potential earnings beat when Qantas reports results on August 25. They predict strong domestic revenue growth next year now that capacity levels are back at rational levels after calling off a turf war with Virgin (although both are slashing prices on routes to Hong Kong), lower fuel costs and a $500 million share buyback.
Qantas, which stopped paying dividends between 2009 and 2015, has returned $1.63 billion to shareholders since October 2015. About $1.4 billion of that was spent on share buybacks, which has reduced the shares on issue by 18 per cent. The average price paid was $3.41 per share, which compares to Friday's closing price of $5.30. In July, the stock traded about the $5.45 a consortium of private investors offered for the company 10 years ago.
Qantas shares hit $5.87 on July 11 but have fallen back to $5.30 in the past two weeks, partly on the back of some weak results by global carriers. The consensus of analyst 12-month price targets on the stock is $5.78. Others, while pleased with the airline's performance, believe growth has peaked.
"We think this complex company is one of the best managed in Australia, but for now we would like to watch from the sidelines." Credit Suisse analyst Hasan Tevfik says. Qantas has removed Qantas from its "long" portfolio but notes it has held the stock since August 2016 when it traded on a PE of 5.8 times compared to 9.2 times now.
Sustainable footing

Others say the stock is undervalued. Citi analyst Anthony Moulder has a target price of $7.09 on the stock. He argues Qantas' PE discount to the all industrials is deeper than its historical average though earnings are now on a sustainable footing. Its EV/EBITDAR discount to other airlines also fails to reflect its better margins, returns, capital management.
At its annual investor day in June, Qantas outlined plans to cut costs at its international business, which faces intense competition as rivals slash fares. It also talked up the prospects for its Frequent Flyer business which is expected to grow EBIT from $500 million to $600 million by 2022. There are no plans to float the business. Qantas will also continue to invest in products and new lounges.
The industry globally is in better shape than it has been for years but not everywhere. Richard Branson last week sold a 31 per cent stake in Virgin Atlantic, the airline he founded in 1984, to Air France-KLM.

Singapore Airlines, which was on the nose after surprising investors with a fourth-quarter loss in May, redeemed itself with a 45.6 per cent jump in first-quarter operating profit last year. Like Qantas, Singapore says the international market remains challenging but it is buying more modern aircraft to become more competitive. Etihad posted a $US1.87 billion annual loss on Friday, reflecting the pressure Gulf-based carriers are under. Emirates also reported its first fall in annual earnings in five years.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berkshire Hathaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air France-KLM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>21</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBIT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbus A380</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Joyce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EV/EBITDAR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Clifford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlackRock Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buffett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing 747</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southwest Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Branson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth-London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Atlantic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seattle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Buffett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasan Tevfik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Moulder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulf-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frequent Flyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.87</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dreamliners</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas' PE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goyder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifford</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OSAKA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
