<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398230940159893</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/round-19-power-rankings-reece-homfray-wraps-up-the-weekends-afl-footy/news-story/164c5bd61c37d9752da70018d6561054</url>
  <title>AFL Rankings: Why this Showdown is huge</title>
  <content>
McGovern's manic game saver

CLEAR your diary for Sunday afternoon. It™s been eight years since we™ve had both teams inside the eight going into a Showdown and in the most even season in ages, it promises to be game on.

To kick off your Monday, here are 10 talking points to start the lead up to Showdown 43.

1. Is this the biggest Showdown since the 2005 semi final?

For starters it's 21-21 going into Showdown 43 so we're all locked away. And with the exception of their first meeting this year in Round 3, you have to go back to Round 6, 2009, to the last time both teams were inside the top-eight when they played in a Showdown. That year it was 5th v 7th and the Power won by 26 points.

Based on ladder positions and what's on the end of the result given we're in the final month of the season, you could easily mount an argument that this is the biggest Showdown since the 2005 semi-final, not taking into account the emotion of what happened in 2015 but that day it was 9th v 12th.

Early verdict: Yes.

2. Will Eddie play?

Richard Douglas had his appendix out mid-season in 2015 and missed two games, Jimmy Bartel missed two games in 2007 while Shaun Hampson (2013) and Danyle Pearce (2007) just the one. So it would appear Betts is a 50/50 prospect. The good news is he had the surgery on a Sunday so this Sunday will be two full weeks since the op.

Early verdict: Yes.

3. Can Port Adelaide tag Rory Sloane?

In Adelaide's four losses this season Rory Sloane has been contained. In Round 14 against Hawthorn it was Daniel Howe (23 touches); Round 11 against Geelong it was Scott Selwood (23 touches); Round 8 against Melbourne it was Bernie Vince (11 touches) and Round 7 against North Melbourne it was Sam Gibson (18 touches). It's pretty simple really, Sloane is Adelaide's best player and when he doesn't play well the chances are the team doesn't either. He was shadowed by Levi Greenwood on the weekend and Adelaide stole a draw. Port Adelaide hasn't got a tagger per se. Brad Ebert could do it but his focus is to win the footy and Darcy Byrne Jones might be worth a crack but there is no specialist shutdown player in the team.

Early verdict: No.

4. Who gets first crack at Tex?

Jack Hombsch is back in the team, Tom Clurey has done some big jobs this year and Tom Jonas has been their most consistent key defender, although he's likely to start on Betts if he plays. I'd expect Hombsch to get Tex and follow him up the ground while Clurey will be the stay at home defender on Josh Jenkins.

Early verdict: Jack Hombsch.

5. Paddy or Sauce, who would you rather have?

Interesting debate on the weekend when comparing their stats going into Round 19. Jacobs had 117 more hit-outs, 17 more hit-outs to advantage, took 13 more marks and had 48 more disposals. Ryder had taken one more contested mark, kicked two more goals, laid five more tackles and had 21 more clearances, even though he'd played one less game. If you're picking the All-Australian ruckman right now, there is no splitting them but THAT hit-out to Robbie Gray to help Port Adelaide beat St Kilda is one for the ages and may get Ryder over the line.

Early verdict: I can't go past Ryder based on what he did on Saturday night and if he goes forward Adelaide's defence will be in trouble.

6. Who wins the Showdown Medal?

The last 10 winners of the Showdown Medal, in order, have been Rory Sloane, Matt Crouch, Tom Lynch, Scott Thompson, Robbie Gray, Sam Jacobs, Hamish Hartlett, Chad Wingard, Travis Boak, Sam Jacobs.

The market according to UBET has Rory Sloane and Robbie Gray $7.50 favourites, then there's Eddie Betts and Ollie Wines at $10, the Crouch brothers and Rory Laird at $13.

Early verdict: With the focus on Gray and Sloane, I'm tipping Wines to go nuts and dominate in the middle.

7. Will Dixon fire?

Dixon has played in just two Showdowns since arriving in town at the end of 2015. The first one he had 8 touches and kicked 0.1, the second he had 12 touches and 1.0 so has hardly imposed himself. He missed the Round 22 Showdown last year and is in career-best form this season. Could get either Kyle Hartigan or Daniel Talia and looms a potential match-winner particularly after he rediscovered his best in Saturday night's win over the Saints.

Early verdict: Yes.

8. Does Robbie Gray start in the middle and stay there?

He's got to doesn't he? Started forward against St Kilda then went into the middle in the second quarter on Saturday night and changed the game. Without Chad Wingard there is a more pressing need for Gray to play midfield, we saw what he's capable of with an amazing final quarter on the weekend and instead of waiting for the game to get away from them against the Crows, Hinkley should start him in the middle at the first bounce.

Early verdict: Yes.

9. Who is the biggest x-factor going into the game?

Depends on your definition of x-factor which can be pretty broad, but if it means maximum impact from minimal touches from a player you're not really expecting it from then there are a few candidates. Mitch McGovern can't be in that category after what we saw on the weekend but the Crows have a few others including Charlie Cameron, Wayne Milera and Jake Kelly. Port has Sam Powell-Pepper, Karl Amon and Sam Gray.

Early verdict: For mine it's Charlie Cameron. We saw glimpses of his game-breaking pace in the third quarter on Saturday, I sense he craves the big stage and could get off the chain on Sunday. Just got to get his goalkicking right.

10. Who wins?

I think Adelaide will win the flag but I have a smell about the Power in this week's Showdown. I don't expect they'll fall flat from the high of Saturday night's win over St Kilda. Showdowns are always tight, the Crows will start favourites and Ken Hinkley says they're the best team in the competition, and will instil the underdog mentality in his own side.

Power press conference

"We look forward to it though, we do look forward to it," Hinkley said post-match on the weekend. I think Port will win a close one.

Early verdict: Port Adelaide, just.

POWER RANKINGS

All 18 teams are assessed and ranked every week based on form to chart the movers and sliders throughout the season.

1. Adelaide (13-1-4)

Previous ranking: 2, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 3, 2, 2, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1

Let's start with the good - Adelaide climbed off the canvas, from 50 points down in the third quarter and scraped out a draw away from home. Players like McGovern and Jenkins found a way to get involved after going missing in the first half, and McGovern's ice cool kick after the final siren is a big tick for his character. Then there was his pack mark, no wonder so many clubs reportedly want his signature. Then the bad, if Adelaide is serious about contending for the flag it must address why it was opened up so badly by a bottom-eight side. They weren't just beaten in the first half but smashed. That said, they found a way to fight back without three of their best players in Brad Crouch, Jake Lever and Eddie Betts so more good than bad from the result.

Ladder position: 1st

Coming up: Port Adelaide (Adelaide Oval), Essendon (Etihad Stadium), Sydney (Adelaide Oval)

2. Geelong (12-1-5)

Previous ranking: 6, 7, 4, 4, 2, 3, 4, 8, 3, 3, 1, 1, 1, 2, 2, 1, 1, 3

Cats press conference

The Cats won but that became secondary on Saturday night to the debate surrounding Paddy D's tackle on Matthew Kreuzer. No doubt Dangerfield is a fair player and a ball player but driving a player into the ground when they hit their head is never looked upon favourably by the MRP. We wait with anticipation for Monday afternoon.

Ladder position: 2nd

Coming up: Sydney (Simonds Stadium), Richmond (Simonds Stadium), Collingwood (MCG)

3. Sydney (10-8)

Previous ranking: 12, 9, 12, 16, 17, 18, 17, 15, 11, 15, 16, 14, 7, 7, 4, 4, 3, 2

The door was wide open for the Swans to take top spot on the rankings but they squandered it. They were bound to trip up sooner or later and Hawthorn was bound to be the team that would do it to them. It doesn't hurt their premiership credentials but it might hurt their top-four chances and in some respects, makes the mountain one step higher to climb. Rare quiet night for the Sydney midfield which will be hungry to bounce back in potentially match of the season against Geelong this weekend.

Ladder position: 6th

Coming up: Geelong (Simonds Stadium), Fremantle (SCG), Adelaide (Adelaide Oval)

4. Richmond (12-6)

Previous ranking: 8, 5, 2, 2, 4, 5, 7, 10, 12, 10, 6, 5, 6, 6, 5, 7, 6, 4

Tigers press conference

Richmond ticked the box of going to the Gold Coast and coming home with the four points but a massive fortnight coming up followed by a trip to Perth which will make or break their top-four hopes.

Ladder position: 4th

Coming up: Hawthorn (MCG), Geelong (Simonds Stadium), Fremantle (Subiaco)

5. GWS (11-2-5)

Previous ranking: 18, 10, 7, 5, 3, 2, 2, 2, 2, 2, 2, 3, 3, 1, 1, 2, 4, 5

Wasn't pretty or convincing against Freo but it was a win, and the Giants hadn't tasted that for a month. Now it looks like Brett Deledio is ready to return and the more they get back the more dangerous they will become. Still not sure they can win the flag but should be in the top four discussion based on their draw to come.

Ladder position: 3rd

Coming up: Melbourne (Manuka Oval), Western Bulldogs (Etihad Stadium), West Coast (Spotless Stadium)

6. Port Adelaide (11-7)

Previous ranking: 1, 2, 3, 6, 6, 6, 8, 6, 4, 4, 4, 4, 4, 5, 7, 5, 5, 7

Ken Hinkley said this was a win that could well define a season and he's right. So much to like about their character to fight back from 10 points down. Jared Polec took the game on, Charlie Dixon presented all night and Justin Westhoff and Aaron Young won a 2 on 4 contest to keep the Power in it. But if it wasn't for two freakish acts in the final minute of the game thanks to Ryder and Robbie Gray then Port loses that game and big questions would have been asked. Instead they charge into the Showdown without a worry in the world.

Ladder position: 5th

Coming up: Adelaide (Adelaide Oval), Collingwood (Adelaide Oval), Western Bulldogs (Ballarat)

7. Melbourne (10-8)

Previous ranking: 5, 8, 8, 12, 11, 10, 12, 9, 10, 9, 11, 7, 5, 4, 6, 6, 7, 6

Demons press conference

Another result we should have seen coming. Forget the ladder positions when these two teams play, the Kangas have it mentally over Melbourne and taking the game to Tasmania doesn't help the Demons' cause. Now they're without Jesse Hogan with a broken collarbone and have to front up to GWS in Canberra.

Ladder position: 7th

Coming up: GWS (Manuka Oval), St Kilda (MCG), Brisbane (MCG)

8. Hawthorn (8-1-9)

Previous ranking: 11, 16, 18, 18, 15, 16, 16, 16, 16, 13, 15, 17, 17, 15, 11, 9, 9, 9

Why didn't we see this coming? The Hawks are playing good footy, Sydney was due for an off night sooner or later and Hawthorn seem to match up really well on them. Love the way Sicily plays and Jack Gunston to half-back has been a very smart move.

Ladder position: 12th

Coming up: Richmond (MCG), North Melbourne (Tasmania), Carlton (Etihad Stadium)

9. Western Bulldogs (10-8)

Previous ranking: 7, 3, 5, 3, 5, 4, 3, 5, 7, 5, 5, 6, 9, 8, 10, 12, 12, 11

Gutsy from the Dogs who, can you believe it, went into the game against last year's wooden spooner as underdogs. Four goals from Jason Johannisen was the difference and now they're only outside the top eight on percentage. Can't see them winning it from here but stranger things have happened - like last year.

Ladder position: 9th

Coming up: Brisbane (Gabba), GWS (Etihad Stadium), Port Adelaide (Ballarat)

10. Essendon (9-9)

Previous ranking: 3, 4, 10, 13, 10, 12, 14, 11, 9, 11, 12, 9, 11, 9, 12, 11, 10, 8

A chance gone begging for the Dons who trailed by two goals with five minutes to go and lost by 30 points. The Dogs are hungry but that was a statement game for Essendon who are now back in the pack for a spot in the eight.

Ladder position: 10th

Coming up: Carlton (MCG), Adelaide (Etihad Stadium), Gold Coast (Metricon Stadium)

11. St Kilda (9-9)

Previous ranking: 13, 11, 11, 8, 9, 7, 5, 4, 8, 7, 7, 12, 14, 10, 8, 8, 8, 10

Saints press conference

Ten points up with a minute to go, it's the loss that may well haunt St Kilda this year. Seb Ross simply had to go with Robbie Gray at that final stoppage when he took off behind Ryder who tapped the footy into his lap. Membrey's three goals were good and Carlisle showed a bit but it doesn't mean much without the four points that they should have taken.

Ladder position: 11th

Coming up: West Coast (Etihad Stadium), Melbourne (MCG), North Melbourne (Etihad Stadium)

12. Collingwood (7-1-10)

Previous ranking: 9, 13, 6, 9, 12, 11, 17, 14, 12, 8, 8, 9, 10, 12, 15, 16, 15, 13

Should be shattered by that result. Adelaide is top of the table for a reason but you can't let any team off the hook when you've got them by 50 points in the second half. Daniel Wells was awesome and a performance like that will almost make Magpies fans forgive the hierarchy for recruiting Chris Mayne as well.

Ladder position: 13th

Coming up: North Melbourne (Etihad Stadium), Port Adelaide (Adelaide Oval), Geelong (MCG)

13. West Coast (10-8)

Previous ranking: 4, 6, 9, 7, 8, 8, 6, 3, 6, 6, 9, 10, 8, 11, 9, 10, 11, 12

Simply had to take care of business against Brisbane at home and they did. Six goals to Josh Kennedy would have been a sight for sore eyes for Eagles fans but now the big test once again - can they win in Melbourne against St Kilda this weekend?

Ladder position: 8th

Coming up: St Kilda (Etihad Stadium), Carlton (Subiaco), GWS (Spotless Stadium)

14. Fremantle (7-11)

Previous ranking: 17, 17, 13, 10, 7, 9, 9, 7, 5, 8, 10, 13, 15, 14, 16, 14, 13, 14

Nat Fyfe had 31 possessions and kicked two goals, proving he is definitely back to his best and the Dockers were very brave against the Giants but couldn't quite finish the job. Still, positive signs from a side that has had its share of disastrous losses this season.

Ladder position: 14th

Coming up: Gold Coast (Subiaco), Sydney (SCG), Richmond (Subiaco)

15. Gold Coast (6-12)

Previous ranking: 15, 18, 14, 11, 13, 13, 10, 14, 15, 16, 13, 11, 13, 16, 14, 15, 16, 16

Suns press conference

Losing Ablett didn't help when they are already hit hard by injuries, then lost three more players during the game. The Tigers were always going to be too good but the Suns now face three very winnable games if they can pick themselves up off the canvas.

Ladder position: 15th

Coming up: Fremantle (Subiaco), Brisbane (Gabba), Essendon (Metricon Stadium)

16. Brisbane (4-14)

Previous ranking: 10, 14, 16, 17, 14, 17, 18, 18, 18, 18, 18, 18, 18, 18, 17, 17, 17, 15

Tough day at the office for Lions fans. But the feel-good story was Sam Skinner's goal with his first kick on an AFL debut that was put on hold for 12 months last year when he did his knee in the week he was set to be named.

Ladder position: 18th

Coming up: Western Bulldogs (Gabba), Gold Coast (Gabba), Melbourne (MCG)

17. North Melbourne (5-13)

Previous ranking: 14, 12, 17, 15, 16, 14, 11, 13, 13, 14, 14, 16, 16, 17, 18, 18, 18, 18

One for North Melbourne's pride and continued psychological advantage over the Demons. So nice that Majak Daw took a contested mark in the final minutes after copping a very public spray from his coach last week, and Ben Brown is now equal leader of the Coleman Medal.

Ladder position: 16th

Coming up: Collingwood (Etihad Stadium), Collingwood (Tasmania), St Kilda (Etihad Stadium)

18. Carlton (5-13)

Previous ranking: 16, 15, 14, 14, 18, 15, 13, 12, 17, 17, 17, 15, 12, 13, 13, 13, 14, 17

Blues press conference

Didn't really put up a fight against Geelong but no one expected much. Continue their slide down the rankings and the ladder and must win one of their next three to ensure the back half of the season hasn't been a complete disaster.

Ladder position: 17th

Coming up: Essendon (MCG), West Coast (Subiaco), Hawthorn (Etihad Stadium)

WHO'S YOUR MVP?

Analysis of how best-and-fairest voting may look at Adelaide and Port Adelaide using a 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, basis every week of the season.

Round 19 votes

Adelaide

5 votes: Brodie Smith

K: 15 M: 8 H: 11 G: 1.0

When Adelaide got going in the third quarter it was no surprise it was off the back of Brodie Smith and his run from defence. Finished with 26 disposals and kicked a huge goal in the final quarter to keep the Crows in it.

4 votes: Mitch McGovern

K: 9 M: 8 H: 1 G: 4.2

Barely sighted in the first half then virtually won them the game in the second. Three goals in the third term and his fourth after the final siren which sealed the draw. And what about that pack mark to be able to kick it? Not many players in the comp can do that and no wonder his signature is so sought after.

3 votes: Matt Crouch

K: 13 M: 0 H: 23 G: 0.0

Game-high 36 disposals, 15 were contested and he laid 10 tackles. One of very few Crows who had a crack in the first half when the side was blown away.

2 votes: Rory Laird

K: 12 M: 5 H: 13 G: 0.0

Another reason Adelaide got back in the contest after half-time. Accumulated possessions all game but had his greatest impact in the third term with some important one-on-one contests as well.

1 vote: Richard Douglas

K: 16 M: 4 H: 12 G: 0.0

With apologies to Tex Walker, Josh Jenkins and David Mackay, Douglas stepped up with Rory Sloane being heavily tagged and finished with 28 hard-fought disposals.

Port Adelaide

5 votes: Paddy Ryder

K: 11 M: 4 H: 4 G: 0.0

I'd be prepared to give him the five votes for that final game-winning hit-out alone, but Ryder had 44 others and they were awesome. He was in everything early and took another step towards Port's best-and-fairest in an amazing season.

4 votes: Robbie Gray

K: 15 M: 5 H: 12 G: 1.1

That goal will be replayed at Port Adelaide, or at least in supporters' heads forever. Gray dominated the final quarter but his third wasn't bad either with a trademark one-handed mark. Started forward but wasn't long before he went into the middle.

3 votes: Charlie Dixon

K: 9 M: 5 H: 7 G: 1.1

Dixon's best game for a while. Directed his aggression in the right places - at the ball. Pushed up the ground and had the ball on a string like it was a dry night. Crucial mark and goal in the final term the icing on the cake.

2 votes: Ollie Wines

K: 15 M: 1 H: 8 G: 0.1

A total of 17 of Wines' 23 disposals were contested which is immense. Easily Port's best midfielder on the night and took a big contested mark in the final term when the game was on the line.

1 vote: Jared Polec

K: 18 M: 6 H: 12 G: 1

Finished with 30 touches and was brave and skilful enough to take the game on in the final five minutes which was a big reason Port got over the line. Kicked it up the middle, took a contested mark in the last quarter and his pressure was excellent.

LEADERBOARDS

Adelaide

37: Rory Sloane

34: Matt Crouch

28: Sam Jacobs

25: Rory Laird

22: Taylor Walker

19: Jake Lever

18: Tom Lynch

15: Brodie Smith

10: Hugh Greenwood, Richard Douglas

Port Adelaide

39: Ollie Wines

27: Charlie Dixon

26: Brad Ebert, Robbie Gray

24: Paddy Ryder

20: Chad Wingard

19: Tom Jonas

13: Travis Boak

12: Sam Powell-Pepper

10: Jared Polec

BURNING QUESTIONS

This week - Will we see a record Showdown crowd on Sunday?

The most recent Showdown in Round 3 drew 53,698 which is an all-time high for these two teams, but that game was on a Saturday night which appeals to SA footy fans more than Sunday twilight. 50,000 given the timeslot will be a good result.

Last week - Does Jack come back?

Yes. Two weeks in the SANFL was more than enough time for Jack Hombsch who was best-on for the Magpies then came in and rediscovered his run and mojo for the Power against St Kilda. Back in the senior team and that's where he'll stay for the rest of the season.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dixon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 15 M: 8 H: 11 G: 1.0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 13 M: 0 H: 23 G: 0.0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Majak Daw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Wingard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Hartlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subiaco</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Byrne Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Cameron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Skinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Membrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Ryder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown Medal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 16 M: 4 H: 12 G: 0.0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Sloane</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ablett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Powell-Pepper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 18 M: 6 H: 12 G: 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Jonas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ollie Wines</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levi Greenwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Clurey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Jenkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sicily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 9 M: 5 H: 7 G: 1.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballarat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sloane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 11 M: 4 H: 4 G: 0.0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tex</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S YOUR MVP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Selwood (23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Hartigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Dixon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Howe (23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Talia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hombsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Laird</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray $7.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Ebert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clurey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryder</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wines' 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tex Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Lynch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Mayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Polec</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 15 M: 5 H: 12 G: 1.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hinkley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 15 M: 1 H: 8 G: 0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Douglas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metricon Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Hampson (2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 9 M: 8 H: 1 G: 4.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 22 Showdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danyle Pearce (2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Rankings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie Vince (11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K: 12 M: 5 H: 13 G: 0.0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Boak</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SANFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nat Fyfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Amon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seb Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Milera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Bartel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Hombsch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Gunston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Westhoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlisle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Gibson (18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Greenwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Crouch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
