<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398149335779916</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/markets-live/markets-live-investors-gird-their-loins-20170730-gxly8v.html</url>
  <title>Markets Live: Investors gird their loins</title>
  <content>
James Packer's Crown Resorts is facing allegations from a former first aid manager that the casino told staff to ignore a domestic violence incident because it involved a visiting south east Asian politician, and did not let a chef attend the first aid office until the end of his shift even though he had serious burns.

​In a document filed in the Federal Circuit Court, Crown's former first aid manager, Audrey Gatt, claims she witnessed and complained about more than 20 occupational health and safety incidents at Crown Resorts in the five months she was employed at the casino.

Ms Gatt says in March 2017, security told first aid officers to "ignore" a domestic violence incident involving a notable politician from south east Asia, and to leave the badly beaten woman alone to attend to her injuries.

She says the visiting politician threatened not to attend Crown in the future if he was exposed. She says she complained about the incident the following day.

Ms Gatt also claims that in February she complained about a chef who sustained extensive burns to his right arm but was made to work all day before being allowed to go to Crown's first aid office for treatment. 

She alleges when the chef asked his supervisor for permission to go to the first aid office, he was told there was no one to replace him and he needed to continue working. As a result he needed a skin graft, she claims.

"The chef was not able to speak English and was frightened he may lose [his] job if he tried to argue or attend the first aid office without authority to do so." 

Ms Gatt says on another occasion, a heavy box fell and severed a staff member's finger and  security personnel was delayed in retrieving the finger, which meant the finger could not be reattached. 

She says the accountants employed by Crown at the time "appeared more concerned with the staff's blood having stained the money, and the resulting inability to then count and bank the money, rather than the welfare of the staff member who had just lost his finger".

Just quick post on our early headline "Investors gird their loins", here's a quick explainer (and handy chart) on where the expression "gird your loins" comes from, and it's not where you (or at least, we) might think.

Unfortunately, this historical description assumes only men do any loin girding, but after it's passage into popular idiom we think the expression would be now gender-neutral in its application.

So, :

Back in the days of the ancient Near East, both men and women wore flowing tunics. Around the tunic, they'd wear a belt or girdle. While tunics were comfortable and breezy, the hem of the tunic would often get in the way when a man was fighting or performing hard labor. So when ancient Hebrew men had to battle the Philistines, the men would lift the hem of their tunic up and tuck it into their girdle or tie it in a knot to keep it off the ground. The effect basically created a pair of shorts that provided more freedom of movement. Thus to tell someone to "gird up their loins" was to tell them to get ready for hard work or battle.

If anybody knows better, let us know!
A fresh record close for the Dow, rising overall global earnings optimism and further gains in oil have set the ASX up for a higher open.

ASX futures advanced 24 points or 0.4 per cent to 5658. The Australian dollar edged 0.2 per cent higher, remaining within striking distance of the US80¢ mark despite rising bearish calls - Goldman has even called for investors to place bets that the $A will drop.

The local reporting season begins in earnest this week on high expectations - have profits reached a peak as many brokers expect? UBS sees headline earnings growth of about 18 per cent for fiscal 2017; Deutsche Bank targets a little below 15 per cent. Both reflect a rebound after two tough fiscal years for the resources sector.

Excluding resources, UBS sees more modest profit growth of 5.7 per cent, and that's forecast to slow to as little as 2 per cent in fiscal 2018 as resources become a drag. 

"The market has had a decent bounce off its early July lows as banks and resources return to favour though constrained earnings growth (and expensive valuations where there is growth) still suggests to us that the Australian market will be something of a laggard," UBS strategists David Cassidy and Dean Dusanic said in a July 26 note.

Rio Tinto reports on Wednesday and Tabcorp on Friday, among others. The two most hectic weeks will be August 14-18 and August 21-25. 

Locally the focus this week, for a second consecutive week, is on the Reserve Bank. Tuesday brings a policy meeting, a no-change rate decision is expected. Words will be parsed as usual for any bias tweak. 

"In the space of a few months, markets have moved from pricing in a small chance of a rate cut to a chance of a hike over the next 12 months," said Janu Chan, senior economist at St George Bank. "It partly reflects an improvement in domestic economic conditions. 

Investors also will be keying on the Statement of Monetary Policy and renewed economic forecasts on Friday.
Good morning and welcome to the Markets Live blog for Monday.

Your editors today are Jens Meyer and Patrick Commins.

This blog is not intended as investment advice.

Fairfax Media with wires.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Audrey Gatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Markets Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Near East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Dusanic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Resorts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Commins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hebrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Statement of Monetary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janu Chan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jens Meyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Circuit Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Cassidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer's Crown Resorts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gatt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
