<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398235235127253</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/07/31/labor-defends-planned-family-trust-tax-after-liberal-partys-criticism</url>
  <title>Labor defends planned family trust tax after Liberal Party's criticism</title>
  <content>
Labor insists a planned crackdown on how family trusts are used will not prevent the protection of assets or succession planning.

1 HOUR AGO  UPDATED 6 MINS AGO

Labor leader Bill Shorten has dismissed as desperation the Turnbull government's response to his planned crackdown on high-income earners who use family trusts to minimise income tax.

The coalition has branded the move to impose a 30 per cent tax rate on trust distributions to people over 18 a "lazy and cynical envy tax".

"I think the only envy going on here is the government didn't think about the idea," Mr Shorten told ABC radio on Monday.

The opposition leader insisted Labor was not planning to prevent trusts being used legitimately to protect assets or for succession planning.

Trust arrangements used by farmers, charities and deceased estates would be exempt.

But Labor intends targeting the unfair use of more than 300,000 trusts Australia's wealthiest earners and small business use to split income among family members to avoid paying a top tax rate of nearly 50 per cent.

"You can't get away with paying no tax on income that you've earned," Mr Shorten said.

Shadow treasurer Chris Bowen says the Labor plan will not affect 98 per cent of Australian taxpayers.

Instead it targets tax minimisation by high earners who use family trusts to split their incomes amongst family members.

"It's just an artificial mechanism to reduce your tax," he said.

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull accused Mr Shorten of making one attack after another on business.

"All he provides is every day another outburst about inequality and the targets for his outbursts is inevitably hard-working Australians in small businesses," he told ABC radio from Perth.

Accountancy firm BDO Australia has also questioned how the Labor policy would work for lower income earners.

It offered the example of a pair of nurses who earned $70,000 each and paid a combined $31,400 income tax, and a pair of plumbers whose small business used a trust and earned $140,000 (same as the nurses) but who would pay a combined $42,000 tax under Labor's plan.

"Disadvantaging small business people in the pursuit of high-income earners does not seem like a smart move," BDO tax partner Mark Molesworth said.

"It should be a case of targeting the behaviour, not the entity."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BDO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 6 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Molesworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BDO Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
