<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397805738391856</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/golf/australias-karrie-webb-falls-one-shot-short-of-ladies-scottish-open-title-20170730-gxlxrh.html</url>
  <title>Australia's Karrie Webb falls one shot short of Ladies Scottish Open title</title>
  <content>
Irvine: Mi Hyang Lee took advantage of Karrie Webb's late double bogey to win the Ladies Scottish Open for her second LPGA Tour title.
A stroke ahead of Lee with two holes left at a chilly Dundonald Links, Webb dropped a shot back with the double bogey on the par-five 17th after driving into a bunker and having to play out backwards.Photo: Getty Images
"I bent down, picked my tee up - thought I hit a perfect drive there," Webb said.
"When I stood up, I went to tell [my caddie] Jonny [Scott] that I absolutely knotted my three-wood exactly how I wanted and he said it kicked into the bunker. I have no idea how it did that."Photo: PA
Lee, playing in the group ahead of Webb, increased the margin to two with a birdie on the par-five 18th.
Needing an eagle to force a play-off, Webb closed with a birdie to tie for second with Mi Jung Hur.

Webb didn't know she was two strokes behind because of the lack of a leaderboard on the final hole in the tune-up event for the Women's British Open next week at Kingsbarns.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It's pretty bad to not have a leaderboard on the last," Webb said.
"That's the first time I've ever been [at a tour event] that hasn't had a leaderboard on 18 ... We didn't know if Mi Hyang had birdied or not, because there wasn't like a loud cheer like she had."
The 42-year-old Australian reached the green-side bunker in two shots.
"Well, my bunker shot, I said to Jonny, 'I don't know if I need to hole this or get it up-and-down'," she said.
"Imagine if you went for it and overplayed it and you only had to get it up-and-down. I was trying to make it but also not being overly aggressive."
Lee shot a six-under 66 to finish at six-under 282. After playing the front nine in five under with six birdies and a bogey, the South Korean player made eight straight pars before birdieing the last.
She also was confused on 18 without a leaderboard, thinking she needed to an eagle to tie Webb.
Webb, tied for the third-round lead with Sei Young Kim at six under, had a 73.
The 42-year-old Australian chipped in for eagle on the par-five 14th and bogeyed the par-four 16th before losing the lead on 17.
Carlota Ciganda (70) and Cristie Kerr (72) tied for fourth at four under, while Australia's Minjee Lee also recorded a top 10 finish.
Lee finished on her own in eighth after a final round of three-under 69 to be four off the winner.
AP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladies Scottish Open</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irvine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LPGA Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Minjee Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webb</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingsbarns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MI Hyang Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlota Ciganda (70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sei Young Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dundonald Links</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mi Hyang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cristie Kerr (72</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Karrie Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mi Jung Hur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karrie Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's British Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
