<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398140745845132</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/four-days-on-search-of-port-philip-bay-for-missing-japanese-kayaker-scaled-back-20170730-gxlxnm.html</url>
  <title>Four days on, search of Port Phillip Bay for missing Japanese kayaker scaled back</title>
  <content>
There are fears that a Japanese kayaker who has been missing in Port Phillip Bay for four days may never be found as authorities begin to scale back their search efforts.
But friends of Junichi Yoshimura remain hopeful, as his yellow kayak is yet to be recovered.

Up Next

Rosebud has the highest proprotion of widows

00:46

More Victoria News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Police search for missing kayaker

Water police commence a search for a missing man in Altona. Colleagues raised the alarm when he failed to show up for work. Vision courtesy Seven News.

The 41-year-old man has been missing since he launched his kayak from an Altona boat ramp, about 5am on Thursday.
His car, a white 2002 Subaru Forester with registration RXS 891, was found at the boat ramp on Friday.

Over the weekend, a large search effort involved water police, the coast guard, marine volunteers, and a police helicopter.
Saturday's extreme weather made the search difficult, with Port Phillip Bay subjected to strong wind gusts.

On Monday morning, police confirmed they would carry on looking for Mr Yoshimura but said the operation would be less intense.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The search continues but has been scaled back and is no longer utilising volunteer resources," a police spokeswoman said.Photo: Facebook
Monday's search will involve the police helicopter and water police, she said.
Friends and colleagues at Torquay's Zeally Bay Sourdough, where he had been working as a baker for several months, remained hopeful that Mr Yoshimura would be found.Photo: Supplied
"If they think he's still in the water, then I think what they've done is appropriate, so we can only hope that he's somewhere safe," bakery owner Joel Farnan said.
"We're a fairly small bakery and we make everything by hand, so we stand side by side every day and rely on each other.
"Everyone's very worried and a bit upset by the whole thing."
He said the missing kayak, a distinctive "2 Monks" boat in canary yellow, gave him some hope.
"The fact that they haven't found the kayak, that means there's still a chance that he might be found alive, so we're clinging to that," Mr Farnan said.
Mr Yoshimura's family are due to arrive in Melbourne, from Japan, on Tuesday morning.
Anyone who sees the kayak or who has information should call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
With Neelima Choahan
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torquay's Zeally Bay Sourdough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neelima Choahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Phillip Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Yoshimura</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Junichi Yoshimura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru Forester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RXS891</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Farnan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Farnan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Altona</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
