<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398273889833391</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4820025/were-a-free-country-all-because-of-them/?cs=305</url>
  <title>'We're a free country all because of them'</title>
  <content>
LABOUR OF LOVE: Gary Mitchell's passion has been to put a name to the unidentified graves at Sandgate Cemetery. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

IN the general portion of Sandgate Cemetery, there are more unmarked graves than marked. That just doesn't sit well with Gary Mitchell.

"A lot of these men have come home [from war], maybe they couldn't find a job and they have died paupers," he said. "Hence the reason why they are in unmarked graves. Forever forgotten."
Forgotten no more.
With a passion for military history that transformed into an "obsession", Mr Mitchell has spent more than a decade commemorating Newcastle's war heroes at Sandgate, ensuring those who made the ultimate sacrifice are forever etched into memory.
Through meticulous research, Mr Mitchell tracks down the names of soldiers who may have served and were buried at Sandgate, using clues found in service records, the Newcastle Family History Library and the Newcastle Morning Herald archives to build a profile and tell their story online through the Sandgate Cemetery website.

If a grave he identifies is unmarked, he places a white cross donated by the Morpeth Men's Shed, sometimes in a ceremony attended by the soldier's direct descendants.
"Some of them have no idea their descendants were buried there," Mr Mitchell said.
"Some of these descendants I've met at the grave site. I've placed a cross while they've been there, and it really is quite moving, they really do appreciate it."

Gary Mitchell at Sandgate Cemetery. Picture: Jonathan Carroll
At a ceremony last month, about 100 people turned out to commemorate the life of Private Jim Antcliff, who was honoured on the 100th anniversary of the Battle of Messines.  

A ceremony for another war hero researched by Mr Mitchell is planned for later this year.
The Newcastle man estimates he has located 700 graves, with close to 100 in unmarked graves. 
However, he said the job is not yet done, with an "awful long way to go".
In a list of names kept by the cemetery of everyone who is buried there, Mr Mitchell has only reached "g".
Motivated by the drive of living in a free country, made possible by those who gave their lives, he said he would keep powering on until the job is done.

"I think we all need to remember why we are here today and why we are the way we are," Mr Mitchell said.
"It's easy for us to say a lot of these men's lives were needlessly sacrificed - and in a lot of cases they were - but if they didn't do what they did, history would be quite different. We are a free country and it's because of men, not just in the First World War, but in the Second World War and onwards, who made the supreme sacrifice. At certain times we all just need to reflect on that."

Nominate someone for the Newcastle Herald's Hunter Water Hunter Hero Awards. Each week we profile someone doing something extraordinary in and for our community. Email community@theherald.com.au or phone 4979 5999.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Private Jim Antcliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Family History Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandgate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Second World War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First World War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battle of Messines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald's Hunter Water Hunter Hero Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mitchell</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LABOUR OF LOVE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Mitchell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morpeth Men's Shed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Morning Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandgate Cemetery</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
