<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398398443886381</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/07/31/09/57/new-footage-of-fiery-plane-crash-on-us-highway</url>
  <title>New footage of fiery plane crash on US highway</title>
  <content>
A new video has been released of a fiery plane crash on a US highway last month where two people miraculously were pulled out alive from the wreckage.

The video taken on the 405 Freeway in Santa Ana opposite John Wayne Airport shows a twin engine white Cessna 310 slam into to the middle of the road on June 30 and erupt into a giant ball of fire.

The aircraft narrowly missed dozens of cars travelling in both directions.

Earlier footage shows an off-duty fireman pulling the plane's occupants -  pilot Francis Pisano, and his wife, Janan -  from the wreckage.

An accident report released by the National Transportation Safety Board showed the couple took off from the airport just after 9.30am when the plane lost power, s reports.

"Hey, we got a mayday. We got a mayday," Pisano told the control tower as he frantically tried to manoeuvre back towards the runway.

The tower informed the pilot his landing gear was still up.

Related Articles

"Yeah, I know. We're still trying to get a little altitude. I lost my right engine," Pisano responded.

As the pilot attempted to land, his aircraft lost altitude on route and crashed into the median strip dividing the two lanes of the highway.

Authorities told the US publication that given the severity of the explosion and the surrounding peak hour traffic, the accident could have been a lot worse.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Wayne Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Transportation Safety Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessna 310</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francis Pisano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Ana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
