<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398398443886393</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/gay-marriage-same-sex-marriage-vote-openly-gay-mp-trevor-evans/8758852</url>
  <title>Queensland's first openly gay MP, Trevor Evans, wants same-sex marriage vote now</title>
  <content>
Queensland's first openly gay MP wants a parliamentary vote to immediately resolve the same sex marriage debate, calling on the Turnbull Government to dump its election commitment to hold a plebiscite.
Trevor Evans, the federal Liberal member for Brisbane, has not ruled out crossing the floor and supporting a Labor to suspend standing orders and introduce a bill to change the Marriage Act.
"I don't think it necessarily has to come to that," said the first-term MP.
"There's a number of ways forward.
"I'd like to think that the Government can take control of the agenda and organise a parliamentary vote on our terms and resolve this matter in a businesslike fashion."

A week out from Parliament returning from its long winter break, Mr Evans said the Coalition should dump its policy to hold a plebiscite on the issue given it had been rejected by Labor and the Greens in the Senate earlier this year.
While Mr Evans supported the plebiscite, he wanted the matter resolved in the quickest way possible.
"This issue is distracting from the Government's very real achievements in areas like cutting taxes for small businesses, passing industrial relations laws and passing the budget," he said.

He said his opinion was merely adding his voice to find a different way forward.
"The entire community is frustrated to see that this issue continues to be on the agenda when it should have been resolved in line with our election commitment," he said.
"I would like to think there is enough good will in the Government and in the Parliament to find a way forward to resolve this."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Evans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
