<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398368379115019</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/widening-of-major-coast-roads-sparks-furore-with-b/3206868/</url>
  <title>Widening of major Coast roads sparks furore with businesses</title>
  <content>
DURING peak hour, commuting on Nicklin Way can be a headache for motorists.
So it was with excitement a proposal from the Department for Transport and Main Roads to alter Nicklin Way between Main Dr and Waterview St was welcomed by residents.
But small businesses along the strip and the Kawana Chamber of Commerce are up in arms, concerned it would "decimate" business as customers would not be able to park in front of their stores.
The widening involves adding a lane, the installation of traffic lights at Production Ave and removal of car parking on Nicklin Way, northbound, and on Production Ave.
Business owner of Flair Jewellery Peter Turner, whose business would be directly affected, has joined other business owners to create a petition to stop the widening.
"It's the only space our clients have to park in," he said.
"It would cruel the ease of access to our business. One of the main features of our businesses is that people can avoid shopping centres.
"It's vitally important that we have this."
Mr Turner said the group had presented many alternatives.
"We have talked about alternatives such as parking bays cut into the existing greenery," he said.
Mr Turner said he wanted people to sign the petition to help put a sense of urgency behind the alternatives they proposed.
A spokesperson from TMR said the upgrade was still under investigation and was part of the project to improve access to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital.
The spokesperson said the project would "significantly improve traffic flow, as well as cyclist and pedestrian safety".
"We are currently reviewing and considering feedback as part of the ongoing planning and stakeholder engagement phase of the project," they said.
"These investigations are ongoing and are expected to be finalised in the coming weeks."
For further information, TMR can be contacted on 54517055. Or to sign the petition, visit www.gopetition.com
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicklin Way</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Production Ave</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TMR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flair Jewellery Peter Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterview St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
