<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398359789180286</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/morris-on-monday-territory-rugby-league-a-shadow-of-its-former-self/news-story/561a4aa434c963b6b070459c170e90b9</url>
  <title>Territory league a shadow of former self</title>
  <content>
REMEMBER the glorious era of Darwin rugby league, when Brothers and Nightcliff ruled the roost and big crowds made daily pilgrimages to Richardson Park in Ludmilla?
It was a time when rugby league was the dry season sport, boasting big names like De La Cruz, Motlop, Stokes, AhMat and Johnson and Darwin clubs competed in the Amco and Pacific Cups and even met and frightened the touring Poms in a 1984 match in Darwin.
Now, Richardson Park is a hulking ghost stadium and the competition runs under the exhaustive banner of the longest name in rugby league, NTRLNT.
Contained under it is an A-grade competition that consists of as many byes and forfeits as it does competitive matches, a sad and sorry state of affairs for a sport that used to hold the No.2 mantle in Darwin for participation rates.
There has been a succession of general managers, little or no interest from its parent body, the Australian Rugby League, and member clubs more interested in their own welfare than the future direction of rugby league in the Top End and across the Territory.
In 2017, the grim reaper made his presence felt, presenting a strange and confusing draw, particularly in Round 10 when players, officials and fans were treated to one game, an 84-0 stroll by Litchfield against an undermanned South Darwin.
There are 12 senior teams, not including Souths, who forfeited three reserve grade matches, which led to their expulsion from the competition, but the average fan would struggle to name them on any given day.
And what of Katherine, the town that jumped up and down to be included in the A-grade competition but only play matches when they feel like it.
This writer is a serious tipster, but in the case of the not so mighty Katherine Cowboys, my heart rules my head and I never fail to tip the home town.
But watching the Cowboys forfeit matches or field weakened teams makes a mockery of my tipping capabilities and what is already a struggling competition, bar the top four - Palmerston, Brothers, Litchfield and Nightcliff - who seem to be fair dinkum about their rugby league.
I call on my old mate Steve "Buddha'' Kelly and the great Paul Jennings to call a crisis meeting in Katherine on whether the town wants a rugby league team or not.
If they do, start to negotiate a deal with Jabiru and Gove where the "Country'' team came from in the 1980s and maybe then the players will play with the passion and heart required.
Meanwhile, the Warren Park saga continues where clubs are still unhappy with how general manager Nigel Roy has handled the situation.
Three clubs pulled their support for NRLNT's $25 million new home at Marrara last month, a combination of a protest against the league and the fact South Darwin, who own the land and who will have the last laugh when the lease is -renegotiated.
It is way past time egos and selfishness were put aside for the good of Darwin rugby league and where it will be in 50 years.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRLNT's $25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marrara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jabiru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nightcliff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Motlop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NTRLNT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmerston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine Cowboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Roy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AhMat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De La Cruz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ludmilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Cups</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Litchfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
