<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398355494212896</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/lifestyle/life-and-relationships/dating-with-autism-is-hard-but-a-simple-selfcare-routine-helped-20170726-gxj8jk.html</url>
  <title>How I worked out that dating isn't a game</title>
  <content>
Dating is like playing charades. It's a movie, and the movie is "right now" so quickly guess what might or might not be happening: Was what I said funny? Is a raised eyebrow good? Are they checking their phone because this is... boring? Are there knots in my stomach because I shouldn't have eaten the edamame, or because I don't actually like this person?
Add autism to the equation and it's like playing the game blindfolded, while still hoping for a win. The prize? A different picture of the future from the one where I'm in a bath tub praying to the field of infinite possibilities that, somehow, despite it all, I won't end up with 70 cats that I feed amid piles of numerology books because numbers and animals are the only things I seem to be able to communicate clearly and succinctly with.Photo: Hector MacKenzie
But, with or without autism, all dating appears to be speed dating. We are expected to want the sex and/or the partner, now. Every interaction that we have then becomes an evaluation, and it's exhausting. Want sugar in your coffee? Are we dating? What time does the lecture start? Are we dating? Swipe right? Are we dating? Thanks for the text? Are we dating?
Years ago I left a cafe feeling excited for a salad I was going to have with the barista in her apartment when she finished her shift at 11pm because I love leafy greens, and I love new friends. But a co-worker had to explain to me that I was 110 per cent headed toward DateTown, and that they were very inspired by my sudden decision to start seeing women.

Unfortunately, I hadn't realised I was doing either of those things, so in a DEFCON 1 Autistic Panic I cancelled and couldn't bring myself to order a soy cappuccino from that cafe ever again, even though they were the only establishment in a three-kilometre radius that used Bonsoy. Yet, to this day, part of me still wonders what salad with her would have been like.
It can take weeks, months or even years to figure out the feelings that we have for someone. I was with a guy for a year before I knew for certain that we were wrong for one another and that I wasn't attracted to him at all. Now, my therapist doesn't say much, but I'm quite certain he restrained himself from cheering when that particular existential crisis came to an end.

Why? Because fear of loneliness had lured me into an unsuitable relationship and, inevitably, nothing good could come out of it.
But, whether you're single or in a relationship, it can be hard to imagine comfort coming from anywhere but someone else's arms. Self-love in our culture is synonymous with punishment. There's nothing patient or gentle to be said about it: it's partying hard, it's juice cleansing hard, it's Vipassana retreating hard, it's checking out on PayPal hard. So, of course, when facing the possibility of no one being in our bed tonight, it can be difficult to discern where else to find a sense of safety, or relief.  
Days before my first breakup I remember catching my own gaze in the mirror as I applied body oil after a shower and a voice from the ether bellowed: "Do this after every shower or bath, whether you're in a relationship or not. Because even if no one else's hands are going to be caressing your skin, this matters. Self-care matters."
It was one of the best pieces of advice I didn't receive from anyone else.
The ritual of applying body oil after every shower or bath is something I've now done before and after dates, through relationships, brief encounters, unrequited loves,  and confused courtships - even though it took a while to understand that it wasn't just about nicely-moisturised elbows and knees. It was about love.
Once I realised this, my attitude toward dating completely changed. It isn't something that needs to be played like a game, acquired quickly, worked out, guessed at or analysed. It isn't about navigating the difficulties that arise with autism or Alexithymia. The key to dating and fulfilling relationships is loving myself.
This gave me the confidence to end a relationship that wasn't right and embrace the prospect of my own company but, of course, within a month, the stars aligned with a man who I've now been with for three years.
And it revealed itself when I was alone, looking in the mirror, naked, wondering what on earth to do next because I couldn't understand what I, or anyone else, was thinking or feeling. Creating a ceremony dedicated to self-care was all I had left.
So I looked around, I saw the body oil, I picked the thing up, opened it, and poured it all over myself until I didn't know what I was doing or where I was anymore. And it didn't even matter because I realised that the one person I'd forgotten to love, all along, was me.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonsoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexithymia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paypal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DateTown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEFCON 1 Autistic Panic I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hector MacKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
