<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398441393559843</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/automotive-transformation-minister-kyam-maher-says-new-holden-museum-exhibit-will-keep-sas-very-proud-history-of-carmaking-alive/news-story/bae7c5f4abe690a29e67c9280bc599d6</url>
  <title>Museum to keep Holden history alive</title>
  <content>
A PERMANENT display celebrating more than half a century of carmaking at Holden's Elizabeth factory will live on in SA after the company closes its door on October 20.
An exhibition telling the story of Holden will be established at the National Motor Museum in Birdwood, in partnership with the History Trust of SA.
The [Re]assembled exhibition will replicate six assembly-line stations from GM Holden's Elizabeth Plant, suspended from the ceiling.
In addition, the social history of car manufacturing will be told through a focus on automotive workers and community, and supply-chain companies.
The exhibition will also include digital displays and each station will carry a vehicle at different stages of assembly right through to a fully-assembled car.
It will feature "screen-based video information", interactive augmented reality and the development of an app to support the visitor experience. There will also be an education program about technical and social history outcomes.
The exhibition will be opened during the Bay to Birdwood on September 24.
Holden announced almost four years ago that it would follow Mitsubishi and cease operations in Adelaide, a move that will result in the industry exiting SA in less than three months' time.
Automotive Transformation Minister Kyam Maher said SA "has a very proud history of car manufacturing and it is appropriate that we support a lasting legacy, to ensure future generations understand how important automotive manufacturing is to our state's history".
"For over 50 years, generations of South Australians have worked in the automotive industry,
and we should be proud that we are one of only 13 countries who can build cars from scratch," he said.
"We are delighted to be sponsors of this display at the National Motor Museum, which plays an important role in documenting the history of cars in Australia."
The State Government's Automotive Transformation Taskforce has delivered $110,000 towards the $600,000 display, with Arts SA also providing $20,000 and further funding from Holden.
GM Holden Corporate Affairs Manager SA Sophie Milic said her company "built the auto industry in Australia and Adelaide" and the permanent display would "be a tribute to the
people, skills and engineering capabilities that contributed to this industry".
"Our people are building the best cars we've ever built and this display will be a permanent
reminder of the quality and care they have shown," Ms Milic said.
National Motor Museum Director Paul Rees said the exhibition "gives the past a future now" and "assists us tell the all-important story of the people behind automotive manufacturing".
"I am particularly pleased that the final car in the display is what's called 'the signature car', which has been signed by hundreds of recent and current workers from the Elizabeth Plant," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Milic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsubishi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GM Holden's Elizabeth Plant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Motor Museum Director Paul Rees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>History Trust of SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Plant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Automotive Transformation Minister Kyam Maher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GM Holden Corporate Affairs Manager SA Sophie Milic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Motor Museum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government's Automotive Transformation Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden's Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
