<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398402738853730</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/weekend-donations-destroyed-in-cairns-salvation-army-stores/news-story/a82b7c5a8dcf38a496a4c0e4e3cb8dc6</url>
  <title>Donations destroyed</title>
  <content>
AS MONDAY morning rolls around Salvation Army volunteers get ready for the worst part of their week.
The goods donated during the weekend are scattered across the carpark, there are broken pieces of crockery, books ripped open, and clothes left out in the weekend's weather.
The Salvation Army team is sick of it.
Salvation Army area manager Alison Geno told the Cairns Post volunteers came into work early at the start of every week to begin the clean up.
"It can take three or four hours to clean everything up," she said.
"It's extremely frustrating for volunteers, they have to clean up before they can even register their hours for the day."
She said people who went through the donated items often up-ended bags and roughly discarded things they didn't steal from the collection points.
"It's regular for us to clean up broken goods," she said.
"People come and take what they want. We never get half the goods that are donated on a weekend."
She said for each destroyed donation there was money being taken away from the community.
"We rely on the income from donated gods to run services in this community," she said.
"Money raised here stays in the community, so it's a shame to think that people will come in here and damage the things donated to us."
Ms Geno said it was especially tough for workers who knew the good spirit that the goods were donated with.
"The only positive here is to say thank you to the people who are donating," she said.
"We'd really urge them to come in during work hours if they can because we want and need the things that are donated."
She said anyone experiencing financial difficulty could visit any of the Cairns Salvation Army stores.
"If you need something, just come in and ask for it," she said.
"Rather than just helping yourself come in and see us and we'll try to help. It's what we're here for."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alison Geno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Salvation Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Geno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
