<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398187990486301</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/st-kilda-champion-to-reveal-his-playing-future/news-story/18644e33bde7b63265f26e080215df9c</url>
  <title>Is Saint Nick about to call time?</title>
  <content>
ST KILDA will make a major announcement about the future of one of its champions today.
The Saints are expected to reveal whether Nick Riewoldt will play on into an 18th season.
Leigh Montagna is also yet to decide if he will play on next year.
The announcement will be made at 2pm today.

Major announcement from Saints today. One of their veterans will reveal their retirement plans. About 2pm. More

Riewoldt has played 333 games and was rested against Port Adelaide on Saturday night.
"He'd be the first to admit that his last couple of performances have been below his best, it was time for him to have a spell. We'll get him back next week, all going well in terms of the plan and he'll be better for that break,'' Saints coach Alan Richardson said.
END OF THE LINE?
MARK ROBINSON:
Asked about Riewoldt's future, he said: "All I can really say on that is the conversations are absolutely private but they are ongoing.
"Both camps know exactly where they sit, there are conversations between player and coach, there are conversations between management.''
Montagna won't play again this season unless the Saints make the finals after suffering a bad hamstring injury against Sydney a week ago.
Last week .
"Same deal (for Montagna), let's see how you're going physically, there's no doubt that it's not great timing, I think he said as much,'' Richardson said.
"We'll make that call and we'll have those ongoing discussions and make a call in the next few weeks.''
MORE TO COME
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saint Nick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Montagna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARK ROBINSON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montagna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
