<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398445688527264</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/end-political-donations-labor-senator/news-story/e88846043cc4537edcc272125ff2eb11</url>
  <title>End political donations: Labor senator</title>
  <content>
A prominent Labor senator who allowed a state-linked Chinese company to pay part of his travel bill is now calling for a total ban on political donations.
Sam Dastyari candidly admits he was one of the "weapon suppliers in this arms race" during his time as secretary of Labor's NSW branch.
"It needs to come to an end, and the time for that is now," he told ABC-TV's Australian Story on Monday.
Cabinet minister Peter Dutton wasn't impressed by the senator's call.
"I wouldn't take Sam Dastyari as the perfect specimen here to be providing advice to anybody frankly when it comes to political interactions or donations," he told ABC TV.
"So I might take it with a grain of salt, if you don't mind."
Labor leader Bill Shorten stopped short of backing Senator Dastyari's call for a ban on all donations.
"We're up for donations reform," he told ABC radio.
"I want to wean us off relying on foreign donations."
The Greens accused Labor of using different messages for different audiences.
While Senator Dastyari was going the 'full monty', Mr Shorten was pushing the minimalist version of reform that went no further than some transparency changes to reporting and a ban on foreign donations.
"Labor's official position will not clean up politics or end the corrupting influence of political donations," democracy spokesperson Lee Rhiannon said in a statement.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC-TV's Australian Story</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Rhiannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dastyari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Dastyari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
