<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397578105122420</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/mama-tribe-the-online-movement-for-mothers-thats-catching-on-in-canberra-20170719-gxe2f0.html</url>
  <title>No mums will be left behind with this movement</title>
  <content>
Modern motherhood can be isolating and overwhelming as women feel the pressure to be on top of it all.
But a new social movement, The Mama Tribe, picking up steam across the country is reminding women to connect with other 'bad ass mums' in their area who will have their back.Photo: Sitthixay Ditthavong
The new social network with the motto: #NoMumLeftBehind is the brainchild of two Queensland mums, Hayley Finlayson and Nikki McCahon, who both experienced crippling loneliness following the birth of their babies.

Co-creators of Mama Tribe Haley Finlayson and Nikki McCahon with their babies. Photo: Mama Tribe

In the two months since Mama Tribe launched it has gathered nearly 10,000 mums in more than 60 local tribes.
Genevieve Cody is one of more than 200 mums to join the Canberra sub group led by first-time mother Zoe Heuzenroder. 

Genevieve Cody, Renee Henderson with Evelyn and Edward, Nerida Casey, Carson, Zoe Heuzenroeder with Adele Smith, and Marty Baker. Photo: Sitthixay Ditthavong

Ms Cody has recently moved to Australia from the United States, leaving behind her strong family network.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

She has two sons, aged 4 and 22 months old, and is two weeks from having her third child. 
"I saw it online and thought this is exactly what I need in my life right now," she said. "I don't know many people but I know I need help in that journey."
She experienced postnatal depression after having her second child Carson.
Putting a support network in place gave her a sense of relief and a hosts of new buddies to commiserate with about sleeplessness and other common stresses of parenthood. 
This past seven days the network have united thousands of mums around Australia and New Zealand to celebrate the first ever 'No Mum Left Behind' week. 

Zoe Heuzenroeder with Adele Smith. Photo: Sitthixay Ditthavong

With her daughter Adele in her arms Ms Heuzenroder explained how starting Canberra's Mama Tribe tested her as she battled anxiety, but was worth it to share the #NoMumLeftBehind message. 
"I have a lot of anxiety and for ages, it stopped me from reaching out to people and I was going through a really bad time with postnatal depression and had completely retreated," she said. 
"For me it's about saying we are not going to let anyone else hide away, not get out there and get through that hard time in their life." 
She said Mama Tribe differed from other online groups by hosting regular meet ups and was focused on removing any pretence or pressure to make sure members always felt comfortable and connected. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mama Tribe</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra's Mama Tribe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Heuzenroder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mum Left Behind</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nerida Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Heuzenroeder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marty Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genevieve Cody</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tribe Haley Finlayson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NoMumLeftBehind</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikki McCahon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Cody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Heuzenroder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evelyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-creators of Mama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sitthixay Ditthavong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley Finlayson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renee Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
