<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397586695057217</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/07/31/pm-kicks-wa-trip-schools-package</url>
  <title>PM kicks off WA trip with schools package</title>
  <content>
Malcolm Turnbull will kick off his visit to Western Australia with a promise of $46.7 million in extra funding for indigenous students in the state.

3 HOURS AGO 

Malcolm Turnbull is promising to more than double the amount of funding for indigenous students in WA over the next decade as he drums up support in the west.

The prime minister will on Monday announce a $46.7 million package as part of his government's changes to school funding.

The arrangement is expected to see support for indigenous students in Western Australia grow at a faster rate than any other state or territory - from $1,480 per student a year in 2017 to $2,626 by 2027.

The government claims previous school funding arrangements would have left WA students with less money than if they went to the same school in another state.

Mr Turnbull said the reforms would be a game-changer for students in WA.

"My government's new schools funding plan will ensure the students that need the most support get the most support," he said.

Australia's most senior indigenous politician, Ken Wyatt, said the additional support for indigenous students in WA was critical to level the playing field.

"There can be additional barriers indigenous students face compared with those from non-indigenous backgrounds and I'm proud that the Turnbull government is the first in Australia's history to adopt real needs-based funding," he said.

The announcement kicks off Mr Turnbull's visit to WA, his first in nearly six months.

The prime minister arrived on Sunday ahead of a cabinet meeting on Monday, and is set to spend much of the week in the state.

A Galaxy poll published in The Sunday Times predicted the Liberals could lose four seats in the west at the next federal election, with primary support down 10 percentage points to 39 per cent.

WA's Labor premier Mark McGowan said on Sunday the prime minister needed to stop avoiding issues affecting the state, including its GST share.

"He knows these issues are here, he needs to deal with them. Better to bite the bullet and get it over with," he told reporters.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA's Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
