<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397844393098117</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/national/man-armed-with-a-tomahawk-breaks-into-the-bakery-cafe-in-eildon/news-story/1e67cfe81ecca005ce85715e2587a195</url>
  <title>Axe-wielding man smashes way into cafe</title>
  <content>
AN AXE-WIELDING man has broken into an Eildon cafe, causing staff to fear for their lives.
Staff at the Bakery Cafe in Eildon were working late on Friday night when just eight minutes after their shift, a man with a tomahawk broke into their business.
Cafe owner Jo Teklenburg said the man tried to smash into the back of an ATM located in her shop.
"He was armed with what appears to be a Canadian style tomahawk axe," she told the Herald Sun.
"He's obviously been in the store before to know where the ATM is located. He was in and out in four minutes."
The man jumped the fence and broken into the store via the back doors.
"I feel violated. These crooks have no regard for anything," Ms Teklenburg said.
"It makes my staff and I feel uneasy and on edge.
"It's a sinking feeling, watching CCTV of someone creeping into your business.
"I wouldn't have liked to come face-to-face with the guy."
Ms Teklenburg said there was a local drug problem and it was hard for local police to deal with an escalating crime problem in the area.
"We're all hardworking, decent people and the constant crime gets the locals a bit cranky," she said.
The man was carrying a duffel bag, was wearing black gloves and had a flashlight attached to his head however failed to get away with anything of value.
Police confirm they are investigating the burglary.
"It is believed an unknown male offender entered the business by forcing rear doors at about 9pm," Victoria Police spokeswoman Lauren Kells said.
"The man allegedly attempted to open an ATM once inside, however was not successful.
"It is believed the offender was wearing a disguise and gloves.
"The investigation remains ongoing."
Anyone with information is urged to call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bakery Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AXE-WIELDING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eildon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Teklenburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATM</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Kells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Teklenburg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
