<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398398443886388</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/canberra-cricket-fans-in-the-dark-with-sydney-thunder-yet-to-announce-bbl-venue-20170730-gxlzaq.html</url>
  <title>Sydney Thunder yet to announce venue for fifth BBL game</title>
  <content>
Canberra cricket fans are still in the dark about the immediate future of the Big Bash League in the capital, with the Sydney Thunder yet to announce a venue for their fifth home game.
The BBL fixtures were published on Monday morning but the Thunder are yet to confirm the venue for their additional home game, but Manuka Oval is in the frame.Photo: Melissa Adams
The BBL will be expanded to 40 regular season matches this summer and Manuka Oval shapes as an ideal location for the Thunder's fifth home game, if the price is right.
The Thunder were considering playing their fifth home game at their regular venue - Spotless Stadium - in the wake of a series of sell-out crowds.
However the club was in talks with Cricket ACT and the ACT government about bringing the match to Canberra as the capital looks to make up for being left off the men's international schedule.
Canberra was squeezed out of the men's international schedule for the upcoming Ashes summer despite being midway through a four-year deal to have international cricket played in the capital.

Canberra will still get a taste of international cricket when Manuka Oval hosts two Twenty20 matches as part of the women's Ashes series in November this year.
The BBL fixtures were published in bizarre fashion, with a handful of tweets from the Sydney Sixers the only peep on social media from any of the franchises or the league itself in the build-up.
A sell-out crowd of 11,837 witnessed the BBL|04 final at Manuka Oval and Cricket ACT is keen to operate a franchise of its own with Canberra amongst a host of cities eyeing a team of their own.
But at this stage expansion discussions are hypothetical with no immediate plans to introduce new clubs to the eight-team competition.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Sixers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBL|04</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket ACT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Thunder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thunder</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
