<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398359789180310</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/darwin-rovers-given-the-tough-task-of-beating-aleague-champions-sydney-fc-in-ffa-cup-clash/news-story/cbd3f872a2df480c467b16c4a2284b12</url>
  <title>Rovers revved for big battle against Blues</title>
  <content>
DARWIN Rovers skipper Simon Bell describes it as the proudest moment of his life and for 11 players in green and white hoops Wednesday's FFA Cup clash will be exactly that.
The Rovers meet reigning A-League champions Sydney FC in the biggest game of football Darwin has seen.
A win for either side will guarantee a berth in the national competition's Round of 16 and for Bell, the chance of a monumental upset gives the game even more impetus.
"Our plan is not to stop them scoring, we're going out there to win the game,'' he told the NT News.
"We're not working on damage control where we try and keep the scoreline from being embarrassing.
To tell you the truth we'd rather have that happen knowing we went full pelt and tried our best to win as opposed to losing 1-0 or 2-0 and not giving our all.''
Sydney FC's coach Graham Arnold has indicated a full-strength Blues side will be in Darwin for the Round of 32 knockout fixture, including marquee players Bobo and Milos Ninkovic and inspirational captain Alex Brosque.
But Bell is confident his side has the weapons to neutralise their opponent's firepower.
"It's a big jump in class, we all know that, but we're determined to bring them down to our level and make it a very physical game,'' he said.
"We've got some good defenders and big centre halves that can win everything in the air, so it's not going to be a walk in the park for them."
For Bell, the Rovers squad equates to his side's tradies against their millionaires.
"They played Arsenal and Liverpool in warm-up games to get ready to play us and this game basically,'' he said.
"We're all tradies who play for fun basically, while they drive Lamborghinis and -Ferraris.''
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsenal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARWIN Rovers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Arnold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday's FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lamborghinis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milos Ninkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Brosque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
