<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398441393559809</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/motor-sport/daniel-ricciardo-put-out-of-hungarian-f1-grand-prix-by-teammate-max-verstappen/news-story/2f808c17a65607e804cd5b93e3298b27</url>
  <title>Video: Filthy Ricciardo punted by teammate</title>
  <content>
DANIEL Ricciardo's Hungarian Grand Prix was over as soon as it began after he was hit by teammate Max Verstappen on lap one.
The disastrous collision took place at turn two when Verstappen locked his brakes, sending his Red Bull careering into the side of his teammate's.
Ricciardo fumed about the incident on the radio: "Someone hit me. Was that who I think it was? ****ing sore loser."
LIVE stream the Belgian GP on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
SORRY:
EXCLUSIVE:
WATCH:
REPORT:
Verstappen was handed a 10 second time penalty by stewards for causing a collision, but that was of little comfort to an incensed Ricciardo.
"There was never a pass there," Ricciardo told TV crews. "It was just a mistake. There's no way there was ever room, because Valtteri (Bottas) was covering the inside anyway.
"I couldn't have done anything else. I was just on my line. Obviously he got the penalty and all that, and it's obvious whose mistake it was, it doesn't change my race.
The Australian argued that "immaturity," not inexperience, was behind his teammate's error and insisted his team would address the situation after the race.
"Obviously, the team will do their bit and I'll do mine. Yeah, there shouldn't be too much to say but sure we'll sort it out.
"He doesn't like when a teammate gets in front of him. It was a very poor mistake. It wasn't on and [it was] amateur to say the least.
"I honestly don't think it's trying too hard or an excuse for it. It's like he tried T1 outside, it didn't work and he had the line taken from him. What looks a good start is a bad start, I go past and it's 'oops, I've got to fix it.'"
Verstappen, who admitted fault for the incident, recovered to finish fifth and hot on the heels of both Mercedes drivers.
"We were both fighting for position in Turn 2 so we braked quite deep into the corner," Verstappen told TV crews.
"I tried to keep it to the inside but then I just got locking, locking, and then I unfortunately touched Daniel on the weakest point of the car, in the side.
"Of course I was trying to avoid Daniel but unfortunately that was not possible.
"It is never my intention to hit anyone, but especially not your teammate, and especially with the relationship I have with Daniel - it's always really good and we can always have a laugh.
"This is not nice and I apologise to Daniel for that and also to the team because we could have scored some good points here. I'll speak with Daniel in private and we'll sort it out."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Filthy Ricciardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turn 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verstappen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Verstappen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DANIEL Ricciardo's Hungarian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valtteri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgian GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bottas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricciardo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
