<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398355494212937</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/venezuela-deadly-protests-mar-election/8758694</url>
  <title>Venezuela election: Deadly protests mar ballot as voters snub Maduro constituent assembly</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Deadly protests have rocked Venezuela as voters broadly boycotted an election for a constitutional super-body that unpopular leftist President Nicolas Maduro vowed would begin a "new era of combat" in the crisis-stricken nation.

Key points:

Critics says new body would have power to dissolve opposition-run Congress
US says election is a step towards dictatorship
Opposition estimates 7 per cent voter participation by mid-afternoon

Opposition parties are sitting out what they call a rigged election aimed at consolidating Mr Maduro's power, leaving streets deserted and polling stations largely empty and dealing a blow to the legitimacy of the vote.
Anti-Maduro activists erected barricades on roads and scuffles broke out with security forces who moved in quickly to disperse the demonstrators.
Authorities said seven people were killed in the unrest and the opposition said the true death toll was about a dozen people, which would make Sunday one of the deadliest days since massive and sustained protests kicked off in early April.
Mr Maduro, widely reviled for overseeing an economic collapse during four years in office, has pressed ahead with the vote to create the all-powerful assembly despite the threat of US sanctions and months of opposition protests in which about 120 people have been killed.
Critics say the assembly will allow Mr Maduro to dissolve the opposition-run Congress, delay future elections and rewrite electoral rules to prevent the socialists from being voted out of power in the once-thriving OPEC nation.
US ambassador to the United Nations Nikki Haley said Washington would not accept the result.
"Maduro's sham election is another step toward dictatorship," Ms Haley said on Twitter.
"We won't accept an illegit govt. The Venezuelan ppl & democracy will prevail."
In what could be the spread of more aggressive tactics, a bomb exploded in Caracas and injured seven police officers.
The opposition has vowed to redouble its resistance and US President Donald Trump has promised broader economic sanctions against Venezuela after the vote, suggesting the oil-rich nation's crisis is set to escalate further.
"Even if they win today, this won't last long," said opposition supporter Berta Hernandez, a 60-year-old doctor, in a wealthier Caracas district.
"I'll continue on the streets because, not long from now, this will come to an end."
State employees pressured to vote

Mr Maduro, a former bus driver and union leader narrowly elected in 2013, has accused right-wing governments of trying to sabotage "21st century socialism" created by his predecessor, the late Hugo Chavez.
"The 'emperor' Donald Trump wanted to halt the Venezuelan people's right to vote," said Mr Maduro, as he quickly voted in the early morning in a low-income area of the capital Caracas that has turned on the Government.
"A new era of combat will begin. We're going all out with this constituent assembly."

But with polls showing some 70 per cent of Venezuelans oppose the vote, the country's 2.8 million state employees are under huge pressure to participate - with dozens sources saying they were being threatened with dismissal.
Workers were being blasted with text messages and phone calls asking them to vote and report back after doing so.
The opposition estimated participation was about a paltry 7 per cent by mid-afternoon, but warned the Government was gearing up to announce some 8.5 million people had voted.
Police officers injured in bomb blast

In Sunday's gravest incident, a bomb went off as a group of police officers on motorbikes sped past Caracas' Altamira Plaza, an opposition stronghold.
The state prosecutor's office said seven officers were injured and four motorbikes burned.
Clashes were also reported in the volatile Andean state of Tachira, whose capital is San Cristobal, where witnesses said an unidentified group of men had showed up at two separate street protests and shot at demonstrators.
Authorities confirmed nine deaths over the weekend, including two teenagers and a candidate to the assembly, killed during a robbery in the jungle state of Bolivar.
The state's Socialist Party Governor, Francisco Rangel, said the death was a "political hit job" and blamed it on the opposition.
Supporters of "Chavismo", the movement founded by Mr Chavez, Mr Maduro's more charismatic predecessor who enjoyed high oil prices for much of his mandate, said they wanted to halt the unrest.
"The [opposition] wants deaths and roadblocks and the Government wants peace," said Olga Blanco, 50, voting for candidates to the assembly at a school in Caracas.

Reuters

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugo Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Cristobal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berta Hernandez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olga Blanco, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Maduro</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Haley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socialist Party Governor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tachira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Nikki Haley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chavismo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas' Altamira Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolivar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francisco Rangel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OPEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
