<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398145040812469</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/trinity-beach-junior-puts-bite-on-rivals/news-story/ddbc925875201ddd499758cf57ac7a39</url>
  <title>Trinity Beach junior puts bite on rivals</title>
  <content>
MANUNDA high-flyer Corey Flint reached great heights at Cazalys Stadium yesterday afternoon but he was the lone Hawk as Centrals Trinity Beach marched towards a top-two AFL Cairns finish.
In the rare Sunday fixture, the second-placed Dogs were not overly convincing but did enough to win, 13.12 90 - 22.14 146.
Without a number of their senior players, Trinity Beach youngster Max Culpitt broke the game open early in the third term with four quick goals.
Culpitt, in his fluoro boots, finished with nine majors as Jayden Holt and Jackson Williams found plenty of the footy for the Bulldogs.
The Hawks kicked four of the last five goals of the third to send a scare through the Trinity Beach camp but the Bulldogs settled from then on.
Culpitt was over the moon to kick a career-high goals in senior football.
"We have got a good forward group, we rotate through the midfield a lot and keep us fresh," Culpitt said.
"It was a great win for the club today. We played well in patches but we got through."
Bulldogs coach Mick Seymour said the attacking junior footballer had the potential to be a standout in the AFL Cairns competition for years to come.
"Max has come through our junior system and goes away with all the representative age group squads," Seymour said.
"Today's game was the first time he has played as a permanent forward and he went through a real purple patch there. He is a talented young kid and he showed that today."
The result sets up a mini-final for Manunda and Cairns Saints next Saturday afternoon, with the winner in the box seat to finish fourth.
The Hawks are an honest and hardworking side but at times they lack the polish to make the most of their opportunities going forward.
Yesterday was a prime example: they had many more inside 50s than their opponents but went into halftime with just one goal to their name while Trinity Beach had seven.
The Hawks' relentless early tackle pressure handed them chances as their own mistakes let the Dogs off the hook.
Flint provided the highlight of the afternoon for the Hawks faithful, taking a huge pack mark late in the third term right in front of the Cazalys Stadium stand.
He was one of their best, as he has been all season, in whatever role Marc Harbrow gives him.
The win solidifies the Bulldogs in second place on the AFL Cairns ladder.
The Hawks remain in fourth place with Cairns Saints still in the hunt to play finals this season.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Cairns</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Harbrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MANUNDA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayden Holt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Seymour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trinity Beach</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Culpitt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cazalys Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seymour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrals Trinity Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Culpitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Flint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
