<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398355494212926</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/illfounded-attacks-wont-help-anyone/news-story/0e576a3c2ab4a94fb47fea7747464f2a</url>
  <title>Ill-founded attacks won't help anyone</title>
  <content>
LETTER: In response to Senator Ian Macdonald (TB 26/7), I find it astounding that he clearly has no idea of my background.
I began my working life as an apprentice hairdresser and then at the age of 18 I became a small-business owner in partnership with my mother.
Upon completion of my apprenticeship and my return from studying and working overseas, my husband and I owned and successfully operated a range of small businesses in the retail, hairdressing and vocational education and training sectors for many years.
I have worked in the TAFE sector in teaching, curriculum development and project management roles.
I have also worked at CEO level in the mental health community managed sector, managing 100 staff and millions of dollars across North and Western Queensland including Palm Island.
I also have board experience at the state and national peak body levels.
Senator Macdonald would better serve this community by putting his energy into job-creating opportunities for the unemployed and assisting small business to meet the challenges that they face, rather than personally and inaccurately attacking my work history.
He could start by standing up for the Queensland communities affected by Cyclone Debbie and insist that his government commits adequate funding to disaster relief,
Ill-founded personal attacks will not help our communities to move forward.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyclone Debbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Ian Macdonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Macdonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TB 26/7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palm Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
