<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398372674082341</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/maleny-players-to-host-open-day-for-theatre-groups/3206854/</url>
  <title>Maleny Players to host open day for theatre groups</title>
  <content>
THE Maleny Players turn 40 this year and to help celebrate, an open day is planned for all Maleny-based theatre groups.
All performers old and new - or even anyone just thinking of becoming involved in theatre - are encouraged to attend.
Maleny has punched above its weight theatrically for years and can boast having at least eight different performing groups over the years, which have performed 650 times in more than 230 different shows and at least 18 different venues.
More than 950 people have been on stage or behind the scenes. They have performed works by more than 100 playwrights and musicians and have been directed by in excess of 70 directors or musical directors.
That amazing list of statistics will be available for visitors to peruse through at their leisure on the day.
To celebrate these facts, and their own birthday, The Maleny Players will open up the Maleny Playhouse at the showgrounds on Saturday, August 5, at 4pm.
A plethora of past presidents and guest directors will be present, along with other guests including six current presidents of coastal-based theatre companies, which have all had a working relationship with shows in Maleny.
Many a tale will be retold, myths will be busted and new folklore created - sure to be a highly amusing walk through the past and a glimpse into the future.
So if you were or are involved with The Maleny Players, Random Acts, Hypocrytes, SRT, Le Bagge Productions, Maleny Community Theatre, The Maleny Singers, Clap Trap Productions or Wild Women Productions, head to the showgrounds.
An array of posters, programs and photos has been assembled and will be on show.
A bar will be open and nibbles will be available.
There will be music and a short presentation plus a few guest speakers who will regale everyone with stories from the past.
"I've been quite surprised by who's come out of the woodwork so far," project co-ordinator Simon Denver said.
"People are coming from near and afar just to catch up with old friends and see what has been happening."
The afternoon will culminate in an airing of a new play by Jo Denver: The Reluctant Bride at 6pm.
This sparkling one-act comedy cast is made up of people who have been members of The Maleny Players sometime over the past 40 years (Joy Marshall, Rachel Fentiman, Clayton Storey and Robert Walton).
The show costs $10 and bookings are essential. Book with Ray Oldfield on 5499 7791.
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Ten Acres family farm and bakery launched in April in Ninderry
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Denver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Acres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton Storey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joy Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wild Women Productions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninderry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hypocrytes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Denver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Fentiman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SRT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Bagge Productions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Oldfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Walton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny Singers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reluctant Bride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clap Trap Productions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny Community Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny Playhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny Players</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
