<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398484343233488</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/cbd/court-defeat-adds-to-200m-loss-from-retail-adventures-collapse-for-jan-cameron-20170726-gxjaeb.html</url>
  <title>Court defeat adds to $200m loss from Retail Adventures collapse for Jan Cameron </title>
  <content>
Jan Cameron has worn many hats over the years: Kathmandu founder, philanthropist, conservationist - and more recently corporate agitator at Bellamy's. 
Easy touch is not on her CV, just ask the casualties from Bellamy's board spill in February. 

Up Next

Labor's 'war on the rich' - not

02:00

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Bellamyas pricing a ashemozzlea

At Bellamyas EGM, shareholder Jan Cameron blames a sudden price increase in November 2015 for the companyas downfall.

Or the 1000-plus staff who lost their jobs at the misadventure she had at Retail Adventures, which collapsed twice under her watch and cost the Kathmandu founder most of her fortune - roughly $200 million according to some counts. 
And that figure does not include the $13.8 million she had to pay Retail Adventures' liquidators in August 2014 to settle claims of insolvent trading.Photo: Vince Caligiuri
This was one month after she had appointed receivers - KordaMentha's David Winterbottom and Rahul Goyal - to her private company DSG, which had taken over the so-called viable stores in Retails Adventures' business after the 2012 collapse. Let's call it Retail Misadventures II.
She did not return for a third try at reviving the discount chain operator. Her receivers ended up having to wind down what remained of the business after no buyers were found in 2014. 

But the pain has not ended there for Cameron and her receivers. 

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

We now know, from a lawsuit Cameron launched in the NSW Supreme Court this year, that Winterbottom and Goyal were offered an "incentive fee" for conducting the receivership of DSG.
The court documents tell us the incentive fee was designed to give the receivers a ... er, incentive to get a better return for the secured creditor (Cameron) than the forecast return of $6 million. 
"They claimed to have become entitled to an incentive fee, and deducted what they said was its proper amount from the proceeds of the receivership that they paid to or at the direction of the secured creditor," said the judgment released last week.Photo: Nic Walker
This means Cameron got a $6 million-plus return on her $200 million-plus double failure at Retail Adventures.
It was not enough to console the conservationist. Cameron argued the receivers were not entitled to the fee and sued for the undisclosed fee plus interest.  
It was argued that the fee deed required a "stocktake". The question was whether this required the receivers to roll up their sleeves and conduct a physical count of DSG's stock or they could instead rely on a review of the retailer's inventory records - which is what they actually did. 
Keep in mind this was a discount retailer with 143 stores across the country and an estimated 15 million items in store, in warehouses and in transit from the company's suppliers.
All with an average value of $2, which sounds astounding for goods such as "health pet treat puppy porky clod bone", "drumstick pop van maple" and "many thousands of other items of irresistible consumer appeal", according to the court documents. 
The retailer collapsed because many of its stores were losing money, so time was literally money down the drain. And as the receivers' lawyers argued, a physical stocktake would be expensive and require the temporary closure of stores. 
More importantly, the fee formula meant the receivers would be enriching themselves at the expense of their client by carrying out the physical stocktake.  
Lawyers acting for the KordaMentha pair argued that to "deprive the receivers of their incentive fee because they had failed to carry out a lengthy and time-consuming process that could only have increased their return was commercially absurd".
Justice Robert McDougall agreed, saying: "In my view, full application of the supposed requirement to undertake a full physical stocktake would lead to commercial absurdity." 
The judgment found that the receivers could undertake the "stocktake" by reviewing DSG's inventory levels and rejected Cameron's claim for repayment of the incentive fee, and added the defendant's court costs to her $200 million-plus losses from the sorry misadventure.  
Fahour's last post

Executive perks come in all shapes and sizes, so CBD is intrigued by the thought of what might happen to a certain heritage post box in Melbourne's blue-blood enclave of Hawthorn.
Many years ago, CBD spies noted that a standard post box on the corner of Isabella and Coppin groves was replaced with a dazzlingly freshened-up heritage box.
"The street posting box at this location was rusted and required replacement," said a Post spokeswoman at the time.
"We have several heritage street posting boxes in storage and we made the decision to replace the box with a heritage box, in keeping with the historic streetscape of the local area."
It just happened that Australia's highest-paid public servant, a postie by the name of Ahmed Fahour, had recently moved into a $20 million bolthole on Coppin Grove called Invergowrie mansion. 
Today is Australia Post's first day without fearless Fahour as its leader, so CBD would love it if our eagle-eyed Melbourne spies could keep an eye on this particular post box for any signs of a downgrade.
Follow CBD on . Got a tip? 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retail Adventures</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamya</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coppin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retail Misadventures II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invergowrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fahour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KordaMentha's David Winterbottom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goyal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Fahour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EGM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathmandu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coppin Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DSG</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KordaMentha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winterbottom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Robert McDougall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jan Cameron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rahul Goyal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince Caligiuri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
