<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398527292906945</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/shorten-reiterates-two-state-solution/8758732</url>
  <title>Bill Shorten reiterates support for two-state solution after NSW Labor Palestinian motion</title>
  <content>
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten has avoided supporting unilateral recognition of Palestine as a state, saying acknowledgement should be part of a two-state solution.
Speaking on RN Breakfast, the federal Labor leader said any recognition needed to address the concerns of both sides.
"There's two issues, one is the legitimate aspirations, and I stress legitimate aspirations of Palestinians to have their own state and I do support that, but also the legitimate aspirations of the people of Israel to live in secure borders," he said.
Mr Shorten has come under pressure to confirm his stance on the matter, after a motion was passed at the NSW Labor conference at the weekend calling for the next federal Labor government to recognise Palestine as a state.
He reiterated his support for federal Labor's long-held position on a two-state solution.
"If you support a two-state solution ultimately that includes recognition of Palestine," Mr Shorten said.
Former foreign affairs minister and News South Wales premier Bob Carr put forward the motion for Australia to become the 138th nation to recognise the state of Palestine saying: "We can't be left stranded in history."

The motion was successful, prompting opposition from the New South Wales Labor Israel Action Committee.
Similar motions were passed at the QLD and ACT Labor conferences at the weekend.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RN Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor Palestinian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales Labor Israel Action Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palestinians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palestine</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
