<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398527292906953</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/north-northeast/parafield-airport-draft-master-plan-could-add-750-more-jobs-but-locals-angry-at-extra-noise/news-story/dc234d5bffeaf8ffe2393c5fa72872d9</url>
  <title>New jobs for airport, but noise too</title>
  <content>
UP TO 750 jobs are ready for take-off at Parafield Airport - if plans for a massive increase in flights are approved.
But locals are objecting in force, saying the extra noise will cause them to pack up and leave the neighbourhood.
This follows the release - for community feedback - of Parafield Airport Limited's draft master plan.
The plan, described as a "vision" rather than a fully costed project, provides a framework for ongoing development at the airport across the next 20 years.
The number of Parafield flights would increase to 345,000 a year by 2037 - a 61 per cent increase on the 214,000 logged in 2016.
An enterprise precinct - housing a range of commercial, industrial and aviation industries - would also be established.
It is envisaged that this precinct would provide 600 of the predicted 750 ongoing on-site jobs.
Parafield Airport managing director Mark Young said the development of commercial opportunities would help support the general economy.
"This continued growth is providing local job opportunities and a significant contribution to the northern Adelaide region," Mr Young said.
But the increase in local flights has left its neighbours frustrated.
One resident, who did not want to be identified, said she had lived near the airport for almost 40 years - and found a traffic increase "disturbing".
"We used to have aircraft flying overhead every 20-30 seconds for several hours," she said.
"I developed hypertension after stress from years of high noise exposure.
"Many family and friends have moved away due to the aircraft noise and in reality that is the only option that most people have if the aircraft noise affects them."

A person has died after two planes on the ground collided at Parafield Airport - Courtesy Nine News Adelaide

Pilot dies in freak tragedy at Parafield Airport
The Parafield noise factor had made another neighbour, Gery Jeltes, equally distressed.
"At times I can't have my door or windows open due to the noise," Ms Jeltes said.
"The thought of them increasing the amount of air traffic to 450,000 planes a year is going to make the noise and pollution intolerable."
A Parafield Airport spokesman said it will continue to look at ways to minimise the impact of aircraft noise.
Last year, the airport contributed $162 million towards the northern economy and provided more than 2440 jobs - both on and off the base.
The airport, which started operating in 1927, is the state's premier general aviation and pilot training facility.
Its four runways have the capacity to take more than 450,000 aircraft movements each year.
Feedback on the masterplan is open until October 18.
Written submissions on the plans can made to Building 18, Tiger Moth Lane, Parafield Airport 5106 or at .
Copies of the plan be viewed at Parafield Airport, Adelaide Airport, Salisbury Council and .
Once feedback is incorporated into the plans, it will be subject to approval by the Federal Government.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiger Moth Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parafield Airport 5106</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jeltes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parafield Airport Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gery Jeltes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parafield Airport</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salisbury Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parafield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtesy Nine News Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
