<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398484343233502</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/chamari-liyanage-takes-fight-to-clear-her-name-to-high-court/news-story/625cf17baef50c6e12323ce91a9ce10d</url>
  <title>Killer suffered "miscarriage of justice"</title>
  <content>
A WA doctor convicted and jailed for killing her abusive husband with a mallet has taken the fight to clear her name to the nation's highest court.
Chamari Liyanage walked free on parole in March after spending nearly three years behind bars for the manslaughter of husband Dinendra Athukorala, whom she bashed over the head with a 1.79kg mallet as he lay in bed in their Geraldton home in June, 2014.
During her trial, evidence emerged her husband, also a doctor, had subjected Ms Liyanage to years of physical, emotional and sexual violence and control.
In June, the Court of Appeal rejected her appeal against her conviction and sentence.
But last week, Ms Liyanage's lawyer George Giudice lodged an application for special leave to appeal to the High Court, arguing there were 10 grounds that resulted in his client receiving an "unfair trial" and suffering a "miscarriage of justice".
The grounds include excluding evidence from a social worker about the risk Ms Liyanage was facing from her husband, the nature of domestic violence and typical responses of victims, and a claim the jury should have been told Ms Liyanage had no legal duty to "retreat" from her husband.
Mr Giudice told PerthNow the High Court appeal, if allowed and upheld, could have wider ramifications for domestic violence criminal cases, with this matter attracting the attention of law academics in Australia, Canada and New Zealand.
"When women defend themselves against partners in self-defence, prosecutors ask juries to consider questions such as 'Why did she stay?', 'Why did she leave and come back to him?', 'Why didn't she seek help?', 'Why does she still say she still loves him?', 'Why didn't she just simply walk out the door?" he said.
"The appeal is about the need for the jury to be assisted in understanding that women all around the world find themselves in these types of relationships and do not leave.
"Another question raised by this appeal is 'Why is it OK for a man to stand and fight to defend himself when he is being threatened?' There is no duty on him to flee.
"The woman entrapped in an ongoing abusive relationship is expected to flee rather than defend herself."
Mr Giudice said his client, a Sri Lankan-born doctor, had community support and was rebuilding her life by focusing on her art, and re-entering the workforce part time.
Ms Liyanage will have an art exhibition in Geraldton in September but is not allowed to practise medicine after making an undertaking to the Medical Board of Australia.
Ms Liyanage, who claims she has no memory of killing her husband, was facing deportation to Sri Lanka after her release from jail but the Department of Immigration agreed to reinstate her permanent residency.
Mr Giudice said her aim was to work as a doctor again.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Giudice</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lankan-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PerthNow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Giudice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Court of Appeal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Immigration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Liyanage</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geraldton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chamari Liyanage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medical Board of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lanka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dinendra Athukorala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
