<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398492933168204</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/stage/sydney-stage/rice-brings-human-scale-to-global-issues-20170728-gxkixl.html</url>
  <title>Michele Lee's prize-winning play brings human scale to global issues</title>
  <content>
RICE
★★★ 1/2
Griffin Theatre, July 26. Until August 26
Michele Lee's 80-minute two-hander has enough ideas in it to fill an edition of The Economist and roles sufficient to feed a company of six. You need to be switched on just to keep up.RicePhoto: Brett Boardman Photography
Lee condenses matters geopolitical, cultural and socio-economic into a wry comedy opening in the glass tower HQ of Golden Fields, an Australian corporation with a lot of fingers in a lot of pies.
Nisha (played by Kristy Best), is one of the rising stars of the company, a young second-generation Bengali-Australian piloting a push into India's massive but tightly controlled rice market. A deal could be worth billions.Photo: Justin McManus
Working in the same office - though only for an allotted two minutes a day - is a contract cleaner, Yvette (Hsaio-Ling Tang).
Nisha is setting up meetings with important Indian ministers. Yvette is emptying bins on less than minimum wage. An unbridgeable gulf exists between them, you might think. But as Nisha's naivety is exposed during a business trip to India and Yvette's entrepreneurial and life experience is revealed, the two women find common - if not exactly smooth - ground on which to meet each other eye-to-eye.
While there are elements of the microcosmic in Lee's ideas, Rice is overwhelmingly a human story and a very authentically voiced one, too. There isn't an ounce of didactic fat in it, and that leanness - the product of close editing and fine-grained dramaturgy - allows director Lee Lewis' sparely designed production to run on a greased rail.
Tang and Best play several recurring characters in the course of the show (a snippy activist daughter and a hipster food truck-operator boyfriend among them) and are adept at switching them on and off in a blink. But it's in the interplay between the earthy gravitas of Tang's Yvette and Best's precariously situated Nisha that this show's intriguing stage chemistry resides.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yvette</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RicePhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin McManus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Boardman Photography</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HQ of Golden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristy Best</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michele Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bengali-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nisha</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hsaio-Ling Tang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tang's Yvette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffin Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
