<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398492933168248</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/music/ravel-unspools-its-magic-russian-romantics-get-expression-20170730-gxlns0.html</url>
  <title>Ravel unspools its magic, Russian Romantics get expression</title>
  <content>
The Singing Violin. Australian Brandenburg Orchestra. Dimitry Sinkovsky. City Recital Hall. July 26.
★★★The Singing ViolinPhoto: Peter McCallum
Ravishing Ravel. Sydney Symphony Orchestra. David Robertson. Susan Graham. Opera House Concert Hall. July 29.
★★★★ 1/2
By calling his ballet Daphnis and Chloe a "Symphonie choregraphique" Ravel invited the listener to focus on musical development rather than the story.
Paradoxically, by the simple device of projecting a synopsis of that story while playing the complete ballet score, David Robertson and the Sydney Symphony Orchestra created, arguably, a more purely musical experience than the usual concert hall presentation of the music as a pair of orchestral suites which Ravel extracted from the score.

It not only made the structure comprehensible, it also allowed one to focus on the way the main ideas are developed while putting the many effective but incidental gestures - an outburst of laughter, a sudden change of mood - into a subsidiary position. Robertson, the SSO and the Sydney Philharmonia Choirs were thus freed to concentrate on the work's essence - a masterpiece in the application of delicate orchestral colour that is almost without peer. 
Careful balance, unforced beauty of tone and a feeling for pace that both pauses for languor but maintains fleeting energy all made this an experience to savour.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Though every moment was captivating, special mention must be made of guest flautist Samuel Coles in the haunting representation of Pan and clarinettist Alexander Morris. The first half began with Stravinsky's brilliant early piece Fireworks, opus 4, (an apt counterpart to the SSO's recent Australian premier of the same composer's recently rediscovered Funeral Song from the same period) before a superb creation of floating sensuality in Ravel's song cycle Sheherazade by soprano Susan Graham. Graham focused the sound and text with supple line and rhythm, seemingly endless variety of tone and tellingly expressive French articulation. 
In his concert with the Australian Brandenburg Orchestra, violinist Dmitry Sinkovsky applied the expressive style of the Romantic Russian style of playing to the challenges of so-called historically informed performance on period instruments.
Playing a beautiful 17th-century instrument with a tone of hushed sweetness and velvety denseness, he demonstrated that many of the Romantic virtuosic techniques that exploit the springiness of the modern concave shaped bow can also be achieved on the older Baroque convex bows playing on gut strings.
The sound was most satisfying in Vivaldi's Concerto in E minor, 'Il favorito', opus 11, No. 2. There was abundant energy and virtuosity in Telemann's Concerto in B flat and Leclair's Concerto opus 7, No. 2, though at times the accompanying orchestral tone lost resonance and the scrubbed gut string sound dominated the ensemble.
Vulnerable in a different way was the natural horn sound in Vivaldi's Concerto for Two Horns in F major (Darryl Poulson, Doree Dixon) in which the articulation capacity of the older instrument struggled to find focus in a modern hall.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singing ViolinPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Symphony Orchestra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Il</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ravel</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Philharmonia Choirs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter McCallum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dmitry Sinkovsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Symphonie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opera House Concert Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baroque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singing Violin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daphnis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheherazade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stravinsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darryl Poulson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SSO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vivaldi's Concerto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Brandenburg Orchestra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Robertson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Recital Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Graham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doree Dixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Funeral Song</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romantic Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leclair's Concerto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian Romantics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telemann's Concerto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dimitry Sinkovsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Two Horns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
