<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398488638200885</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4822099/saints-champion-nick-riewoldt-set-to-announce-his-retirement/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Saints champion Nick Riewoldt set to announce his retirement</title>
  <content>
St Kilda champion Nick Riewoldt is set to retire at the end of the season.
Fairfax Media understands that the veteran, who is a six-time best and fairest with the Saints and a five-time All-Australian, is due to tell his teammates of his decision at the club's Seaford headquarters on Monday morning.
The club has called a press conference for Riewoldt and coach Alan Richardson for 2pm on Monday.
Riewoldt, 34, was rested on the weekend from the match against Port Adelaide, which St Kilda narrowly lost, and had been pushing for a decision from the club about his future in recent weeks.

Riewoldt is St Kilda's longest-serving captain and made his debut in 2001. He gave up the captaincy last year, with Jarryn Geary replacing him.
He has played 14 games this year, with his career tally currently standing at 333, and kicked 25 goals so far this year for a total of 714. He played in three grand finals - a loss to Geelong in 2009, and the famous drawn grand final of 2010 with Collingwood, then losing the grand final replay the next week.
His father, Joe, tweeted on Monday that there were just "4 more games".
In the final four rounds of the home-and-away season, St Kilda will play West Coast at Etihad Stadium, Melbourne at the MCG, North Melbourne at Etihad Stadium, and Richmond at the MCG, although the day and time of the fixture against the Tigers has yet to be finalised.
It remains unclear what the plans of fellow Saints veteran Leigh Montagna are after he severely tore his hamstring. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seaford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Montagna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryn Geary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
