<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398033371661105</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:54</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/report-suspects-arrested-in-sydney-counter-terror-raids-planned-a-gas-attack-on-a-passenger-plane-2017-7</url>
  <title>REPORT: Suspects arrested in Sydney counter-terror raids planned a gas attack on a passenger plane</title>
  <content>
The four suspects arrested in a series of raids by counter-terrorism police on Saturday in Sydney may have been planning to deploy a toxic gas on a passenger aircraft, incapacitating everyone on board and crashing the plane, according to .

The group - two fathers men and their adults sons who are all related by marriage - was allegedly working on an "elaborate" plan to take down a plane and the sophistication of the plot has led authorities to believe they may have had direction from overseas.

Prime minister Malcolm Turnbull announced stricter security measures at all domestic airports on Sunday morning with immediate effect. Passengersand three hours before international flights to allow extra time for security screening.

Significant delays are expected at Australian airports today as a result of the new screening protocols.

The Australian that the four suspects "were constructing an explosive -device that could have emitted a toxic, sulphur-based gas that would have killed or immobilised everyone on the aircraft."

"It is understood the device was in the final stages of readiness, prompting police to swoop," the report said.

Police, seizing a range of items and arresting the four suspects.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Passengersand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
