<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398016191791784</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/money/super-and-funds/claims-super-is-biased-against-women-are-nonsense-20170727-gxjv3w.html</url>
  <title>Claims super is 'biased' against women are nonsense</title>
  <content>
Superannuation is back in the news. It started with a research study commissioned by the Australian Services Union that showed many women retire with half the superannuation that men have. This led to . The claims are nonsense: superannuation is nothing more than a structure that lets people build assets in a low-tax environment.
The mathematics speak for themselves. The amount a person has in superannuation when they retire depends mainly on two factors: the amount that is contributed, and the earning rates that the member can achieve within the fund. Obviously, people in low-paid jobs or irregular jobs will not end up with as much superannuation as people in higher paid jobs, who contribute more. Casuals also miss out on super, but get more money in their pay to compensate. Then those who do not manage their superannuation effectively for the best returns will end up with significantly less money than those who take the time to get the best return possible.Photo: Glenn Hunt
The ASU report was followed by news of a survey done by the Association of Superannuation Funds of Australia (ASFA), which indicated that, on average, women were not as engaged with their superannuation as men.
The following example shows the effect of the earning rate within the fund. Think about two people aged 30, each earning $30,000 a year and whose only superannuation is the employer contribution of 9.5 per cent. As they are lower paid workers we will assume salary increases by 2 per cent a year. One is disengaged with their super and their fund earns just 4 per cent a year. The other takes advice and chooses higher growth assets inside the fund. This enables their fund to earn 7 per cent a year. At age 65 the former would have $246,000 in super, the latter $451,000.

Next came a raft of press releases from the government proudly telling us they were were trying to change the superannuation system so life, total and permanent disability (TPD) would become "opt-in" rather than "opt-out". The rationale was that younger people were "unfairly affected" because they were paying insurance fees on multiple superannuation funds, and that a recent analysis found a worker on $65,000 a year now could lose up to 45 per cent of their final balance in unnecessary life insurance over their working life.
But life insurance is a critical element in the financial planning process. Sadly, like making a will, it is often neglected. Consequently, I have long been in favour of the opt-out process, which is currently part of most compulsory employer superannuation. This means that life insurance is automatically included as part of your employer superannuation unless you specifically choose to opt out.

In most cases, having insurance inside your superannuation fund is the least costly because the premiums can be paid with pre-tax dollars, and the fund can usually arrange cover at wholesale rates.

You will now receive updates from

Money Newsletter

Money Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But there can be traps:  Total and permanent disability (TPD) pays out only if you can no longer work in any occupation, and trauma insurance is not offered at all within super.Photo: Wayne Taylor
Of course, anybody who has not made the effort to amalgamate a number of superannuation funds may well be paying unnecessary insurance premiums. But that is not the fault of the system: it is the fault of the person who is not prepared to take the time to organise their affairs for maximum effectiveness.
So either way, it should be the member who decides whether to opt out or opt in, and the type and amount of insurance they need. At the end of the day it's about getting engaged in your own financial future, but sadly, a major finding of the Cooper inquiry into superannuation was that 80 per cent of fund members were "disengaged" with their superannuation. This means most of them did not have a clue as to whether they have insurance in their superannuation or not, and whether their superannuation was invested in assets that were appropriate for their age, goals and risk profile.
Noel Whittaker is the author of Making Money Made Simple and numerous other books on personal finance. His advice is general in nature and readers should seek their own professional advice before making any financial decisions. Email:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Association of Superannuation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TPD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Making Money Made Simple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Whittaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Funds of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
