<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398497228135552</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/matildas-continue-their-giant-killing-run/3206880/</url>
  <title>Matildas continue their giant-killing run</title>
  <content>
ON Friday, the Matildas made history with a first ever win over world champions the USA.
On Monday, they've done it again, this time with a big 4-2 win over Asian champions Japan to go to the top of the table in the Tournament of Nations.
Led by a brilliant first-half Sam Kerr hat-trick, Emily Van Egmond then scored a penalty on the hour mark to recover from a horror start after Japan took the lead six minutes into the match.
But that only served to kick the Aussies into gear, who themselves had a good chance just 60 seconds into the match.
Up stepped Kerr, who hit a lethal double in five minutes.
Her first came after Elise Kellond-Knight played Hayley Raso in behind, with the right winger flying beyond Japan's back four to square the ball to Kerr for a tap in on 11 minutes.
Then Kerr did it herself in the 16th minute, winning the ball back high up the field to race in behind one-on-one with the goalkeeper to score.
And just as Japan probed for an equaliser on the stroke of half-time, Kerr scored a break away solo goal to seal her hat-trick.
Japan then scored a late consolation goal in the second minute of stoppage time, but it was Kerr who stole the show.
You can watch the Matildas v Brazil in the Tournament of Nations from 9.10am AEST Friday on Fox Sports 503.
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerr</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Van Egmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley Raso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports 503</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elise Kellond-Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
