<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398054846497717</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/world-travel/north-america/new-yorks-most-iconic-logo-almost-didnt-exist/news-story/e2fbeb7cf620ee6ad3cfe5e5a9cecd50</url>
  <title>New York's most iconic logo almost didn't exist</title>
  <content>
Activists Commemorate Anniversary of 1917 Silent Protest in NYC. Credit - YouTube/Lily Haight via Storyful
1:18

Activists in New York City gathered outside of Bryant Park to commemorate the 100 year anniversary of the 1917 NAACP Silent Protest on Friday, July 28. The 1917 demonstration led by the NAACP was one of the first mass protests denouncing lynching and anti-black violence. Civil rights leaders such as James Weldon Johnson and W.E.B Du Bois attended the 1917 march along with 10,000 people who marched silently, wearing all white down New York's Fifth Avenue. Artists and activists gathered outside of Bryant Park dressed in all white, played music and held signs with pictures of black men and women who have been killed by police to commemorate the anniversary of the Silent Protest, as shown in this video. Credit: YouTube/Lily Haight via Storyful

July 29th 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

The I heart NY logo has become the most iconic slogan for the Big Apple.

Hana R. AlbertsNY Post

Share

A LOGO that almost didn't exist is now one of the most iconic in the world - thanks to a chance visit to the holiday island of Bermuda.
The "I [heart] NY" emblem turns 40 this year, and its creators, including graphic design guru Milton Glaser, told the  about the origins and enduring legacy of their symbol - believed to be the most copied in the world.
Back in 1977, the logo was commissioned as part of a larger advertising campaign by New York State's Department of Commerce. It was meant to lure out-of-state travellers to a place then beset with problems: a bankrupt government, high crime rates, a drug epidemic, a homelessness crisis, abandoned buildings, raging fires and a major blackout.
Governor Hugh Carey gave Commerce Commissioner John Dyson the go-ahead to try to change New York's image. With his deputy, William Doyle, Dyson tapped advertising firm Wells Rich Greene (of Alka-Seltzer's iconic "I can't believe I ate that whole thing" fame). Creative director Charlie Moss came up with a slogan, "I Love New York." Jingle writer Steve Karmen set it to music. On a shoestring budget, the team started to create ads touting Broadway shows and upstate's natural beauty.

I heart NY merchandise is everywhere in New York City.Source:istock
Visually, though, the campaign was lacking. Dyson and Doyle selected Glaser, a South Bronx native who had co-founded New York magazine nearly a decade earlier.
That summer, Glaser's first attempt resulted in a lukewarm response from the team. So during a cab ride a few days later, he took a red crayon and scribbled down four characters on the back of an envelope: "I," a heart, "N" and "Y." (It's now on display at the Museum of Modern Art.)
"The big secret of that is replacing a verb with a noun. Change the language and make people solve a problem," Glaser, 88, told The Post.
"The 'I' is a complete word, the heart is a symbol for an emotion, and NY is the initial for a place. So you have to figure it out, otherwise it's impenetrable. It's a puzzle that is easily solved."

Tourists stock up on souvenirs.Source:istock
Moss and the advertising team, however, believed the design was too abstract and cryptic. Doyle disagreed and had two T-shirts with the logo mocked up on his own dime, which he and his then-girlfriend (now wife of 39 years) wore on the beach in Bermuda during a long weekend trip.

"People came up to us on the beach and said, 'Oh, my God, I love it'," Doyle said. "I can still see the ladies. It brought huge smiles, and people's eyes were glistening. It really worked."
Armed with eyewitness evidence, he returned to the city and insisted the logo be used. It was immediately tacked on to ads that were already running, and so began the journey toward ubiquity.
"That was the moment of truth, I think," Doyle added. "Had there been no trip to Bermuda, there wouldn't be any logo."
This article originally appeared on the  and was reproduced with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube/Lily Haight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NY</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Love New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Karmen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commemorate Anniversary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NYC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Museum of Modern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York State's Department of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAACP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W.E.B Du Bois</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryant Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Moss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Bronx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York's Fifth Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milton Glaser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glaser</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commerce Commissioner John Dyson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Weldon Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silent Protest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bermuda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hana R. AlbertsNY Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dyson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAACP Silent Protest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wells Rich Greene (of Alka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor Hugh Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doyle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glaser, 88</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
