<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398016191791768</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/lifestyle/lost-teenager-tread-water-for-two-hours-before-rescue-in-queensland/news-story/00ae46eb52a2d4f1be6ccf43b7184dd4</url>
  <title>Teen boy's stunning survival off Queensland coast</title>
  <content>
A TEENAGE boy has spent a terrifying two hours treading water in choppy conditions without a life jacket off the Queensland coast after falling off his grandparents' yacht.
Paramedics are stunned by the 14-year-old's survival after his grandparents failed to notice he was missing.
He was saved two hours later when someone on another boat spotted him in the water off Gladstone and pulled him to safety on Sunday afternoon. He had swallowed a lot of water and been battered by waves as he fought to keep his head above water near the mouth of the Gladstone marina. His grandparents only realised he was missing after returning to the marina, sparking a panicked call to authorities and an air search.
But before a rescue chopper could find him, the second boat spotted him, and those on-board pulled him to safety and got him back to shore, where paramedics treated him for nothing more than exposure to the cold.
"The boy was treading water for approximately two hours. The average person could tread water without much difficulty for about 30 minutes. For the boy, he was very, very lucky to survive," ambulance service spokesman Chris Pereira said.
"The boy states he did this remarkable act without the aid of a life jacket as well." The boy was found about 12 nautical miles from the marina, in choppy conditions.
"At the mouth of the marina there was quite an amount of waves and he did swallow quite a bit of water. So he's extremely lucky under the circumstances." The boy was taken to the Gladstone hospital in a stable condition.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Pereira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
