<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398445688527293</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/truck-driver-david-stubbs-jailed-over-wantirna-crossing-crash-that-killed-kathy-curlis/news-story/e7099b2a29cfca947b9123c1cca005af</url>
  <title>Truck driver jailed over fatal crash</title>
  <content>
A TRUCK driver has been sentenced to three-and-a-half years in jail for causing the death of a mother of three at a Wantirna zebra crossing.
David Stubbs, of Ferntree Gully, was not paying attention when his truck rear-ended a car in front of him, propelling it into Ringwood woman Kathy Curlis, who was on the crossing, on the corner of Boronia Rd and Mountain Highway on July 18 last year.

The drivers of both vehicles came to the aid of the 60-year-old but she did not survive the night in hospital.
Stubbs, 45, pleaded guilty to dangerous driving causing death and was jailed last Wednesday and must serve a minimum of one year and 10 months in jail before he is eligible for parole.
County Court Judge James Montgomery said Stubbs had a "lack of attention" and failed to keep a proper lookout.
"This was a serious breach of the proper management and control of your vehicle," he said.
He hoped the sentence would deter other dangerous drivers in future.
Stubbs raised his eyebrows and let out a sigh upon hearing the sentence.
"That's a disgrace," he said under his breath, telling his kids to "be good" as he was taken out of court.
Stubbs claimed he looked to the right to check for traffic and when he looked back he saw the car in front had stopped.
His truck was travelling at 68km/h when it crashed into the back of the Toyota Corolla on a clear afternoon.
Ahead of his sentencing, Stubbs posted on his Facebook page that the crash was "the worst day of my life".
"A family lost a very much loved mother wife grandma and friend. I am responsible for the most unfortunate and life-changing accident," he said.
Ms Curlis was the second person in eight years to be killed at the zebra crossing, after an 83-year-old man died in 2009.
After a Leader campaign, VicRoads announced earlier this year the crossing would be upgraded, with $200,000 in improvements.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>County Court Judge James Montgomery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stubbs, 45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wantirna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Corolla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountain Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stubbs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy Curlis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Curlis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boronia Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Stubbs, of Ferntree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
