<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398484343233485</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/rock-art-site-may-close-due-to-vandals-thieves-and-cheapskates/8757856</url>
  <title>Sacred Cape York site could close due to cheapskates, vandals and thieves</title>
  <content>
Split Rock, on the outskirts of Laura on the Cape York peninsula, is UNESCO-listed and recognised among the world's 10 most significant rock art galleries.
But thieves, vandals and cheapskates have cultural centre operators wondering: do we honestly value ancient Aboriginal rock art?
For $5, visitors are permitted access, unaccompanied by a guide or traditional owner.
An 'honesty box' greets walkers at the gate of the 600-metre uphill rock path.
But more than half who make the climb to witness the ancient culture firsthand don't pay, according to Quinkan Regional and Cultural Centre (QRCC) manager Lex Bloomfield.

"We monitor and we've come up with a figure - 60 per cent don't pay," Mr Bloomfield said.
"People walk in there, have a look at the sign - sometimes they put a washer in there, a battery, sticks, stones, and just move through.
"It's an insult to the local people and the culture; they're not asking much."

QRCC is entrusted with maintaining four major sites, including Split Rock, Mushroom Rock, Giant Horse and the Quinkan Galleries; the not-for-profit tourist venture is one of the remote community's main employers.
Mr Bloomfield said non-payers hurt Laura's economic development with tourism one of the few industries that exist.
"It keeps us alive, because we're not funded," Mr Bloomfield said.
"They're doing guides out of an income and that's what keeps [Laura] going."
Honesty box targeted by vandals and thieves

John Ross is related to the Uw Olkolo traditional owners and said they were contemplating closing Split Rock, fed up that the honesty box is also being raided.
"We've built so many honesty boxes over the years and they've just been broken into," Mr Ross said.
"We don't lose millions of dollars but we lose a lot of money.
"It all goes to fixing our roads, the buildings, the plumbing, and paying our guides."

Security at the Split Rock site is being upgraded to include cameras, a new steel-frame door and reinforced padlocks; Lex Bloomfield said that was to keep up with thieves who were going to extraordinary efforts.
"They would've needed some sort of hydraulic equipment, the two latches were popped by some equipment, but that won't happen now," Mr Bloomfield said.
"They don't get much out of it but it costs us a lot of money."
Major events make up for poor start to season

QRCC said it experienced an unprecedented number of guided tours during a busy June when the community hosted its annual race weekend and the biennial Laura Dance Festival.
"It's caught us up for the season," Mr Bloomfield said.
"The season got off to a very bad start, not just here but everywhere."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinkan Galleries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uw Olkolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lex Bloomfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cultural Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QRCC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Split Rock</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNESCO-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Dance Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinkan Regional</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mushroom Rock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bloomfield</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giant Horse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
