<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398149335779881</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/07/you-need-to-be-at-the-airport-two-hours-before-your-australian-domestic-flight-now/</url>
  <title>You Need To be At The Airport Two Hours Before Your Australian Domestic Flight Now</title>
  <content>
Image: iStock
Qantas confirmed in a statement this morning that passengers will need to arrive at the airport two hours before a domestic flight to allow for additional security screening.

The amped-up security measures were put in place by the Australian Government after four people were arrested in connected to a suspected terrorist plot to bring down an aircraft.

"The Australian Government has introduced additional aviation security measures at international and domestic terminals at Australia's major airports," the update from Qantas reads, "Customers can expect to experience an increased level of security scrutiny at the airport so it may take a little longer than usual to get through the process."

The airline advises:

Passengers should arrive at the airport two hours before domestic flights and three hours before international flights to allow ample time for screening.

Passengers should limit the amount of carry-on and checked baggage they travel with as this will help to ensure security screening is efficient.

Qantas says there are no changes to what can and cannot be carried on-board the aircraft.

It is unclear how long these measures will be in place. This story is developing.

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>iStock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Need To</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airport Two Hours Before Your Australian Domestic Flight Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
