<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398484343233481</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/afl/afl-fitzys-hall-pass-kb-says-danger-will-get-off-riewoldt-to-retire/news-story/f7604a3fbcbf2541d932286722217960</url>
  <title>AFL: Fitzy's hall pass; KB says Danger will get off; Riewoldt to retire</title>
  <content>
McGovern's manic game saver
1:29

AFL: With 25 seconds to go, Collingwood's Jordan De Goey gets Adelaide forward Josh Jenkins holding the ball, but the Crows weren't done yet.

July 30th 2017
16 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/AFL/

His right foot is a thing of beauty too. (Photo by Michael Willson/AFL Media/Getty Images)

Share

JEREMY McGovern stole the headlines with his spectacular mark and game-tying goal - but it was Taylor Walker who really turned on radio star Ryan Fitzgerald during the Crows-Magpies draw on Sunday.
The Nova breakfast host is a Crows diehard - he played eight games for the club in 2002 - and was watching as the ladder-leaders attempted to take care of business at the MCG.
Adelaide captain Taylor Walker put his stamp on the contest early, drilling a pinpoint pass to set up Tom Lynch for the opening goal of the game.
Walker's field kicking was recently described by Hawthorn great Dermott Brereton as "as good as we've seen" but Fitzy took things a little further.
Just informed my wife that Taylor Walkers left foot is my hall pass.
It was a rollercoaster of emotions for Adelaide fans from that point as their team coughed up a 50-point deficit before rallying in the second half to close within six points with seconds on the clock.
Enter McGovern, who took a huge pack mark before slotting a goal after the siren to secure two points for the visitors.
Fitzy was pretty excited by that moment too.

A post shared by Ryan Fitzgerald (@fitzy18) on

KB: DANGER WILL BE OK

Patrick Dangerfield after tackling Matthew Kreuzer.Source:AAP
Patrick Dangerfield's hopes of winning a second Brownlow Medal hang in the balance with the AFL match review panel set to meet.

The MRP on Monday will hand down their verdict on the Geelong star's tackle on Carlton ruckman Matthew Kreuzer in Saturday night's clash at Etihad Stadium. Dangerfield pinned Kreuzer's arms and dumped the ruckman head first into the turf during the third quarter.
Kreuzer was ushered to the Carlton rooms and wasn't sighted for the rest of the match as the Cats went on to win by 65 points, with the Blues later confirming he had suffered a concussion.
The MRP are likely to pay close attention to the fact Kreuzer's arms were pinned, meaning he had no opportunity to protect himself.
That would meet the criteria for a dangerous tackle, but the MRP must also judge whether Dangerfield used "excessive force" in bringing down the 101kg Kreuzer. If the MRP decide Dangerfield has a case to answer, it seems almost certain he will face suspension.
The Cats star had been joint favourite to become the first back-to-back Brownlow winner since St Kilda champion Robert Harvey did so in 1997 and '98. Former Brownlow medallist Adam Cooney on Sunday said he believed Dangerfield would receive a one-game ban.
But Richmond legend Kevin Bartlett disagrees. "There was no lifting in the tackle by Dangerfield. There was no sling or second action," Bartlett told SEN.
"It was most unfortunate that Kreuzer's head hit the ground. I expect the MRP findings to be Dangerfield's tackle was not unreasonable in the circumstance."
- AAP
RIEWOLDT TO ANNOUNCE RETIREMENT TODAY

Nick Riewoldt won't be going around again. (Photo by Quinn Rooney/Getty Images)Source:Getty Images
St Kilda legend Nick Riewoldt is set to announce his retirement at the end of this AFL season.
The Saints have called a 2pm media conference on Monday at their Seaford headquarters, where Riewoldt and coach Alan Richardson will speak.
Speculation has been rife this season about Riewoldt's playing future. This could also be the last season for fellow Saints veteran Leigh Montagna, who is sidelined with a hamstring injury.
Riewoldt, 34, has played 333 senior games since his 2001 debut and is one of the game's great key forwards.
Only Robert Harvey has played more games for St Kilda, with 383. Riewoldt holds the club record for the most games as captain with 220 and also the most best and fairest awards with six.
He gave up the captaincy last year, handing over to Jarryn Geary. Taken with the priority No.1 pick in the 2000 national draft, Riewoldt is a five-time All-Australian.
Riewoldt was also named captain of the 2009 All-Australian team. He came agonisingly close to being a premiership captain, with the Saints narrowly losing the 2009 grand final to Geelong and then drawing the 2010 decider to Collingwood before going down in the replay.
Riewoldt was rested on the weekend as the Saints lost to Port Adelaide by two points and he has played 14 games this season.
This month, his manager Tom Petroro denied a media report that Riewoldt was pressing the club for a decision on his playing future.
He has struggled for much of his career with chronic knee problems and this would have been a key factor in the decision on when he retires.
- AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Bartlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood's Jordan De Goey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Harvey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dermott Brereton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seaford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nova</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JEREMY McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DANGER WILL BE OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIEWOLDT TO ANNOUNCE RETIREMENT TODAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Montagna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinn Rooney/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Willson/AFL Media/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crows-Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bartlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Cooney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Petroro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryn Geary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
