<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398492933168213</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65439/airbag-recalls-keep-growing-mazda6-cx7-cx9-bmw-x5-x6</url>
  <title>Airbag Recalls Keep Growing: Mazda6, CX-7, CX-9, BMW X5, X6</title>
  <content>
The world's largest recall continues to grow, with the potentially deadly takata recall expanded yet again with  and  adding more vehicle to the list.
Although both brands have already issued recalls for numerous vehicles, the latest recall expands the reach of the existing recall campaigns.
In both instances, vehicles are being recalled with a risk of metal shrapnel exploding as the airbag is deployed, resulting in an increased chance of injury to vehicle occupants.

Mazda6

Mazda vehicles included in the latest round of recalls include the ,  and  offered for sale in Australia between 2007 and 2013.
BMW has announced that its  and  SUVs sold between 2007 and 2012 are also part of the action.
Mazda owners wishing to know more can contact Mazda Customer Support on 1800 034 411 while BMW has set up a special web portal at  to allow owners to self-check the recall status of their vehicle with a VIN or chassis number.

BMW X5

TMR urges owners of any vehicle affected by the Takata airbag recall, regardless of vehicle brand, to take immediate action where possible following the death of a Sydney man earlier in the month owing to injuries caused by airbag shrapnel.
It is believed that over 700,000 vehicles in Australia are still waiting to have air bag units replaced, with owners facing delays owing to parts supply and service department availability, while other owners have failed to react to recall notices.
MORE:  |  |

Published 31-Jul-2017

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TMR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Recalls Keep Growing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW X5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda Customer Support</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mazda6</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CX-9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CX-7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jul-2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Takata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
