<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397715544077737</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/sunshine-coast-groups-monster-crocodile-encounter/3206810/</url>
  <title>Sunshine Coast group's monster crocodile encounter</title>
  <content>
A SUNSHINE Coast woman has captured amazing images of a monster crocodile lunching on a kangaroo in the Northern Territory.

Crocs scattered from the bank of the Daly River as this monster boss croc stomped out of the scrub with a kangaroo in its mouth,

With the rotting roo's leg hanging out of his mouth, the saltie made a beeline for the water where he sat in the shallows letting the carcass soften.

Vicki Burnett, was in a 4m tinny with three other people when she snapped the photos.

A big croc emerges from the bush with a kangaroo leg in his mouth. PICTURE: Vicki Burnett

She reckons the croc would have easily been bigger than their boat, estimating that it was around the 5m mark.

Hailing from the Sunshine Coast, she said the group was gobsmacked when they saw the croc emerge from the scrub.

"He just stepped out with his head and just looked and then he casually walked down straight into the water," she said.

This croc isn't shy about showing off his catch. PICTURE: Vicki Burnett

"We were gobsmacked; we were like 'oh my god look at this thing'."

She took the photo on Thursday around 3pm and said they hung around for a couple of minutes to watch the croc before moving on.

A monster croc takes a dip in the water with his catch. PICTURE: Vicki Burnett

The group went out with the intention of catching a barra but Ms Burnett said the crocs were easily the best part of the day.

"We'd seen crocs all day and some big ones but that one took the cake," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daly River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Burnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicki Burnett</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
