<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397925997477529</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/motorsport/formula-one/f1-max-verstappen-apologises-for-collision-with-daniel-ricciardo-in-hungarian-gp/news-story/204e6b2606e7ee7c82f5b063eb546787</url>
  <title>F1: Max Verstappen apologises for collision with Daniel Ricciardo in Hungarian GP</title>
  <content>
F1: Max Verstappen apologises for collision with Daniel Ricciardo in Hungarian GP

Jonathan Green, Sky Sports

Share

MAX Verstappen has publicly apologised to Daniel Ricciardo and Red Bull for the first-lap collision which knocked his teammate out of the Hungarian GP.
The pair came together at Turn Two after Verstappen locked up attempting a move down the inside of Ricciardo, causing terminal damage to the Australian's car.
In an explosive interview with Sky F1, Ricciardo called Verstappen "amateur" and said he made a "very poor mistake" as the Dutchman was handed a 10-second penalty by the race stewards.
LIVE stream the Belgian GP on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
WATCH:
RESULTS:
That penalty would cost Verstappen the chance to challenge for the race win and after finishing fifth, the 19-year-old held his hand up for causing the incident.

Ricciardo taken out by Max
1:57

Formula One: Daniel Ricciardo has been knocked out of the Hungarian Grand Prix by teammate Max Verstappen.

July 30th 2017
10 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Motorsport/

"I apologise to Daniel and also to the team because we could have scored some good points. I'll speak to Daniel in private and we'll sort it out," he told Sky F1.
"It's of course not what you want. Everything started in Turn One. The start was actually quite good but then I got squeezed wide by (Valtteri) Bottas and lost quite a bit of speed and then we were both fighting for position in Turn Two.

"We braked quite deep into the corner but I had a car in front of me and locked the front. From there I was just a passenger. I was trying to avoid Daniel but it was not possible.
"It's never my intention to hit anyone but especially not my teammate and especially with the relationship I have with Daniel which is very good."
Apologies to  and  for the start. But after that the balance and pace were good. That's positive.

'MAX SHOULD HAVE CONCEDED CORNER'
The two Red Bulls had started fifth and sixth on the grid with Verstappen leading Ricciardo into Turn One.
But the Dutchman went wide while attacking the Mercedes and Ferraris in front of him, allowing Ricciardo to move around the outside at Turn Two.
Aiming to stay ahead, Verstappen locked up at the corner and rammed into the other Red Bull. Ricciardo was then left stationary, sideways on the track, causing an early Safety Car.
Red Bull team principal Christian Horner said Verstappen should have conceded the corner to his teammate but added that he accepted the teenager's apology.
"You never want to see teammates touch and get the result that happened today," Horner told Sky F1.
"Max went in too deep at Turn Two, made a mistake and locked up and if Daniel hadn't been there I don't think he would have made the corner.
"Max is on the limit and he made a mistake today and it was costly for him, the team and for Daniel.

Ricciardo explains collision
1:52

Formula One: Daniel Ricciardo gives his perspective of the collision that knocked him out of the Hungarian Grand Prix.

July 30th 2017
9 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Motorsport/

"Daniel had got a run. It all started the corner before. Max had a good run at Turn One but had to back out from Kimi and went out wide. That gave Daniel the run and he had the corner for the next turner and Max should have conceded there. He tried to win it back and just got a bit too deep.
"He's stuck his hand up and said 'I made a mistake' and we'll accept it and I'm sure Daniel will accept it. They've got a great relationship.
"We'll talk about it openly in the debrief. What happened shouldn't have happened. Golden rule number one is leave space at Turn One and Turn Two. Max is man enough to say he made a mistake and apologise.
"All drivers make mistakes. The important thing is when you do make one you put your hand up, accept it and apologise. He's done that and I'm sure he'll go see his teammate and everybody will move on."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turn Two</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAX SHOULD HAVE CONCEDED CORNER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Safety Car</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Ricciardo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turn One</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verstappen</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Verstappen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valtteri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky F1</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Formula One</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgian GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bottas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Horner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian GP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutchman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricciardo</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
