<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398535882841653</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/webb-left-lamenting-double-bogey-at-scottish-open/3206893/</url>
  <title>Webb left lamenting double bogey at Scottish Open</title>
  <content>
GOLF: It's been over three years since Karrie Webb last tasted success on the LPGA Tour.
And the 42-year-old Australian veteran will have to wait a bit longer after seeing victory slip through her fingers at the Scottish Open - a tune-up event for next week's British Open.
Webb led by a stroke with two holes left at Dundonald Links, but produced a double bogey on the par-five 17th, handing the title to Mi Hyang Lee.
"I bent down, picked my tee up - thought I hit a perfect drive there," Webb said.
"When I stood up, I went to tell (my caddie) Jonny (Scott) that I absolutely knotted my 3-wood exactly how I wanted and he said it kicked into the bunker. I have no idea how it did that."

Needing an eagle on the final hole to force a playoff with lee, Webb closed with a birdie to tie for second with Mi Jung Hur.
Webb wasn't aware she had fallen to two strokes behind because of the lack of a leaderboard on the final hole.
"It's pretty bad to not have a leaderboard on the last," Webb said.
"That's the first time I've ever been (at a tour event) that hasn't had a leaderboard on 18. ... We didn't know if Mi Hyang had birdied or not, because there wasn't like a loud cheer like she had."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LPGA Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webb</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scottish Open</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MI Hyang Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dundonald Links</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mi Hyang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mi Jung Hur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karrie Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
