<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397840098130677</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4817366/henny-penny-saga-remains-a-mystery/?cs=308</url>
  <title>Henny Penny saga remains a mystery</title>
  <content>
"EYESORE": The old Henny Penny site at 54 Ridge Street, Merewether.

TOPICS won't let the old Henny Penny site at Merewether rest in peace.
We're back on deck for a week while the usual custodian of this page is on leave and we've got Henny Penny on our mind.
Not so much the bacon fillet burger or the Portuguese chicken tenderloins (do they still sell those? Must inquire), but more the dilapidated, disused building in Ridge Street. Topics did our best deep dive on this issue in March and got a huge response from people who wanted to know what was going on with the site.

Despite drawing a number of inferences after conversations with property lawyers, real estate agents, Newcastle City Council and others, we are yet to get a definitive answer as to why the owner has never developed the site.  
And people are still emailing in with their memories, or with ideas about why the site has been allowed to fall into disrepair after closing more than 14 years ago. 
One reader thought the site's previous life as a service station (another reader said it was called the Golden Fleece service station in the early 1960s) might be behind the delay. "The more likely theory as to the non activity on the site is that the steel fuel tanks beneath the concrete slab have corroded to the point where the contents have leached into the surrounding soils," the reader wrote.
"The clean up bill would be astronomical thus rendering the property unsaleable or undevelopable. "A check with the EPA or local council may dig up some dirt.
"There may be a geotech report somewhere to confirm this theory."
DELAYED SUCCESS FOR SHOW

LIMBER: Lee Cossey in the Australian Ninja Warrior grand finale. Picture: Nine

HOW about that Australian Ninja Warrior series? It's a great spectacle, it's encouraging an active and adventurous lifestyle and people seem to love it. 
In fact, the show broke Australian TV rating records during its two week run, with the final stage on Tuesday night blasting past 3 million viewers nationally.
Channel Nine is already talking up next season and has put a call out to try and find the ninjas of tomorrow.
But what's weird about all this is that it took Australia so long to catch on to this TV phenomenon. 
We are so starved for decent content on free-to-air TV that when we do finally get our own reboot of a popular US or UK reality TV series it goes bananas. But Ninja Warrior has been a thing for decades. 
It started with the show Sasuke on Japanese television in 1997. 
Since then US television stations have been running American Ninja Warrior with huge success since 2009. 
That's ok, right? We're usually at least a few years behind the US.
Well have a look at the rest of these countries that got a Ninja Warrior franchise before Australia.
Bahrain, China, Denmark, France, Germany, Indonesia, Italy, Malaysia, Singapore, Sweden, Turkey, Vietnam just to name a few.
That's embarrassing for Australia, a country where training disciplines like Parkour, CrossFit, rock climbing, essentially all of the elements of Ninja Warrior have become extremely popular in recent years. 

Instead of praising our free-to-air networks for bringing us this content, we should be asking what took so long. 
THE MOOCH MISQUOTES 

MOOCH: Anthony Scaramucci, incoming White House communications director.
Donald Trump's new White House communications director, Anthony "Mooch" Scaramucci is paying for his old tweets that don't comply with the political views of his new boss. But none have been more embarrassing for him than this. 

"Dance like no one is watching. Sing like no one is listening. Love like you've never been hurt and live like it's heaven on earth. Mark Twain," Mooch tweeted in 2012. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henny Penny</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Fleece</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Twain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Cossey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ridge Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasuke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CrossFit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bahrain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUCCESS FOR SHOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOOCH MISQUOTES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portuguese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
