<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398497228135557</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/motorcycle-crash-victim-tells-of-struggles-two-yea/3206818/</url>
  <title>'I lost more than my legs that day'</title>
  <content>
TWO years ago, Terry Pepi's life changed in a split second.

The 57-year-old was once an active partner, father and granddad, who enjoyed spending time four-wheel driving, fishing and going for joyrides on his Harley with his wife Helen.

He loved his job at Aurizon, where he had worked for 40 years as a tutor driver, and cherished the little things, like a straight nights sleep or being able to run around with his four-year-old grandson.

But now all that has changed for Terry.

On June 26, 2015, he was involved in a serious collision while riding his motorbike to work along Mackay-Eungella Rd.

A driver failed to stop at a give-way sign and collided with Terry, who was travelling at 100kmh.

As a result, Terry had extensive and serious injuries including a gash in his leg, six broken ribs, a broken wrist, broken shoulder, fractured neck and a broken back, which left him a paraplegic.

He was admitted to ICU, where he remained in a coma for a week, while his family went through huge trauma, not knowing if he would survive or what his quality of life would be.

He later suffered complications as a result of the crash and his condition was raised from paraplegia to quadriplegia. He has no feeling in his body from his chest down.

"I lost much more than my legs that day," he said.

"Although at first, when I was coming to terms with everything, I thought to myself 'okay you won't be able to walk, it's not the end of the world' you don't realise at that time everything else that goes.

"I have ridden motorbikes all my life, my wife and I loved travelling and going camping with our swags, all of that was gone and I didn't realise that then.

"I didn't realise people in wheelchairs can't control their bladders or bowels, have no sexual function.

"I loved my job and it never dawned on me that I couldn't do that too.

"Your whole world is honestly just ripped from you."

The driver of the car that collided with Terry's motorbike, 24-year-old Bradley Younger, was eventually charged with driving without due care.

He was fined $1500 and a conviction was recorded on his traffic history.

Terry Pepi became a paraplegic the day of his accident and has needed to use a wheelchair ever since.Contributed

Meanwhile, Terry spent nine months in hospital being rehabilitated and learning to cope with his new way of life.

"That driver, for him it was just one moment, one second of inattention," Terry said.

"But for us that moment will now last a lifetime, we will deal with those consequences instead."

While the negatives would often bring Terry down at first, he said he tries his best to focus on the positives in life that he still has.

"While I was in hospital there was a kid laying across from me who wouldn't have been more than 19 years old, he felt nothing from the neck down and his life had barely started," Terry said.

"There are always people worse off than you and I try to remember that I still have a beautiful wife who has stuck by me, children and amazing grandchildren - one of the little buggers just spent a fortnight with us."

Terry and Helen are now living in Brisbane. They were required to relocate for Terry's medical needs and to receive suitable modifications to their home by Work Cover.

Terry and his wife Helen rooting for Queensland.Contributed

"When Terry was rendered quadriplegic his needs were greater and, unfortunately, staying in Mackay wasn't plausible any more," Helen said.

"We would have been coming back to Brisbane every week for the doctors.

"Also, the modifications that needed to be done to our house were deemed too expensive and we were told we would need to relocate, so on all counts it meant we couldn't go back to our home."

The couple have been living in Brisbane for two years, boarding with a family friend, and have recently saved enough money to purchase a new house with the necessary modifications.

They were also recently approved to have a car modified for Terry, meaning he can finally drive again and can get to his appointments with more ease.

Helen is working full time as a firefighter and doing her best to care for Terry, along with medical staff.

Terry hopes his story will urge drivers to use more caution on the roads, and never let themselves become distracted, even just for a moment.

Terry's lawyer, Jillian Barrett, of Maurice Blackburn Lawyers, said all too often similar incidents occured on the roads, leading to catastrophic events that changed people's lives.

"Already in 2017, 33 motorcycle riders have died on Queensland roads - two more than at the same time last year - and countless others have been injured," she said.

"It's up to all of us as road users, to be alert on the roads and ensure that other people don't suffer the same catastrophic injuries as Terry."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurizon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jillian Barrett, of Maurice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Work Cover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 26, 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Pepi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland.Contributed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay-Eungella Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackburn Lawyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley Younger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
