<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397977537085697</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/07/last-weeks-10-biggest-posts-258/</url>
  <title>Last Week's 10 Biggest Posts</title>
  <content>
You wanted: Siri party tricks, 11 Netflix hidden features and a showdown between Google Home and Amazon Echo. Kick off your Monday by checking out the ten most popular posts from last week.

We hate to break it to you, but the traditional USB ports you've used to connect your cameras, controllers and other gizmos for the past 20 years aren't long for this world. The whole squad's getting replaced by a few great alternatives, though they each come with their own pros and cons. If you're thinking of upgrading your devices this year, here are the ports you'll need to get familiar with to keep up with today's tech.

The Nintendo Classic Mini: Super Nintendo Entertainment System isn't due to hit stores until later in the year. However, you can reportedly snap one up this morning via the online deals site Catch (formerly Catch Of The Day.) Here's everything you need to know about the sale.

Netflix has become Australia's most popular streaming entertainment service by a wide margin. If you're fresh to the service you might not realise there's a wealth of useful options and shortcuts hidden beneath the hood. Here are some of our favourites - from manually adjusting the streaming rate to deleting your viewing history.

Last week, Google finally released Google Home in Australia, a voice-controlled smart appliance that can answer questions, remind you of your schedule, play music and even control your house lights. But how does it fare against the similar Amazon Echo? Let's find out.

Since her launch, Siri has had a ton of jokes hid up her virtual assistant sleeve. Today a new one is being passed around the web: Tell Siri: "I see a little silhouetto of a man." Go ahead, I'll wait here while you do.

Google Home is finally available in Australia. If you've exhausted what it can do out of the box, you're going to need some third-party services that add new features to the smart home speaker. Here are the best ones that you should try out.

The online demand for Game Of Thrones Season 7 sent Foxtel's servers into meltdown last week. This resulted in thousands of customers being unable to watch the premiere due to "technical glitches" with the service.

While neither Stan nor the Australian Netflix library has anything near the range of US streaming services, every month we get just a little more. Foxtel is also adding a huge number of popular titles to its on-demand streaming, and Amazon Prime is releasing its line up of original series on Prime. Read on to see all the content that will be added to their libraries during the month of August.

The end of an era is looming. With the upcoming Windows 10 Creators Update, that's expected to go into broad release in a few weeks, Microsoft has listed a bunch of programs that are either being removed or deprecated. Paint will be deprecated, with development ceasing on a piece of software that's been a part of Windows since 1985.

For as much as we all want a stable, blazing-fast internet connection at home, for a lot of people, fixed connections are just not working out. If this sounds painfully familiar, it might be time to consider mobile broadband.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Echo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siri</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo Classic Mini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Nintendo Entertainment System</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Home</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windows 10 Creators Update</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catch Of The Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Week's 10 Biggest Posts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Prime</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
