<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398488638200845</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/rear-window/gail-kelly-rewrites-westpac-history-like-a-boss-20170729-gxljyk</url>
  <title>Gail Kelly rewrites Westpac history like a boss</title>
  <content>
Former Westpac chief executive Gail Kelly was a trailblazer, to be sure. While she's best remembered for smashing her way through corporate Australia's glass ceiling - an unquestionably welcome and important step-change - Kelly also proved that even a Latin teacher could run one of the Big Four. Apparently that's boast-worthy! And to think we interpreted it as an inculpatory anecdote of our set-and-forget banking oligopoly.  
Last week, presumably mistaking herself for a former prime minister, a revolutionary Silicon Valley auteur or even a Scientology escapee rather than the one-time manager of a public utility, Kelly released her memoir, Live Lead Learn: My Stories of Life & Leadership.
The self-regard required to initiate such a monument to oneself and one's relatively unspectacular legacy is an exhausting thing to imagine, let alone personally bear. But then this is the woman who had her underlings carry her into St George's staff Christmas party on a sedan-chair .
The book itself is one of the most egregious revisions of business history we've ever had the grand misfortune of reading. Recalling the pasting Westpac copped for its mortgage rate rise 20 basis points higher than the RBA's cash rate increase in December 2009, not far from the apogee of the GFC, she blamed "my public relations and media team" for advising her not to hold a press conference because "my appearance would add fuel to the fire". So, in a book supposedly about leadership lessons, the leader throws her advisers under the bus for not getting adequate shine on a turd entirely of the leader's own making. Here's some free PR advice: Westpac's mistake wasn't how the decision was announced, its mistake was the decision - an indefensibly grasping one.

Louise Kennerley

And the greatest schoolteacher since Robin Williams turned up at Welton, by omission, also abrogates responsibility for the  with David Murray's Financial System Inquiry, during which Kelly was the Australian Bankers' Association chair, and the result of which is $16 billion or so more capital now atrophying on the Big Four's balance sheets.

The truth is that we, the media, gave Gail Kelly the easiest run of all time, mainly because she was so expertly shepherded through the vast part of her tenure. Again, that's not how she sees it, wishing she'd had "a strong, highly-skilled and experienced media relations team. I was sorely in need of the fearless advice and counsel. In later years, Carolyn McCann brought exactly that."
Cleopatra's efficacious PR slaves, now squished beneath her litter, get this special thank you from the Egyptian empress whose often brittle ego they so deftly obscured. While McCann, who, still serving Brian Hartzer, helped edit this book and who, besides Kelly herself, has in her alleged fearlessness, done more to show us the true Gail Kelly than anyone else, is lauded. We couldn't keep that down with a cast-iron stomach.
It is instructive that Kelly describes the news of her Westpac appointment in 2007 leaking out early as "unfortunate". She also describes "the announcement of my retirement" as "well planned", having "all the hallmarks of good preparation and execution." It was "on my own timetable" and "this was important to me."
This would explain why in the days before her retirement was announced, McCann and another Westpac exec Peter "Banana Smoothie" Hanlon, both of them (by their own subsequent admissions to us) parties to the well-planned announcement, . Control was so important to Kelly that, we must deduce, dishonesty was not only acceptable but desirable. Another risible leadership lesson.

Sasha Woolley

So damaged was the bank's trust with its media stakeholders as a result of this proud yet pointless deception that in Hartzer's early months he had to bring back McCann's exceptional predecessor, where he thanklessly remains.
Oh and just for the record, for all the reputational prejudice borne by Cleopatra, she took more loot out of that joint than God. $72.2 million in eight statutory years and another $10.65 million that vested after her (so meticulously managed) retirement. Yep, nearly $83 million, which doesn't include the 68,000 WBC units she got thanks to the bank controversially excluding IT expenses of $505 million from FY15 cash earnings, nor the 1.42 million shares that converted from the St George shares already in her skyrocket, a skyrocket the dimensions of which Latin was never designed to convey. While CEO, she collected $50.5 million selling her shares in the bank, but still owns 1.8 million shares worth around $60 million. And she needed a book deal? "Relevance deprivation is something men are more likely to experience. I think I will be fine," she wrote, also, we can now confidently conclude, without a scintilla of irony. Now excuse us but we're going back to our deckchair (not even carried by slaves). If only Cleopatra had stayed on hers.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scientology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banana Smoothie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stories of Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCann</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Four</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleopatra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Kelly</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasha Woolley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Murray's Financial System Inquiry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolyn McCann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hartzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bankers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FY15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Kennerley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Egyptian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Hartzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Welton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Live Lead Learn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
