<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397930292444942</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/world/rape-victim-in-bangladesh-has-head-shaved-by-attackers-wife/news-story/bb3a48e849d10a59a9c0cfcefb861a7c</url>
  <title>Teen rape victim's head shaved</title>
  <content>
A MANHUNT is underway in Bangladesh for a woman who beat and shaved a teenager as punishment after she was allegedly gang raped by the woman's husband.
Police have arrested four men over the alleged gang rape including Tufan Sarker, a unionist linked to the ruling Awami League party, after pictures of the victim and her mother at hospital with shaved heads caused outrage.
Police are still hunting Sarker's wife Asha Khatun, who is accused of dragging the teenager and her mother to their home, beating them and forcibly shaving their heads.
Sarker, 25, has been charged with raping the 16-year-old at home on Friday, said local police spokesman Sonaton Chakroborty.
"He threatened to kill her and her mother if she would dare to talk to anyone about the incident," he told AFP.
Another officer told AFP that Sarker was a local leader of the labour wing of the Awami League, which has been ruling Bangladesh for most of the last decade.
Photos of the victim and her mother at hospital with their heads shaved spread quickly online, outraging Bangladeshis who urged police to take prompt action.
The victim, whose identity has not been disclosed, said Sarker's wife suspected she had engaged in a relationship with her husband.
"They shaved my entire head. I repeatedly apologised but they didn't listen. They even beat my mother and shaved her head," she told a local news channel.
Police said they were also pursuing Sarker's sister-in-law, a councillor in Bogra city, for allegedly abetting the assault by sending thugs to help beat the victims.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tufan Sarker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladeshi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarker</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asha Khatun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarker, 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bogra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Awami League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonaton Chakroborty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
