<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398192285453666</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:31</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/guardian-youth-care-charity-minister-significantly-culpable-for-violent-assault-20170728-gxkrq4.html</url>
  <title>Guardian Youth Care charity, minister 'significantly culpable' for violent assault </title>
  <content>
A 15-year-old girl picked up a long glass shard from a shattered photograph frame and slashed her youth worker across the neck.
But in sentencing her for wounding with intent to cause grievous bodily harm, a judge has found the girl was not the only one to blame.Photo: Louie Douvis
District Court Judge Martin Sides has found "significant moral culpability" on the part of the Sydney not-for-profit company providing the girl's full-time care on behalf of the Minister for Family and Community Services. 
Run by former Wallaby Glen Ella, Guardian Youth Care has come under sustained scrutiny in recent months, facing accusations by the government of misappropriating nearly $20 million. 
The money was paid in allegedly unauthorised subcontracts to companies with links to former criminals, including a murderer, which have refused to open their books to administrators. Fairfax Media has detailed allegations by former residents and youth workers that Guardian Youth Care failed to provide adequate resources or staffing levels to keep children safe.
The girl convicted of the wounding charge, who cannot be named for legal reasons, had a history of mental illness including post-traumatic stress disorder.

On the night of March 27 last year, she was staying in a Guardian Youth Care house with the youth worker she would later assault. The girl, then 15, was allowed to go out unsupervised with a man twice her age who then allegedly sexually assaulted her, the court heard. 
Judge Sides found that permission was "entirely inappropriate" and "profoundly disturbing". The court heard the alleged assault aggravated the girl's mental health conditions.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Three days later, she punched the youth worker in the head when she was at the hospital for complications from the morning-after pill, and later made death threats. 
An apprehended violence order was put in place and the girl's lawyer wrote to Guardian Youth Care, advocating that the youth worker not be rostered on to the girl's care. But she was. 
During her next visit on April 13, 2016, the girl shouted death threats, placed the youth worker in a headlock, kneed her in the stomach and slit her neck with a 20-centimetre piece of glass, leaving a 4-centimetre cut that required stitches.
Judge Sides, taking into account the girl's mental health problems, sentenced her to a minimum 18 months in custody. He criticised Guardian Youth Care and the Minister for Family and Community Services, then Brad Hazzard, who was her legal guardian.
"The only conclusion that one can come to is that the Minister, the Department and the victim's employer all bear significant moral culpability for the young offender's offence and the position in which the victim was placed on the night of the offence," Judge Sides wrote in his judgement. 
"The Minister and the responsible department need to carefully review the use of the victim's employer in providing care for anyone."
Judge Sides' decision in early June came three weeks before the charity was placed in administration and ceased trading. 
Guardian Youth Care has accused the government of withholding funding over several years. The government is claiming $19.6 million in unauthorised subcontracts was misappropriated, according to an administrators' report.
A department spokesman commenting on the case of the 15-year-old girl said the Minister, the department and the care provider "share the responsibility for the safety, welfare and wellbeing of the young person in out-of-home care".
"The young person has a case plan with FACS that is regularly reviewed and revised to ensure it supports the young person in detention and following release," he said. 
Mr Hazzard was unavailable for comment. Directors of Guardian Youth Care did not answer questions. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Hazzard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian Youth Care</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court Judge Martin Sides</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hazzard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallaby Glen Ella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Sides</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FACS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
