<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398578832515161</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/orman-joining-top-company/3206892/</url>
  <title>Orman joining top company</title>
  <content>
JIM Orman has completed a smooth transition from apprentice to senior rider at the Ipswich track.

Last season's Ipswich Apprentice Jockey Premiership winner welcomed in the latest to win that title but not before riding a winner of his own at Bundamba on Wednesday.

Orman streeted the field last season for the apprentice's title with almost 30 winners.

Last Wednesday, he rode his 12th and final winner for the 2017 season to give a decent return in his first full year as a senior rider.

That left Orman in good company equal with Tegan Harrison and Larry Cassidy, and just short of Nozi Tomizawa, Ipswich Cup winner Michael Cahill and the season's premier apprentice Tiffani Brooker. She finished the season in outright fourth with 15 wins.

That 15th season win came aboard Bold Gypsy last week for Sunshine Coast trainer Garnett Taylor.

Even though Brooker claimed the apprentice's title and fourth place on the overall jockey's ladder, she was a long way behind the breakaway ladder topping trio of Jim Byrne, Jeff Lloyd and Robbie Fradd.

Byrne claimed a record eighth senior jockey's premiership along with apprentice awards earlier in his career.

Lloyd collected a winning treble on Wednesday to overtake Fradd for second, finishing on 29 season winners, three behind Jim Byrne.

Lloyd's winners were all favoured in the betting and duly saluted, including Heart of Australia for former Melbourne Cup winning trainer John Meagher and the Toby Edmonds trained duo of Chloe's Comet and Fabvier.

Meagher's galloper deserved the maiden win having placed 10 times in 12 career starts adding $20,000 including the QTIS bonus to give her $72,000 in career prizemoney.

Toby Edmonds travelled from the Gold Coast with just three stable entrants.

He would have been well satisfied with two out of three for the day.

Gollan's reign continues

EAGLE Farm trainer Tony Gollan collected a winner on Wednesday with Miss Arabella, which was one of nine stable starters at Ipswich on the day.

The three-year-old filly was win number 21 for Gollan at Ipswich, well ahead of second placed Marcus Wilson with 12 at the completion of the 2017 season.

This was Gollan's third consecutive Trainer's Premiership title at Ipswich with big margins recorded in each of those.

Valuable functions

HUNDREDS of thousands of dollars have been raised at the Ipswich Turf Club for charitable, sporting and community organisations over the years and this trend continues strongly today.

A prime example of such an event is the Newro Foundation Raceday on August 11.

Ipswich resident Sarah Harling has organised this day after being inspired by family friend Craig who recently conquered the massive odds of a five-year long brain cancer sufferer to complete the Gold Coast 42km marathon, a day prior to undergoing the next round of chemotherapy.

Fundraising for such groups while enjoying a day out at the races has become an annual event for many organisations allowing the Ipswich Turf Club to be involved in contributions to the community which has long shown strong support of the club.

Anyone interested in attending or being involved in this day should contact the Ipswich Turf Club on 32821500.

Next meeting

Racing continues on Friday for the first Ipswich meeting of the new season. This is the first of four consecutive Fridays program at Bundamba before another Wednesday date on August 30.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newro Foundation Raceday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Edmonds</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Apprentice Jockey Premiership</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Byrne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QTIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Turf Club</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tegan Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JIM Orman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe's Comet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Arabella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiffani Brooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bold Gypsy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gollan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundamba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Gollan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Fradd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EAGLE Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heart of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cahill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Harling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Meagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garnett Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fabvier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Cassidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fradd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trainer's Premiership</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nozi Tomizawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
