<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398398443886403</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/real-estate/gpt-takes-control-at-highpoint-in-a-680m-deal-20170728-gxl2uf</url>
  <title>GPT takes control at Highpoint in a $680m deal</title>
  <content>
GPT has taken up its pre-emptive rights to buy up the 25 per cent of Melbourne's Highpoint shopping centre it doesn't already hold in a $680 million deal with its co-owners,the Besen family.
The stake will be taken up by the unlisted GPT Wholesale Shopping Centre Fund, which co-owns the majority of remainder of the massive suburban shopping centre alongside its manager, GPT itself.
The deal was struck on an extremely sharp 4 per cent yield, indicative of the high prices institutional investors are paying for exposure in dominant shopping centres.
Highpoint is one of the leading super regional shopping centres in the country and is in the Top 5 of the Big Guns of shopping centres, with an annual moving turnover of almost $1 billion.

announced in April they were looking to offload sell their 25 per cent stake in the Highpoint mall. The family's Highpoint Property Group was a co-owner of the 153,000 square metre mall, one of the biggest in Australia.

The purchase takes GWSCF's ownership in the asset to 83.33 per cent while The GPT Group (GPT) retains a 16.67 per cent interest. GPT continues to be the manager of the Highpoint Shopping Centre.
GPT has steadily increased its ownership of the sprawling 153,000 sq m mall, since buying a half stake in 2006.The fund manager had pre-emptive rights to buy out the remainder if the Besen family elected to divest its stake.
In April this year Marc Besen, chairman of Highpoint Property Group, said the family had decided to review its ownership of a 25 per cent interest in the Highpoint centre.
"Highpoint is a most important retail asset showcasing leading Australian and international brands," he said at the time.

"The Besen family has enjoyed a strong relationship with GPT over the last 10 years and our shared interest in Highpoint has been very successful for both owners."
GPT completed a $300 million redevelopment of Highpoint in 2013, adding 25 per cent more retail space including a fresh food market and a full-line .
In 2013, added international retailers including Zara, Topshop, Apple and Samsung to the more than 500 stores in the centre. The mall in Maribyrnong, about eight kilometres north of Melbourne's CBD, attracts more than 16 million visitors a year.
Grant Samuel and Arnold Bloch Leibler are advising HPG.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Besen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highpoint Property Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HPG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highpoint</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>18</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highpoint Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnold Bloch Leibler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top 5 of the Big</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maribyrnong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Samuel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Besen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT Wholesale Shopping Centre Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWSCF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Topshop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Highpoint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
