<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398578832515168</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/qld-no-body-no-parole-law-up-for-debate/news-story/1d528e23a5ad33972519a919169ba236</url>
  <title>Qld 'No Body, No Parole' law up for debate</title>
  <content>
Sonia KohlbacherAustralian Associated Press

Share

The Queensland government's proposed 'no body, no parole' legislation will be debated in state parliament next week.
Attorney-General Yvette D'Ath introduced the bill to Queensland's parliament in May. If passed it would mean murderers who haven't identified the location of their victims' bodies won't be released without serving maximum time.
The proposed law was one of the key recommendations of the Sofronoff Review into the state's parole system, sparked by the killing of 81-year-old grandmother Elizabeth Kippin in her Townsville home last July allegedly by a man paroled just hours earlier.
"I would hope there is support across parliament from the Opposition and the cross-bench on this important bill when it's debated next week," Ms D'Ath said on Monday.
The laws would be retrospective and apply to people convicted of murder, manslaughter, accessory after the fact to murder and conspiring to murder.
Queensland's Legal Affairs and Community Safety Committee recommended the legislation be pass earlier in July, despite concerns raised by legal bodies and civil libertarians.
The state's Law Society, Council for Civil Liberties and Bar Association supported the intentions of the proposed legislation but objected on grounds where offenders might not be able to comply.
The Queensland Law Society opposed the bill on the basis that inmates would be unable to provide accurate information in cases where they were wrongly convicted or where natural events had played a role.
The QCCL, meanwhile, raised a concern that those who were wrongfully convicted of homicide offences due to miscarriages of justice would never be able to be released.

The Department of Justice and Attorney General said existing criminal justice mechanisms would be relied upon in cases where prisoners claimed innocence and therefore could not co-operate.
The opposition Liberal National Party held up the passage of broader reforms in May to introduce their own 'no body, no parole' bill.
But Ms D'Ath claimed that legislation was "sloppy" and had to be reworked so it could be properly implemented.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Law Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's Legal Affairs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General Yvette D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sofronoff Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Kippin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms D</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bar Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonia KohlbacherAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Safety Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QCCL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ath</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civil Liberties</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
