<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398531587874276</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/music/little-mix-review-this-time-the-recipe-is-just-right-20170731-gxm09m.html</url>
  <title>Little Mix review: This time the recipe is just right</title>
  <content>
Little Mix
Qudos Bank Arena, Olympic Park, July 29
George Palathingal
★★★ 1/2
Well, this is more like it.
It's just over a year since Little Mix last played in this same arena and, mercifully, things have changed all around.
For a start, the female foursome with the Mariah-wannabe voices can now fill the room. Last time, while practically national treasures in their native Britain, as one of those rare X Factor winners who had managed to keep the hits coming locally, they found they weren't quite as popular in Sydney.
In a clearly scaled-down version of their show, they performed to a half-full room, the songs didn't sound big enough and atmosphere, let alone dignity, was conspicuous in its absence.
Luckily for everyone on this night, Shout Out to My Ex happened a couple of months later. Seemingly capturing everyone's imagination, the empowering dance-pop confection preceded an album, Glory Days, that finally nudged Little Mix into the global-superstar bracket to which they had mistakenly thought they belonged before.
So, this time we get the whole enchilada. The excitement starts well before the show, with screams for every track the DJ plays featuring one J. Bieber (which, admittedly, seems to be about every pop song around). Video cameras aimed around the crowd give fans a few glorious seconds of fame on the big screen and there are more than enough bodies to make a decent human wave.
Eventually, the teasing stops and the lights go down. Little Mix stride onstage, pose like Wonder Woman's long-lost sisters and launch into the business of hitting the high notes and gyrating alongside their male backing dancers.
There's no band again, the music still all pre-recorded, but the vocals are strong enough, songs new and old sound fresh and there are all the bells and whistles of an arena-pop extravaganza: fireballs during opener Power, a confetti explosion during Wings and fireworks during the climactic Shout Out to My Ex.
In a lean hour and a quarter - the perfect length for both children and chaperones - Little Mix thrill with the feistier anthems (Salute, Hair), wring out the emotion with the ballads (notably LGBTIQA-adopted, and acknowledged, anthem Secret Love Song) and tell us how much they love us.
Regarding that last bit, it's nice for everyone that this time there's a decent number of fans to reciprocate.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariah-wannabe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTIQA-adopted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Mix</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wonder Woman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glory Days</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qudos Bank Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Palathingal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X Factor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Love Song</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J. Bieber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shout Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
