<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398583127482508</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/webb-left-lamenting-double-bogey-at-scottish-open/3206893/</url>
  <title>Webb left lamenting double bogey at Scottish Open</title>
  <content>
GOLF: It's been over three years since Karrie Webb last tasted success on the LPGA Tour.
And the 42-year-old Australian veteran will have to wait a bit longer after seeing victory slip through her fingers at the Scottish Open - a tune-up event for next week's British Open.
Webb led by a stroke with two holes left at Dundonald Links, but produced a double bogey on the par-five 17th, handing the title to Mi Hyang Lee.
"I bent down, picked my tee up - thought I hit a perfect drive there," Webb said.
"When I stood up, I went to tell (my caddie) Jonny (Scott) that I absolutely knotted my 3-wood exactly how I wanted and he said it kicked into the bunker. I have no idea how it did that."
Needing an eagle on the final hole to force a playoff with lee, Webb closed with a birdie to tie for second with Mi Jung Hur.
Webb wasn't aware she had fallen to two strokes behind because of the lack of a leaderboard on the final hole.
"It's pretty bad to not have a leaderboard on the last," Webb said.
"That's the first time I've ever been (at a tour event) that hasn't had a leaderboard on 18. ... We didn't know if Mi Hyang had birdied or not, because there wasn't like a loud cheer like she had."
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LPGA Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webb</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scottish Open</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MI Hyang Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dundonald Links</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mi Hyang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mi Jung Hur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karrie Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
