<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398617487221320</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-07-31/2017-heywire-competition-now-open-for-entries/8756494</url>
  <title>ABC Heywire 2017 competition now open for entries</title>
  <content>
This year young Australians will have been telling their own unique stories through the ABC's Heywire competition for two decades.
The 20th annual competition is now open and regional Australians aged 16 to 22 are being invited to tell their story about life in their part of the world.
Heywire stories range from fun and whimsical to deeply personal accounts. They can be told in any format: writing, photography or film but all give a distinctly youthful perspective on regional Australia.
One of last year's winners Claire Wright from Tennant Creek in the Northern Territory told of her family's experience with multiple sclerosis.
"My story was quite personal," Ms Wright said.
"I just needed to tell myself that no-one would read it and then when they did I found that I was actually fine with it."
Forty winners will receive an all-expenses-paid trip to Canberra for the Heywire Regional Youth Summit.
Participants at the summit work together to nut out ways to deal with some of the issues closest to them, and then the Foundation for Rural and Regional Renewal provides cash grants to make many of the ideas a reality.

2016 Heywire winner Jamilla Dempsey says the competition gave her confidence.

2016 Heywire winner Jamilla Dempsey says the competition gave her confidence.

ABC Heywire

It was an experience 2016 participant Jamilla Dempsey from Austinmer in New South Wales described as enchanting.
"I made some amazing friends from across the country - people I thought I would never normally be able to meet," she said.

"I also got a really strong sense of confidence that I can make a difference, and that I can solve the issues I want to solve."

ABC Regional Director, Fiona Reynolds, said the Heywire competition provided a unique opportunity for young people to make a difference.
"Heywire is a powerful way for young people to be heard across the nation - through the ABC and in Canberra," Ms Reynolds said.

"It's also an unparalleled opportunity for them to drive lasting change in their communities."

Deputy Prime Minister and Minister for Agriculture and Water Resources, Barnaby Joyce, said regional communities underpinned our national identity and the Australian way of life, and the strength of that contribution was matched only by the diversity of the people who made it.
"Most Australians know that to be true, but not the reasons why. If you're young and from the bush, you can change all that, get involved in Heywire and tell your story; it matters and it's one we can all be proud of."
Over the years, Heywire winners have used the experience as a springboard to exciting careers, including work in community development, design, farming, and media.
For 25 young people the summit had been the first step to a career with the ABC.

2016 Heywire winner Molly Hunt advises anyone thinking of entering to "Just do it".

2016 Heywire winner Molly Hunt advises anyone thinking of entering to "Just do it".

ABC Heywire

Molly Hunt from Wyndham is one of the most recent winners to find work with the national broadcaster.
She attended the Regional Youth Summit earlier this year and is now working with ABC radio in Broome.
"Straight after Heywire I got a job with the ABC so right now I am in Broome working as an intern," Ms Hunt said.
"My advice is just to do it," she said.
"If you have a story, write it in - no harm done, it is a really great opportunity."
The competition is open until September 16 and stories can be submitted via the
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyndham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Regional Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heywire I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Youth Summit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamilla Dempsey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heywire Regional Youth Summit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennant Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broome</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austinmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Heywire</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly Hunt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Renewal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Heywire 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heywire</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
