<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398570242580322</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/guildford-residents-score-victory-in-battle-to-stop-mcdonalds-restaurant-opening/news-story/9d1a563e2324253054adee8f42c09412</url>
  <title>Fight to keep Macca's out of Guildford heats up</title>
  <content>
RESIDENTS in the historic suburb of Guildford have scored a victory in their battle to stop the opening of a McDonald's restaurant.
The Metro East Joint Development Assessment Panel is being urged next month to refuse the fast-food giant's bid to build a 24-hour restaurant behind the Guildford Hotel.
A responsible authority report, prepared by the City of Swan, said the $2.75 million building's "faux" heritage masonry facade - an attempt to fit in with the historic surrounds - "diminished" the town's character.
An 8m-high illuminated sign featuring the famous "golden arches" was also out of character with Guildford's "integrity and individuality".
The McDonald's is proposed to share 43 on-site carpark bays with the Guildford Hotel, resulting in a shortfall of up to 81 bays. There are concerns customers would park along Johnson Street.
The 134-year-old Guildford Hotel reopened last year, eight years after it was gutted by fire.
Hotel owner Luke Martino first raised the ire of residents with plans to build a seven-storey apartment block at the rear of the heritage-listed pub.
Of the 861 submissions made on the McDonald's plan, 837 were against.
Concerns about the proposal included the impact the restaurant would have on Guildford's heritage, traffic, parking and its proximity to Guildford Primary School.
In a submission, the Department of Education said the fast-food outlet was "too close to the school".
But planners said it was "difficult to see how parents of young children ... would be compromised in their capacity to exercise parental control over what their children eat".
The McDonald's plan prompted Heart Foundation to suggest fast-food "exclusion zones" be introduced around WA schools to prevent kids' easy access to junk food.
The Heritage Council did not object, but the National Trust of WA raised concerns about the faux facade and the "dominating" red sign.
Last month revised plans submitted, which proposed erecting McDonald's illuminated "golden arches" on top of the existing Guildford Hotel pylon sign.
That idea was later scrapped on the advice of the council.
More than 5000 people signed a petition opposing the proposal.
The panel is expected to make its decision on August 7.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Martino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro East Joint Development Assessment Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heritage Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guildford Hotel</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guildford Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Trust of WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heart Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guildford</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Swan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
