<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398574537547757</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/st-kilda/st-kilda-champion-to-reveal-his-playing-future/news-story/18644e33bde7b63265f26e080215df9c</url>
  <title>It's over: Saint Nick hangs up boots</title>
  <content>
ST KILDA champion Nick Riewoldt will tell the footy world today he is drawing the curtain on his brilliant career.
The Saints have called a press conference with Riewoldt and coach Alan Richardson at 2pm.
It is believed Riewoldt told his teammates this morning of his decision to retire.
He is expected to play the Saints' final four matches of the season and will finish on 337 matches unless St Kilda makes a miraculous finals appearance.

Major announcement from Saints today. One of their veterans will reveal their retirement plans. About 2pm. More
Riewodlt's father Joe confirmed the news on Twitter.
Riewoldt has played 333 games and was rested against Port Adelaide on Saturday night.
"He'd be the first to admit that his last couple of performances have been below his best, it was time for him to have a spell. We'll get him back next week, all going well in terms of the plan and he'll be better for that break,'' Saints coach Alan Richardson said.
END OF THE LINE?
MARK ROBINSON:
Asked about Riewoldt's future, he said: "All I can really say on that is the conversations are absolutely private but they are ongoing.
"Both camps know exactly where they sit, there are conversations between player and coach, there are conversations between management.''

Teammate Leigh Montagna is yet to announce his playing future.
Montagna won't play again this season unless the Saints make the finals after suffering a bad hamstring injury against Sydney a week ago.
Last week .
"Same deal (for Montagna), let's see how you're going physically, there's no doubt that it's not great timing, I think he said as much,'' Richardson said.
"We'll make that call and we'll have those ongoing discussions and make a call in the next few weeks.''
MORE TO COME
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saint Nick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Montagna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARK ROBINSON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewodlt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montagna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Richardson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
