<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398574537547713</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Tech Guide</source>
  <url>http://www.techguide.com.au/news/city-now-illegal-cross-road-youre-texting/</url>
  <title>The city where it is now illegal to cross the road while you're texting - Tech Guide</title>
  <content>
A young man texts as he crosses the road

1 min ago
,

Related Articles

The latest danger on the roads today is pedestrians crossing the road while they are absorbed with their phone but if you happen to be in Honolulu it is now illegal.

Honolulu is the first major US city to pass a "distracted walking" law which means anyone looking at or texting on their phone while crossing the road is breaking the law.

The law will be enforced from October 25 with fines ranging from $SU15-35 for a first offence, $US35-75 for a second infringement and $US75-99 if you're caught a third time.

Honolulu Police Department will implement a three-month training period where offenders will be let off with a warning before the law officially comes into effect.

In other parts of the world we've seen designated lanes for pedestrians with phones so they don't hold anyone up.

It's also becoming more common to see signage and warning lights on the pavement so texting pedestrians can see they are coming up to an intersection.

Telstra recently conducted a successful trial of its  where a warning signal can be sent from a vehicle to a mobile device used by a cyclist or pedestrian.

Related Posts

Check Also

It's time to tune in to Episode 309 of the Two Blokes Talking Tech podcast ...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honolulu Police Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HONOLULU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blokes Talking Tech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Episode 309 of the Two</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
