<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398578832515120</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/family-of-jamie-herdman-not-giving-up-hope-of-finding-him-after-daly-waters-disappearance/news-story/56780bc8452c683f2198760ee503eb7a</url>
  <title>Strange disappearance baffles family</title>
  <content>
IT'S been more than a decade since Jamie Herdman disappeared from Daly Waters, but his younger brother Carl has never given up hope of finding him.
Jamie, then 26, was living in Broome and working on a van which he wanted to drive around Australia.
In November 2006, Jamie left WA - driving a bizarre route to Daly Waters where he was last seen on November 26.
As Jamie was a keen fisherman, Carl said he would have expected his brother to travel along the WA coastline before settling in Darwin.
"For him to go through the middle, I don't know what the plan was," Carl said.
"He left Broome in a hurry - we think he was told someone was after him."
Jamie didn't tell anyone he was leaving Broome - not even the furniture removal company he worked for.
Carl said the Herdman family was reigniting calls for information to help find answers.
"At the start there was a lot of hope - a lot of reported sightings, as the years went on the sightings were coming fewer," Carl said.
"It just leaves a hole. You think about it all the time and wake up thinking it."
Carl described Jamie as a quiet man, with a passion for the outdoors and a great sense of adventure.
"He's quite a shy character, sticks to himself," Carl said.
"We just want answers."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daly Waters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2006</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Herdman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broome</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carl</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herdman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
