<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398312544539448</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/sa-racing/mount-gambier-racing-club-to-build-new-track-for-33m/news-story/7187196c790fe2d25ce66c959c707066</url>
  <title>New racetrack for Mount Gambier</title>
  <content>
THE Mount Gambier racetrack will be completely rebuilt under a $3.3 million redevelopment plan.
Funded by $1.5m from the Federal Government's Building Better Regions Fund and $1.8m from Thoroughbred Racing SA, the project will provide a new racing surface with improved drainage and irrigation.
"We are delighted that the Federal Government has recognised the importance of the racing industry to regional areas, in particular," TRSA chair Frances Nelson said.
TRSA chief operating officer Nick Redin joined Minister for Regional Development Senator Fiona Nash and Federal Member for Barker Tony Pasin MP in Mount Gambier on Monday to announce the redevelopment.
"This is very exciting news for the local community and thoroughbred racing in the South East," Redin said.
"The project will include removing the existing main track in its entirety and replacing it with a track that provides a better racing surface ... which should ultimately allow the club to extend its racing season each year."
Mount Gambier Racing Club chairman John Fartch also welcomed the announcement.
"We're very excited about this project because of the abilities it will give us to avoid the weather problems we've had in the past and allow us to extend our season," Fartch said.
"It's great news for the club and the community and we're extremely grateful to the Federal Government and TRSA for their support."
The new track has already been designed by Jeremy Clapp from FMG Engineering and is tender-ready.
"As soon as the tender process has been finalised, we expect the project will take about 12 months to complete," Redin said.
"The industry will now work with the club and local participants on the project's timing."
The Mount Gambier redevelopment will create the fourth new racetrack in SA since 2009, following track rebuilds at Morphettville, Gawler and Murray Bridge.
ben.scadden@news.com.au
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Gambier</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government's Building Better Regions Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barker Tony Pasin MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Gambier Racing Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FMG Engineering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRSA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Member</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fartch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Redin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thoroughbred Racing SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Development Senator Fiona Nash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gawler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frances Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Clapp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Fartch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphettville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
