<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398316839506788</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/life-of-kylie-jenners-alienating-vanity-series-20170728-gxl2sq.html</url>
  <title>Life of Kylie: Jenner's alienating vanity series</title>
  <content>
Life of Kylie
Monday, E!, 11am, 9.30pm
It's quite off-putting to see one of the richest teenagers in the world throwing herself a pity party at the start of her new vanity TV series - a series that will add yet another pile of cash to the $US41 million ($52 million) she reportedly earned last year.Photo: Rich Fury
No doubt the isolation of hyper-fame can be a bummer and the 19-year-old Kylie Jenner has already had to deal with that for a decade. But some ways of seeking sympathy work better than others. Jenner elects to begin by having an interviewer ask how she responds to people who think she has the perfect life. "Laugh," Jenner replies. "In their face."
The voice in which Jenner delivers this startlingly poor choice of words has a hardness and ingratitude to it that will immediately alienate most viewers. Well, most viewers apart from the millions who habitually tune in to watch Jenner and the rest of her family on Keeping Up with the Kardashians. For them it will presumably be confirmation that Jenner is indeed a saintly figure forced to martyr herself daily on the altar of Instagram in order to deliver us from the hell of not seeing selfies of her showing off new hats and wigs.
Still Jenner goes on: "When I know I can buy any car, any house, that happiness lasts two seconds." At least those cars provide a topic of conversation for someone conspicuously short of them - Jenner is soon prattling on about feeling guilty for leaving her Lamborghini in the garage all the time because she likes all her other cars better.
But the show's executive producers, Jenner's mum, Kris, and evil mastermind Ryan Seacrest, don't want her to look completely awful. They're arranging for her to accompany a dateless boy to his high-school prom. And it's here that - against all odds - sympathy for Jenner does start to sneak in.
She didn't get to go to her own prom because she had to leave school to focus on being famous. Her closest friends are one old school chum and three employees she clearly knows very little about. She can't take commercial flights because, as archive footage shows, her mere presence at an airport causes terrifying pandemonium.
All that said, there's no more reason to start watching this than there is to start whacking yourself between the eyes with a rubber mallet.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keeping Up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E!, 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenner</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kardashian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Seacrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Jenner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lamborghinis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US41</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
