<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398656141927544</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4822214/additional-security-at-newcastle-airport/?cs=305</url>
  <title>'Additional security' at Newcastle Airport</title>
  <content>
Increased security: Newcastle Airport has asked passengers to arrive early for their flights, after a series of arrests in Sydney on the weekend.

Passengers travelling from Newcastle Airport are being urged to arrive well ahead of time after arrests in Sydney in connection with an alleged terrorist plot.
A Newcastle Airport spokesperson posted a message to travellers on Facebook on Monday morning asking passengers to arrive early enough to allow for "additional security measures".

On Twitter, responding to a question about the possibility of increased wait times, an airport spokesperson wrote: "Yes, we have increased security measures in place".
"Passengers may experience slight delays at the screening point and should allow for this."
Newcastle Airport has been contacted for further comment.

Four people were arrested during a series of raids across Sydney on Saturday, after authorities received a tip-off about plans to allegedly blow up a passenger plane after it left Sydney Airport.

at Sydney Airport's domestic terminal on Monday morning.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Airport</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
