<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398656141927533</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/boss/book-review-the-man-who-knew-the-life-and-times-of-alan-greenspan-20170714-gxbkyl</url>
  <title>Alan Greenspan's surprising personal life</title>
  <content>
by
Aaron Patrick

Who would have thought? Alan Greenspan, one of the most consequential central bankers of the past half-century, was a serial dater.
Among financial crises, political intrigue and changing economic theory, Sebastian Mallaby reveals that the jazz-playing saxophonist from Upper Manhattan combined a vigorous love life with high government office.
The personal detail is one aspect of this weighty biography that makes it such an enjoyable and informative read.
The entire postwar development of the United States economy and economics profession is explored through Greenspan's career. The head of the US Federal Reserve from 1987 to 2006 collaborated with his biographer, although he didn't have a veto over the text, according to Mallaby.

The Man Who Knew is not a paean to Greenspan. It's a well-told insight into one of the most consequential, and partially self-taught, economists of our time. It's also an insight into how power works in Washington, from the Oval Office to the newsrooms of the city's publications.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mallaby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Greenspan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenspan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man Who Knew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Mallaby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Patrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
