<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398660436894889</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/former-chief-magistrate-supports-drug-decriminalisation/8759172</url>
  <title>Tasmania's former chief magistrate Michael Hill backs reform to end 'ineffective war on drugs'</title>
  <content>
A former Tasmanian chief magistrate has thrown his weight behind the call to decriminalise all illicit drug use in the state, saying the war on drugs is failing.
Community Legal Centres Tasmania today released a report calling for a health-focused response to drug use in Tasmania, with greater State Government investment in education and treatment.
The report cited Australian Crime Commission statistics that showed the number of drug seizures nationally had almost doubled over the decade to 2014-15 and drug convictions had risen by 70 per cent, while the cost of drugs fell.
Magistrates Court research in the report found the surge in drug use meant on average about 1,000 Tasmanians were charged with drug-related offences each year over the past decade.
In the report, economist Dr Paul Blacklow from the University of Tasmania estimated decriminalisation could lower the total cost of illicit drug use by about $28.13 million.
Tasmania's former chief magistrate Michael Hill said there were clear economic, health and social benefits of not condemning Tasmanians to the criminal justice system for personal drug use.
"The so-called war on drugs, by way of arresting and charging people across a lot of countries, has been found to be not as effective as people would want it to be," he said.
Mr Hill told ABC Radio Hobart the state's drug diversion scheme, which dealt with "hard-end offenders", was working but there was no mechanism for people who were "just starting to move into the drug area".

"It's been shown that perhaps a more therapeutic approach has a better chance of rehabilitation in that area, causing ... a decrease in the number of people who use drugs being involved in the criminal justice system, better health outcomes," he said.
Mr Hill said the majority of offenders possessed and used drugs in small amounts and were given fines or convictions.
"If you impose convictions on people, that can have an effect, obviously, for employment opportunities, for travel opportunities," he said.
'Continued failure is very expensive'

Former president of the Australian Drug Law Reform Foundation Dr Alex Wodak said Tasmania could adopt Portugal's model for decriminalised illicit drug use.
Taxing and regulating decriminalised illicit drugs was a growing movement across the globe, he said, leading to safer outcomes for the community.
In 2001, Portugal decriminalised the possession of small quantities of all drugs and refocused drug consumption as a public health, rather than a law enforcement, issue.
"Not only in Portugal, but in other places that have liberalised their drug policy, drug consumption and drug harm has not increased," Dr Wodak said.
"What we can do is not sell kilogram bags of 100 per cent bags of heroine and cocaine at supermarket checkouts, but what we can do is look for compromised options that are acceptable to drug users, acceptable to the community ... that's where I think we ought to head."
Dr Wodak was confident Australian policy would follow the global trend.
"There is definitely enough room for governments to start moving in that direction," he said.
"Any approach should be cautious, incremental and subject to rigorous evaluation ... but we need to start that process because continuing failure is very expensive."
A spokesman told the ABC the Government's "strong position" was that it did not support changing Tasmania's current illicit drug laws.
"We believe illicit drugs are a scourge that should be eradicated, not normalised," he said.
Mr Hill said it would "take courage" for any government to decriminalise illicit drug use but the benefits would far outweigh the costs.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Drug Law Reform Foundation Dr Alex Wodak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Wodak</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Crime Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legal Centres Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Paul Blacklow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
