<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398703386568372</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/lifestyle/top-tasmanian-talent-tastes-success-at-nestles-golden-chefs-hat-competition/news-story/f693c4a0f0fd76d7480c26589f222a46</url>
  <title>Top Tasmanian talent tastes success</title>
  <content>
TWO talented young Hobart chefs have out-cooked some of Tasmania's best apprentice chefs to cement their place in Australia's longest-running culinary competition.
Emily Hanson, 21, a pastry chef at Wrest Point Casino, and Sam Peart, 20, an apprentice chef at The Glass House, won the Tasmanian run-off in the Nestle Golden Chef's Hat Award at TasTAFE Drysdale Campus commercial kitchens.
The pair secured a trip to Sydney in September and will represent the state in the national final cook-off in front of a live audience. The national winners will be flown to Vietnam for an international culinary experience.
Ms Hanson, who won the competition for the second year running, was delighted all their hard work had paid off.
"We've been training hard, there were definitely a few nerves but things went fairly smoothly," Ms Hanson said.
"We will give the finals everything we've got."
Mr Peart said the competition was a great way to connect with other chefs at this level.
"I want to gain as much experience and knowledge as possible," he said.
The pair produced an award-winning menu that included a standout dessert, and main course of pan roasted lamb loin with fennel puree, braised Parisian potatoes, blistered carrot and pickled mushrooms.
Nestle Professional executive chef, Mark Clayton, said taking part made young chefs push themselves to the next level.
"Competing is vital to the professional development of young chefs, you learn so much from this type of experience," he said.
Emily and Sam's journey to the finals can be seen at facebook.com/goldenchefs
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Clayton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parisian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wrest Point Casino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Peart, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Peart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nestle Golden Chef's Hat Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasTAFE Drysdale Campus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glass House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Hanson, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nestle Professional</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
