<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397968947150936</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/stage/melbourne-stage/merciless-gods-review-challenging-stereotypes-with-brutality-and-tenderness-20170728-gxkm35.html</url>
  <title>Merciless Gods review: challenging stereotypes with brutality and tenderness</title>
  <content>
THEATRE
MERCILESS GODS 
★★★★
Little Ones Theatre
Northcote Town Hall, Until August 5

Queer theatre outfit Little Ones is a leading light on Melbourne's indie scene. Under director Stephen Nicolazzo, the company has developed a heightened, gender-bending, physically precise performance style. "Camp" might be too limiting a word to describe it. These artists thrive on the playful artifice and subversive humour associated with that aesthetic mode, but also expand its ambit through meticulous rigour and, more recently, the fullest kind of emotional palette.Photo: TS Publicity
In adapting Christos Tsiolkas' short story collection Merciless Gods, they break new theatrical ground. The show covers the gross and scope of Tsiolkas' fearless imagination and feels almost like a retrospective.
Its first vignette seems to spring from the same well as The Slap - five middle-class urbanites gather to smoke joints and play a parlour game; the stories of revenge that ensue rip off a veneer of politesse to reveal savage instincts underneath.Photo: TS Publicity
Masks continue to drop through a triptych of scenes, all of them challenging stereotypes of motherhood.
First, Jennifer Vuletic delivers a monologue in Italian and broken English - one that starts as an amusing "Nonna's guide to porn" and ends in a piteous portrait of a mother grieving her dead son. Brigid Gallacher follows with an offbeat soliloquy from a soccer mum, poised between love and loathing at the man her teenage boy is becoming, and bristling at the limits of her own role.

The third scene launches into a black and hilarious burlesque, in which a prim young Australian feminist (Gallacher) and her well-tamed partner (Paul Blenheim) lock horns in Berlin with the woman's mother (Vuletic) - a novelist, raging alcoholic and bohemian grotesque who violently upends every parenting piety.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Death provides dramatic impetus in the second act, though not as cogently. We wander through a maze of junkie rent boys (Blenheim and Charles Purcell), an ugly-pretty monologue from a vicious criminal (Peter Paltos), and a death-guide (Sapidah Kian) floating through scenes of bareback sex at a gay sauna.Photo: TS Publicity
Tsiolkas' brutality and tenderness are best embodied in a moving sequence where a dying father (Vuletic, in a brilliant gender-reversed performance) embraces suicide, his family present.
Kate Sfetkidis' lighting and Eugyeene Teh's excellent design (a tapered traverse stage, either shaft or wedge depending on where you imagine the void lies) both shape and sharpen the action.
Dan Giovannoni's script is talented and Nicolazzo directs charged performances with an earthier hue than usual. Neither flinch from the disgust and discomfort, nor the piercing of delusion, Tsiolkas demands. Though not for the squeamish or easily offended, Merciless Gods is compelling, confronting theatre.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Giovannoni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brigid Gallacher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolazzo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TS Publicity</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Ones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Purcell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eugyeene Teh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christos Tsiolkas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vuletic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nonna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Sfetkidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northcote Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Nicolazzo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sapidah Kian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallacher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Vuletic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Blenheim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ones Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BLENHEIM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tsiolkas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merciless Gods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Paltos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
