<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398617487221397</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/lauren-brant-on-how-her-relationship-with-barry-hall-changed-after-their-baby-was-born/news-story/ba195d6dd4995d78b1b03f9a018d67b6</url>
  <title>I looked at Barry and said 'I miss you'</title>
  <content>
Former Hi-5 star and new mum Lauren Brant writes for Kidspot about the moment she realised having a baby changed her relationship with AFL great Barry Hall forever.
Without a doubt, having a child and becoming a mum is hands down the most amazing thing I have ever experienced, however there are a lot of challenging and tough times.
Whenever someone asks me how I am finding motherhood, of course I say it's amazing and it's great, but I do face challenges and the truth is, it's not all rainbows and butterflies for me.
It hasn't been easy
Barry and I had our everyday habits and routine exactly how we wanted them with hot coffees, sit down meals, gym dates and a wind down conversation before a good nights sleep. Oh and of course, me smothering him on the couch.
Well becoming parents has changed all of that and more, and really, we couldn't have prepared for it. Was I supposed to start drinking iced coffee? Not sleep? Eat while exercising (like carrying a 5kg sandbag - cause that's like holding a baby) and wean myself off Barry?
I know these are changes that all parents experience and really we just adapt and deal with it, but one thing I am not willing to accept is a distance between Barry and I.
I looked at Barry and said 'I miss you' and he replied 'I miss you too.'
We were at breakfast the other morning and I looked at Barry and said: "I miss you. I see you every day, I sleep next to you every night, I kiss you and tell you I love you but ... I miss you." He looked back at me and said: "I feel exactly the same way."
So we decided it was time for our first 'date night.'
I was so excited, I put a status up on my Facebook asking my friends for their favourite restaurants, I picked out an outfit (it had sequins) and I took up my mothers ongoing offer to babysit.
Barry and I independently got ready like it was our first date. He groomed and brought out that special cologne and I wore my expensive lingerie and brushed my teeth three times. But, I did have to resort to dry shampoo (shh!).
I actually had butterflies in my stomach, almost like I was nervous for the date and giggled as I admitted it to Barry, who said he felt the same.
As we were about to drop Miller off, he decided to cry uncontrollably, we went through the whole checklist and nothing seemed to be wrong. I almost suggested that we try 'date night' another night, but luckily Miller settled right when it was time to leave, so we headed off to enjoy a dose of exactly what we needed - alone, adult time.
Reconnecting after a baby
What I found is that the night had layers. In the car, we recognised that we were deprived of each other, we discussed the fact that all our attention had moved from us to our son, that although we loved one another just as much - if not even more, we had not found the time to show it due to looking after bub and/or being tired.
We realised that individually, we had lost a little bit of ourselves in amongst the crazy eight weeks of negotiating life with a child and I think the biggest identification we made was that we were so concerned for how each other felt that it was dragging us down.
Discussing that out loud already reinstalled the connection we had been missing. So we pointed out a couple of things that could be changed to ensure we didn't feel that way again and that was the serious part of the night done and dusted.
We arrived at dinner, Barry opened all the doors for me and pulled out my chair. CUTE! We ordered a cocktail (which felt naughty for some reason) and began to reminisce about our first date. Well, let me just say - I got all hot for Barry!
I was looking at him thinking how handsome and strong he is, how I love his deep voice and his powerful presence ... OK I'll stop there ... but damn he looked and smelt so good.
Our 'over the table hand hold' and deep stare was interrupted by the waiter, who seriously must have thought we were on an actual first date - the way we were flirting with each other. It was so much fun and it didn't stop until we finished dessert.
Why date nights are so important
Then we starting talking about our son, Miller, and that we could not wait to get back home to him. We drove home with a full tummy, peace in our minds and love in our hearts and (oh no this is embarrassing) watched videos of Miller that we had recorded that day!
From feeling disconnected and overwhelmed - to full of butterflies and completely present, I have to say that, as parents, having 'date nights' is so important. Those few hours to ourselves has set us back on track as individuals, a couple and parents. So I guess all I can say now is, any more restaurant recommendations?

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miller</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidspot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Brant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hi-5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
