<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398535882841645</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/marilyns-toastmasters-success-already-speaks-volum/3206889/</url>
  <title>Marilyn's Toastmasters success already speaks volumes</title>
  <content>
THE Sunshine Coast's Marilyn Freeman doesn't need to talk herself up: she's a fine speaker.
She outshone contestants representing more than 180 local Toastmasters clubs to win the district-level competition of the Toastmasters International Speech Contest.
Marilyn now advances to the semi-final rounds of the contest, vying for one of 10 spots in the World Championship of Public Speaking to be held at the Toastmasters International Convention on Friday, August 25, in Vancouver, Canada.
Marilyn, a member of Mercury's Motivators (www.facebook.com/ mercurysmotivators) faced fierce competition to win over the judges with her speech, Life on the Run.
The speech touched on the stresses of today's world and how to stay sane. When it comes to connecting with an audience, she said, "The key is to be authentic and have a storyline that is both relatable and entertaining."
Marilyn will compete with 101 other winners from districts around the world who advanced to the 2017 semi-final round after a six-month process of elimination through club, area, division and district speech competitions. Their five- to seven-minute speeches were judged on content, organisation, gestures and style.
"Toastmasters speech contests are another way to build your confidence, sharpen your skills and speak to many different audiences," Marilyn said.
"I'm looking forward to challenging myself by competing in front of a much bigger audience in Vancouver."
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercury's Motivators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championship of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters International Convention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn's Toastmasters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters International Speech Contest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast's Marilyn Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vancouver</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
