<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398626077156079</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/cutest-cats-of-the-sunshine-coast-revealed/3206900/</url>
  <title>Cutest cats of the Sunshine Coast revealed</title>
  <content>
WE PUT the call out to our readers to find the Sunshine Coast's cutest cats.
Hundreds of kitties entered so we've selected our eight favourite felines on the Coast - but did yours make the cut?
Check out our office favourites below.
TOOTIE
Daily reader Chynnay Erin shared the story of her car Tootie.
"She was dumped in the bush near my old house six years ago," she said.
Chynnay started feeding the cat, who ended up moving into the house and eventually moving to a new house with Chynnay.
"She's been with us ever since," she said.
CASPER
Casper is one impressive cat. He can high five and comes when you whistle.
Owner Maria Coulter classified her kitty as "totally kissable"... and we agree.
"He is constantly meowing and talking to us," Ms Coulter said.
"He loves a cuddle and a snuggle as you can see."
NUGGET
Nugget is an adventurer. He's a little guardian to his owner Kristina Gorogh.
Nugget is strictly an indoor cat but Ms Gorogh said she makes sure that he gets time outside without impacting on the Coast's wildlife... responsible cat ownership has never looked cuter.
FRANKIE
Frankie's owner Jessie Bettega said her cat is a bit chunky and food obsessed - but frankly, Frankie, who isn't?
"He'll do anything for an extra biscuit or piece of meat," Ms Bettega said.
"I love him because he loves to have a chat when he sees you and likes to sit at the table when it's time for dinner."
MISO
Miso might look like your average cat, but this friendly feline has been a rock for owner Georgia Snow.
"Gotten me through some of the toughest times of my life with her unconditional love and warm cuddles," Ms Snow said.
"(She's) my whole world."
RUPERT
Any cat wearing a jumper is a good cat in our books.
Owner Jac Everett-Mars said Rupert was a special boy because he had a hyperactive disorder.
"We wouldn't have him any other way," Jac said.
SOCKET
Socket has not one but two families on the Sunshine Coast.
Owner Anita Humphreys said he spends time with two families that live a few streets apart.
"(He) spreads his love around with both his families," Antia said.
On top of spending time with his two families, Socket also visits the residents at Opal Aged Care in Kawana.
DWAINE
Dwaine is 85% blind but that doesn't stop him from living his best life.
"Dwaine was dumped and found at only a few days old," his owner Hannah Halstad told the Daily.
"He has so much love to give even though humans have given him a rough start to life.
"He puts a smile on my face everyday and has certainly rescued me as (much as) I have rescued him."
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DWAINE</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Snow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anita Humphreys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Coulter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chynnay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah Halstad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jac Everett-Mars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristina Gorogh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria Coulter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessie Bettega</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOOTIE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bettega</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUPERT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gorogh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opal Aged Care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Snow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chynnay Erin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CASPER</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
