<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397586695057208</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/legless-boozer-caught-getting-hiss/3206805/</url>
  <title>Legless boozer caught getting on the hiss</title>
  <content>
TERRITORY coppers deal with boozed up and irate customers every day on the beat.

But when two remote officers came across this legless boozer recently, they were sure to handle him with care,

The thirsty snake got itself stuck in a VB can and was unable to make its way back out.

Senior Aboriginal Police Officer Charles Pollard said the snake, thought to be a mulga, was in a foul mood when he and Sergeant Paul Wilson found it about 5km outside Ali Curung.

"He was alive and pretty aggro," he said.

With no wildlife services around, the officers tried to rescue the highly venomous snake themselves.

"We tried to get it off with a stick but we couldn't. We thought about killing it, but there was a family there so we said 'righto, we'll let youse deal with it'," he said.

"He was a good size; probably just under a metre."

Rex Neindorf from the Alice Springs Reptile Centre said it wasn't uncommon for snakes to get stuck in discarded tinnies.

"When someone discards a can, generally they contain sugar so an insect will go in there, followed by a skink or a gecko, then a snake can smell that trail from the gecko," he said.

"They go in there and when they try to get out, the can gets under their scales and they can't get out."

"You shouldn't leave cans lying around at all, but if you do see one in the bush and can't take it with you, you should at least squash them."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>VB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs Reptile Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal Police Officer Charles Pollard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Paul Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Neindorf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Curung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
