<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398312544539455</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/ricciardo-lashes-teammate-verstappen-after-crash-in-hungary/8758208</url>
  <title>Hungarian Grand Prix: Daniel Ricciardo lashes 'amateur' teammate Max Verstappen after crash</title>
  <content>
Australian Daniel Ricciardo has blasted Red Bull teammate Max Verstappen for "amateur" driving after the Dutch teenager shunted him out of the Hungarian Grand Prix on the opening lap.
Sebastian Vettel won a tense finish in a Ferrari one-two that stretched his championship lead to 14 points after Mercedes rival Lewis Hamilton sportingly surrendered third place to his teammate.
Ricciardo and Verstappen made good starts from sixth and fifth respectively, both jumping Hamilton on the first turn.
Ricciardo then passed his Dutch teammate into turn two to move into fourth before Verstappen hit him as they came through the next corner.
The incident did irreparable damage to Ricciardo's Red Bull, which went off the circuit and was spilling a lot of oil.

The incident sparked an angry reaction from Ricciardo over the team radio.
"Someone hit me. Is that who I think it was?" Ricciardo asked his race engineer.

"Yes," came the reply from Red Bull, and then Ricciardo did not mince his words.
"F***ing sore loser," Ricciardo exclaimed.
While the incident ended Ricciardo's race, 19-year-old Verstappen was given a 10-second penalty but still managed to finish the race in fifth as he barrelled down on the Mercedes of Hamilton at the death.
'It was an emotional response'

Ricciardo was left to fume some more when asked by reporters at the circuit about the collision between the two Red Bulls.
The Aussie said it was unrealistic for Verstappen to have tried to pass on turn two, labelling it "over-ambitious", "a very poor mistake" and a product of the Dutchman's "youth" and "immaturity".

"That was amateur to say the least," Ricciardo said.
"It's not like he was trying to pass. He doesn't like people passing him.
"I didn't really know what happened. It's just frustrating - it was not even an overtaking move.
"It was an emotional response."

Verstappen said he would be apologising to his teammate.
"It is never my intention to hit anyone, but especially not your teammate, and especially with the relationship I have with Daniel - it's always really good and we can always have a laugh," the 19-year-old said.
"This is not nice and I apologise to Daniel for that and also to the team because we could have scored some good points here. I'll speak with Daniel in private and we'll sort it out."
Given Verstappen's tale of woe in recent races, which has seen him retire five times this year, Ricciardo was asked if he felt his teammate might have an excuse for pushing so hard, but the Australian was having none of it.
Red Bull team principal Christian Horner said the drivers had spoken about this very issue shortly before the race.
"What happened shouldn't have happened," Horner said.
"We discussed it this morning and said 'right, golden rule number one is leave space for each other at turn one and turn two. Has everybody got that?'
"Everybody nodded, and then what happened?"
ABC with wires

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes of Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricciardo's Red Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Ricciardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Vettel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verstappen</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Verstappen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Horner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutchman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricciardo</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Daniel Ricciardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
