<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398488638200876</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/breaking-news/liberal-trio-push-for-vote-on-gay-marriage/news-story/6a4dec3c147005e1d035a255c37a2680</url>
  <title>Liberal trio push for vote on gay marriage</title>
  <content>
The Turnbull government is facing a looming revolt within its ranks over a free parliamentary vote on same-sex marriage.
A trio of gay Liberals want the issue dealt with to avoid handing Labor a political weapon through to the next federal election.
A week out from federal parliament returning from its long winter break, Brisbane MP Trevor Evans says he is in discussion with a number of his colleagues about different options to settle the issue.
"But I think the quickest and most likely course now is to allow politicians to have a free vote ... and I support that," he told The Australian on Monday
Colleague Tim Wilson argued Liberal MPs had discharged their responsibility to honour the party's election promise for a plebiscite and now could have a free vote.
"It's in our best interests to move on from this issue so we can focus on the sorts of things I think people voted for me and for my party to deal with - tax reform, fixing the budget, national security," he told Sky News.
"I also have a personal conflict which torments, frankly, and challenges me on a daily basis and I'd like to see this issue resolved."
Liberal senator Dean Smith says the issue is putting lead in the party's saddle bags.
"The government should not feel obligated to commit political suicide by handing its opponents a massive political cudgel by allowing the question of marriage equality to remain unresolved and fester over the next two years," he wrote in the Australian Financial Review.
He has a private bill legalising same-sex marriage that could be put to an upper house vote as soon as next week.
Some conservatives in the coalition argue allowing a free vote breaches a secret agreement between the Liberals and Nationals.
But Mr Wilson says he'd never seen that agreement and wasn't convinced those who argued that point had either.
"The right of a conscience vote is the right of every single federal Liberal parliamentarian and it's not something that can be traded away," he said.
Senator Smith said while some conservatives saw preventing marriage equality as a measure of political success, it would be "a temporary and pyrrhic victory".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane MP Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
