<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398716271470660</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:33</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/breaking-news/top-cop-to-brief-qld-cabinet-on-security/news-story/d6ced93440277b7bbce4eb0adf0a3d2d</url>
  <title>Top cop to brief Qld cabinet on security</title>
  <content>
Queensland's police commissioner will brief the state's cabinet about airport security after the weekend terrorism raids in Sydney.
Airports across Australia have beefed up security procedures after the raids, with travellers being asked to pack light and arrive early for their flights.
Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk said the revelations about an alleged plot to blow up a domestic flight were "very concerning".
She said police commissioner Ian Stewart would be discussing the issue with her cabinet on Monday - the first day of a week-long visit to the Gold Coast.
"Many people have been very concerned to hear the results of raids that have happened and the impact that could have caused to the travelling public," Ms Palaszczuk said.
"The police commissioner will be briefing my cabinet this morning about the security in relation to airports not just in the Gold Coast and Brisbane, but across Queensland."
Ms Palaszczuk said she remained confident in the "very strong" security measures for next year's Commonwealth Games but didn't rule out changes to plans depending on the information received at Monday's briefing.
Following typical long lines at Sydney and Melbourne airports during the Monday morning peak hour rush, some commuters were surprised to have passed through security quickly and not encountered any extra scrutiny.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
