<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398407033821104</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/aldis-hilarious-vegetarian-options/3206873/</url>
  <title>Aldi's hilarious 'vegetarian' options</title>
  <content>
AN ALDI customer has noticed something very bizarre about his local supermarket's vegetarian section.

The freezer shelves seem to be devoid of much variety, as they're packed solely with garlic products, The Sun reports.

the "vegetarian" section at my local aldi is literally just garlic bread and as a vegetarian i'm very happy and here for it

Journalist Joe took Twitter to share a photo of the stock, commenting: "The 'vegetarian' section at my local aldi is literally just garlic bread and as a vegetarian i'm very happy and here for it" (sic).

Since he uploaded the amusing snap yesterday, it's racked up more than 4,200 likes.

Dozens of people have also responded to the tweet.

Many have joked that it would be easy to give up meat if it meant eating the carby treat all day.

One Twitter remarked: "Always wondered what I'd eat if I was vegetarian, I could do this diet."

Another added: "I could totally be a veggie if it meant living off garlic bread."

Get urself down to Aldi garlic bread boy , they've got 3 fridges full

Joe isn't the only shopper to notice the abundance of garlicky products at the supermarket store.

One Twitter user posted a snap of THREE fridges packed full of flavoured bread.

Customers are completely spoiled for choice in this instance, as they can choose between pizzas, baguettes or traditional slices.

Aldi is responsible for a lot more than garlic bread mania.

The German chain lures people in with seasonal deals like these summer slip n' slides, and offering a complete school uniform for a fiver.

61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
