<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398750631209506</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/construction-starts-on-16-million-coast-retail-hub/3206922/</url>
  <title>Construction starts on $16 million Coast retail hub</title>
  <content>
COAST play centre owner Stacy MacKeller says the features of a $16 million development made moving from her current location a "no brainer".

Mrs MacKeller plans to have her Chipmunks Playland and Cafe out of Birtinya and into the new Central development at Sippy Downs by the start of December.

Developer Evans Long directors Matthew Evans and Dirk Long were at the Sippy Downs Dr site on Monday for the start of construction.

Mrs MacKeller said the facilities, location, increased size and parking access motivated to her to move her business.

"The current location just can't fit us," Mrs MacKeller said.

"We want to get in first so that everyone knows where we are and can visit from there."

Mr Evans said a 120-space car park at the retail and food hub would be linked with the neighbouring Coles supermarket car park.

It will feature Chipmunks, Dominos, Banjo's bakery, a Japanese food outlet and a boutique restaurant as well as a chemist and medical centre.

"We believe Sippy Downs has got to the level where it needs its own infrastructure," Mr Evans said.

He said University of the Sunshine Coast and Chancellor Park educational facilities as well as the currently-under-construction Youi international head office were examples of growth.

"We think it's about time we provided a little food precinct for the residents out here."

Construction is expected to be completed by the end of November.

Mr Evans expected there would be 16 or 17 tenancies within the hub.

"If you average 10 to 12 employees per tenancy you will probably create a fair bit of employment for the area."

Sunshine Coast Councillor Christian Dickson said Sippy Downs had changed in the past five years from a town centre that was not developing to a booming area.

"Now I'm getting complaints from people in the local area saying 'too much is happening, there is too much development'," Cr Dickson said.

"People are spoiled for choice and this is going to bring jobs to the local area."

He said the area needed more developments like Central.

"This is no longer the forgotten suburb.

"Everything is happening here and it is happening very quick."

He said he was really trying to sell the opportunities of the development.

"Families say they want jobs, on the other hand they say 'we are a bit worried about the development that's happening'.

"When we build these types of developments in an area that is approved... it gives people the opportunity to work in and have new experiences."

Coast man hospitalised after an argument turns violent
Businesses worry loss of parks could impact trading
Did your cat make the list?
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Councillor Christian Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs MacKeller</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chipmunks Playland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chancellor Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birtinya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stacy MacKeller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dirk Long</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Evans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans Long</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
