<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398235235127240</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-07-31/advice-on-farm-gate-business-hinterland-feijoas/8741156</url>
  <title>The pros and cons of farmgate tourism</title>
  <content>
It was a brave step when Sally Hookey and Peter Heineger bought four hectares of land with sweeping views at Belli Park on the Sunshine Coast hinterland and started farming feijoas.
Growing a fruit that few Australians had heard of, they built up an award-winning business that cuts out traditional markets by focusing on farmgate sales, value adding and food tourism.
The region's Food and Agribusiness Network organised a workshop at Hinterland Feijoas, so the couple could share information with people contemplating starting, or building, on existing farmgate businesses.

Sally Hookey discusses the pros and cons of farmgate business with the Sunshine Coast Food and Agribusiness Network.

Sally Hookey discusses the pros and cons of farmgate business with the Sunshine Coast Food and Agribusiness Network.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Planning crucial to success

"We most definitely learnt along the way," Ms Hookey told the crowd that gathered on a verandah with sweeping views towards the range.
"The house was derelict but we chose this land that we loved for its aspect, its water, and its proximity to tourist locations.

"The first trees we planted we lost half of them, so we learnt how to grow them differently and then we became certified organic."

For motorists, the farm is an easy day trip destination, just 15 minutes' drive inland from the popular market town of Eumundi.

'Myrtle' the caravan has been retrofitted as a licensed commercial kitchen.

'Myrtle' the caravan has been retrofitted as a licensed commercial kitchen.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Playing the long game

"Especially with a crop that wasn't known to the general markets we really had to bring people here to experience that and it's given us an all-year-round offering that we didn't have before," Ms Hookey said.
The farm had no cash flow for five years, until the newly planted trees matured and fruited.
The feijoa harvest only lasts for six weeks but the farm is open every Saturday between 9:00am and 3:00pm.

Homemade scones are on the menu as Hinterland Feijoas opens to visitors on Saturdays.

Homemade scones are on the menu as Hinterland Feijoas opens to visitors on Saturdays.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Customers provide instant feedback

"We've really had to build our brand and our market awareness of our product but also we've had to invest in a farm shop and a food van to give something to people all year round," Ms Hookey said.
"I have a food licence.

"The van saves me having to rent a commercial kitchen out but also means that we can prepare a wider range of foods on site and offer full light lunches and organic coffee, gourmet feijoa products and good quality foods," Ms Hookey said.

"I have a huge range from traditional, right through to vegan, gluten-free, paleo, everything.
"Amazing home-cooked scones, and I make a sausage roll using a local pork supplier.
"A lot of our customers are interested in health and we just listen to them and ask 'What do they want?'"

Hinterland Feijoas saved $100,000 to invest in retrofitting their commercial food van and building a farm shop.

Hinterland Feijoas saved $100,000 to invest in retrofitting their commercial food van and building a farm shop.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Policy of not borrowing from banks

Adding the farm shop and retrofitting 'Myrtle' the food van cost the couple $100,000 but they did it without approaching a bank.

"We don't borrow and I feel that that's a really important thing for farmers these days.

"I know it's hard but when you have a high-risk product like a crop I feel it's important not to borrow against it.
"Careful planning and hard work, they are the two basics."
Their farm was designed to be family friendly.

Sally Hookey says Emerald and Elzi, the miniature dairy goats, are popular with visitors.

Sally Hookey says Emerald and Elzi, the miniature dairy goats, are popular with visitors.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Have a point of difference

Miniature animal breeds are another attraction with dairy goats, Elzi and Emerald, and ponies Twinkle Toes and Smokey the Bandit.
The couple offered some sage advice: build a business with a point of difference, choose an accessible location, make sure you have good relations with your neighbours, think ahead, ensure you have planning approval, and protect yourself from the risk of litigation.
"It's very costly, at least $3,000 a year.

"We use an insurance broker. Every single time we change our product we ask them the question, what do we need to do?

Fresh feijoas are transformed into value-added products that can be sold year round.

Fresh feijoas are transformed into value-added products that can be sold year round.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Make sure you are insured

Ms Hookey said farmgate businesses needed to tell people what they can and cannot do on the property, making sure there was appropriate signage, and that steps were in good working order.
"The pros of farmgate tourism are that you can offer a year-round thing, which is unusual in a farming sense, and increase the diversity of your product range," she said.
"The cons are that you've got a year-round business so you don't have a down-time."
As the more reserved member of the relationship, Peter Heineger has had to learn how to respond to a barrage of questions from inquisitive visitors.

"People are at your home, in your house, so you have to be someone who is happy with that," Ms Hookey said.

Christine Ballinger and Peter Huddart are keen to learn how they can increase business at their herb and edible flower farm in Mapleton.

Christine Ballinger and Peter Huddart are keen to learn how they can increase business at their herb and edible flower farm in Mapleton.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Development applications a stumbling block

Christine Ballinger and Peter Huddart travelled from The Falls Farm at Mapleton to learn from the Hinterland Feijoas' experience.
"Currently we have extensive market gardens, herb gardens and edible flowers and we've planted our first orchard areas," Ms Ballinger said.
The couple has converted an old forestry shed into a farmgate business that operates from an honesty box during the week and stocks more produce, preserves, sauces and dips on Saturdays.

"Our long-term vision is to have a cooking school and potentially a restaurant," Ms Ballinger said.

"Very long term at the moment," Mr Huddart joked, adding there were many challenges ahead.
"Probably at the moment, getting an effective development application through with the council and also all our neighbours, we need to be able to work with them and hopefully they work with us in what we want to pursue," he said.
"Part of the dilemma is the planning scheme, which prescribes certain land use and we're obviously zoned rural and then you've got the economic development section of council, which are looking at ecotourism and agritourism.
"They don't necessarily meet and co-habit and that's an issue that needs to be addressed."

The feijoa harvest only runs for six weeks a year, but the farmgate business runs year round.

The feijoa harvest only runs for six weeks a year, but the farmgate business runs year round.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Know the law

Food and Agribusiness Network director and commercial and corporate lawyer Tony Sowden said planning considerations were the initial stumbling block for a lot of people considering a farmgate business.
"Particularly those who want to establish their business organically and let it grow and they presume a lot of things in relation to legal requirements.

"As the well known cliche applies, 'Ignorance of the law is no excuse'.

"It pays people to look into planning considerations before they turn a sod. Whether or not you have a view as to how fair or otherwise that is, the law is there to be applied and council's job is to apply it."

Smokey the Bandit and Twinkle Toes are Hinterland Feijoas' friendly miniature ponies.

Smokey the Bandit and Twinkle Toes are Hinterland Feijoas' friendly miniature ponies.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

But despite the potential hurdles Sally Hookey hopes the farmgate sector grows.
"It's very vital because if we can get a mass and become known as a food tourism destination in the hinterland, with a farmgate trail, then imagine the visitors that will come.
"You know they've got the beautiful beaches and then they've got this fantastic place to go to have food and wine and meet the farmers."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feijoas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mapleton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Huddart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falls Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twinkle Toes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Rural</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Nichols</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emerald</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elzi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ballinger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myrtle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Ballinger</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bandit</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smokey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hinterland Feijoas</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eumundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Huddart</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Heineger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Food</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hookey</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Sowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agribusiness Network</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belli Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Hookey</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
