<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398746336242101</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/raw-mcdonalds-beef-patty-forces-disgusted-mum-to-return-burgers-at-mcdonalds-ludmilla/news-story/5e1368afb6d66ff4f61093cca1792867</url>
  <title>Macca's burger hits raw nerve with customer</title>
  <content>
IT took one bite of Sherre Scheide's burger to realise something was wrong - but what she didn't expect to see was this.
The Karama woman took her children to a Darwin McDonald's store on a Sunday lunch treat, ordering Quarter Pounder meals for each of them.
"As I started biting into the burger, I though it didn't taste right, then I looked down and opened the patty and it was raw," she said.
"I took all the burgers back and the manager came racing around the corner and shook my hand and said she'd speak to the staff members."
Ms Scheide's meals were then replaced with chicken meals but she wasn't offered a refund.
"I didn't finish the chicken burgers because I was disgusted and feeling sick from the first burger," she said.
"I said to the manger that I'd like someone from head office to contact me.
"(When they did), they had a carefree attitude and she told me the meat had to only be checked once in a 24-hour period. I said I wasn't happy with the response and that I'd be taking it to the health and safety food inspectors and she just said 'do what you've got to do'."
Though Ms Scheide's yet to file the complaint, she's been turned off Maccas for good.
A company spokeswoman said McDonald's took food safety seriously and incidents such as these were rare.
"The restaurant confirmed the issue was isolated and did not affect any other products," she said. "We have also reinforced cooking procedures with this restaurant."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macca</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherre Scheide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Scheide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quarter Pounder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
