<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398742041274733</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/barnaby-joyces-water-woes-grow-with-joint-sa-call-for-action-20170730-gxly7w</url>
  <title>Joyce's water woes grow with joint SA call for action</title>
  <content>
Attempts by the federal government to defuse anger over alleged water theft have failed with South Australia's state and federal political parties uniting to demand a full judicial inquiry and for Barnaby Joyce to be stripped of the Water Resources portfolio.
A day after the government tried to shut down the issue by  of the Murray Darling Basin Agreement, SA's Labor Premier Jay Weatherill, federal Labor Senator Penny Wong, Australian Conservatives Senator Cory Bernardi, Greens Senator Sarah Hanson-Young and Nick Xenophon have appeared together to reject this emphatically and demand a inquiry with teeth.
In addition, federal and state Labor, the Greens and the Nick Xenophon Team said there can be no faith in the agreement while Mr Joyce remains Water Resources Minister.
The only party absent was the SA Liberal Party although its MPs, state and federal, are concerned at what is perceived to be a bungled response last week to the allegations by Mr Joyce.

"This is a important show of unity fro South Australia's Senators, standing up for our state and the river," said Senator Hanson-Young, in a joint press conference on Monday in Adelaide

"We need a judicial inquiry but we also need faith to be restored in the MDBA and that won't happen while Barnaby Joyce remains water minister," she said.
The issue flared on Monday last week when the ABC's Four Corners aired allegations of water theft by NSW cotton farmers and claims the NSW bureaucracy was helping undermine the agreement.
Mr Joyce played down the allegations, saying they were a localised matter akin to cattle rustling and an inquiry ordered by the NSW government would be adequate. on Wednesday night when he  to attack the objectivity of Four Corners and confirm that he had demanded Malcolm Turnbull give him the water portfolio to protect irrigators from "greenies".
In a bid to defuse the anger,  and announced a compliance audit to be carried out by the Murray Darling Basin Authority.

But this was immediately attacked as useless because the states had to agree to participate and it would have no powers to seize documents, compel witnesses or protect whistleblowers.
A joint statement released by all parties in SA on Monday said:
"We as South Australians stand together in solidarity for our River Murray and in support of the Murray-Darling Basin Plan."
"We call on Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull to commission a fully independent judicial inquiry into the allegations raised on Four Corners in order to be sure that the Basin Plan is not undermined and will continue to deliver our share of water to South Australia.

"A healthy River Murray is vital to South Australia's future. The Basin Plan will support the agriculture, business, jobs and residents who rely on the water flowing downstream to our state. The Basin Plan must be delivered on time and in full."
Senator Bernardi said it was not only SA under threat if the agreement was undermined but townships and irrigators further up the system.
He had with him NSW irrigator Rob McBride who is just as angry at the alleged theft and actions by the NSW government.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA's Labor Premier Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Joyce</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Senator Sarah Hanson-Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MDBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Senator Penny Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basin Plan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Resources Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Conservatives Senator Cory Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia's Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson-Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Corners</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob McBride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
