<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397930292444912</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/08/25/boy-survived-for-hours-by-treading-water-after-falling-off-yacht</url>
  <title>Boy survived for hours by treading water after falling off yacht</title>
  <content>
A teenage boy has spent a terrifying two hours treading water in choppy conditions without a life jacket off the Queensland coast after falling off his grandparents' yacht.
Paramedics are stunned by the 14-year-old's survival after his grandparents failed to notice he was missing.
He was saved two hours later, when someone on another boat spotted him in the water off Gladstone and pulled him to safety on Sunday afternoon.
The boy had swallowed a lot of water and been battered by waves as he fought to keep his head above water near the mouth of the Gladstone marina.
His grandparents only realised he was missing after returning to the marina, sparking a panicked call to authorities and an air search.
But before a rescue chopper could find him, the second boat spotted him, and those onboard pulled him to safety and got him back to shore, where paramedics treated him for nothing more than exposure to the cold.
"The boy was treading water for approximately two hours. The average person could tread water without much difficulty for about 30 minutes. For the boy, he was very, very lucky to survive," ambulance service spokesman Chris Pereira said. 

Related Articles

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Pereira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
