<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398703386568473</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/real-estate/queensland/new-house-sales-fall-over-29pc-as-industry-adapts-to-new-normal/news-story/36fb405da2a67811287f45cddaee52e7</url>
  <title>New house sales fall over 29pc as industry adapts to new normal - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
HIA believes Queensland's drop in new homes sale could just be "timing issues". Picture: Liam Kidston.

QUEENSLAND has logged a massive 29.3 per cent monthly fall in new house sales, as residential building eases off 2016's highs.
The Housing Industry Association recorded the fall for June over the May figures, though the result was also 24.1 per cent lower than a year earlier.
HIA senior economist Shane Garrett said Australia's largest states were at their lowest level since October 2013, with national June home sales numbers down 6.9 per cent over May (-11.9 per cent down on June 2016).
The Courier-Mail
Mr Garrett said the results supported HIA's forecasts that new dwelling commencements would continue easing until late 2018.
But he said the major states were coming off recent record peaks.
"The fall in sales needs to be considered against the backdrop of residential building coming off a record peak of activity in 2016. We project that residential building will still be operating at a historically high level," he said.
The HIA new home sales report said Queensland's June decline "could just be reflecting timing issues" given it was off "a similarly large increase in May".
The report said "the quarterly figures give a clearer picture" with the June quarter seeing detached house sales down 3 per cent over the March quarter, and having fallen 7 per cent over the same period in 2016.
*and
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Industry Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May (-11.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Garrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Garrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Kidston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
