<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398746336242128</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/halal-boss-taunts-australian-women-need-muslims-to-fertilise-them/news-story/3341182741745d4027eb9b8744579eee</url>
  <title>HALAL BOSS TAUNTS: AUSTRALIAN WOMEN NEED MUSLIMS TO "FERTILISE THEM"</title>
  <content>
The head of the Halal Certification Authority says he was just teasing "bigots" when he wrote that Australian women needed Muslim men to fertilise them to "keep them surrounded by Muslim babies", with fertility rates declining so fast that the "white race will be extinct" in 40 years. A  strange joke. More like an invitation to a fight.

THE head of the Halal Certification Authority says Australian women need Muslim men to fertilise them to "keep them surrounded by Muslim babies", declaring that the "white race will be extinct" in 40 years.
Mohamed Elmouelhy made the comments on Facebook in response to a study by researchers from the Hebrew University, published in the journal Human Reproduction Update, which  among men in North America, Europe, Australia and New Zealand.
"According to the Hebrew University, Australian men [sic] sperm count has declined by 52 per cent over the last 40 years so your men are a dying breed, Australian women need us to fertilise them and keep them surrounded by Muslim babies while beer swilling, cigarette smoking, drug injecting can only dream of what Muslim men are capable of," Mr Elmouelhy , which was first reported by The Daily Mail and has since been deleted.
"If the country is left to the bigots the white race will be extinct in another 40 years. Muslims have a duty to make your women happy because you are declining, better go chose [sic] a plot for yourself at your local cemetery. If you can't afford it, commit suicide it is a cheaper alternative for bigots."
In an email to news.com.au, Mr Elmouelhy said the post was intended to "stir the bigots" who had now descended on his Facebook page "using all manner of expletives and attacks possible including promises of physical attacks etc."...
He attached a longer version of the original Facebook post, which continued the theme. "It will [sic] mandatory for all women to wear hijab or burka if they prefer, bikinis will be displayed in Museums but not on nubile bodies anymore," he wrote.
"When that happens everything in Australia will be Halal certified. Bigots and pigs will be declared Haram and must not be approached or touched, they can live together in reserves. There will be a Halal butcher on every corner, all other butchers will be offered to convert to Halal or given [sic] a passage back to where their ancestors came from."
One more reason for a reform of halal certification so that the process is run by government, with the funds not going to people likeMohamed Elmouelhy and his pet causes.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRALIAN WOMEN NEED MUSLIMS TO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halal Certification Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Reproduction Update</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Elmouelhy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Elmouelhy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>likeMohamed Elmouelhy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HALAL BOSS TAUNTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hebrew University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
