<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398742041274755</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/at-work/i-need-more-worklife-balance-and-other-boasts-you-should-keep-to-yourself/news-story/5854afeae670301d45f64ccb1a0f0d33</url>
  <title>'I need more work-life balance!' And other boasts you should keep to yourself</title>
  <content>
Five tips to achieving a work-life balance
1:41

Sometimes it can be hard to juggle your career and your personal life...here are five tips to help find that balance.

July 27th 2017
4 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Lifestyle - syndicated/

Don't complain that you're overworked. It might upset people.

Jason Murphy

Share

DO YOU ever complain about work-life balance? Wish you had a bit less time at work and a bit more time at home?
Warning: That could be seen as a boast. A bit like complaining your Ferrari goes too fast so you're always getting speeding tickets.
For more and more Australians, too much time at work is not the problem. The big problem is not enough time at work.: Underemployment in Australia is on an absolute surge.

Maybe we need to redefine the term work-life balance for our new reality. It normally refers to reducing the amount of work to a manageable level. But balance should go both ways. If you have too much life in your week and not enough work to fund it, you also have a problem.
The reality is we've already done a lot to curb the most outrageous working hours. If you're standing round at a party, and someone's telling you about their 80-hour weeks, chances are they are just trying to impress you.
The average number of hours Aussies work is falling. The 40 hour week is becoming and endangered species - it is now a reality for less than half of workers, while shorter weeks are becoming more common.

THE PROBLEM OF UNDEREMPLOYMENT: WAGES
Underemployment is a sneaky problem. Official statistics count people as employed if they work one hour a week. For a long time unemployment and underemployment moved in parallel, but recently, underemployment has shot up as unemployment has shrunk.
It means the unemployment rate, which is a decent sounding 5.6 per cent, is not the best guide to what's really going on. The average part time worker - who is counted as employed - wants another 14 hours of work a week.

That is a big part of why wages growth has been so weak in Australia recently. Underemployed represent a big source of untapped potential and the economy will need to add a lot of full-time jobs before it has soaked up all the people willing to work in them.
WHO'S GETTING THE HOURS?
The spread of hours in the Australian economy is not equal. Underemployment is a double whammy, because it is highest in the jobs and industries that tend to pay worse.
As the following graph shows, people in mining are highly unlikely to be looking for more hours. The finance and insurance sectors are much the same. But in retail, hotels, motels and cafes, underemployment is rife.

A similar pattern applies by job type. Managers and tradies are mostly getting all the hours they want, but some of their underlings seem to be scraping to get enough shifts.

So be careful when you're boasting about your demanding schedule. If you're so busy you can barely scratch yourself, maybe try talking about the weather instead? And that goes especially if you're talking to women - underemployment is a bigger problem for females than males.

It seems like Australia has plenty of jobs, but not enough hours. Instead of jobs and growth, maybe the new political slogan should be about growing some of the jobs?
Jason Murphy is an economist. He publishes the blog . </content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>S GETTING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Murphy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROBLEM OF UNDEREMPLOYMENT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Lifestyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
