<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398187990486275</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/opinion/columnists/donald-trump-a-white-house-disaster-i-underestimated-20170728-gxl8n0</url>
  <title>Donald Trump: a disaster I underestimated</title>
  <content>
Four days before Donald Trump was sworn in as President in January, I sent an internal email to editors suggesting that we must be "open-minded", "giving him a chance to govern" and not fall into the trap of most media by defaulting to "anti-Trump" coverage.
After all, 63 million Americans had voted for Trump to be the leader of the free world and he had nominated serious people to his cabinet.
A paralysed Washington certainly needed a shake-up. Just maybe, I thought, it was possible a rampaging  to smash through.
Six months in to the great Trump experiment, it is patently obvious I was sadly misguided.

John Kehoe

Trump is shaping up as a disaster, worse than I imagined. He is sending a disturbing signal to uneasy allies and partners around the world.

Thriving on chaos

The disrupter-in-chief is incapable of governing effectively. The almost-daily dysfunction is largely self-inflicted.
Trump thrives on chaos, like the vitriolic  that spilled over into the public last week.
In a soap opera resembling House of Cards, in just six months the former reality television star has lost his chief of staff, national security adviser, deputy national security adviser, communications director, press secretary and Federal Bureau of Investigation chief. Others will exit too.

The appointment of General John Kelly to replace Priebus as chief of staff is intended to install military discipline and end factional staff wars in the West Wing. Yet the chief instability instigator is the President himself, who appears incapable of steady leadership.
Trump has no understanding of policy. He is all about symbolic wins to con his most loyal supporters. They love his defiant antagonism. The 35-40 per cent of Americans who approve of his performance will not abandon him, no matter what.
Contempt for rule of law

Trump's misguided philosophy on trade, immigration and climate change are not necessarily the biggest concern. Rather it is the unhinged behaviour of a man who controls the most powerful institution in the world.

An authoritarian, he has contempt for the rule of law and due process, as evidenced by his Twitter abuse of Attorney-General Jeff Sessions, desire to sack special counsel on Russia, Robert Mueller, and firing of FBI director James Comey.
The  crossed a red line.
The President has repeatedly undermined intelligence agencies, attacked independent courts and demonised the free press. He has repeatedly told mistruths and channelled falsehoods.
America needs brave patriots to resist the President's abuses of power. The constitution's separation of powers between the executive, legislature and judiciary faces a stress test.

Republicans must stand firm. There are encouraging signs conservatives are drawing a line in the sand. Republicans scolded Trump on his bullying of Sessions and moved to legislate protections for Mueller. They thumbed their nose at the President by passing tougher .
Party elder John McCain and two other Republican senators blocked the unwinding of Obamacare, in hope that a bipartisan healthcare fix can emerge.
The egocentric President last week had the gall to declare himself the country's second-most presidential leader behind the great Abraham Lincoln. That is an insult to Ronald Reagan, Franklin D. Roosevelt and George Washington, to name just a few.
Some good ideas, but unlikely to achieve much

Not everything Trump does is a disaster.
His tax overhaul goal has the potential to boost the economy. But all the signs suggest he will only achieve modest tax cuts - not real reform of the special interests' system - that simply add to the country's debt and deficit.
Long overdue infrastructure investment would be helpful. But Trump will rely on Democratic support, given Republican resistance to the government spending more. He seems incapable of negotiating effectively with Congress, as the healthcare failure showed.
His planned energy boom by creating more conducive conditions for oil and gas is a decent idea, even if the "revolution" he talks of is exaggerated.
Trump's call for NATO members to meet their defence spending obligations is appropriate.
Yet governing is only going to get harder. A showdown over the country's $US20 trillion debt ceiling looms in late September.
As the November 2018 midterm elections approach, worried Republicans will grow more wary of their unpredictable leader.
Hewing back to the base

To survive, Trump will resort to more desperate base politics to keep his hardcore supporters engaged, in order to discourage congressional Republicans from ditching him.
Quitting the Trans-Pacific Partnership, abandoning the Paris climate change agreement, blocking the entry of citizens from six Muslim-majority nations, impulsively banning transgender people from the military, are only an entree of what is to come.
Trump is yet to face an international crisis. When he inevitably does over the next four or eight years, the world will hold its collective breath.
North Korea's  on the weekend is a case in point. An inevitable clash with China over North Korea and trade also looms.
Australia's political class can no longer delude itself that the "adults" at the Cabinet table will restrain Trump.
Defence Secretary James Mattis and Secretary of State Rex Tillerson are honourable men. But their influence is limited. Even if they have private misgivings about the President, the world would be better served if they remain in the Trump administration to try to temper the President's worst impulses.
When Trump withdrew from the Paris accord in June, he declared foreign countries and leaders won't be "laughing at us anymore".
The world is not only laughing at you Mr President, it is shaking with trepidation.

Under  Trump, America has become one of the most disruptive forces in the world.
John Kehoe is US correspondent for The Australian Financial Review in Washington

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin D. Roosevelt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trans-Pacific Partnership</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Cards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McCain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Bureau of Investigation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronald Reagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abraham Lincoln</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defense Secretary James Mattis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General Jeff Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obamacare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kehoe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim-majority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
