<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397852983032821</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/national/terrorist-cell-planned-gas-attack-police/news-story/bddd24181e12304dcf4ab78d95a85acf</url>
  <title>Terror cell</title>
  <content>
Police foil plot to 'bring down plane': PM

A FAMILY of suspected Islamist -extremists allegedly plotted to bring down an Australian commercial jet by gassing the passengers, in what authorities believe was a major terrorist attack plan orchestrated by Islamic State milit-ants from within Syria.

Travellers were warned last night to expect major delays at the nation's airports as authorities rolled out extra security measures to counter what sources said was a fast-moving, still unfolding terror conspiracy,

Four Lebanese Australians - two fathers and two sons - were in custody after police swooped on the cell and thwarted what they will allege was a sophisticated -attempt to kill hundreds of people by crashing a civilian plane.

The Australian has been told the men were allegedly constructing a "non-traditional'' device, one that would kill the occupants of the plane with poisonous gas.

Multiple sources have told The Australian the four, who were -related by blood and marriage, were constructing an explosive -device that could have emitted a toxic, sulphur-based gas that would have killed or immobilised everyone on the aircraft.

Read

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebanese-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
