<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398784990948228</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/much-of-queensland-headed-for-hottest-july-on-record-20170731-gxm256.html</url>
  <title>Much of Queensland headed for hottest July on record</title>
  <content>
Much of Queensland looks to be headed for its hottest July on record after a warm, dry month without much cold air blowing up from the south.
Provisional figures from the Bureau of Meteorology show a "large swathe" of the state, particularly the top half, likely to break average maximum temperature records for the month.Photo: Michelle Smith
The final results would not confirmed until later this week, as the bureau waited for temperatures to top out on Monday and then its climate department checked them all to confirm the results.
BoM meteorologist Adam Blazak said it was too early to confidently predict which exact centres would break records but a "large swathe" of the state, including most of central and north Queensland, looked likely to set records.
A record-breaking month appeared less likely in south-east Queensland, with Brisbane on track to miss out on breaking its average maximum for July by just 0.3 degrees.
As of Monday, the city weather station's average temperature for the month was sitting at 22.7 degrees, still well above the historical average of 21.8 degrees but just below the record.

BoM forecaster Harry Clark said there had been a lack of "penetration" of cold air from the south.
"We haven't really had any major cold blasts," he said.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"We did have that one, if you remember, a few weeks ago that led to those cool daytime temperatures and that was quite windy but besides that we haven't really seen much cold air in Queensland and given that it's also been really dry, which allowed the temperatures overnight to cool off quite quickly but also during the day to warm up quite quickly.
"I guess you can attribute that to a persistent ridge that's really been sitting over southern Australia for quite a while now."
Brisbane was headed for a top of 26 degrees on Monday, with the coasts a degree cooler and 27 degrees expected in Ipswich.
Mr Blazak said August was also expected to be hotter than usual.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Blazak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Blazak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-0.25</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
