<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398802170817649</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:53</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/07/31/bowling-ladies-get-down-beyonce-video-save-beloved-melbourne-club</url>
  <title>Bowling ladies get down to Beyonce in video to save beloved Melbourne club</title>
  <content>
Terry Foster, 82, Janine Hall, 82, and Wyn Hewett, 72 love their club so much they have posted a video parodying Beyonce's 'Single Ladies' which has gone viral.

By

10 MINS AGO 

Members of the Chadstone Bowls Club in Melbourne's southeast have released a parody version of Beyonce's 'All the single ladies' in a bid to save their beloved club. 

The video, featuring choreographed moves and their own take on the world-famous lyrics, was uploaded to . 

It has since had over 500,000 views. 

The three stars of the video, Terry Foster, 82, Janine Hall, 82, and Wyn Hewett, 72 sing "All the bowling ladies, all the bowling ladies..."

"We love our club, we've had enough, we want to keep fit and this is it, please don't take it from me."

The club is at risk of redevelopment, with the local council announcing it is the preferred site for a new sports stadium.

 

Hoping Stoninngton council will back down on plans to bulldoze the club, which is 59-years-old and has over 600 members, a  petition has also been created. 

So far it's collected over 3000 online signatures. 

While Melbourne's Lord Mayor, Robert Doyle has tweeted his support for the club, calling it a cause he "can get behind." 

And he's not the only one.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoninngton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Single Ladies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janine Hall, 82</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyn Hewett, 72</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Foster, 82</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadstone Bowls Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
