<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398784990948233</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/rabaul-queen-case-court-dismisses-manslaughter-charges/8759398</url>
  <title>Rabaul Queen trial: Court dismisses manslaughter charges against Australian ferry owner</title>
  <content>
A court in Papua New Guinea has dismissed manslaughter charges against the Australian owner of a ferry which capsized in 2012, killing at least 140 people.
.
The ship's owner, captain Peter Sharp, had pleaded not guilty to 172 charges of manslaughter, although .
PNG's National Court accepted a no case submission from Sharp's lawyers, who said the State had failed to prove there was any risk associated with the normal use of the ship.
It also dismissed manslaughter charges against the ship's master Anthony Tsiau, who was in command of the vessel when it sank.
Lawyers for Sharp and Tsiau had told the court there was no overcrowding on the ship and that evidence of negligence had not been confirmed.
Sharp, Tsiau and some other staff still face charges for sending an unseaworthy vessel out to sea.
A Commission of Inquiry set up after the disaster could not determine the exact number of fatalities, because the crew did not compile a manifest.
However, lawyers for Sharp produced a manifest during the trial which led to the number of manslaughter charges against him being reduced.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tsiau</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG's National Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Sharp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabaul Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commission of Inquiry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Tsiau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
