<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398789285915608</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/swoop/rob-wright-stands-down-as-swifts-coach-in-super-netball/news-story/a7f9e074e4d12e670e9904148050a0b5</url>
  <title>Wright stands down as Swifts netball coach</title>
  <content>
HE believes the Swifts are destined for great things in Super Netball but one of netball's most successful male coaches won't be around to see it happen.
The club is now on the hunt for a new coach with Rob Wright standing down from the role.
Wright says his decision is for personal reason but he will continue as the assistant coach of the Australian Fast5 team contest the World Series in October.

Wright's grand plan for the Swifts was to rebuild the club from scratch in the first year of Super Netball by sourcing new young talent and then building from within to make the club a championship contender within two to three years.
The new coach of the Swifts will inherit players chosen by Wright for this purpose with the Swifts roster for 2018 already confirmed.
Wright was one of two male coaches in the 2017 Super Netball competition with Adelaide's Dan Ryan.
He was the first male coach in the now defunct trans-Tasman league and coached the Swifts in 61 matches across that league as Super Netball, winning 34, losing 22 and drawing five for a win percentage of 56%.

He also lead the Swifts to the 2014 playoffs and then back-to-back Grand Finals in the 2015 and 2016 trans-Tasman competition.
"This has not been an easy decision to make but I feel now is the right time for me to take some time out and I will continue to focus on individual athlete coaching and development,'' Wright said in a statement.
"Both the Club and Netball NSW have been very understanding in this matter and I remain steadfast in the belief that this current crop of players we have at the Swifts are destined for great things.
"The club's 2020 vision remains very much intact and having seen such wonderful potential on display this season I feel confident I am leaving the club in a very strong and settled position.
"This is very much a personal decision.''
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netball NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Fast5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swift</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Netball</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's Dan Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
