<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398759221144149</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/bull-impresses-at-under-23-world-championships/3206917/</url>
  <title>Bull impresses at under-23 world championships</title>
  <content>
CANOE: Alyssa Bull is primed for a strong performance at the world championships in the Czech Republic later this month after capturing medals in the under-23 edition in Romania.
The 21-year-old claimed gold (K1 1000) and silver (K1 500) in Romania to confirm her status as one of the rising stars in the sport.
But her focus is still on the K2 and her partnership with fellow Sunshine Coaster Alyce Burnett.
The pair shocked many to reach the final at the Rip Olympics last year.
"I do love the K2. I hate going out there by myself, I'm more of a teamwork person," she said.
"I do miss having AB behind me pushing me down the course, but it is nice to know every now and then you can get out and do it by yourself.
"This year's focus at worlds is the K2 500 and I think it is going to be that way for this four-year cycle. I'm really looking forward to it."
A former ironwoman, Bull won a round of the elite summer surf lifesaving series as a teenager in 2013 but switched to kayaking a couple of seasons later.
The move paid off as she rapidly climbed the rungs of the sport, mainly alongside Burnett.
She's still improving as an individual competitor too and her performances in the junior world titles have provided her with a morale boost ahead of the world championships proper.
"It's pretty cool to be able to go back to your age group and have a race, but I miss doing it with my buddy AB," she said.
"Sometimes it's nice to be able to put a good race together in the K1, it makes you a little bit more confident and excited to do it in the front of the K2 as well."
Another Coaster, Bill Bain, finished eighth in the men's under-23 K1 1000 final.
Coast man hospitalised after an argument turns violent
Businesses worry loss of parks could impact trading
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Czech Republic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K2</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alyssa Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K1 1000</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coaster Alyce Burnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rip Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K2 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K1 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Bain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulls</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
