<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398703386568424</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/markets/deeply-troubling--sirtex-faces-class-action-20170731-gxm1m6.html</url>
  <title>'Deeply troubling' - Sirtex faces class action</title>
  <content>
Biotech company Sirtex Medical faces a shareholder class action over the events surrounding the controversial departure of its chief executive.
Maurice Blackburn and litigation funder IMF Bentham announced the class action on Monday morning and called for shareholders to participate.Photo: Michael Amendolia
Just before Christmas Sirtex announced a trading update where it revealed slower than anticipated sales triggering a 37 per cent drop in the company's share price.
A week later the company announced it was investigating trades earlier in the year by chief executive Gilman Wong. That triggered a 9 per cent price drop as Mr Wong stood aside pending the outcome of the probe.

"Mr Wong sold 74,968 Sirtex shares in October 2016, and following the investigation, Sirtex terminated his employment," an IMF statement to the ASX said.
The Maurice Blackburn class action will allege that engaged in misleading or deceptive conduct and potentially breached its continuous disclosure obligations.

It is the second action against
Maurice Blackburn national head of class actions Andrew Watson said the events were "deeply troubling".
"We've investigated this potential matter for some time now, and it appears the company has serious questions to answer about its conduct and that of the then chief executive," Mr Watson said.
"When a chief executive dumps more than $2 million worth of stock shortly before the company releases a surprise announcement of a severe decline in earnings and sales growth, and investors then suffer a 37 per cent share price dive off the back of that, it immediately rings alarm bells about compliance with continuous disclosure laws."
Wayne Attrill, senior investment manager at litigation funder IMF Bentham, said the case warranted "serious scrutiny"
Shareholders that purchased Sirtex shares between 24 August to 19 December 2016 may be eligible to participate in the action.
More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas Sirtex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirtex</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilman Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMF Bentham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirtex Medical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Attrill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maurice Blackburn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Amendolia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
