<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398484343233521</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/nrl/melbourne-storm/storm-skipper-cameron-smith-became-just-the-third-player-in-nrl-history-to-reach-350-games/news-story/400eadf9b74dabe800e4a3d1bc8b2541</url>
  <title>Storm skipper Cameron Smith became just the third player in NRL history to reach 350 games</title>
  <content>
Smith wants to play 400
2:14

NRL: After playing his 350th game, Cameron Smith thinks he can play hrough to 400.

July 30th 2017
14 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/NRL News/

Cameron Smith high-fives Hawthorn's Shaun Burgoyne as he forms part of the Auskick Guard of Honour. Pic: Michael Klein

GILBERT GARDINER

Share

CAMERON Smith almost got away with being an Auskick dad at the MCG less than 48 hours before playing his 350th NRL game.
Complete with fluoro jacket the record-conquering Melbourne Storm captain looked just like any other parent watching their sons and daughters create memories on the hallowed turf.
But Smith, 34, was not afforded the same stealth treatment at AAMI Park on Sunday.
"I was doing my very best to keep a low profile there at that game but that didn't work," Smith said.
"I even tried to sneak an Auskick jumper on and look like an official but they (TV cameras) still found me.
"I think I was more excited than my young bloke (Jasper) actually, and all his mates together, just to get out on the 'G again.
"We gave some high fives to the Hawkies boys when they ran out for the third quarter but I think today may have just topped that a little bit."
MATCH REPORT:

Cameron Smith high fives Hawthorn's Shaun Burgoyne as he forms part of the Auskick Guard of Honour. Pic: Michael KleinSource:News Corp Australia
The proud Queenslander, who has called Melbourne home for the best part of two decades, was the toast of the purple nation - and rightfully so.

Smith has earned every accolade and backslapping he has received over the journey.
An inspirational leader and teammate at Storm, Queensland and Australia, Smith became just the third player in NRL history to reach the 350-game milestone, joining Terry Lamb (350) and Darren Lockyer (355).
Before Smith the legend took centre stage, Smith the father and son got to savour a moment with family.
A kiss for mum, Sonia, and handshake for dad, Wayne, was followed by hugs and kisses for children Jasper, Jada and Matilda, before the quartet marched through the banner which read: 350 Inspirational Games Simply The Best.
No truer words could be spoken about the boy from Logan, Queensland, who signed with Melbourne as a 17-year-old in search of one NRL game.
"I just took a moment there, just before kick-off, just to have a look around and soak up the atmosphere," Smith said.
"It's hard, it's really hard to take in the whole week and the milestone of 350 games because my job is to go out and play well today and get my job done for my teammates and the coaches.
"It was nice that we ended up putting in a pretty good performance and getting a strong win against quality opposition.

Cameron Smith in action for the Storm.Source:AAP
"It's been a fantastic week but I'll celebrate the 350 and the victory tonight and it's back to business as usual tomorrow."
The pectoral injury which threatened to delay the magical milestone only reared its head momentarily during the warm-up, not that it bothered Smith any for the next 80 minutes of blistering play.
He cut one way and weaved the other making a mockery of players with far less miles in the legs.
The only thing better than Smith's master class on Sunday was young Jasper Smith and Jake Slater, son of Billy, flicking the Steeden around stylishly next to the try line about 50m away from the post-game celebrations and presentations.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Klein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GILBERT GARDINER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Lamb (350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Lockyer (355</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jasper Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn's Shaun Burgoyne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auskick Guard of Honour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storm.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspirational Games Simply</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael KleinSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steeden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jasper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auskick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
