<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398797875850293</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/120-a-week-and-we-are-just-sitting-there-time-for-toll-road-charge-overhaul-say-experts-20170725-gxig28.html</url>
  <title>$120 a week and 'we are just sitting there': time for toll road charge overhaul, say experts</title>
  <content>
For people like Jason Cook, the daily commute from NSW's Central Coast to Sydney quickly eats into their time and hip pockets.
Driving his ute to building sites in Sydney's inner south where he has been working lately is about $70 a week in tolls, once he passes electronic gates for the M2 in the city's north, the Lane Cove Tunnel and the Harbour Tunnel.

Up Next

Jeremy Strode: The chef's chef

03:01

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Beaches Link smokestack locations revealed

Sites close to schools, parks and homes have been proposed for the smokestacks for the planned Western Harbour Tunnel and Beaches Link.

It can escalate further if Cook, who installs sprinkler systems, is working in Sydney's outer west. "It would be up to $120 a week for me, especially if I go out west. It is expensive," he says.
Unfortunately, paying tolls doesn't always mean a quick journey. Traffic can "back up massively" on the Harbour Tunnel at peak hours, Cook says, and "we are just sitting there".Photo: Janie Barrett
Stretching for 135 kilometres, the labyrinth of toll roads in Sydney makes up one of the largest user-pays road networks in the world.
That is before a nine-kilometre NorthConnex tunnel linking the M1 and the M2 in Sydney's north opens in 2019, and the more controversial 33-kilometre WestConnex toll road - to be Australia's largest - is completed in stages by 2023.

Now, the state government has advanced plans for more: a , and a 14-kilometre tollway from the inner west to the northern beaches known as the

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

have revealed the government is looking at slapping $3 tolls for cars on northbound journeys of the Sydney Harbour Bridge and Harbour Tunnel to help cross-subsidise the $14 billion cost of building a Western Harbour Tunnel and Beaches Link.Photo: Peter Rae
"What they are saying is that everyone coming from the north shore has to pay more of a toll so the good burghers of the northern beaches get into town quicker," says the City of Sydney's chief transport adviser, Terry Lee-Williams. 
"There aren't enough people on the northern beaches to justify such an expensive tunnel. [The government has] already admitted it doesn't stack up financially because you have to toll other people to fund it."Photo: Nick Moir
Donning a hard hat and safety vest as she showcased a  this week, Premier Gladys Berejiklian batted off questions about whether extra tolls should be placed on the Harbour Bridge and Tunnel to help fund the new road projects. "I'm not going to enter a conversation that we have not yet had within government," she remarked.
'We are all tolled out'

The pressures on Sydney's road and public transport networks are huge - and growing. An extra million people are forecast to call the city home within the next decade.
Berejiklian has a difficult balancing act in appeasing residents in Sydney's south and the blue-ribbon north, as well as those within her own party who want priority to be given to projects in or near their electorates. Weeks before several byelections in northern Sydney in April, she declared her government was  to building the long-promised link to the northern beaches.
Federal Liberal MP for Mackellar Jason Falinski says the Beaches Link is "absolutely necessary".
"All the records show that the three of the 10 worst-congested roads are either on the northern beaches or feed to the northern beaches," says Falinski, a former staffer to NSW Transport Minister Andrew Constance.
In Sydney's south, the likes of the Liberal MP for Cronulla and state's Attorney-General, Mark Speakman, believe work needs to start on extending the F6 "sooner rather than later" because of worsening congestion. In fact, it has been a high priority for him since he declared in his inaugural speech to Parliament in 2011 that he  would "fight for the F6 extension".
Irrespective of which toll road is given priority, Sydney motorists are already in danger of reaching "toll saturation" - a point where they are unwilling to spend more on tolls no matter how much time travelling they can save, warns David Hensher, the director of the Institute of Transport and Logistics Studies at Sydney University. 
While helpful in prodding motorists into paying directly to use roads, Hensher recently told a state inquiry into Sydney's toll roads that the benefits are not always evident because "we basically have congestion across the whole network".
"What that tells me is we have got the toll wrong," he said.
 
Hensher, who describes Sydney as "a great laboratory to study toll roads" given their large number, believes it's time for network pricing - that is, basing  tolls on aspects such as the time of day  motorists travel. In other words, motorists would pay more to drive during peak hours than they would at quieter times of the day.
The federal government is inching towards a larger debate about a national scheme whereby motorists are charged on how far they drive in return for cheaper petrol and lower registration fees.
"What the Prime Minister and I have said is that it's a 10- to-15-year road journey," Urban Infrastructure Minister Paul Fletcher said  this week,  when asked about road-user charging.
The government will appoint within the next few months an "eminent Australian" to oversee a study into how motorists pay for roads, and how new roads will be funded and existing ones maintained, at a time of declining revenue from sources such as fuel excise.
For any government, road-user charging is a political minefield. Well aware that the next state election in 2019 will be won or lost in the city's west, NSW Labor has campaigned strongly against the
After all, tolling of motorists raises questions of social equity, because it is often people from lower socio-economic households in Sydney's west who are paying. A leaked "Final Business Case" for the Western Harbour Tunnel and Beaches Link even noted the discrepancies: "Northern beaches residents express more sensitivity to price compared to current toll road users, most likely reflecting their lower exposure to toll roads."
With their constituents among the biggest users, mayors in western Sydney are pushing for distance-based tolling and a cap on the cost of journeys for multiple motorways, as well as lower charges for off-peak travel.
"Most of the toll roads are in western Sydney ... so we are paying another set of taxes for being Westies," Blacktown mayor Stephen Bali says. "Whichever way you look at it, we are copping it and there needs to be a rethink - we are all tolled out."
Yet the dilemma for government officials considering a shake-up of the tolling regime is that the concession agreements for many of the existing toll roads still have decades to run, and vary in how annual increases in tolls are calculated.
Tolls on the M2 and Eastern Distributor are, due to contracts signed with private companies, rising at 4 per cent a year, more than twice the present rate of inflation.
In an era of low wage growth, it means a greater proportion of motorists' income is funnelled into paying for toll roads. Under so-called escalation rates for WestConnex and NorthConnex, their tolls will also rise at 4 per cent annually or at the rate of inflation, whichever is greater. 
'Poorly based and poorly organised'

Aside from the early losses for investors in the Cross City and Lane Cove tunnels, Sydney's toll roads have been delivering super-profits for their owners - notably Transurban, which has a stranglehold over them.
Tony Harris, a former NSW auditor-general, says the state's toll network has been "poorly based and poorly organised" since tolls were imposed on the M4 in the early 1990s.
"This has led to motorists paying the private sector significantly more than the economic or efficient cost of those roads," he says. "It has also meant that the government has not been able to introduce a soundly based system for pricing the use of tolled roads."
Harris believes a simple solution is for the government to become the owner and funder of new road projects, noting that the cost of its borrowings tend to be lower than the private sector's.
Or, if the government is curbed in its ability to borrow, an alternative would be to allow the private sector to fund, maintain and develop a road. It would then be leased to the state for a payment that reflects traffic volumes.
Importantly, Harris contends that these approaches will allow the government to alter tolls to reflect demand. This, he says, helps overcome the inefficiencies of a fixed toll.
"It is a big step but if you don't want to do that you have to put up with what we've got, which is episodic tolls on people and greater congestion," he says. "The problem is getting bigger and bigger." 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lane Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M.2</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Strode</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Lee-Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logistics Studies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Harbour Tunnel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackellar Jason Falinski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Final Business Case</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Infrastructure Minister Paul Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harbour Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Liberal MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falinski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transurban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaches Link</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cross City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Hensher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Speakman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW's Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harbour Tunnel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NorthConnex</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaches Link.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Institute of Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Transport Minister Andrew Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Distributor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Harbour Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Moir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WestConnex</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hensher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lane Cove Tunnel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F6</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janie Barrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Rae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
