<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398866595327677</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/energy/oil/origin-energy-doubles-petroleum-sales-20170730-gxlyf2</url>
  <title>Origin Energy doubles petroleum sales </title>
  <content>
Origin Energy has more than doubled annual sales of oil and gas, driven primarily by the ramp-up of its APLNG venture in Queensland but also reflecting growth in the conventional oil and gas business about to be spun off as Lattice Energy.
Full-year sales in oil and gas in 2016-17 reached $2.2 billion, up from $1.08 billion on a year earlier, thanks to both higher prices and production.
Revenues excluding APLNG, which will remain with the parent company after the Lattice sale, increased 26 per cent to $746.9 million.
Sales from Origin's 37.5 per cent interest in APLNG surged by almost $1 billion to $1.46 billion.

, with a decision expected by September.

Several parties are understood to be in the bidding process for Lattice, including a venture involving Beach Energy. , which are likely to be developed for the LNG market.
Production from the oil and gas activities rose 40 per cent overall, to 232 petajoules, helped by the start-up of the second production unit at APLNG last October and the beginning of production at the Halladale/Speculant project off the south-east coast.
Chief executive Frank Calabria said the uplift in output and sales "reflects strong operational performance across our upstream operations".
, paving the way for some $US3.4 billion of shareholder guarantees for the project debt to be released this September quarter.

In the June quarter, production rose 30 per cent from a year earlier to 89.2 petajoules, which was also up 12 per cent on the March quarter. APLNG shipped 33 cargoes in the June quarter.
Shares in Origin, which also has a large utilities business whose revenues aren't included in the quarterly report, were up 5¢ at $6.91 at 10:27am AEDT.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Calabria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lattice Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin's 37.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APLNG</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halladale/Speculant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEDT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin Energy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US3.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
