<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398789285915561</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/city/this-fourbedroom-home-really-makes-the-most-of-its-gardening-space/news-story/92a521182e454dfe9676e353969c0ef3</url>
  <title>This four-bedroom home REALLY makes the most of its gardening space - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Max, 3, in Jack and Judy Condous' verge garden outside the 46 Johns Rd, Prospect home they are selling. (AAP Image/MATT LOXTON)

DON'T have room for a veggie patch at your home? Think again.
Looking to live a more self-sufficient lifestyle, artist and OAM recipient Jack Condous and his wife Judy planted out the verge of the home they have owned for the past 22 years.
"A couple of years ago I couldn't stand that nothing much was happening out the front so I contacted the council who were keen for residents to do something, they provided the soil and I did the irrigation system off the two tanks down the side of the house and bingo," Mr Condous said.
"I think it's a fantastic thing that I wish more people would do."

46 Johns Road, Prospect. Pictures supplied by Ouwens Casserly.

Mr Condous said his verge garden was a hit with the local community.
"The neighbours know that if they knock on the door we can go out and pick what they want because there's plenty there," Mr Condous said.
"I downsize in summer because water's so expensive, but now with all the winter veggies coming on, it's just the right time to sell the home.
"People will come over with eggs and I'll send them home with vegies."

Inside Jack and Judy Condous' 46 Johns Road, Prospect home. Pictures supplied by Ouwens Casserly.

Mr Condous' verge is currently planted out with snow peas, beans, cabbage, spinach, lettuce, onions, garlic and herbs, and whatever produce the couple can't use fresh they preserve to enjoy later.
The couple are now selling the home for $780,000 through Margie Saint of Ouwens Casserly Real Estate, to downsize to a retirement village.
Mr Condous said he hopes whoever buys the home will continue to keep the verge garden going.
"If they buy the house and let the verge go I'll be hopping mad - I'll come back and tell them off," Mr Condous said.

The home also has an extensive established garden out the back.

Real Estate Institute of South Australia chief executive officer Greg Troughton said the environment and self-sufficiency was becoming more central to buyers' thinking.
"There is a growing awareness among buyers for a desire to be self-sustainable, whether that be in terms of home gardens, or even more broadly," Mr Troughton said.
"While the back garden in terms of size is ever diminishing, the ability to grow your own garden in innovative ways in small spaces is becoming the new norm."
"Even in high density housing, the ingenuous ways herb gardens are created are not only self-producing, but also great style in small spaces."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Condous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johns Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Condous</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP Image/MATT LOXTON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Troughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy Condous' 46 Johns Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johns Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max, 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ouwens Casserly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy Condous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margie Saint of Ouwens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casserly Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estate Institute of South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Troughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
