<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651397973242118366</docid>
  <date>30/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/liberal-mp-trevor-evans-speaks-out-as-chances-grow-of-gay-marriage-in-australia-by-end-of-year-20170730-gxlxhv.html</url>
  <title>New MP speaks out as chances grow of gay marriage in Australia by end of the year </title>
  <content>
The move to legalise gay marriage in Australia is gaining momentum and likely to happen before the end of the year, with another government MP signalling he is willing to cross the floor to support change, and a Liberal senator warning failure to recognise marriage equality would be "political suicide." 
On Monday, the federal Liberal MP for Brisbane Trevor Evans said he supported a free vote. His comments are being interpreted by supporters of gay marriage as a coded signal that he would be willing to cross the floor to help bring on a vote and force the issue to be dealt with by Parliament. 

Up Next

Methamphetamines deaths double in Australia

01:19

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Postal plebiscite not the answer

Liberal backbencher and same sex marriage supporter Dean Smith has rejected the idea of a postal same sex marriage plebiscite, saying it'll be divisive.

Mr Evans - who is openly gay -  the Coalition should dump its policy to hold a plebiscite on the issue given it has been rejected by Labor and the Greens in the Senate.
"I think the quickest and most likely course now is to allow politicians to have a free vote ... and I support that," he said.

"I am talking with colleagues, quite a number of colleagues, about different options that sit in front of us at the moment."
Sources pushing for marriage equality said Mr Evans' comments should be read as a sign that is willing to cross the floor on the issue, which would potentially deliver campaigners the numbers they need in the Parliament to force a vote.

Liberal senator Dean Smith, who is also openly gay, is drafting a bill to legalise same-sex marriage. Australian Financial Review he urged his colleagues to vote in Parliament by Christmas.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The government should not feel obligated to commit political suicide by handing its opponents a massive political cudgel by allowing the question of marriage equality to remain unresolved and fester over the next two years," he wrote.Photo: Robert Shakespeare
"Far too much time and energy has already been consumed by this debate. It is time to resolve the matter, in Parliament, as our constitution provides.
"Australian voters are perplexed about why so much time and energy is being expended on an issue where the community attitude is now crystal clear and why the government would continue to harm itself by delaying a free vote."
In a separate piece for The Australian, Senator Smith cites former prime minister Tony Abbott - an opponent of change - as saying the 2015 pledge to hold a plebiscite would be the last binding vote on the Coalition party room. 
With the plebiscite blocked by the Senate, supporters now argue they are free to vote according to their conscience if a private members' bill is put to the Parliament instead. 
An absolute majority of 76 is required to bring on a vote in the House of Representatives. That means the Labor Party would need four Liberal MPs to cross the floor to succeed in interrupting the scheduled business of Parliament to bring forward the private members' bill. 
Liberal MPs Mr Evans, Warren Entsch, Tim Wilson and Trent Zimmerman are all likely candidates to cross the floor. The government does not hold a majority in the Senate. 
The push to force a free vote would cause a major dispute within the Coalition party room and potentially threaten Malcolm Turnbull's prime ministership. Mr Turnbull supports gay marriage and a free vote but agreed to continue the policy to hold a plebiscite as part of his deal to take over the prime ministership from Mr Abbott. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs Mr Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Evans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
