<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398784990948238</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-airport-no-delays-from-boosted-security-over-foiled-sydney-terror-plot-20170731-gxm27k.html</url>
  <title>Security boost sees minimal delays at Canberra Airport</title>
  <content>
Passengers travelling from Canberra Airport were urged to arrive only 10 to 15 minutes earlier to clear heightened security screening on Monday.
On Sunday, Australians were urged to arrive at airports up to three hours ahead of departure after .Photo: Rohan Thomson
A Canberra Airport spokeswoman said on Monday that it was business as usual at the capital's airport.
"The enhanced and upgraded security measures have been implemented in full at Canberra Airport and there are minimal delays to the public," the spokeswoman said.

The biggest delays would occur during the airport's peak times between 5am and 7am, and from 3:00pm to 6:00pm.
"In those times, the delays are around 10 minutes. Canberra Airport is advising that people should arrive at the airport 10 to 15 minutes earlier than normal in these peak times only," the spokeswoman said.

The spokeswoman reminded passengers security did not open until 5am so there was no need for passengers to arrive earlier.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Passengers were urged to limit the amount of carry-on and checked baggage to clear security faster but there had been no changes to what could and couldn't be carried onboard.
Police raided five properties across Sydney over the weekend after receiving a tip off about a terrorist plot to bring down a plane with a bomb.
AFP Commissioner Andrew Colvin said on Sunday they didn't believe airport security had  been compromised but heightened security measures had been implemented.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull said security measures had been upgraded at all of Australia's major airports.
"Some of the measures will be obvious to the public, some will not be. Travellers should be prepared for additional scrutiny at screening points," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP Commissioner Andrew Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Airport</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
