<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398754926176825</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/former-rebels-bikie-accused-torture-rape-women/3206923/</url>
  <title>Former Rebels bikie accused of torture, rape of women</title>
  <content>
A FORMER Rebels Motorcycle Club is facing allegations of shocking domestic violence offences including torture and rape.

eported the Rebels Motorcycle Club has provided provided a statement to police about the ex-member.

The man is charged with 23 crimes, including torture and rape, against his ex-wife, and 44 against a more recent partner. The 33-year-old father of four, who cannot be named to protect the alleged victims, unsuccessfully applied for bail in Townsville Magistrates Court on Friday.

The ex-wife made complaints of historic abuse allegedly committed between 2006 and 2012.

Senior prosecutor Mark Fenlon told the court that many of the 44 fresh charges, allegedly committed since October, breached a Western Australian restraining order and a Queensland domestic violence order (DVO).

Coast man hospitalised after an argument turns violent
Businesses worry loss of parks could impact trading
Did your cat make the list?
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FORMER Rebels Motorcycle Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebels Motorcycle Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Fenlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
