<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398797875850288</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>01:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/07/deals-become-wall-street-ready-with-this-mba-bundle/</url>
  <title>Deals: Become Wall Street Ready With This MBA Bundle</title>
  <content>
Earning an MBA is a surefire way to prepare yourself for success in the world of business, but not everyone has the funds, or time, to shell out for a university education. Fortunately, you can still master the essentials of the field with the

Featuring instruction in communication, leadership, business models, and writing, this seven-course collection comes loaded with training to familiarize yourself with the cornerstones of an MBA program. You'll understand how to read and generate statements, work with KPIs, and master project management fundamentals as you make your way through the entire collection.

You can catalyse your MBA education with the MBA Bootcamp Bundle,  [$49 USD].

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

All deals are carefully vetted to ensure relevance and value to Lifehacker readers. Commerce Content is independent of Allure Media editorial and advertising, and if you buy something through our posts, we may get a small share of the sale. Click  to learn more.

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifehacker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allure Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commerce Content</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Become Wall Street Ready With This MBA Bundle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBA Bootcamp Bundle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
