<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398540177808969</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>00:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sing-dance-and-live-life-to-the-full-at-concert/3206886/</url>
  <title>Sing, dance and live life to the full at concert</title>
  <content>
CITTAMANI Hospice at Palmwoods will benefit from a musical afternoon at Kawana Community Hall on Saturday, August 19, at 2pm.
The Sunshine Coast Concert Band, directed by Ken Chadwick, will present its Sing and Dance Concert.
Guest singers will be Dave Stygall and Tanya McFadyen with The Merryatric Players as a special treat.
All proceeds are in aid of Cittamani, which provides professional palliative care to people who are dying and their families.
The hospice offers compassionate care and honours clients' individual choices.
Its aim is to provide the highest-quality service from the time of diagnosis through to the bereavement period.
The belief is that this service is best provided in a healthy and supportive community where death, dying and bereavement are openly discussed and accepted.
So head along to the hall in Nanyima St, Buddina, to support this worthwhile cause.
Tickets at the door are $15, which includes afternoon tea. Email sunshinecoastconcertband@ gmail.com for more information. Check out the band's website at www.sccb.org.au and Facebook page.
61-year-old dead after collision with four-wheel-drive
How a positive approach is defying a cancer death sentence
One Nation's bid to redirect funding has fallen on deaf ears
LOCAL government, community and business groups took up challenge.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
Move over cotton wool kids. Make way for the wannabe ninjas
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmwoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanya McFadyen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dance Concert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cittamani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanyima St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana Community Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Stygall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Concert Band</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Chadwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merryatric Players</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
