<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398961084610225</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/forgotten-game-of-thrones-characters-who-could-return-2017-7</url>
  <title>These 10 'Game of Thrones' characters disappeared, but could come back in a major way this season</title>
  <content>
There are tons of characters on "Game of Thrones," and it's hard enough to remember all the main character's names sometimes, let alone the minor ones.

And on this show, anyone could come back unexpectedly. So to help you be the one who can tell your friends exactly who that character you haven't seen a while is, here's our guide to forgotten "Game of Thrones" characters who could return in the future - some in a very big way.

Here are some forgotten "Game of Thrones" characters who could return in season seven or season eight:

HBO

As the only remaining bastard of King Robert Baratheon, Gendry is the only Baratheon left alive. This definitely has some significance, so it would be shocking if we never saw him again.

The last we saw him was back in season three, when Davos set him free from Stannis and Melisandre, who planned to sacrifice him to the Lord of Light.

Until we meet again, Gendry's still rowing.

HBO

Don't remember Salladhor Saan? Fair enough. He's barely in the show. He's a pirate and friend of Davos from his days as a pirate. In fact, he's a pirate lord and sellsail who commands a fleet of thirty ships. Salladhor is recruited by Stannis Baratheon (thanks to Davos) to help in the Battle of the Blackwater, but abandons the cause after Stannis loses.

In season five, Stannis and Davos secure a loan from the Iron Bank of Braavos. This allows Davos to pay Salldhor for his service to Stannis' cause, but that's the last time we see him.

Will Davos recruit Salladhor for Team Dany to replace the ships and people lost in Euron Greyjoy's attack on Yara's fleet? It's certainly a possibility, and would explain why we got that scene between Davos and Salladhor in season five.

HBO

Illyrio is a Magister in Pentos and a supporter of House Targaryen. In season one, he sets up the marriage of Daenerys Targaryen and Khal Drogo, and feeds Varys information on Dany and Viserys, who both support the latter's claim to the Iron Throne. In season five, though unseen, he lets Varys and Tyrion stay in his home in Pentos after their escape from King's Landing together.

Varys could bring Illyrio onto Dany's team for some more foreign support. He's also super wealthy, which could prove helpful to Dany.

HBO

Robin is a dumb kid, but as Lord of the Vale (Littlefinger is Lord Paramount right now), he's very powerful. Due to its basically impenetrable castle and powerful Knights of the Vale, House Arryn is a beneficial ally. Robin has deferred that power to Littlefinger for now, but that might change if, say, Sansa Stark turned on Littlefinger and told Robin the truth about how his mother, Lysa, died.

HBO

Kinvara, a high-ranking Red Priestess, was last seen in Meereen in season six. Tyrion and Varys recruit her to help convince the common people that Dany is their guardian and protector, not a conqueror or an invader.

Kinvara believes that Dany is the one who was promised. If Melisandre dies (which is pretty likely considering her track record), Kinvara could step in as the Red Priestess on duty.

HBO

OK, it hasn't been that long, so you probably haven't forgotten about Jaqen H'ghar, Faceless Man -- the guy who taught Arya how to be an assassin. Jaqen H'ghar could be anyone (as long as they're dead), and he's been to Westeros before. Maybe he'll make a surprise appearance, helping Arya when she needs it most.

HBO

Poor Daario. It hasn't even been that long since Dany told him that she's more into taking over the Seven Kingdoms than she is into him, and we've already forgotten he was a thing. Dany made him stay in Meereen on Tyrion's recommendation, because he'd be a liability in the Seven Kingdoms.

But he's been fiercely (sometimes violently) loyal to Dany ever since he met her, so it might be difficult for him to leave her alone. There's always a chance he could show up in Westeros in an attempt to protect her and help her take the Seven Kingdoms.

HBO

Arya's dance master (and The First Sword of Braavos) probably died at the hands of Meryn Trant back in season one. But since we didn't see his death happen with our own eyes, we can dream of a world where he escapes King's Landing unscathed, and comes to Arya's aid when she's taking someone particularly difficult to kill off her list.

HBO

Ser Ilyn Payne is a knight and the King's Justice, the royal executioner, to Robert Baratheon and his successor Joffrey Baratheon. He beheads Eddard Stark for treason on Joffrey's orders, in season one, but we haven't seen him since season two's 'Blackwater.'

He's only been mentioned in passing, perhaps because the actor  was diagnosed with terminal cancer. He had a miraculous recovery, and has expressed interest in returning to the show. Illyn Payne was last mentioned in the season four finale, which aired in June 2014.

Will Illyn Payne return to behead people (or worse) for Queen Cersei? He's a fan favourite, so maybe.

HBO

In the end, will King Tommen's cat win the game of thrones? We're not betting on it, but that would be a twist.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Viserys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illyn Payne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euron Greyjoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ser Ilyn Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stannis</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joffrey Baratheon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baratheon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddard Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salldhor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Tommen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meereen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Kingdoms</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salladhor Saan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lysa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salladhor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knights of the Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daario</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meryn Trant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pentos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joffrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davos</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dany</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Robert Baratheon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arya</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Bank of Braavos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Priestess</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Dany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord of Light</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Sword of Braavos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Targaryen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gendry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Arryn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Baratheon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illyrio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Paramount</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys Targaryen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kinvara</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Littlefinger</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord of the Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khal Drogo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Cersei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaqen H</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battle of the Blackwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Landing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stannis Baratheon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Throne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melisandre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
