<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398879480229953</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/patrick-dangerfield-says-tackle-on-matthew-kreuzer-was-fair-but-footy-greats-predict-dire-mrp-ruling/news-story/4c0d71f7efa87128bee12060cd4c653f</url>
  <title>Tackle verdicts will guide MRP on Danger</title>
  <content>
PATRICK Dangerfield has defended the tackle which concussed Carlton ruckman Matthew Kreuzer, adamant it was a "fair tackle".
The superstar Cat's decision to pin Kreuzer's arms in the dangerous tackle is the single threat to his Brownlow Medal chances.
for a week.
MARK ROBINSON:
JON RALPH:
MATCH REPORT:
It is understood the three chief discussion points for the MRP to assess a dangerous tackle are a lifting moment, double movement or rotation of the body to build speed and momentum.
Dangerfield's tackle had none of those qualities, but his decision to pin Kreuzer's arms as he rode him to the ground creates a problem.
That could be enough for the MRP to rule his tackle had "excessive force", which will lead to a suspension.
One of the criteria for dangerous tackles under MRP guidelines is "The player being tackled is in a vulnerable position (ie arms pinned) with little opportunity to protect himself."
If it is assessed as a careless and dangerous tackle he will miss at least one week for a medium-level incident.
MRP members Jason Johnson, Nathan Burke and Michael Jamison will rule on the case, with Jimmy Bartel unavailable on business and Michael Christian overseas.
The decision will also have to be ticked off by acting footy boss Andrew Dillon, in only his second week in the role.
Lance Franklin is unlikely to miss Friday's clash against Geelong as his careless, low impact tackle on Luke Hodge would be handed a fine at worst.
Dangerfield's tackle again sparked calls for an overhaul of the Brownlow criteria, Cooney adamant the league should drop the "fairest" element.
The Cats star has never been suspended in 196 games, with fellow contender Dustin Martin also on the edge given two low-level fines.
"I actually thought he still had the ball, so that's why I've turned around and put my hands in the air (to appeal for a free kick),'' Dangerfield told Channel Seven.
"I haven't been cited for anything. I felt it was a fair tackle, there was no umpire's call at the time so I don't see an issue with it, but it's not up to me.
"It wasn't paid a free kick at the time, but like I said, we will have to wait to see how it plays out."
The AFL will not be helped by two tackles from early in the year - Cam McCarthy on Sam Gilbert and Shaun Burgoyne on Sam Reid.
McCarthy's tackle resulted in a two week suspension but had a clear double movement, while Burgoyne escaped suspension but did not pin Reid's arms.

Cooney said the decision to pin Kreuzer's arms meant Dangerfield had a duty of care to the Blues ruckman.
"You would think given the precedents set he has to miss one week for this,'' he told SEN.
"It's not a sling, it's not a dump, but you know if you have a player's arms wrapped up and you know you can hurt them.
"I am not saying Patrick Dangerfield tried to hurt Kreuzer but he would have been fully aware he had his arms pinned and dragged him to the ground and the first thing that will hit the ground when you have his arms pinned is the head.
"You would think on precedents he has to miss a week for this."
Former Melbourne star David Schwarz agreed Dangerfield would be suspended for Friday's clash against Sydney.
"I feel as though the ball was gone, he has got both arms pinned and when you pin both arms it's your responsibility not to hurt the player.
Said Dal Santo: "I would love to see him get off but from what we have seen and what has been deemed to be unacceptable this year I think it's worth at least one."
Former Tiger Nathan Brown was adamant Dangerfield should not be suspended for the incident.
Brown said any ban for Dangerfield would be a disgrace.
"If he goes for that and can't win a Brownlow medal, or even gets a week just in general, I think it's a disgrace, where we've come to in that rule, which is very confusing," he said on Channel 9.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JON RALPH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Burgoyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Schwarz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Christian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burgoyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARK ROBINSON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Dillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jamison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiger Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Bartel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dal Santo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
