<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398870890295076</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/a-public-place-youd-like-to-hang-out-at-what-a-radical-idea-20170727-gxk7ba.html</url>
  <title>A public place you'd like to hang out at? What a radical idea!</title>
  <content>
And this week's public relations coup goes to the independent republic of Yarra for its proposed memorial to victims of heroin overdose at Richmond's notorious drug hot spot, the Victoria and Lennox streets intersection. The idea, floated by the council as part of an upgrade to the troubled area, sparked predictable outrage though not always from predictable places. One strong dissenter from within the council, Socialist Stephen Jolly, said, "We need to be uniting people in the area to fight this drug problem, not putting up a sign that says 'hey, it's not nice to be around here'." He described the memorial plan as "just a thought bubble from the Greens". Socialists versus Greens: how vintage inner-city Melbourne.
The memorial proposal is clever because it's already served Yarra's agenda: stoking the debate about supervised injecting rooms, which the council, a range of public health experts, the Coroner and now even the state's former police chief, Ken Lay, believe is worth trying as a way of saving lives and making the streets safer. As for putting up a sign that broadcasts how "not nice" it is to be in a neighbourhood where dealers police the corners, users shoot up in gutters, syringes litter the sidewalks, retailers shut up shop and death stalks the streets - well, it also has great potential for misery tourism. How long before some enterprising outfit monetises, yes glamourises, the drug scene by offering a "gritty walking tour of Melbourne's epicentre of H"? - which might just draw more people to the area, break the drug trade's monopoly of the space, rendering it more hospitable for locals, and thus help solve the problem by advertising the problem.

Up Next

Fourth thinnest tower to be built in Melbourne

01:00

More Victoria News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

A monument to the lost?

Yarra council's proposal for a monument to dead heroin addicts in Richmond has ignited fresh debate into what can be done to improve lives in the area. Artist: Matt Davidson

And this brings me, in a morbid way, to the broader point, which is that Yarra Council deserves applause for its leap of faith on public space. I'm talking about Yarra's roughly $250,000 plan to spruce up the Victoria-Lennox street corner - a blueprint well-ridiculed this week, quite apart from the memorial proposal, as lipstick-on-a-pig. The council proposes widening and repaving the intersection to make more room for cyclists and pedestrians, installing more street lights, planting new crepe myrtle trees, removing the single concrete bench that's there now and replacing it with smaller tables and chairs.
Sure, in the absence of a solution to the drugs crisis the new streetscape might do little more than give junkies a more welcoming and user-friendly space in which to transact and consume - Yarra's mayor, Amanda Stone, conceded as much in an interview with Jon Faine. But only the state government can act on injecting rooms or other harm minimisation measures, and so far its headline response to Victoria Street's woes has centred on kicking the can down the road by funding CCTV cameras, which are likely to do little more than push the trade into surrounding streets. The council had to cough up a quarter of a million to match Spring Street's contribution to works in the area. What did it do? Commendably, Yarra eschewed surveillance, a response based in fear, in favour of an approach grounded in openness and trust - inviting regular locals to hang out where the action is because there's safety in numbers.
While Yarra's leap of faith is especially stark, most urban authorities weigh trust against fear in designing public spaces. I was in New Zealand over summer and in Auckland, and other cities, I saw nature strips with deck chairs and free Wi-Fi; the public encouraged to linger and mingle. "We trust you," the city chiefs were saying, and people young and old were repaying that trust, reclining in the deck chairs, bent over their devices. (Some were even talking to each other!)
In Melbourne, the default position, from the public and urban planners, is one of paranoia. As soon as the state government announced the sky rail project last year objectors warned the viaducts underneath - envisaged as civic plazas among other uses - would be colonised by antisocial types.Photo: Chris Hopkins
And much as I admire the aesthetic, cultural offerings and big-events ambition of Federation Square, for instance, it's not a space that welcomes the loiterer. I encounter this problem every year during the Melbourne International Film Festival when I'm invariably looking for a comfortable spot in the square where I can wolf down my baguette before the lunchtime session at ACMI. (I know, life's taxing in the creative industries.) No seating in front of the screens, no seating generally, the steps too shallow and windswept to mimic the conviviality of Rome's Spanish Steps. Writing in The Conversation in May, La Trobe University PhD candidate Aaron Magro attributes Melbourne's ambivalence about public spaces to a colonial legacy; Governor Richard Bourke told surveyors new towns must not include European-style piazzas lest they promote rebellion.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

At this moment we should promote rebellion against the fear, surveillance and paranoia that stifle the enjoyment of public spaces in our city. As the Danish urbanist Jan Gehl puts it, "A good city is like a good party: guests stay because they are enjoying themselves." In the case of Richmond's Victoria Street the invites are going out - we just need that party to be drugs-free and safe.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Faine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socialist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hopkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond's Victoria Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor Richard Bourke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Magro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jan Gehl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Lay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Trobe University PhD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome's Spanish Steps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lennox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socialist Stephen Jolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne International Film Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria-Lennox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
