<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398956789642845</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/12/15/numan-haider-inquest-melbourne-police-stabbed</url>
  <title>Inquest finds police had no choice but to shoot radicalised teen Numan Haider</title>
  <content>
An inquest into the death of Melbourne teenager Numan Haider, who was shot after stabbing two police officers, has found the officer who shot him dead had no other choice.
Haider, 18, was shot outside the Endeavour Hills police station in September 2014, after he stabbed the AFP and Victorian Police officers who had arranged to meet the teenager to assess his recently cancelled Australian passport and his attitude towards the Australian government. 
A coronial investigation was launched just 10 days after Haider's death and heard that the teenager pulled out a knife and stabbed the Victoria Police officer in the arm and the AFP officer in the chest during the attack. 
The inquest was told Haider was on top of the AFP officer when he was shot by the Victoria Police officer who had shouted at him to drop his weapon. 
Victorian Coroner John Olle this morning ruled Haider's death was not preventable "other than at the expense of Officer B's life". 

"There was no time or opportunity for the officers to use a lower force to prevent further injuries," he said.
No adverse findings were made against police and Haider's radicalisation was found to have ultimately caused his death 
Haider was radicalised and "fit the stereotype of a dangerous young man" who was "drawn into extremist views", Coroner Olle said.
Haider emigrated to Australia from Afghanistan when he was seven years old. He came to the attention of authorities in 2014.
Posts on social media included a photo of Haider wearing a balaclava and holding a Shahada flag. 
Three Victoria Police officers who gave evidence at the inquest said ASIO had not shared information about extremist social media postings with the force.
The officers who came under attack said they would have reconsidered meeting Haider if they had known about the posts.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shahada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haider, 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Coroner John Olle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Endeavour Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Numan Haider</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haider</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coroner Olle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officer B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
