<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398875185262572</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/taylor-lands-medal-on-last-day-of-world-championsh/3206934/</url>
  <title>Taylor lands medal on last day of world championships</title>
  <content>
SWIMMING: Taylor McKeown may not have finished amid the top few in her preferred event but the University of the Sunshine Coast swimmer will return from the world championships with a relay medal.
The 22-year-old captured a bronze on the final day of competition on Monday, when she bolstered the Australian women's 4x100m medley relay team.
She clocked 1min06.29sec for breaststroke, combining with Emily Seebohm, Emma McKeon and Bronte Campbell to record 3:54.29.
The quartet finished behind United States (3:41.55) and Russia (3:53.38).
It was a promising way to finish the meet for McKeown, who had earlier competed in the 100m and 200m breastroke events.
In the latter, she qualified third fastest for the final before finishing seventh.
But she'll return to the Sunshine Coast as a medal winner, alongside younger sister Kaylee, who was a revelation at her first major international competition.
The 16-year-old was fourth in the 200m backstroke in 2:06.76 with a world junior record and she snared silver as a heat swimmer in the 4x100m mixed medley relay.
"Can't believe my little sister just broke the junior world record and went 2.06 for her 200 backstroke," Taylor said via social media.
"Such an amazing swim, finishing fourth and she only just turned 16....(she) has a bright future."
Kaylee also received praise from the likes of Sunshine Coast's two-time Olympic gold medallist Melanie Wright.
"Little legend. Well done superstar."
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
MUCH-loved Sunshine Coast sportsman dies in tragic circumstances
Coast man hospitalised after an argument turns violent
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States, 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor McKeown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma McKeon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronte Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melanie Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKeown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia, 3:53.38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Seebohm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaylee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
