<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398875185262504</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/andrew-banks-valuable-rankings-points-in-californi/3206940/</url>
  <title>Andrew banks valuable rankings points in California</title>
  <content>
SURFING: Keely Andrew has some insurance on her world tour spot, after faring well at a significant second-tier event.
The Sunshine Coaster, who hovers perilously outside the top 10 on the sport's main circuit, pushed into the top five of the Qualifying Series with a fifth placing at the Paul Mitchell Neon Supergirl Pro in California.
"It's my fifth year here and I feel like this is the first year where I really know the wave just because it changes so much with the tide," Andrew said.
"I've got two empty results on the ratings so it's nice to fill it with a decent number, but I just want to keep bettering myself each event whether it's the CT or QS."
The top six on the second tier, not including surfers who are also in the top 10 on the world tour, will earn berths on next year's main stage.
Andrew was scheduled to resume her Championship Tour campaign at the Vans US Open of Surfing in California from Monday night. It's the sixth stop on the 10-event schedule.
"It's starting to click and to know that my boards are feeling good heading into the US Open is great," she said.
Meanwhile, fellow Coasters and world tour hopefuls Dimity Stoyle and Isabella Nichols claimed 17th and 25th placings respectively amid 109 surfers in the QS event. Sophie McCulloch was 37th.
They are 13, 16th and 45th on the QS standings.
Mitch Coleborn was scheduled to compete in a prominent men's QS event in California from Monday night, in his pursuit of a world tour berth.
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
MUCH-loved Sunshine Coast sportsman dies in tragic circumstances
Coast man hospitalised after an argument turns violent
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie McCulloch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Mitchell Neon Supergirl Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vans US Open of Surfing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dimity Stoyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isabella Nichols</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Championship Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qualifying Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Coleborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keely Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
