<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398952494675397</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/entertainment/music/mel-c-shows-off-her-incredible-physique-while-performing-at-charity-event-carfest-north/news-story/f4e87f59732bf319a63ad38efbadbd07</url>
  <title>Sporty Spice looking sportier than ever</title>
  <content>
IF YOU were ever wondering why Mel C was always better known as Sporty Spice, all you need to do is look at these pictures.
The former Spice Girl, who is currently promoting her seventh album Version Of Me, performed at the British charity event CarFest North over the weekend - and the photos, which picture Mel C showing off her incredibly toned physique, speak for themselves.
The 43-year-old singer has been open about her battles with body image in the past,  this year that comments about her involvement in the girl group led to her being diagnosed with depression and excessively exercising.
"That all ended up in me not eating properly and exercising obsessively, because I thought I had to be a certain way to be deserving of everything that was happening to me ... to be a popstar I had to be perfect, and that was my way of trying to achieve perfection," she told the publication.
"I'd never starved myself, but I wasn't eating properly and I was exercising obsessively and all of my time with the Spice Girls I think I was probably living on adrenaline, God only knows how I got through it and I think my body just got to the point where it was like - enough," she added.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Version of Me</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CarFest North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sporty Spice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spice Girls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spice Girls I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel C</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
