<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398913839968993</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/2gbs-ray-hadley-hits-back-following-john-laws-scomoinspired-swipe-20170727-gxjp06</url>
  <title>2GB's Ray Hadley hits back following John Laws ScoMo-inspired swipe</title>
  <content>
There's nothing we love more on this column than a good ol' fashioned barney - and so any chance we get to fan the flames on a public stoush, we're all over it like a rash.
Hence why our ears pricked up late last week when old Golden Tonsils himself, John Laws - the only broadcaster known to man who continues to work despite being technically embalmed - decided to pick a fight with his former colleague, Ray Hadley - using ScoMo as a blunt instrument.
Broadcasting on 2SM (yes, it still exists, but it's not a patch on its "Rock Of The Eighties" days), Laws introduced a live interview with the Treasurer alluding to the kid from Cronulla had with 2GB's Hadley this year when he cheated on Hadley by appearing on ABC Melbourne.
"I hear you've had a falling out with my friend Roy," Laws ventured, to ScoMo's confusion. "Oh sorry, Ray," Laws clarified. (Geddit?). Being a man of the faith, ScoMo skated diplomatically through a reply, saying he wasn't "a bitter man" and was simply grateful anyone gave him air-time, anywhere. 

So we asked Hadley if he was troubled that his name was being used in vain ... to the four pensioners who tune in to Laws each morning. 

Said Hadley: "People stopped listening to John 14 years ago and more recently have stopped listening to the Treasurer, as well, to the extent he's been reduced to appearing on a program that has so few listeners it doesn't participate in the radio ratings and hasn't for years."
Hashtag mic drop.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Laws ScoMo-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rock Of The Eighties</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Hadley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Tonsils</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Laws</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ScoMo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hadley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
