<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398875185262619</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/07/would-you-pay-1000-for-gin-with-old-harley-davidson-parts-in-it/</url>
  <title>Would You Pay $1000 For Gin With Old Harley-Davidson Parts In It?</title>
  <content>
Perhaps, as a member of the common folk, my tastes are not quite as exquisite as those of the wealthy. I sometimes pronounce menu items wrong and I often stay away from foods I've never heard of, which means I am likely not affluent enough to enjoy the taste of $1,000 gin with motorcycle-engine parts in it.

Silly me, being not high enough within society's ladders to know any better, thought that engine parts were only for engines. My lack of wealth and status kept me from the ultimate realization that engine parts are not only necessary for a vehicle's engine to run-they're vital for your health and longevity, too.

At least there are those who do have taste and good breeding. They shelled out between $1,047 and $1,280, plus shipping, at current exchange rates for this alcohol sweetened with the nectar of decades-old Harley-Davidson parts that were retrieved by a man, Uwe Ehinger, who makes his living doing just that.

Thus, Ehinger, founder of the Ehinger Kraftrad shop that designs motorcycles, parts and apparel, used his findings to create what his press release calls the world's first premium dry gin with Harley-Davidson engine parts in it. How silly of us to not think of this idea before.

The gin comes in three different flavors, if you will: 1939 Flathead camshafts from the Mexican desert, $1,279.46; 1947 Knucklehead screw-nuts from Chile, $1,163.25; and 1962 Panhead rocker arms from South Korea, $1,046.83. Ehinger named his engine-infused beverage "The Archaeologist" after the nickname he received for discovering so many parts.

I can only dream of one day finding such self-importance. From the release:

As an analogy to Ehinger's motorcycles, ˮThe Archaeologist" is pure craftsmanship: The parts of the motorbikes are specially cleansed and sealed with a tin alloy to make it safe for them to be utilized in a drink. Subsequently, they are soldered onto a steel structure and encased by a handcrafted bottle. The creative concept was developed by Serviceplan Group together with renowned Hamburg designers "Studio Oeding".
The entire look and feel recreates the original packing of the antique engine parts - using authentic materials and historic techniques. Packages are made using selected cardboards and colours, printed on an original Heidelberg Tiegelprinting press from 1931. Waxed wrapping paper tells the story of each discovery.
This unique design is completed by hand-stamped, tamper-proof seals and clenched hang-tags, each bearing the unique serial number of the engine part in its respective bottle.

The press release said Ehinger's first batch of engine gins, offered in a "limited number" on his website, sold out within hours. Ehinger will be taking orders in advance from now on.

I only wish I'd known about the first batch ahead of time. I'm losing years off of my life here, and I need the distilled spirits of the motorcycle gods to rejuvenate me. But, as the common person I am, I must first pray to them for money to buy some.

This story originally appeared on .

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panhead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uwe Ehinger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pay $1000 For Gin With Old Harley-Davidson Parts In It</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oeding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ehinger Kraftrad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ehinger</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley Davidson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ˮThe Archaeologist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg Tiegelprinting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serviceplan Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
