<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398956789642813</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/babies/presidents-daughter-sparks-debate-with-breastfeeding-photo/news-story/e2f7dd83cdc417b1cc6586ddcee60942</url>
  <title>President's daughter sparks debate with breastfeeding photo</title>
  <content>
In a Parliament First, Australian Senator Breastfeeds Baby While Giving Speech. Credit - Australian Parliament via Storyful
0:29

Australian Greens Senator Larissa Waters breastfed her baby daughter, Alia, while moving a motion in the Senate on Thursday, June 22. Waters made headlines just weeks earlier for being the first federal lawmaker to breastfeed during Senate proceedings. On Thursday, Waters was breastfeeding when she was called to move a motion about black lung disease. In the footage, Chair of Committees Sue Lines can be seen smiling while Waters feeds her baby and stands to speak. Waters later tweeted: "First time I've had to move a Senate motion while breastfeeding! And my partner in crime (Alia) moved her own motion just before mine, bless her". Breastfeeding in parliament has not been without controversy. In 2003 MP Kirstie Marshall, of Victoria's state parliament, was kicked out of chambers after she breastfed her 11-day-old daughter. Credit: Australian Parliament via Storyful

June 22nd 2017
a month ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Is this picture of a mother breastfeeding in her underwear offensive? Picture: Aliya Shagieva

Share

ALIYA Shagieva is a young mother who just wants to look after her baby.
She's also the youngest daughter of Almazbek Atambayev, the president of Kyrgyzstan - a conservative Muslim-majority country in Central Asia.
The 20-year-old shared a photo of herself breastfeeding her son Tagir in her underwear, with the caption: "I will feed my child whenever and wherever he needs to be fed."
The image caused a severe backlash.

This image was removed from social media after it was accused of being 'vulgar' and 'immoral'.Source:Supplied
Aliya was accused of being "immoral" and "vulgar", and the trolling became so severe she was eventually forced to remove it altogether.
However, she's holding her head high and launching an attack on a culture she says is hyper-sexualising the female body.
"This body I've been given is not vulgar. It is functional, its purpose is to fulfil the physiological needs of my baby, not to be sexualised," she told the .
"When I'm breastfeeding my child I feel like I'm giving him the best I can give. Taking care of my baby and attending to his needs is more important to me than what people say about me."

on

While it is acceptable to breastfeed in public in Kyrgyszstan, women are typically required to cover themselves and their baby with a cloth.

Victoria Tahmasebi, a Canadian gender studies expert, tweeted: "From a capitalist view point women's breasts can create profit as long as they are sexualised. Breastfeeding in public makes women's breasts less sexy, therefore it is not acceptable."
Even Ms Shagieva's parents, the country's President and First Lady, disapproved.
"They really didn't like it. And it is understandable because the younger generation is less conservative than their parents," she said.
The artist is known for being socially progressive - giving birth just six months after her marriage to a Russian man, and maintaining a vegetarian diet despite the fact that meat is a staple in the ex-Soviet country.

on

She has at least 32,000 followers on Instagram, and her carefully composed images focusing on family life have been shared around the world.
However, she insists she's not trying to make a political statement.
Rather, she's simply trying to normalise women's bodies and break the taboos surrounding something they've been doing since the beginning of time.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Almazbek Atambayev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Lines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Tahmasebi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Shagieva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Lady</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrgyszstan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aliya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Kirstie Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tagir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALIYA Shagieva</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Senator Breastfeeds Baby While Giving Speech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Parliament</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrgyzstan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 22</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Greens Senator Larissa Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament First</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim-majority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chair of Committees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
