<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398879480229964</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/drug-the-sceptics-make-children-shorter/news-story/b5cc7604773cd52ca4433699eee5d5f6</url>
  <title>DRUG THE SCEPTICS! MAKE CHILDREN SHORTER!</title>
  <content>
Meet the global warming extremist from New York University  invited to Australia to explain his new plan to stop the planet heating: drug the footdraggers until they give up, and dose children with chemicals to keep them short and more planet friendly. Caution: this is not a hoax.

youtube

People unwilling to act on the climate-crisis narrative should be assisted with drugs that improve and promote conformity, according to eminent bio-ethicist Professor Matthew Liao, of New York University, who also wants to see parents dosing their children with hormones and diets to keep them shorter and less of a burden on the planet.
He wants such people to be given the . This would increase their trust and empathy and make them more ready to change to emission-saving lifestyles.
As his peer-reviewed study puts it, "Pharmacologically induced altruism and empathy could increase the likelihood that we adopt the necessary behavioral and market solutions for curbing climate change." He emphasises there would be no coercion. The drugs would merely help those who want to be climate-friendly behaviour but lack the willpower
Once sufficiently drugged, parents would be less likely to reject notions of "human engineering" techniques that will be needed to create Humans 2.0. These amended species will be 15cm shorter than now, hence more energy efficient and less resource-demanding. His study, , is in Ethics, Policy and the Environment.
Some US reaction to Liao has been adverse. Investor's Business Daily used the headline, "...
Liao's study theorises that shorter humans could be achieved through embryo selection during IVF, plus drug and nutrient treatments to reduce birth weights. (High birth weight correlates with future height; low weights obviously correlate with risk to the baby). Anti-growth hormones could be fed to toddlers by climate-caring parents to create earlier closing of their bubs' epiphyseal (growth) plates. Oh, and he also wants ecocidal meat eaters bio-altered to induce unpleasant reactions if they put pleasure ahead of planet and tuck into a T-bone.
His paper, although now five years old and sometimes mistaken for a sceptic hoax, features today on his  It merited him a gig at a recent Leftist-stacked Festival of Dangerous Ideas at Sydney Opera House, where he spoke in front of a banner, "Engineering humans to stop climate change". His compere was the respectful Simon Longstaff, boss of Sydney's , who introduced his guest as a "really great speaker...He is on the up, this guy. He is on the up!"
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-bone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-growth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Longstaff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IVF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Humans 2.0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leftist-stacked Festival of Dangerous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Matthew Liao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liao</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investor's Business Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Opera House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
