<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398875185262496</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/breaking-news/trade-minister-slams-qldfirst-policy/news-story/471f73eaec121c2b227380313abda3e0</url>
  <title>Trade Minister slams 'Qld-first' policy</title>
  <content>
The state government's "Queensland-first" procurement policy will only leave Queensland's exporters last, according to federal Trade Minister Steve Ciobo.
Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk announced over the weekend her government will encourage departments to award contracts to local businesses.
Under the policy, preference will be given to businesses located within 125km of where work is needed.
Ms Palaszczuk said where possible, one regional and one Queensland supplier would also be invited to quote or tender for every contract.
Mr Ciobo says while the plan sounds good to voters, in reality it has the potential to restrict Queensland's trade relations with overseas markets.
"The simple fact is, you can't have your cake and eat it too," he said.
"The simple fact is you can't open up export markets internationally and close off Queensland, you either have them both open or both closed."
The premier defended her policy on the Gold Coast on Monday, saying her government's first priority is creating work for Queenslanders.
"We want to see as many Queensland businesses enter into those overseas markets (as possible) but what I want to see here in Queensland is Queensland jobs first," she said.
"This is about ensuring local people living in local, regional economies can get that sort of work."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ciobo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trade Minister Steve Ciobo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld-first</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland-first</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
