<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398961084610232</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/raw-mcdonalds-beef-patty-sickens-mum/3206950/</url>
  <title>Raw McDonald's beef patty sickens mum</title>
  <content>
IT took one bite of Sherre Scheide's burger to realise something was wrong - but what she didn't expect to see was this.

The Karama woman took her children to a Darwin McDonald's store on a Sunday lunch treat, ordering Quarter Pounder meals for each of them.

"As I started biting into the burger, I thought it didn't taste right, then I looked down and opened the patty and it was raw," she said.

"I took all the burgers back and the manager came racing around the corner and shook my hand and said she'd speak to the staff members."

Ms Scheide's meals were then replaced with chicken meals but she wasn't offered a refund.

"I didn't finish the chicken burgers because I was disgusted and feeling sick from the first burger," she said.

"I said to the manger that I'd like someone from head office to contact me.

"(When they did), they had a carefree attitude and she told me the meat had to only be checked once in a 24-hour period. I said I wasn't happy with the response and that I'd be taking it to the health and safety food inspectors and she just said 'do what you've got to do'."

Though Ms Scheide's yet to file the complaint, she's been turned off Maccas for good.

A company spokeswoman said McDonald's took food safety seriously and incidents such as these were rare.

"The restaurant confirmed the issue was isolated and did not affect any other products," she said. "We have also reinforced cooking procedures with this restaurant."

Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
MUCH-loved Sunshine Coast sportsman dies in tragic circumstances
Coast man hospitalised after an argument turns violent
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
Imagine being on TV when a spider starts crawling on you
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherre Scheide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Scheide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quarter Pounder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
