<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398952494675380</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/property/besen-family-sells-680m-stake-in-melbournes-highpoint-shopping-centre-20170731-gxm2y6.html</url>
  <title>Besen family sells $680m stake in Melbourne's Highpoint Shopping Centre</title>
  <content>
Melbourne's billionaire Besen family has offloaded a quarter stake in one of Australia's largest malls, the Highpoint Shopping Centre in the city's west, for $680 million.
The sale of its share in the lucrative shopping mall to diversified property giant GPT will significantly boost the family's wealth, estimated by the BRW Rich list to be about $2.4 billion.Photo: Tim White
The family, headed by patriarch Marc Besen, decided to sell its 25 per cent holding in the mall and the neighbouring Maribyrnong Homemaker centre in April.
GPT's Wholesale Shopping Centre Fund picked up the Besen's share after taking up a "pre-emptive" purchase option.Photo: Paul Jeffers
"Highpoint has delivered an exceptional return of 15.1 per cent over the past 12 months. Super prime regional centres of this calibre are rarely traded in Australia," the fund's manager, Brett Williams, said.
GPT and its managed fund already owned 75 per cent of the centre after acquiring a half share in 2006 and further boosting its ownership in 2009 and 2014.

The price reflected a 10 per cent premium to the fund's June 30 book value, GPT said.
The Besen family, who controlled their share through the Highpoint Property Group, would not comment on the deal.Photo: Paul Jeffers
The sale will give GPT and its wholesale fund full control of Highpoint, which is one of the country's largest super regional shopping centres and has an annual moving turnover close to $1 billion.
The fund has ended up with a controlling 83.33 per cent stake in the centre, while the remaining 16.67 per cent interest is held by GPT Group.
Highpoint, in Melbourne's rapidly gentrifying western suburbs, has about 470 stores, including Myer, David Jones and international retailers Apple, Zara and Samsung.
GPT continues to be the centre's manager.
GPT is currently considering expanding the centre's cinema and entertainment areas and developing a second supermarket and fresh food precinct.
"The centre should also benefit from mixed-use development opportunities in the future," Mr Williams said.
Marc and Eva Besen founded clothing retailer Sussan Group, now controlled by their daughter, businesswoman and philanthropist Naomi Milgrom.
Eva Besen is the sister of property billionaire John Gandel, best known for his ownership of Melbourne's other mega-mall, Chadstone Shopping Centre.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Besen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naomi Milgrom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maribyrnong Homemaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadstone Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highpoint Property Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highpoint</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highpoint Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sussan Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Gandel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Besen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eva Besen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Highpoint Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT Wholesale Shopping Centre Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRW Rich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
