<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399004034283804</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/a-12pack-of-soap-aimed-at-my-head-abuse-of-young-sales-staff-is-out-of-control-20170730-gxlql2.html</url>
  <title>A 12-pack of soap aimed at my head: abuse of young sales staff is out of control</title>
  <content>
With the increasing casualisation of the workforce, particularly in the retail sector, and a high demand for young and thereby cheap employees, it is no secret that a significant number of the retail workers you see in your local shops and department stores are teenagers and university students. For young people, the pressure is often on to step into these jobs because they are told they need to learn the value of hard work and gain some real-world skills.
Like many young Australians, when I hit 14 1/2 I got my first casual job. Seven years later, I have been working in a casual retail job in a large retail chain for a third of my life. And if there is anything I have learnt in my retail years it is this - people treat retail workers awfully.

Up Next

Massive fire causes festival evacuation

01:44

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Are Millennials less progressive than Gen Xers?

The Feed look at whether the social attitudes of Millennials have or haven't changed over time, and why it matters. From The Feed on SBS Viceland, 7.30 weeknights.

Sure, you're thinking it is no big secret that retail workers get treated badly. Many retail workers treat the abuse as part of the job. However, in my experience, this abuse has worsened, especially with the proliferation of the "lazy millennial" stereotype.
I have had a 12-pack of soap thrown at my head, which narrowly missed, have been physically threatened by customers, have been filmed for refusing an abusive customer a refund for a product purchased from a different company, and have been called every slur under the sun multiple times a day.

Some of my co-workers have been followed out of the store after their shift by customers with a vendetta. Some have been followed to their cars after a late-night shift.
Fearing for your safety should not be part of the job description.

For staff in these situations, going to work each day can cause incredible stress, emotional fatigue and psychological distress.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The managers can only do so much  - while they back us up where they can and ban the worst offenders from stores, it can be hard to police these bans, especially in large department stores with large numbers of casual staff. Photo: Bloomberg
And even if customers are escorted out of the shop or shopping centre, there is little that can be done to protect us outside, where some of the scariest incidents happen. Buses, car parks, days off - none of these can be protected from customers hurling abuse, or in my case, 12-packs of soap.
At night, managers or fellow team members walk each other to their cars as a measure of safety, but it shouldn't have to come to that.Photo: Marina Neil
Serious changes need to be made to the way some customers treat retail workers, especially young retail workers.
People grossly underestimate the hard work young people in customer service jobs do. Retail work is physically and emotionally draining, with long periods of standing, manual labour and repetitive tasks. Talking to customers and assisting them to the best of our ability can be draining over the course of a shift and difficult customers only make this worse.
With such constant mistreatment of young workers, how can they be expected to take on hard work that is often met with mental, emotional and, increasingly, physical abuse? And how can excellent customer service be expected from people attacked for doing their job?
No retail worker wants to make life difficult for customers.  Individual staff members are not responsible for the stock availability or stock quality - they don't make or order the stock themselves.
Don't blame or abuse staff for a problem they have no control over. If you have made a mistake or are having a bad day, don't take it out on retail staff. Multiple instances of abuse over the course of a shift and the course of a retail career can have incredibly detrimental effects on the health and wellbeing of a retail worker.
Next time you go shopping, think hard about how you treat the people on the other side of the counter. They deserve your respect. They deserve to feel safe.
Hayley New is freelance writer, editor, and blogger. She tweets as @haylesnew and can be found writing at .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS VICELAND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Xers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
