<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399085638663477</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4822140/more-changes-at-newcastle-golf-club/?cs=306</url>
  <title>More changes at Newcastle Golf Club</title>
  <content>
Mark Gilson has left Newcastle Golf Club to take up a sales job.

The changes keep coming at Newcastle Golf Club after professional Mark Gilson started a new job last week outside the industry.
President John Twohill and three of the board's five directors lost their positions in February. Since then, Christian Gillott, from The Lakes, has replaced general manager Paul Foulcher and the club's head greenkeeper has also gone.
But Gilson said he had left on good terms to pursue a change in career as state sales manager for Toro mowers.
"I just thought I'd go down a different path. I tried to do it five years ago selling golf carts to the golf industry, but it just didn't work out," Gilson told Down the Fairway.
"I just wanted a fresh change. I've worked weekends in the golf industry for 20 years."
Gilson's job title at Newcastle was golf manager, and he took the position four years ago knowing that Jason Laws ran the club's coaching academy.

He said he would maintain his membership at the club, which is pushing ahead with plans to redevelop part of the course.
"They've got a really good opportunity. They've got a new person in my role, a new head greenkeeper and the new general manager they've picked, so they've got a great platform, the new board, to start over and start fresh," Gilson said.
"They've got some big plans. They've got some people they've put in place, so they should be able to execute it all.
"Michael Coughlan, the club president, has been great to me while I've been there. My two kids are still there. I've still got a close affiliation with the golf club."
++++++++++++++++++  
Aberdeen's Dylan Perry will play in the prestigious US Amateur this month after finishing in a tie for first in sectional qualifying in North Carolina last week.
Perry, from The Vintage, shot 71 and 65 at Benvenue Country Club for an eight-under total and will tee it up in the US Amateur at Riviera Country Club in California from Monday, August 14.

Dylan Perry after US Amateur sectional qualifying in North Carolina.
The 22-year-old, who was runner-up at the British Amateur in June, will try to emulate the feats of Belmont's Nick Flanagan, who won in 2003, and 2016 Australian champion Curtis Luck.
"It feels good. I played really solid out there this afternoon, blemish-free, which is always nice," Perry told Golf NSW. "I can't wait to get to Riviera."
Charlestown's Blake Windred endured an agonising qualifying experience at Mendon Golf Club in Rochester, New York.
Windred shot two 71s to miss out by a shot after a missed flight, five-hour storm delay and change of course, all of which left him feeling "pretty shattered".
He is a first alternate for the main event.    
++++++++++++++++++  
Newcastle District Golf Association will stage the Oc Olley Cup for B-graders and C-graders at Waratah and Belmont respectively on Sunday.
The event, the biggest on the NDGA calendar, will draw a field of 250 competing in individual nett and stroke competitions and a teams event.
It also doubles as the B- and C-grade district championships, although these are expected to be separate events next year.
++++++++++++++++++  

Association secretary Rod Carruthers stormed to victory in the NDGA Masters at Waratah on Sunday, shooting an impressive 74 off the stick for a nett 61.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President John Twohill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riviera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NDGA Masters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benvenue Country Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C-grade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Amateur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown's Blake Windred</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtis Luck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mendon Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Laws</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Golf Club</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Gillott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C-graders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Gilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-graders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Amateur</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Foulcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rochester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golf NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Coughlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle District Golf Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windred</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Carruthers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aberdeen's Dylan Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riviera Country Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Carolina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oc Olley Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmont's Nick Flanagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NDGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
