<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398999739316340</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/markets/gold-explorers-set-for-solid-earnings-despite-strong-aussie-20170728-gxkiao.html</url>
  <title>Gold explorers set for solid earnings, despite strong Aussie</title>
  <content>
As geopolitics continues to shock like never before, safe-haven gold is on the radar for investors and Australian producers appear to be heading for a solid reporting season. 
Over the last four months, bullion has moved within a 7.6 per cent range, the least in 10 years, while 120-day volatility is at the lowest since 2005, .Photo: Andrey Rudakov
The precious metal has indicated moderate signs of life and is currently fetching $US1269 an ounce ($1594 an ounce) after the US Federal Reserve left its benchmark policy unchanged last week.
"While legislative, security, and economic risks abound, none of these risks have yet to truly materialise into a risk-off, gold positive event," says Christopher Louney, commodity strategist at RBC Capital Markets.
"The market certainly has gotten used to uncertainty and the high level of geopolitical risk, thus leaving gold to trade against the dollar, equities, rates, etc."
But Australian gold producers are set for a solid reporting season say experts; the dramatic mining downturn having forced companies to streamline exploration processes and some recent small cap discoveries piquing the interest of the market.

"Generally, Australian gold miners have done remarkably well to take costs out and take advantage of the gold price in Australian dollar terms," says Victor Gomes, co-portfolio manager of UBS' small cap fund.
"And you would have thought that gold would have lifted, with rising interest rates in the United States and the winding back of quantitative easing, you would have thought it would have peeled off in US dollar terms."
Evolution Mining, with three projects in Queensland, two in Western Australia and one in New South Wales, delivered record production for the last quarter, managing to produce 218,100 ounces at its lowest all-in sustaining cost (AISC) of $825 an ounce.
Regis Resources, with its West Australian and New South Wales projects, comfortably beat analyst expectations, producing 90,500 ounces at AISC of $870 an ounce.
Saracen Mineral Holdings, with its two West Australian projects, produced 80,000 ounces at AISC of $1,127 an ounce and continues to drill in some of its other projects.
However the influence of the fluctuating exchange rates will continue to influence investor sentiment toward gold.
"Many local currency gold prices are doing less well," says Ben Crowley, gold analyst at Macquarie Wealth Management in a note to clients. "This suggests gold's underlying strength is not all that," he added.
But regardless of the price, smaller cap miners are exploring again and larger fund managers are taking notice.
BlackRock - the world's largest asset manager - has taken , currently drilling in Mali, West Africa. BlackRock picked up the majority of its 24.9 million shares at 0.24¢
And Australia's largest gold producer, Newcrest Mining, recently invested , which recently began trading on the Toronto Stock Exchange.
The majors are interested in the potential of early-stage Cascabel project in Ecuador, which analysts have compared to some of the largest existing copper and gold mines, including Rio Tinto's Oyu Tolgoi project.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Louney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1269</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ecuador</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saracen Mineral Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto Stock Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrey Rudakov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Wealth Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regis Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cascabel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto's Oyu Tolgoi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AISC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Crowley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlackRock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcrest Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Gomes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBC Capital Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
