<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399051278924820</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/one-nation-senator-could-replace-himself/news-story/32ce4c5b340e86cf28d835903be502a4</url>
  <title>One Nation senator could replace himself</title>
  <content>
Paul Osborne, AAP Senior Political WriterAustralian Associated Press

Share

One Nation senator Malcolm Roberts could replace himself if found to have been ineligible to run for parliament.
The Queensland senator is facing questions over whether he held British citizenship at the time he ran for election in mid-2016.
Senator Roberts insists he sought to renounce any possible British citizenship before nominating but he did not receive a written reply from British authorities until six months later, well after he was elected to the Senate.
If he is referred to the High Court and disqualified under section 44 of the constitution - which bans dual nationals from being MPs - the next candidate on the Queensland One Nation ticket would take the seat.
That candidate, Fraser Anning, is facing bankruptcy proceedings in the Federal Court, which if proven would render him ineligible to be in parliament.
However, if the bankruptcy status only applies to Mr Anning after the election period it will trigger a casual vacancy - not a recount - meaning any One Nation member could take the seat.
If he was an ex-senator at that point Roberts could then take back his old seat, having only been officially confirmed as an Australian last December.
It is understood the government has made no decision to ask parliament's upper house to refer Senator Roberts to the High Court.
However, it will ask for stood-aside minister Matt Canavan to be referred to the court to test whether his Italian citizenship rendered him ineligible to continue in the Senate.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Roberts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Anning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Anning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Osborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP Senior Political WriterAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
