<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399038394022612</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/12/18/dad-joins-search-for-missing-sydney-schoolgirl-quanne-diec</url>
  <title>Father joins new search for body of schoolgirl Quanne Diec 19 years after disappearance</title>
  <content>
The father of missing Sydney schoolgirl Quanne Diec has joined the renewed police search for her body, 19 years after the 12-year-old vanished.
Quanne was allegedly abducted a few hundred metres from her Granville home on her way to school on the morning of July 27, 1998.
She never arrived and was reported missing by her parents that afternoon.
She was just 12.
This morning, police announced a renewed search for Quanne's remains in bushland off Appin Road at Cataract, saying they remained focused on finding the schoolgirl's body to bring her family some closure.
Her father has joined police at the site.
"The process has been an incredibly difficult experience for her family and we will continue to support them as the search continues," NSW Police said in a statement.

Related Articles

Last November a 49-year-old man accused of murdering the schoolgirl led police to an area of dense bush in Bulli Tops, near Wollongong, where Quanne's body is believed to be buried, however, her body was not found.
Vinzent Tarantino, who lived several hundred metres from the Diec family home at the time, remains before the courts charged with Quanne's murder.
He was a former neighbour of the Diecs and police have alleged he targeted Quanne deliberately.
The reward for information leading to the whereabouts of Quanne's body was increased to $200,000 in 1999.
The current search is expected to last three days.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quanne</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quanne Diec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appin Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Granville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulli Tops</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quanne Diec 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diec</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vinzent Tarantino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
