<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399128588336906</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/100-rescued-from-cable-car-line-in-germany-after-midair-collision-20170731-gxm2tg.html</url>
  <title>100 rescued from cable car line in Germany after midair collision with pillar</title>
  <content>
As many as 100 passengers were evacuated from suspended cable cars that run over the Rhine River in Cologne after a gondola crashed into a support pillar.
Public transportation authorities for the city in North-Rhine-Westphalia state said 32 of the cars were operating when the accident occurred on Sunday.

Up Next

Massive fire causes festival evacuation

01:44

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Dramatic rescue from German cable cars

More than 100 cable car passengers were rescued after an accident left them stranded over the Rhine river in Cologne, Germany.

When the one car collided with the pillar, the others were brought to a stop.
The line was immobilised for hours, and passengers were stuck in their cable cars.Photo: AP
Twenty children were among those stranded.
Rescue workers had to abseil passengers onto a fire department boat on the river.

Other passengers clambered to safety on the shore or a major bridge from fire truck ladders.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

A pregnant woman and a man were slightly injured in the rescue mission. No other injuries were reported.Photo: AP
Rescue teams in Cologne had practised for an incident on the gondola just a week ago, German media reported.
The last person was rescued about five hours after the collision on the line.Photo: AP
Emergency crews from surrounding towns were called in to help.
More than 100 people were involved in the rescue effort.
"Nothing like this has ever happened before," fire department spokesman Christian Heinisch said.
Cologne authorities provided counselling for those people who had been stranded and were rescued.
DPA; Telegraph, London
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Heinisch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhine River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cologne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North-Rhine-Westphalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
