<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399085638663497</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/trust-changes-to-hit-tax-minimising-business-owners/8759514</url>
  <title>Trust changes to hit tax-minimising business owners: expert</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Small businesses have expressed concern about the Opposition's plan to tax payments from trusts at a minimum rate of 30 per cent, but experts are of the view only tax minimisers will likely be affected.
Under the proposal, , distributions from most so-called discretionary trusts will be taxed at a minimum rate of 30 per cent.
The move is designed to make the practice of "income splitting" through trusts less profitable as a means to minimise tax.
, generally family members, who are on low or zero incomes and thus pay less tax on the earnings than the person who actually generated the income.
Many small businesses operate through a trust structure, often to protect their assets from creditors or to facilitate succession planning.

Peter Strong from the Council of Small Business Australia (COSBOA) said his members are concerned about the potential effects of Labor's proposal.
"Go get them in another way, don't punish everybody," he told RN Breakfast.
"Go and get those people who are doing the wrong thing, but at the moment what they've said is ... we're also going to get the people doing it for the right reasons."
But Professor Robert Deutsch, senior counsel at The Tax Institute, said the changes will only affect small businesses using trusts for income splitting.
"They will be affected. They could run those small businesses through a normal, everyday company, they'd pay tax at 30 per cent or as low as 27.5 per cent [for small businesses]," he said.
"By running it through a trust they would [currently] be able to achieve slightly better rates than that by splitting income with other individuals in their family orbit."
Professor Deutsch said that means there should no impact on small businesses that are not using trust structures to minimise tax.
He also believes it is a better alternative to proposals considered in the past to tax trusts as if they were companies.
"It's a vast improvement on the original concept of taxing trusts as companies," he said.
"It's a carefully crafted, clever, well-directed attempt to deal with what are perceived to be the worst cases of abuse in the area of discretionary trusts."
That is because taxing trusts as companies would entitle the beneficiaries of trust payments to franking credits that refund the company tax paid, meaning income splitting would continue to be viable.
'Removal of an entitlement'

However, not all experts are yet sold on Labor's proposal.
The tax leader at Chartered Accountants Australia New Zealand, Michael Croker, said the plan undermines a long-held principle of Australia's progressive taxation system.
"It's based on the removal of an entitlement, and that's the entitlement to the marginal tax rates," he said.
"Labor's identified what it sees as an unfairness in the way in which typically wealthy people can use discretionary trusts and decided to do something about it."
Mr Croker also warned that there will be a lot of complex detail to be worked through before the policy could be enacted.
"Things like franked dividend tax offsets flow through a discretionary trust into the beneficiaries' hands, as do other types of offsets, for example, the entitlement to a foreign income tax offset if income has been derived offshore and foreign tax has been paid," he said.
"There are a number of drafting issues to be worked through."
'No justification' for excluding farm trusts from tax

Professor Deutsch also has one big bugbear with Labor's plan.
"I can't quite understand what is the policy basis for distinguishing between farmers and everybody else," he said.
"I understand there's a certain political imperative to do that but, from a policy perspective, I'm not sure that I can see what is the justification for it.
"I've been told that it's got to do with the fact that farmers have variable income, but I think that argument doesn't really withstand scrutiny."
Professor Deutsch warned that exceptions to the tax could open new avenues for tax minimisation.

"The detail of how they're going to define whether it's a farmer or a primary producer, that's what going to be interesting to see," he said.
The Chartered Accountants have offered their assistance with that process.
"We've contacted Andrew Leigh's people and said we're happy to help with the consultation process," Mr Croker said.
"Mr Shorten and Chris Bowen have said they did consult, but they haven't been consulting with our organisation."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chartered Accountants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Croker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council of Small</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COSBOA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Croker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RN Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Robert Deutsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Leigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Deutsch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tax Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Strong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chartered Accountants Australia New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
