<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398999739316445</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/motorsport/formula-one/f1-magnussen-and-hulkenberg-get-angry-alonso-chills-out-force-indias-lucky-escape/news-story/a6dc5f71b3e95ac796cc029e855c99f5</url>
  <title>F1: Magnussen and Hulkenberg get angry; Alonso chills out; Force India's lucky escape</title>
  <content>
Max's mistake costly for team
2:16

F1: Red Bull team principal Christian Horner discusses the Lap 1 clash between Max Verstappen and Daniel Ricciardo that put the Australian out of the Hungarian Grand Prix.

July 31st 2017
4 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Motorsport/

Kevin Magnussen took exception to Nico Hulkenberg's criticism.

Share

NICO Hulkenberg accused F1 rival Kevin Magnussen of being "nasty" after they argued over their Hungarian Grand Prix clash in front of television crews.
Hulkenberg found himself stuck behind 11th-placed Magnussen in the closing stage, having dropped back with a slow pitstop then caught up quickly on fresher tyres.
With nine laps to go, Hulkenberg attempted a pass around the outside of the tight Turn 2 left-hander but was forced onto the grass in a move that earned Magnussen a five-second time penalty.
During the post-race television interviews, Hulkenberg approached Magnussen and sarcastically commended him for being "once again the most unsporting driver".
Magnussen replied: "Suck my b****, mate."
Speaking to NBC after the spat, Hulkenberg said: "I congratulated him for being the most unsporting driver of the whole grid once again.
"When it comes to racing, he's just nasty.
"Hard defending is fine but when he does this, it's just ruthless and sending people into the wall.
"What he did there, opening up the steering, making me run wide, it's just being an a***hole basically.

"We had really nice words, he said (suck my b****), that was his return, so it's quite interesting with him."
Hulkenberg said he would bring the issue up with race direction: "I'll go and speak to Charlie (Whiting).
"I hear he got a bit of a penalty, five seconds, but in his mind he won't care about that too much."

Nico Hulkenberg.Source:Getty Images

Kevin Magnussen.Source:Getty Images
Haas boss Gunther Steiner believes Magnussen was right to hit back at "bully" Hulkenberg after their run-in.
Steiner argued Magnussen's defensive move was not over the limit, and criticised Hulkenberg for clashing with Haas's other driver Romain Grosjean at the first corner of the race.
"Nico was the guy who destroyed Romain's race," Steiner said. "And then we get a penalty with Kevin.
"Kevin did the right thing and stood his point there, in my opinion. Why would he lift?
"It's a tough battle, and Nico went to the stewards to ask for a harsher penalty of Kevin, which I think is childish, immature.
"Who has ever done that? I'm almost speechless.
"I respect Nico as a driver and as a human being, but what he did there - you don't ask for a more severe penalty for somebody."
Asked by Autosport whether Magnussen was right to use the words that he did in talking to Hulkenberg, Steiner stood by his driver: "It's the right way to say it. Why would he say anything else?
"He got a penalty, if he (Hulkenberg) thinks he (Magnussen) needs more (of a penalty), then he (Hulkenberg) needs to look at his Turn 1 incident.
"Is it sporting to run into Romain? (Hulkenberg) is a bully and he got away a long time with it and maybe now it's time that somebody stands up to him.
"He's a good driver, he doesn't need to be like this."
- ForixWire
ARGUMENT ARISES OVER ALONSO'S ANTICS

Fernando Alonso recreating his well-known scene.Source:Getty Images
Fernando Alonso finished sixth in Budapest and is clearly looking forward to the four-week summer break.
While race-winner Sebastian Vettel stood alongside Kimi Raikkonen (second) and Valtteri Bottas (third) on the podium, Alonso was elsewhere. Famously plonking himself in a deck chair and catching some sun after breaking down during qualifying at the 2015 Brazilian Grand Prix, the Spaniard was back at it in Hungary.
There's a painting at the Hungaroring of Alonso lounging back in a chair on the beach in honour of that iconic moment from two years ago. While the top three finishers were accepting their applause and champagne in Hungary, the Spaniard headed over to the mural and recreated the scene.
Fastest lap ✅
Best finish of the season ✅
Birthday weekend ✅
Time for  to relax  🇭🇺

Alonso has had a horror season courtesy of McLaren's technical problems and continued reliability issues with the team's Honda engines. The two-time world champion is as talented as any driver on the grid but hopes of another title appear further away than ever.
It's a shame noted by former F1 driver and Sky Sports pundit Martin Brundle.
Alonso prob better than 3 guys on podium. Sad he's joking in a deck chair, waste of talent and reminds team bosses why they don't want him

But his wasn't a position shared by everyone. Former teammate of Alonso, Jenson Button, hit back, saying the 36-year-old was just injecting a bit of fun into the sport.
Totally agree Martin, how dare an F1 driver have a personality and bring fun to a sport that sometimes takes itself way too seriously 🤦🏼‍♂️

My point JB is that Fernando is not a comedy act under a podium full of Ferrari/Merc drivers,he deserves to be up there fighting for champs

NEAR-MISS FOR ERROR-PRONE F1 TEAM

All's well that ends well for Esteban Ocon (L) and Sergio Perez (R).Source:Getty Images
Sergio Perez and Esteban Ocon both picked up championship points with ninth and 10th finishes respectively, but the Hungarian Grand Prix wasn't without its dramas for the Force India duo.
Perez ran into Ocon while exiting the first corner at the Hungaroring, causing damage to both cars.
"It was a pretty messy start," Ocon said. "I don't know what Sergio did but he probably missed a bit his braking point and ripped off my floor so it could have been a bit worse.
"At the end, it's a double points finish for the team, which is great looking at how difficult it was for us this weekend."
Perez was just happy to finish in the top 10 after struggling with his speed all weekend.
"It damaged my front wing, which didn't affect too much the balance but in general the picture wasn't good," Perez said. "It's been my worst weekend of the season in terms of speed.
"I've been struggling a lot with the car, so I'm glad we went forwards and scored good points."
The pair have endured a rocky road in 2017.  when the Mexican refused to let his teammate past to have a crack at chasing down Daniel Ricciardo, even though he was on fresher tyres.
, hitting each other and ruining any chance of walking away from Baku with points.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Magnussen.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fernando Alonso</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nico</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magnussen</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLaren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spaniards</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Brundle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hulkenberg</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gunther Steiner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Ricciardo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HAAS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Vettel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ForixWire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turn 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turn 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valtteri Bottas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perez</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Magnussen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Verstappen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Autosport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergio Perez</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenson Button</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nico Hulkenberg.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari/Merc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ocon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esteban Ocon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MISS FOR ERROR-PRONE F1 TEAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whiting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Force India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romain Grosjean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steiner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungaroring of Alonso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baku</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fernando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungaroring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lap 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alonso</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARISES OVER ALONSO'S ANTICS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F1</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimi Raikkonen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Horner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nico Hulkenberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
