<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398922429903863</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/weather/sydney-weather-citys-driest-july-since-1995-and-likely-second-warmest-20170731-gxm0i0.html</url>
  <title>Sydney weather: City's driest July since 1995 and likely second warmest</title>
  <content>
Sydney has posted its driest July in more than two decades but the city's parched parks and gardens should soon start to collect some much-needed rain.
The city's rain gauges gathered 12.6 millimetres as of the monthly cut-off of 9am on Monday, the least since 1995, according to Bureau of Meteorology data for Observatory Hill.

Up Next

Sydney weather: Summer cameos for weekend

01:32

More Environment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Joyce: ABC trying to 'create a calamity'

Deputy Prime Minister Barnaby Joyce tells patrons in a Shepparton pub that an ABC Four Corners report on the Murray-Darling basin plan was aimed at taking more water away from rural communities.

A rain band bringing Sydney's first rain in 16 days will arrive by the early afternoon and deliver falls of about 8-14 millimetres before conditions clear by the evening, Tom Hough, a meteorologist with Weatherzone, said.
While the odd shower is possible over the next few days, the arrival of another low pressure system on Thursday should bring the next chance of reasonable falls, Mr Hough said.

Sydney smashed its record July maximum temperature on Sunday with the mercury climbing to 26.5 degrees, a full 0.6 degrees above the previous high for the month set in 1990.
A slew of other records is likely to have been set across the state during the month. Brewarrina's 30.2 degrees on Sunday in the state's north-west was the first July reading above 30 degrees in NSW since 1958, the bureau said.

While Monday's top temperature for Sydney will still count towards the July figures - unlike rainfall where the monthly reading cuts off earlier - it's unlikely to shift the needle much from the average of 19.2 degrees set so far this month.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

That tally is shy only of the 19.45 degrees average maximum set in 2013, making it likely Sydney will post its second-warmest July by maximums in records that go back to 1858, Mr Hough said.Photo: Nick Moir
Dry, mild outlook

The near-term outlook is for a couple more fronts crossing southern Australia by the end of the weekend but neither of them will make much difference to Sydney's ongoing mild conditions, he said.
According to the Bureau of Meteorology's three-month outlook, most of southern Australia can expect relatively dry conditions to persist, particularly for August.
(See bureau chart below showing the odds of below-average rain for August.)

The dry winter and outlook  to warn of the possibility of an early and active fire season across southern Australia.
Meteorologists note the main driver for this winter's poor rainfall has been the more southerly location than usual of the high-pressure ridge over Australia. That has meant rain-bearing fronts have tended to be pushed further south than typical for winter, largely missing the continent.
The lack of cloud cover has also resulted in cold nights for many regions but also well-above average temperatures during the day.
On Saturday, Victoria matched its record July maximum temperature, with 27.1 degrees recorded at Mildura on the Murray. That equalled the temperature reached at Robinvale in July 1975.
The bureau's outlook for August-October points to continuing warmer-than-usual conditions, particularly for next month.
(See chart below showing the odds favour above-average temperatures for almost all of Australia.)

For Sydney, the coming week is likely to bring a narrow range of temperatures. Overnight lows will range between 8 and 10 degrees and daytime readings between 18 and 20 degrees, the bureau said.
Alpine regions, which have had a slow start to the season compared with a year ago, may collect a fresh layer of snow on Thursday with some sites collecting up to 10 centimetres, Mr Hough said.
 is owned by Fairfax Media, publisher of this website.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Observatory Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinvale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weatherzone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shepparton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August-October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alpine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Moir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mildura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Prime Minister Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brewarrina's 30.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hough</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1975</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
