<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399128588336925</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4822783/mckeon-enters-record-books/?cs=302</url>
  <title>McKeon claims best-ever medal haul and Swimming World Championships</title>
  <content>
SHINING LIGHT: Emma McKeon (second from left) claimed her sixth medal at the Swimming World Championships alongside medley relay teammates Bronte Campbell, Taylor McKeown and Emily Seebohm. Picture: AP

WOLLONGONG'S Emma McKeon has earned her own slice of swimming history, becoming the first Australian woman to claim six medals at a World Swimming Championships.

McKeon drew her huge  seven-event program to a close with a bronze medal as part of the women's 4x100m medley relay team on the final day of competition in Budapest.

Her six-medal tally, made up of four silver medals and two bronze, saw her better Libby Trickett's five medals achieved in 2005 and 2007. 
It means McKeon, who was also Australia's most decorated swimmer at last year's Rio Olympics, will leave Hungary with six of Australia's overall 10 medals.

It the Dolphins lowest medal return since 1991 and the first time since 1985 in which they finished outside the top five with Emily Seebohm's win in the 200m backstroke providing the lone gold.

McKeon has set her sights in helping Australia back to the top of the tally by claiming gold in the future.

"I gave it my all, and after an eight-day meet I'm pretty happy," McKeon said.
"Obviously I wasn't even thinking about medals at the beginning, but now that it's all over I didn't think I'd be on the podium six times this week.
"I think now I'll have a short break and get back in the pool, and inspired to make it a gold in the coming years, because that's what I want to achieve."
The women's medley relay bronze was one of two medals on the final day of competition in Hungary, with Mack Horton claiming bronze in the 1500m freestyle to go with his 400m silver medal.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKeon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Swimming Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WOLLONGONG'S Emma McKeon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swimming World Championships</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor McKeown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma McKeon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mack Horton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronte Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libby Trickett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Seebohm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
