<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399128588336908</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/police-search-bushland-for-body-of-nsw-schoolgirl-quanne-diec/news-story/505080e2000b90bed040c2d2b8f7a48c</url>
  <title>Renewed search for Quanne Diec</title>
  <content>
Police are scouring an area of dense bushland south of Sydney for the body of schoolgirl, Quanne Diec, who went missing on her way to school almost twenty years ago.
Detectives attached to Strike Force Lydney began the three day search at Appin Road in Cataract on Monday, following fresh information about the child's final resting place.
Quanne was abducted just a few hundred metres from her Granville home when she left to go to Strathfield Girls High School on the morning of July 27, 1998.
Quanne, who was then 12 years old, never arrived and was reported missing by her parents that afternoon.
Police said they are determined to return Diec's body to her parents and bring her family some closure.
"Police remain focused on finding Quanne's remains in hope of ending the Diec family's search for answers," NSW Police said in a statement. "The process has been an incredibly difficult experience for her family and we will continue to support them as the search continues."
Vinzent Tarantino, 49, also known as Victor Gerarda, who lived just 700 metres from the Diec family, was charged with the child's kidnapping and murder in November 2016, a matter that is still before the courts.
While Mr Tarantino led police to an area of bushland at Bulli Topps, near Wollongong late last year, the resulting exploration failed to locate the child's remains.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vinzent Tarantino, 49</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quanne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quanne Diec</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appin Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Granville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulli Topps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strike Force Lydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Gerarda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diec</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tarantino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathfield Girls' High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
