<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398999739316377</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/tv-ratings/she-was-truly-remarkable-princess-diana-documentary-wins-ratings-for-sunday-night/news-story/d052ffe1a72e288d13fdf73c049e8026</url>
  <title>'She was truly remarkable': Princess Diana documentary wins ratings for Sunday Night</title>
  <content>
New Princess Diana documentary tells her story through the eyes of her sons
1:31

Princes William and Harry talk about their late mother ahead of the 20th anniversary of her death in new HBO documentary. Rough cut (no reporter narration)

July 23rd 2017
8 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

A documentary about Princess Diana's life has pulled a huge ratings audience for Seven. Picture: Getty Images

Colin Vickery and Nadia SalemmeNews Corp Australia Network

Share

A STIRRING documentary about Princess Diana's life has pulled a huge audience for Seven.
Diana, Our Mother, her Life and Legacy, which featured emotionally-charged interviews with her sons Prince William and Prince Harry, averaged 1.334 million viewers across the five capital cities for Seven's Sunday Night.
It beat the launches of The Block and Australian Survivor, with The Block averaging 1.117 million viewers.

Prince Harry and Prince William opened up about the death of their mother. Picture: Sunday NightSource:Supplied

Prince Harry spoke candidly in Diana, Our Mother, her Life and Legacy. Picture: Sunday NightSource:Supplied

Princess Diana, pictured with her sons Prince William (left) and Prince Harry, on a ski holiday in 1993. Picture: Getty ImagesSource:Supplied
Sunday Night viewers took to social media to praise the candid documentary.
She was truly remarkable and will never be forgotten ❤
Thank you  for sharing her loves, and her legacy.
Great to hear Prince William take a swipe at the vile tabloid media. Treatment of  & her invasion of privacy was appalling.
Wow  we hear "television event" so often. But that was one. Stunning.
In an emotional admission, the pair both revealed , when they were holidaying at Balmoral while she was in Paris.
They reportedly hadn't seen her in a month.
"Harry and I were just in a desperate rush to say goodbye," Prince William said, adding the pair were playing with their cousins at the time.
"If I'd known now obviously what was going to happen I wouldn't have been so blase about it and everything else.
Meantime, the big ratings loser on screens last night was Ten's Australian Survivor which stumbled on 639,000 viewers.

That is a significant drop from last year's launch figure of 783,000.
Ten will be hoping more viewers will tune into tonight and tomorrow night's episodes of the Jonathan LaPaglia hosted reality show - but Seven could spoil that plan.
Seven has another Diana special - Diana's Death: The Search for the Truth - set to screen tomorrow night.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten's Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Vickery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan LaPaglia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balmoral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Night</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nadia SalemmeNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty ImagesSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven's Sunday Night</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana's Death</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday NightSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
