<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399008329251165</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/star-whores-gay-club-show-raising-eyebrows/3206953/</url>
  <title>Star Whores: The gay club show raising eyebrows</title>
  <content>
DARWIN's gay nightclub, Throb, has come under fire from the Top End's sex workers for its controversial new show.

The club, which is famous for drag queen performances, is advertising a new show: Star Whores with appearances from 'Luke Street Walker', 'Jabba The Slut' and 'Princess Layher'.

Some of the Top End's sex workers have responded to it with disgust, saying it "disrespects" their line of work.

Sex worker Ryan Cole posted her disappointment to Throb's Facebook page.

"You can't expect to make stigmatising posters appropriating parts of our lives you find funny or entertaining, use slurs and encourage people to dehumanise us, and think that people won't be upset," she posed to Throb's page.

"The problem is not that people are choosing to be offended, the problem is that it IS offensive.

"I am a lesbian and a sex worker and I can't split myself up into parts and just attend as a lesbian but not a sex worker."

Others equated the show's inappropriateness to "a group of sex workers having a 'fag/poofta night' or similar".

Catherine Gray, a BBW fetish escort, was unimpressed.

"I've been going to Throb for over 12 years now, but as a queer sex worker I definitely no longer feel safe," she wrote.

"The disrespect shown to sex workers is deplorable and inexcusable - both because of their chosen branding containing slurs/stigmatising language (whore, ho, streetwalker), and because of the performers actively trawling comment sections to fight with sex workers who are rightfully upset about this marketing decision.

"Whore belongs to us, get your own word."

Amelie La Roux also posted to the club's page.

"Hey Throb, just because you're a gay club doesn't mean you get to use disgusting and problematic slurs in your marketing in an attempt to be 'edgy'," she wrote.

Performer Kearan Marsh responded with comments including: "You're coming to an adult venue. Be an adult and grow up", and "If you're offended, don't see it, don't comment on it and go about your merry life".

The responses have since been deleted.

Throb did not respond to interview requests by deadline.

Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
MUCH-loved Sunshine Coast sportsman dies in tragic circumstances
Coast man hospitalised after an argument turns violent
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Layher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Whores</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top End</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Street Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Throb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kearan Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Throb's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amelie La Roux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Cole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
