<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398883775197400</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/advocates-supporting-homeless-in-frankston-say-small-act-of-kindness-can-make-huge-difference/news-story/f5c9096f103d2be5edd64d24a65c329b</url>
  <title>Call for warm clothing to help homeless</title>
  <content>
FRANKSTON Homelessness Network is calling on residents to donate new or freshly laundered winter jackets to aid the disadvantaged.
Community Support Frankston manager Steve Phillips said winter was a difficult and dangerous time for some.
"Everyone knows of someone that's fallen on hard times, it impacts us all," he said.
"A small act of kindness can make a big difference to someone whose feeling hopeless.
"With increasing amounts of people in Frankston seeking assistance with basic needs in times of crisis, staying warm and adequately fed is essential to some people's survival during the cold winter months."
Mr Phillips made the comments as part of Homeless Person's Week, (August 7-13), which raises awareness about homelessness.
He said the donated coats would be distributed to disadvantaged locals at a free community event on August 3.
Other services such as warm showers, food, haircuts and more will also be provided for free at the event.
Mayor Brian Cunial urged people to support those in need.
"You could make someone's day with a simple gesture of donating a warm winter coat," he said.
"Helping someone less fortunate is exactly what community spirit is all about and we have plenty of goodwill to share around here in Frankston."
Community Support Frankston is also calling for donations of new sweaters, socks/underpants,
beanies, gloves, sleeping bags, blankets and non-perishable food items.
Donated items must be new and unused and can be delivered in person to Community Support Frankston, 35-39 Beach St Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday and Friday (9am to 4pm) and Thursday (1pm to 4pm).
Second hand items should be taken to a local opportunity shop. Details: 9783 7284.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach St Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Support Frankston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Support Frankston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Brian Cunial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday (1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday (9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeless Person's Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FRANKSTON Homelessness Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
