<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399132883304332</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/breaking-news/liberal-trio-push-for-vote-on-gay-marriage/news-story/6a4dec3c147005e1d035a255c37a2680</url>
  <title>Liberals push for gay marriage resolution</title>
  <content>
Liberal MPs are urging Malcolm Turnbull to resolve the issue of same-sex marriage before the next election.
A Liberal partyroom meeting in Canberra next week - the first since parliament's long winter break - is expected to hear from a number of MPs floating options to bring the issue to a head.
"It's going to be the elephant in the room," one Liberal MP told AAP on Monday.
A growing number of MPs is pressing for a conscience vote on a private bill now that the parliamentary battle for a plebiscite has been lost.
Openly gay Brisbane MP Trevor Evans says a conscience vote is the "quickest and most likely course".
Colleague Tim Wilson argues Liberal MPs have discharged their responsibility to honour the party's election promise for a plebiscite.
"It's in our best interests to move on from this issue so we can focus on the sorts of things I think people voted for me and for my party to deal with - tax reform, fixing the budget, national security," he told Sky News.
"I also have a personal conflict which torments, frankly, and challenges me on a daily basis and I'd like to see this issue resolved."
Liberal senator Dean Smith says the issue is putting lead in the party's saddle bags.
"The government should not feel obligated to commit political suicide by handing its opponents a massive political cudgel by allowing the question of marriage equality to remain unresolved and fester over the next two years," Senator Smith wrote in the Australian Financial Review.
He has a private bill legalising same-sex marriage that he wants put on the Senate notice paper, which could be introduced as early as August 17.
While the coalition agreement between the Liberals and Nationals has never been publicly released, it is understood to cement in place a commitment to a plebiscite as the sole path to same-sex marriage.
Any breach of the deal is likely to seriously impact on relations between the two parties.
However, Mr Wilson says the right to a conscience vote held by all Liberal MPs could not be "traded away".
A Liberal MP told AAP most of his colleagues did not want the issue to be taken to the next election.
One option being floated is to recommit the plebiscite bill to parliament, but make it clear that if the bill fails again, the government will hold a voluntary postal plebiscite.
The latest move has angered the Australian Christian Lobby.
"It is disappointing that so many Liberals do not seem to respect the people who elected them," managing director Lyle Shelton said in a statement.
A petition, with almost 48,000 signatures, that calls for the plebiscite to proceed will be presented to parliament next week.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyle Shelton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane MP Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Christian Lobby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
