<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399300387030845</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/national/uni-wars-as-cqu-competes-against-jcu-with-547m-worth-of-new-projects-for-cairns/news-story/35a8f64040d1ac5791b6582b5db06d00</url>
  <title>Game on, as CQU takes on JCU in Cairns</title>
  <content>
UNI wars have broken out in Cairns, with CQUniversity declaring it is actively going to compete for students and research against James Cook University.
CQU has announced $54.7 million worth of new projects for Cairns, incorporating performing arts, indigenous studies, aviation excellence, and sports science.
The Rockhampton-headquartered university, which established its campus in Cairns' CBD less than two years ago, has previously indicated it would only offer courses to complement those offered by JCU.
However CQUniversity Vice Chancellor Professor Scott Bowman acknowledged his university would, for the first time, be actively competing with JCU by offering the same courses in Cairns, such as sports science and indigenous studies.
"Let's not kid ourselves, there will be some competition with JCU, but I don't think competition will be such a bad thing," he said.
"I think it drives quality, and I think that's what you'll see here, in the city at the moment: two really great providers, providing mostly different things - some things the same - but even when they are providing some things which are the same, delivering it in very different ways.
"If that's game on, then bring it on."
The university currently services 1000 students at its Cairns Square campus on the corner of Abbott and Shields streets, but estimates this will grow to more than 2500 after the expansion is complete.
The new projects include a new, expanded Cairns CBD campus - possibly including expanding the current Cairns Square site; a $16 million aviation hub at Cairns International Airport; a $1.2 million First People's Think Tank and Research Centre; a $2.5 million Creative and Performing Arts Precinct; a $2.5 million research extension for indigenous health and education, and regional tourism; and a $2.5 million Professional Sports Centre of Excellence, to be based at Cairns Basketball Stadium.
Prof Bowman said the university would be seeking federal funding to develop its projects.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton-headquartered</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQUniversity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns International Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Basketball Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cook University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Square</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQUniversity Vice Chancellor Professor Scott Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JCU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns' CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Performing Arts Precinct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First People's Think Tank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professional Sports Centre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Research Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
