<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399171538010456</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/ban-the-draw-why-footy-needs-overtime-and-a-shootout-20170731-gxm4ud.html</url>
  <title>Ban the draw: Why footy needs overtime and a shootout</title>
  <content>
A 1998 study on sports spectators published in the Physiology and Behaviour Journal showed that fans experienced a physiological response dependant on how their team played.
Fans watching their team win had increased levels of testosterone, while fans watching their team lose experienced reduced testosterone levels. Even without the scientific evidence, it is easy as a football fan to relate to the feeling of satisfaction or disappointment that accompanies a result.

Up Next

Cloke kicks a cracker

00:28

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

It is a similar story as a player, where the nourishment that comes from a win provides energy to the playing group that can be incredibly valuable as the year goes on.
Sunday's game between Collingwood and Adelaide was one of the games of the year but left supporters and players alike with neither the high of victory or the low of defeat. After such an epic battle, it doesn't seem fitting that there was no victor, and I feel it's time we explore some options so that the emptiness that a draw brings for all involved is gone from our game.Photo: Michael Willson/AFL Media
There is a strong desire among most fans to stop tinkering with footy, and the rules and interpretations. There is also a fierce desire to protect the idiosyncrasies in our game which continue to make it unique when compared with other ball sports around the globe. But there is also noise from many fans that the game has been as exciting this year as it's ever been, and some of the changes to rules and interpretations in recent years have played a role in that.
With that in mind, I'd like to see overtime added to matches that end in a draw. Rather than have a golden goal, which is unfair to any team that is kicking into the wind, I'd like to see two three-minute halves added on to regular time. Five minutes would probably be preferred by the fans (and TV stations) but knowing just how fatigued players are at the end of the game, I think the shortest possible time at each end but still giving a good chance for a result is the best option.

If scores are still level at the end of overtime, I'd like to see a goal shootout, but with a twist that makes it unique to the AFL and allays fears that we're turning into soccer.
The goal shootout would be the same as any other set shot kick after the siren. There'd be a man on the mark, and the rest of the team on the goal line trying to touch the ball. If one team misses their goal attempt while the opposing team kicks theirs, the shootout is over.Photo: AFL Media/Getty Images
The uniqueness comes from the home team choosing where each set shot takes place from. If Adelaide were the home team for instance, they could have Eddie Betts pick a spot near the boundary line utilising his incredible skill at banana kicks; if their opponent was able to match Eddie's effort, they could take their second set shot from 65 metres out using Tex Walker's booming right foot to their advantage.
Having overtime allows the AFL to capitalise on milking a little bit more out of the most exciting games of the year, a goal shootout that isn't from the same designated spot is a clear differentiation from a penalty shootout in soccer, and ensuring every game has a winner and loser reduces the risk for the number of games in round 23 that count for nothing as it's more likely teams will be on a similar number of points at season's end.Photo: AFL Media/Getty Images
While the extra time during Saturday and Sunday afternoon games would challenge the Channel Seven newsroom, the lead-in from such a close game and extra advertising opportunities would outweigh the negatives of a condensed news offering.
But most importantly, there'd be a completeness to the battle that's occurred in the arena, and a more genuine meaning attributed to the exhaustion experienced by the players who have put on the show.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Media/Getty Images</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tex Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Behaviour Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Willson/AFL Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
