<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399266027292113</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/last-minute-sale-saves-coast-gym-from-closure/3206987/</url>
  <title>Last minute sale saves Coast gym from closure</title>
  <content>
MEMBERS of a much-loved Coast gym are celebrating after the centre was brought back from the brink of closure with a last minute sale.
Owners of Buderim's MyBody Women's Health and Fitness announced the gym would close early next month via Facebook last week due to their "personal and financial situation".
Previous attempts to sell the business were unsuccessful, but now husband and wife duo Kate and James Boileau will take over on August 14 with a seven-day free trial offer.
The gym has been popular with older women due to its range of fitness classes and its community spirit.
Mrs Boileau said the decision to buy the gym stemmed from how highly she thought of the business.
"I've been a member here since February," she said.
"The women here have been the most beautiful, supportive, community for me.
"When we heard the gym was closing James and I just decided to take a look and it was a great opportunity."
The pair have decades of experience between them in the fitness industry with Mr Boileau a qualified remedial massage therapist, personal trainer and group fitness trainer and Mrs Boileau a former Les Mills instructor.
"We will be offering the classes that are already existing here, plus putting on some new classes," Mrs Boileau said.
"Also, he'll be working as a massage therapist here as well.
"We're really excited about it."
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
MUCH-loved Sunshine Coast sportsman dies in tragic circumstances
Coast man hospitalised after an argument turns violent
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Boileau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim's MyBody Women's Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Boileau</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Boileau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
