<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399137178271677</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/woman-slams-toowoomba-kfc-after-pathetic-meal/3206846/</url>
  <title>Woman slams Toowoomba KFC after 'pathetic' meal</title>
  <content>
A TOOWOOMBA woman has slammed KFC at Grand Central after receiving what she describes as a ''pathetic'' meal.

Karissa Gesler ordered a Dippin' Box at the weekend.

A Dippin' Box consists of two original tenders, four nuggets, snack popcorn chicken, small hot gravy, regular chips, a Pepsi Max, dinner roll and two dippin' sauces. 

What she received was quite different and was a far cry from the deliciously displayed photo on the KFC adverts.

Dippin' Box as it appears on the KFC website.

She said she was not happy with the customer service or meal.

"I ordered a Dippin' Box and instead of telling me they were out of bread rolls, they just chucked a bread bun in there and instead of chicken dippers (they) just threw in grilled chicken," she said.

"This is what happens when you have nothing but 12-year-olds working. So mad.

>>>RELATED: Warwick man epicly slams KFC, instantly goes viral

"They just hope and pray that you'll leave without realising there was a stuff up. Pathetic."

It's not the first time KFC at Grand Central has left a customer unhappy.

KFC burger. Expectation vs reality
Last year Peter Terrill order a limited-edition Kentucky pulled pork burger, which contained pulled pork, coleslaw and barbecue sauce on a brioche bun.

He said it wasn't only the look of the burger that he was disappointed with, it was also cold and had barely any pork.

"I took two bites out of it and it was cold in the middle and there was a teaspoon amount of shredded pork," he said.

"We don't eat fast food much these days because we are older we can't handle it as well, so when we do decide to eat out, we shouldn't have to cop this."

A representative from KFC head office apologised for Mr Terrill's unpleasant experience. 

KFC Grand Central was contacted but unable to comment on Ms Gesler's matter. KFC Australia has been contacted for comment. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dippin' Box</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kentucky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Terrill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Central</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karissa Gesler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gesler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Terrill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pepsi Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KFC Grand Central</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba KFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
