<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398913839968962</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/victorian-bishops-say-assisted-dying-laws-will-abandon-those-in-greatest-need-20170731-gxm10v.html</url>
  <title>Victorian bishops say assisted dying laws will abandon those 'in greatest need' </title>
  <content>
Christian leaders in Victoria have combined to voice their opposition to proposed voluntary euthanasia laws,  arguing assisted dying would be akin to killing off the terminally sick and elderly.
An open letter signed by local leaders of the Catholic, Anglican, Lutheran, Greek Orthodox and Coptic Orthodox churches, among others, argues that a decision to legalise assisted dying would also "send a confusing message" about the value of life to those at risk of suicide.    

Up Next

Unusually dry winter wreaks havoc for farmers

01:51

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Euthanasia around the world

Advocate Andrew Denton speaks about Australia's role in spreading euthanasia laws around the globe.

"Euthanasia and assisted suicide represent the abandonment of those who are in greatest need of our care and support," says the letter, which appeared as an advertisement in the Herald Sun on Monday.
Two Melbourne archbishops and five bishops signed the letter, including Catholic Archbishop Denis Hart, Anglican Archbishop Philip Freier​ and Greek Orthodox Bishop Ezekiel.

"No 'safeguards' will ever guarantee that deaths under the proposed laws will be completely voluntary," the letter says.
"There will always be a risk of error, fraud or coercion."

It also argues the laws could lead some terminally ill people to feel social pressure to take the option. 

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"When euthanasia or assisted suicide is an ever present - even if unspoken - option, how long will it be before the option becomes an expectation?"Photo: Jason South
The letter is an appeal to Victoria's 2.8 million Christians, who make up almost half of the state's population, according to 2016 census data.
This figure includes 1.37 million Catholics and 530,000 Anglicans, which are the state's two most biggest religious affiliations, although the census also revealed a decline in Christian affiliation and a sharp rise in those who identify as having no religion.Photo: Supplied
The open letter follows a cross-party committee of MPs' recommendation that Victoria come up with a bill to legalise assisted dying.
The Andrews government plans to introduce the bill for debate later this year, and has accepted all 66 recommendations made in a report written by an expert panel chaired by former Australian Medical Association president Brian Owler.Photo: Luis Enrique Ascui
Victorian MPs will get a conscience vote on the proposed laws and will not vote along party lines, with the exception of the Greens who have a policy in support of assisted dying.
The outcome of the vote is uncertain.Photo: Paul Jeffers
The model proposed by the expert panel has been described as "the most conservative in the world" and contains 68 safeguards against its potential misuse or abuse.
If adopted, anyone who asked to die would go through a three-step request, beginning with a verbal request, followed by a formal written request, then a final verbal request.Photo: Ken Irwin
At least 10 days would pass between the first and final request, unless the person is assessed as likely to die within 10 days.
In releasing the panel's report, Health Minister Jill Hennessy said Victoria's coroner had found evidence that "up to one person a week was currently taking their own life due to the absence of assisted dying here in Victoria".Photo: Jason South
"It is my very firm personal view that we need to do better by those who are dying, those who are terminally ill, those who are bearing suffering that is unspeakable," Ms Hennessy said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coptic Orthodox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Irwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hennessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican Archbishop Philip Freier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Jill Hennessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Owler.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Enrique Ascui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic Archbishop Denis Hart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's 2.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek Orthodox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason South</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lutherans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek Orthodox Bishop Ezekiel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
