<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399266027292125</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/07/ask-lh-whats-a-good-outfit-for-a-big-dude/</url>
  <title>Ask LH: Where Can A Large Dude Find Decent Clothes?</title>
  <content>
Dear Lifehacker, I am fairly tall (6'8") and I have trouble finding clothes that fit me well. Any tips for coming up with a "daily uniform" for the tall guys out there? I could really use some good places to shop and suggestions for what I should look out for. Thanks, Big Fella

image from Shutterstock

Dear BF,

6'8" is "fairly tall"? What are you, a Maasai warrior?

But anyway. As a vertically challenged short-arse, I'm not remotely qualified to answer this question. You need advice from a professional stylist instead. Evan Wolkenstein runs the self-explanatory website  and knows what looks good on every conceivable body shape. Here's what he had to say about big fellas finding clothes that fit:

There is no easy-fix, I'm afraid - it all depends on the offerings of the shops where you'd like to find your gear. Plenty of fashion labels and retail outlets offer clothing specifically for tall dudes. But it's still gotta fit right. That requires you, as I do, to get familiar with which shops' ideas of "fit" match your own.
As a tall man, you can play to your strengths by finding an awesome tailor; some of the clothing for tall men may also be too big. This is why my tailor is on my "Top-10 most important people in my life" list. (I'm sure the other nine wouldn't be thrilled to know that). It will typically cost you under $100 bucks to turn a "meh" fitting shirt into a made-for-you garment.
As for a uniform, there is no "tall dude" uniform - but I will say this: patterns that give you structure (gingham is the holy grail of structure-building pattenrns) will help fill out your proportions.
Pair some dressy pants or dark denim with some wingtips or a pair of desert boots; get a few oxford shirts, a few gingham shirts, a chambray or two and pair with a knit tie, and you'll have the beginning of a uniform.

If you're large in girth as well as height, this video contains some useful style tips for big men:

Hope this helps! We'd also like to hear from our rangy readers: if you have any style tips for taller men, let BF know in the comments section below.

Laura Wells and Jesse McNeilly are Australian models who have forged a successful career in the "plus size" modelling industry. If you're similarly big 'n' beautiful, their advice could prove indispensable in landing your first modelling contract. Read on to discover what you need to get started.

Cheers
Lifehacker

Got your own question you want to put to Lifehacker? Send it using our  on the right.

WATCH MORE: Tech News & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Can A Large Dude Find Decent Clothes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dear Lifehacker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shutterstock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Fella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifehacker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dear BF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maasai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse McNeilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evan Wolkenstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
