<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399175832977828</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/food/your-favourite-dinner-recipes-with-a-healthy-twist/news-story/32eb1933778fdbf6b1bdffcde9ca52af</url>
  <title>A week of healthy dinner recipes</title>
  <content>
YOUR favourite dinner recipes have had a healthy makeover. Think pizza and pasta without the guilt, and curry recipes better than takeaway.
MONDAY
Meat-free Mondays are super easy with this  recipe. This dish is praised for its immunity boosting qualities, which are exactly what you need in flu season. Whip this dish up in no time and top with extra greens if you feel a nutrient hit is in order.
TUESDAY
Healthy winter cooking should be all about simple, tasty dishes that leave you feeling satisfied. Which is why this  is so perfect. Full of fresh seasonal produce, this dinner requires very few ingredients, barely any time to throw together, and it's going to go down a treat as well.
WEDNESDAY
No matter how buggered you are come Wednesday night, this  is going to be just as easy to cook, as it would be to order takeaway. Fresh and full of flavour, this dinner is one you'll feel better after eating and makes a great lunch if you have any leftover.
THURSDAY
There is no dish more delightful to arrive home to than a . Let this ragu simmer away in the pot all day and throw on the pasta or some easy-to-make couscous once you're home. Then just top with fresh herbs and you're ready to tuck into that tender lamb in a rich tomatoey sauce.
FRIDAY
Friday should be all about simple, tasty meals. And wine, it should always be about wine. Luckily, a glass of pinot noir will go down a treat with this  from . Served with glassy rice noodles this dish is the healthy version of takeaway, but you won't even notice the healthy bit.
SATURDAY
For a healthy dinner option this Saturday night why not get your hands dirty by making your own cauliflower pizza bases. These  are great for entertaining. Mix up your toppings, combining any combination of Italian flavours you prefer. Or if you're that person that likes to keep the party in the kitchen, get your friends or family to top their own pizza and everyone can devour their own creation.
SUNDAY
No one is going to notice that this  is completely void of mince. It is rich, inviting and packed full of flavour, perfect for Sunday night dinner at home with the family. Vegetarian lasagne takes the same amount of time to cook, still goes great with garlic bread and freezes for up to a month. So you'll have a healthy home-cooked meal on hand after a long day at work.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
