<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399223077618729</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/07/31/threat-will-dictate-strengthened-airport-security</url>
  <title>Threat 'will dictate' strengthened airport security</title>
  <content>
New security checks will be enforced at Australian airports if the terrorism threat demands it, the federal government says.

3 MINS AGO  UPDATED 1 MIN AGO

Australian travellers will face new airport security measures if the terrorism threat dictates there's a need, according to the Border Security Minister Peter Dutton.

Security checks have been ramped up at Australia's domestic and international airports after a Sydney-based plot to bomb a passenger plane was foiled at the weekend.

Screening for explosives has escalated and there's a heavy police presence at airports after four Sydney men were arrested on Saturday, accused of plotting to bring down a plane mid-flight.

Major Sydney counter-terror raids disrupt plot to bring down aircraft

The strengthened security checks have caused long delays at major airports over the past two days. Those measures will remain in place indefinitely, Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull said on Monday, but would not provide further details about the plot, including whether it involved a bomb or gas attack.

We encourage all passengers to arrive early today due to additional security measures in place. We appreciate your patience.
- Sydney Airport ✈️ (@SydneyAirport)

Mr Dutton has appealed for patience and help as travellers deal with a new normal: two hour check-ins for domestic flights, and three hours for international flights.

He says people should not be passing through airport security check points unless they are travelling, and he's urged all Australians to act as eyes and ears for security agencies.

Related Reading

Asked if the government would consider calls for photo identification for all domestic travellers, Mr Dutton said the government was looking at security arrangements for domestic and international airports.

"If the threat dictates that there is an additional measure or measures that are required, then they will be implemented," he said.

"But at the moment we're acting on the advice from the experts that have all the detail available and we've responded accordingly."

Mr Dutton said there "could be" further arrests over the plot, and anyone who might have a shred of information that might help investigators should call the terrorism hotline.

"These people do have the capacity, through the internet or through instruction otherwise, they have the ability to bring the skill together to execute a plan to bring down a plane, or to bring some device onto a plane," he told ABC television.

"This threat is not going away; it's not abating at all. Anybody with information please provide that to the authorities. We are living in a very uncertain time."

Exceptional work   airport staff managing heightened security measures (+ huge queues). Professional & not a whiff of chaos!
- Joseph Scales (@JosephScales)

Airlines are now enforcing the new two and three-hour arrival advice for domestic and international travellers, and passengers appear to be heeding the new arrangement.

Australian Federal Police Commissioner Andrew Colvin also flagged possible long-term changes, saying security measures were "always" under review.

Brisbane Airport said passengers should prepare themselves for a ramped up police presence, and slower security processing, and more trace testing for explosives.

A Melbourne Airport spokesperson said passengers "should not be concerned" about enhanced security.

"As the measures place an additional burden on the screening system, it may take a little longer than usual to get through the process," they said.

Travellers should "allow ample time for screening and limit the amount of carry-on and checked baggage they travel with" to help ensure efficient security screening, they added.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JosephScales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 1 MIN AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dutton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SydneyAirport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police Commissioner Andrew Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border Security Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Scales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
