<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399304681998254</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/tinder-date-slasher-found-guilty-but-walks-free-20170731-gxm67i.html</url>
  <title>Tinder date slasher found guilty, but walks free</title>
  <content>
A woman who slashed her Tinder date with a kitchen knife after she found out he was already in a relationship has avoided spending time behind bars.
Alana Rose Jones, 26, was sentenced in the Brisbane District Court on Monday to 18 months' jail with immediate parole after pleading guilty to wounding and assault occasioning bodily harm.Photo: Bloomberg
The court heard Jones spent the afternoon drinking at numerous venues with her date in February 2015 before he suggested they go back to her place.
Later that evening while the man was passed out, Jones intercepted text messages from his partner asking where he was.
Jones called the woman and told her they had slept together, but the girlfriend insisted she come to collect him to make sure he was safe.
When the man woke up Jones told him to "get the f--- out" before fetching a kitchen knife, grabbing him by the throat and swinging the blade.

The man suffered a minor cut to his forearm trying to defend himself, although Judge Alexander Horneman-Wren said that was more good fortune than anything else.
"The kitchen knife could have done substantial damage to him," Judge Horneman-Wren said.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

After the man left, Jones called triple-0 saying she thought she had stabbed a man who attacked her in her unit.
The court heard while on bail for the wounding offence, Jones punched a 22-year-old woman in the side of the face seemingly for no reason at all while out drinking in Fortitude Valley.
The woman, who was a stranger to Jones, suffered temporary blindness, a bloody nose and a chipped front tooth.
Judge Horneman-Wren said Jones clearly needed personal deterrence from committing violent offences but noted she had taken steps towards rehabilitation.
AAP 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alana Rose Jones, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Horneman-Wren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortitude Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Alexander Horneman-Wren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
