<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399472185724816</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4823257/merrick-doesnt-want-excuses-in-maitland-trial/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Merrick doesn't want excuses in Maitland trial</title>
  <content>
Merrick doesn't want excuses in Maitland trial

exit

Jets coach Ernie Merrick says his side cannot use the firmness of the Cooks Square Park pitch as an "excuse" when they play Maitland in a trial on Wednesday.

Broadmeadow coach Ruben Zadkovich likened the surface to concrete after his side played there on Sunday, and Magpies coach Phil Dando agreed it could "do with a good water".

Maitland's Matt Comerford (hamstring) and Magic's Jon Griffiths (ankle) and Josh Piddington (knee) emerged from the game with soft-tissue injuries.

But Merrick clearly wants his side to perform well regardless of the conditions after an unconvincing 2-0 win over Weston, improved 5-1 triumph over Magic and disappointing 2-0 loss to the Mariners in their three pre-season games to date.

"Whatever it takes, it takes. We've got to get [rid of] all these excuses. I'm happy that it's not in great condition," he said.

"Not many players will play more than half a game, 60 minutes, anyway, so if they can't cope with it, then that's their problem. They've got to overcome all these excuses not to play well." 
Zadkovich, a former Jets midfielder, said the pitch was "not ideal". 
"But professional footballers it's just your job," he said. "I remember games we had to do it as well when I was a player there at the Jets.

"I'm sure Ernie will have to manage his boys properly and make sure their loads aren't too high on that ground, because they certainly won't be used to it.

"As long as they're careful and both teams play the game in the right spirit, then hopefully no injuries for them."
Maitland captain Matt Thompson will miss the game after having stitches in his eye after an accidental head clash on Sunday.
Dando said he was unlikely to risk the in-form Comerford before Maitland's season goes on the line against Lambton on Saturday.  
"Our problem is to find a fit 11 to put on the park," he said. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Dando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zadkovich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland's Matt Comerford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Piddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie Merrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic's Jon Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooks Square Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comerford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruben Zadkovich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
