<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399390581345216</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/greater-western-sydney-giants/gws-giant-jeremy-cameron-reinjures-hamstring-20170731-gxm53l.html</url>
  <title>GWS Giant Jeremy Cameron re-injures hamstring</title>
  <content>
Giants spearhead Jeremy Cameron has re-injured his right hamstring in a massive blow for GWS and will miss at least three more weeks after suffering a grade-two tear in Saturday's win over Fremantle.
kicking a goal, and played on after copping a painful knock in the second quarter.

Up Next

Cloke kicks a cracker

00:28

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

and now faces a stint on the sideline that could potentially wipe him out for the rest of the regular season.
Medical staff are hopeful he'll return for the final-round blockbuster against Geelong at Simonds Stadium, but they could be tempted to rest him for another two weeks so he's right for the first week of the finals.

"It was no particular incident, he got a hit in his back in the second quarter and felt some symptoms down that leg," GWS head of athletic performance David Joyce said.
"He actually presented worse post-match so we scanned him and unfortunately it's revealed he's got a hamstring strain. 

"He tested really well throughout the second half. We went out repeatedly just to check on him and he was fine. We specifically tested him at three-quarter time and he was fine."
during which his hamstring was tested about 15 times throughout the game.Photo: Getty Images
"There's no reason why he shouldn't have played the game, he was absolutely fine," Joyce said.
"We'd done all the testing, he'd completed the training loads, he couldn't have been more prepared.
"He wasn't rushed back, it was just one of those unfortunate things. It probably means we need to be extra cautious with him now.
"You've got to play the ball that's in front of you but it will certainly come into our mind that we might be even more conservative."
GWS face Melbourne in Canberra on Saturday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giant Jeremy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
