<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399476480692168</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/breaking-news/toddler-suddenly-disappeared-nsw-court/news-story/f17916255c4df5522eb6aea01c966e7a</url>
  <title>Toddler suddenly disappeared: NSW court</title>
  <content>
The toddler daughter of a NSW woman who allegedly talked about sacrificing a child to a "wolfman" suddenly disappeared from a block of units where she lived, a court has heard.
Neighbour Ellen Campbell told the Newcastle Supreme Court on Monday she'd been suspicious about what happened to the toddler.
The child's mother, 44, who cannot be named for legal reasons, has pleaded not guilty to murdering the little girl between Christmas 2000 and Christmas 2001.
Ms Campbell told the court she had been a stay-at-home mum living in a block of units in the Hunter region when she regularly tried to talk to the accused woman but was ignored.
She used to see the woman putting out baby clothes on the line but "all of a sudden" this stopped, which Ms Campbell thought was "really weird".
Ms Campbell at one stage asked the woman where her baby was but she didn't reply.
She described how the curtains were always drawn in the woman's flat and she never turned the lights on. The only thing she could see inside the flat was a candle flickering.
Another witness, Valerie Seymour, told the court she and her late husband, Maurice, had owned the block of units where the accused woman was living with her toddler and they became quite close.
Ms Seymour said the woman wouldn't let the toddler outside unless Maurice was there because she was frightened somebody would grab the little girl.
The woman also had to be moved to another unit after she became convinced someone was living in the roof.
It was after Christmas 2000 when the woman told the Seymours her daughter was being looked after by another couple until she had "pulled herself together".
After visiting the woman one day, Mr Seymour told his wife he was absolutely amazed there was not one photo of the toddler in the woman's unit.
"He couldn't believe it," Ms Seymour said on Monday.
The accused woman later moved to an isolated area in the Hunter region where she gave birth to another girl in late 2003.
Ms Seymour said her husband again visited the woman and returned home to describe how he thought this girl, who was later taken away by authorities, had been starving.
The woman was feeding the girl a bottle of water and some grapes.
"He (Maurice) thought she looked like a Third World baby. She couldn't cry anymore. She was just limp in (the woman's) hands," Ms Seymour said.
The court has been told the woman talked about having to slit a child's throat for the wolfman before her first daughter disappeared.
The sacrifice would mean she would then be allowed to go home with aliens.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas 2000</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas 2001</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maurice</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valerie Seymour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellen Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Third World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Campbell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Seymour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Seymour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seymour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
