<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399347631671642</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/cairns-chamber-of-commerce-boss-deb-hancock-resigns-and-leaves-strong-legacy/news-story/69ccb69bcf6a566d8973298672c86bbf</url>
  <title>Chamber boss bows out</title>
  <content>
THE leader of the Far North business community has stood down to take a new job in Western Australia.
Cairns Chamber of Commerce chief executive Deb Hancock announced her resignation today after almost five years in charge of one of the largest Chambers of Commerce in regional Australia.
Ms Hancock said it was an honour to lead the Cairns Chamber of Commerce.
"I am proud of what we have accomplished as a team on behalf of our members," she said.
"I am certain that the Cairns Chamber will continue to be an increasingly strong force in the business and economic development of the FNQ region in the years to come."
The Developing Womens Leadership Program, Emerging Leaders Program and the inaugural Business Excellence Awards are a few initiatives spearheaded by Ms Hancock.
The Cairns Chamber now has the largest number of funding platinum partners in its history and new membership options.
Chamber president Nick Loukas said Ms Hancock helped secure hundreds of millions of dollars investment for key infrastructure, successfully advocated on behalf of civil contractors involved in the $220 million Peninsula Development Road package, protected the region's interest in the Sustainable Ports Development Bill and hosted numerous international delegations to drive trade and investment.
"By working with our partner stakeholders, members and government, Deb has been integral to the protection of business interests and the growth of our regional economy," he said.
"On behalf of the Cairns Chamber, and our members and partner stakeholders, we sincerely thank Deb for her passion, commitment and dedication over the past five years and wish Deb every success in her new role," said Mr Loukas.
Ms Hancock has accepted another chief executive officer position in Perth and will relocate with family in September.
She thanked the Chamber team for their support.
"I am exceedingly grateful for all of the long hours and hard work that the Cairns Chamber operations team employees have invested to grow the Cairns Chamber to what it is today," she said.
"The accomplishments achieved during my time as CEO were not done alone.
"These were achievements that required a committed team of passionate and tenacious individuals who come together to work relentlessly for a common goal and for this I am very grateful."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula Development Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sustainable Ports Development Bill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deb Hancock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Chamber</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hancock</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Excellence Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Loukas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leaders Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Developing Womens Leadership Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deb</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Loukas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FNQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
