<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399386286377869</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/opinion/columnists/the-super-industry-must-take-the-lead-on-retirement-20170731-gxm37d</url>
  <title>The super industry must take the lead on retirement</title>
  <content>
by
Jeremy Cooper

While the superannuation industry is in agreement that the retirement phase of super is its biggest strategic priority, there's a lack of consensus on what this means in practice.
That's apparent from the industry's early response to the MyRetirement reforms. These reforms seek to add an element of longevity risk pooling to what super does now for retirees. In simple terms that means that retirees can have access to broadly constant, real, lifetime income on top of what they already enjoy.
It's hard to argue with that and consumer research has consistently shown that most members want this type of income in retirement. However, the super industry to date has been focused on flexibility and the highest returns rather than stable income that lasts for life.
As with any major policy reform, particularly in super, there are things that need to be ironed out to arrive at a workable model. Maybe some of the proposed policy settings need to be explored further. But that's not actually the problem.

The real stumbling block is a lack of broad industry leadership. Where are the wise and respected leaders of the super industry on these important retirement income reforms? The general attitude seems to be that the industry is doing fine in the retirement space and doesn't need any regulatory change. Yet the super industry, in its current guise, was born of regulation. If the superannuation guarantee hadn't been mandated, there is no way it would look anything like it does today. It seems that super can't live with government intervention, but can't live without it either.

Is it just a coincidence that, all of a sudden, we have a rash of new entrants trying to disrupt super?
The first recommendation to reform the retirement phase of super in 2010 was opposed by industry and binned by the Gillard government. Phrases like "too much too soon" were uttered and the retirement income can was kicked down the road. We caught up with the can at the end of 2014 with Murray Inquiry recommendation 11 (for CIPRs). Now, in 2017, a workable outcome on MyRetirement should be just around the corner, but some in the industry don't seem up for the innovation; preferring the status quo.
Monty Python  sketch

Some funds are even saying that members aren't asking for new retirement income products so why should they make any? This is reminiscent of the famous Monty Python dead parrot sketch:

Palin: "Super fund A is not dead, it's just resting."
Cleese: "Well why hasn't it come up with a better retirement income offering?"
Palin: "Well, nobody asked it to..."
It would be like car manufacturers saying that nobody had asked them to install pre-crash safety systems or auto emergency braking. Consumers weren't screaming for an iPad before they were launched, either.

Is anyone honestly saying that we can't do any better for retired members or do we accept the reality that the MyRetirement reforms would help most of them to a more secure retirement?
There is also the view that there need to be new incentives to create better retirement solutions for members. The retirement phase is already tax free for all but a few retirees. Still, some are suggesting that without a further monetary incentive, funds are not interested in making the effort. This is a startling position when providing reliable retirement income should be the core business of every super fund.
So, this is a call to action to the super industry. Get involved. Focus on these important reforms. It is plain as day that the retirement phase of super needs to be significantly improved. If you don't like what's being suggested, at least come up with some better solutions, rather than just pointing out potential flaws.
The fact remains: the vast majority of members will either be exposed to the risk of running out of money during their retirement or will enjoy a lower standard of living through fear of running out. Super funds can improve the way income is made available to retired members and longevity risk pooling is part of the solution. A quick glance at the leading pension systems globally (eg Denmark and Netherlands) bears this out. 

Jeremy Cooper is chairman of retirement income at Challenger. He chaired the Cooper review of superannuation in 2009 and 2010. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monty Python</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Inquiry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cooper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MyRetirement</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netherlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CIPRs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
