<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399257437357444</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/act-labor-called-on-to-explore-more-affordable-abortions-20170729-gxld1b.html</url>
  <title>Calls for abortion drugs to be sold in chemists</title>
  <content>
The ACT Labor party has called on the government to consider allowing abortion drugs to be sold in chemists via prescription.
Party members and delegates also moved for a binding vote on abortion law, hoping to start momentum for change to the party's national rules, which allow members of parliament to vote with their conscience.  Photo: Graham Tidy
And they voted up a motion asking the government to force pharmacists who refuse to carry reproductive products like the morning-after pill to place a sign in their window to save women from being discriminated against or humiliated when they go to fill their prescriptions. 
'The ACT has consistently moved to move progressive changes to the party when it comes to a woman's right to choose," Ellie Yates said.
"Wayne Berry and his caucus in 2002 moved to decriminisalise abortion. We have made great steps since then but there is still room for improvement.
"There is currently one provider in the ACT of medical and surgical terminations. The concept of it being safe and accessible has come a really long way but the thing that has been missed and the thing that needs to be worked on more is making it affordable.

"Whether it's surgical or medical, it's $500 in the ACT to access the service. There are women in our community for who $500 is a deal breaker. $500 is whether they can put food on their kids' tables. It's food for them, it's rent, it's whether they can get to work and it's whether they can support themselves going through that time. $500 is too much, $500 is not making it accessible and affordable in our community."
The general resolution called on the ACT government to explore how it could make abortions more affordable, including making abortion drugs available by prescription from pharmacies or from government-run sexual health clinics

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Member for Canberra Gai Brodtmann supported the affordable abortion motion and revealed she was working with Emily's List to decriminalise abortion in Queensland and NSW.
Only one person spoke against all three of the resolutions, United Services Union delegate Brendan Scott, who said he'd been told of women unable to conceive after abortions and of women being forced into one by their partners.
Of the pharmacy signs, he said the motion was "untenable" and was in breach of discrimination laws. 
On the binding vote on abortion law, he said it was unfair to bind religious Labor politicians to vote with the views of a "particular narrow set".
"What's the repercussions for this party if you're only going to allow for a narrow range of people to express a view," Mr Scott said.
Shop Distributive and Allied Employee Association delegate Ellis McNeal said a binding vote would make Labor "unelectable" and drum up support for Cory Bernardi's Australian Conservatives party.
Both were howled down by the floor. ACT MLA Tara Cheyne said she was a member of the united Services Union, and Mr Scott did not speak for her or the women of the Labor party.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Tidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cory Bernardi's Australian Conservatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Gai Brodtmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellis McNeal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily's List</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellie Yates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Distributive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allied Employee Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT MLA Tara Cheyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
