<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399442120953341</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/07/oh-shit-william-could-soon-be-in-charge-of-your-smart-home/</url>
  <title>Will.i.am Could Soon Be In Charge Of Your Smart Home</title>
  <content>
Image: Marvel

Will.i.am has had a  breaking into the tech market. In his latest entrepreneurial venture, he's jumping into the smart home game. What could go wrong?

Will.i.am has a chequered history of making pieces of consumer technology that nobody really wants. Now you can add to that list a pair of Bluetooth headphones.

Innovator and musician Will.i.am's lack of luck in the gadget world has always come down to the fact that he's been so far ahead of his time. It's not that his failed ideas' time has ever come, but it will one day. While people like Musk and Zuckerberg  over how much of a threat is posed by the AI revolution, Will.i.am has been warning us that we need to  before we 3D-print humans. Were you thinking about that? No. He was, long before you.

Among Will.i.am's gadgets that haven't taken off, he's released: a  that had its own app called i.am+foto.sosho, a smart watch that was  that was actually two smart cuffs that you wear at the same time, and, most recently, some  that make you look like your wearing two of Lieutenant Uhura's  at the same time. In 2016, he  another smart watch that required you to pay $US28 ($35) a month for some sort of service and it had no apps. "The last paradigm was the apps thing," he said at the time. And he was right. And it still is.

That shit's in the past and Will is all about the future. The future is smart homes. 2017 is expected to be "" and one  estimates that the tech will have a compound annual growth rate of 13.61% through 2023. Will.i.am's company, i.am+ announced today that it has acquired the beleaguered smart home  and together they are going to control everything in your house. They didn't have a whole lot to share:

If Gizmodo's  with Wink's smart is any indication, the transition wouldn't be too noticeable because our  by a security update.

But that's OK. Will.i.am is here to + up your Wink, and solve that problem. Here's a list of problems that smart home makers have faced in the past that Will.i.am will need to address:

1. .

2.

3.  

4.

5.

We could go on, but there's really no need, Will's got this. Even if you don't ever buy a Wink device, you still might benefit for his new venture. In 2016, a massive botnet used insecure "internet of things" devices to launch a  and it briefly took down a huge chunk of the internet. And now, there's even more i.am+ devices we can bring into this worrisome environment. Great.

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US28 ($35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smart Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D-print</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soon Be In Charge Of Your</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gizmodo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Musk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluetooth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zuckerberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieutenant Uhura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
