<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399300387030908</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/cricket/big-bash/crosscode-stars-expected-to-put-wbbl-before-aflw-commitments-20170731-gxm12w.html</url>
  <title>Cross-code stars expected to put WBBL before AFLW commitments</title>
  <content>
Cross-code stars Jess Cameron and Emma Kearney will be expected to fulfil their cricket engagements should the AFL Women's season start on the same weekend of the Women's Big Bash League finals.
The 2017-18 fixture for the men's and women's Big Bash League was unveiled on Monday, as a heads of agreement in a new pay deal between Cricket Australia and the Australian Cricketers Association was on the verge of finally being confirmed.Photo: AFL Media/Getty Images
Host BBL broadcaster Channel Ten also spruiked its coverage of the summer, a sign the network intends to fulfil the final season of its contract at a time when it remains in financial trouble.
The semi-finals of the BBL and WBBL will be held on February 1 and 2, with the final on February 4. The AFL said on Monday it had not yet confirmed when the women would begin their second season but it's expected to be on that same weekend. This year's AFLW season began with a sell-out between Collingwood and Carlton at Princes Park on February 3.Photo: Getty Images
Cameron and Kearney juggled their commitments with the Melbourne Stars and their AFL clubs this year - Cameron with Collingwood and Kearney with the Western Bulldogs.
However, under the new memorandum of understanding between CA and its players, female cricketers will become part of an official pay deal for the first time.

This means that CA will expect dual-code players to put cricket before football. Under CA's pay offer, the proposed average female player payment for an Australian representative will be $179,000 this summer, while average domestic female player payments will be $52,000. The base wage in AFLW last season was $8500, with priority selections increasing to $12,846 and a marquee playing contract to almost $18,000.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

CA says it would work with Cameron and Kearney to see if they can also play football, as had been the case last summer when training commitments were juggled.
What also needs to be taken into account is that the Women's National Cricket League season continues until the final on February 24.
That CA has released the new fixtures has been seen as a sign of confidence the 10-month pay fight is all but over.
"We know the MOU is still being finalised but we are confident this won't affect the upcoming BBL and WBBL season and we're looking forward to welcoming a huge number of travelling fans who are coming out for the Ashes. This will help them plan," BBL chief Anthony Everard said.
The men's BBL season will feature an extra eight matches, with each team handed one extra home game. New venues have also emerged, although the Etihad Stadium-based Melbourne Renegades have yet to confirm their entire fixture.
"We've had ongoing venue discussions in recent months about opportunities to take one of our matches somewhere new. We hope we'll be able to confirm those plans in the coming weeks for what could be an exciting addition to an already packed season," Renegades chief Stuart Coventry said.
The Stars will have their five home games at the MCG. They will host the first cross-town derby on January 6 at the MCG, with the two clubs heading to Etihad Stadium on January 12.
The Renegades open their season on December 21 in Hobart, with the Stars - desperate to finally win a title - going to Brisbane on December 20.
"Our schedule provides members and fans with more access to Stars matches at the MCG this summer. We're very excited to host our additional BBL home match at the home of the Stars as well as three double-headers and standalone BBL and WBBL games," Stars chief Clint Cooper said.
The WBBL campaign starts on December 9 with three matches, including a double-header at North Sydney Oval.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBL</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kearney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jess Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Kearney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Media/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sydney Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 3.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cross-code</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBBL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Big Bash League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Everard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Stars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's National Cricket League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium-based Melbourne Renegades</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Coventry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFLW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
