<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399394876312557</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/teams/gws/jeremy-cameron-to-miss-at-least-three-weeks-after-reinjuring-hamstring-in-win-over-fremantle/news-story/05f492c8382d2297d90fc15a4c32af7c</url>
  <title>New setback for injury-hit Giants</title>
  <content>
Giants survive Dockers scare

GREATER Western Sydney™s premiership hopes have suffered a colossal blow with No.1 asset Jeremy Cameron ruled out for at least three weeks.

The Giants have emphatically denied any suggestion they rushed Cameron back too soon, given he has re-injured the same hamstring he had only just returned from against Fremantle on Saturday.

FLAG DREAM:

Cameron will now have precious little football under his belt before finals, and his anticipated three-week absence makes the Giants' bid to cement a top four position a significant challenge.

GWS lost against Sydney and Richmond when Cameron was sidelined earlier in the month and they are completely unproven without their dominant goalkicking forward.

The Giants admit they will have to be more cautious with their foundation star heading into the finals, but deny Cameron was unwisely rushed back to face the Dockers.

"There's no reason why he shouldn't have played the game, he was absolutely fine to go into the game," said the Giants' head of athletic performance, David Joyce.

"We'd done all the testing, he'd completed the training loads, he couldn't have been more prepared.

"He wasn't rushed back, it was just one of those unfortunate things. It probably means we need to be extra cautious with him now.

"You've got to play the ball that's in front of you but it will certainly come into our mind that we might be even more conservative."

Cameron fought through the Fremantle contest but alarm bells sounded when he pulled up particularly sore.

It's a grade two hamstring strain but the Giants are confident Cameron might sneak back in three weeks rather than the usual four.

With only four rounds left in the regular season, and the Giants clinging to third spot, the coaching staff have their fingers' crossed.

"It was no particular incident (in the match). He got a hit in his back in the second quarter and felt some symptoms down that leg," he said.

"He tested really well throughout the second half. We went out repeatedly just to check on him and he was fine. We specifically tested him at three-quarter time and he was fine.

"He actually presented worse post-match so we scanned him and unfortunately it's revealed he's got a hamstring strain."

GWS say Shane Mumford should return this week, but Will Setterfield and Steve Johnson face tests.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Setterfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
