<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399433531018704</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/secret-box-hill-interchange-report-could-to-be-released-under-freedom-of-information-act-says-box-hill-mp-robert-clark/news-story/12cd3fb002b1dfc69bf06a5d2e87241c</url>
  <title>Push to release report under FOI</title>
  <content>
PREMIER Daniel Andrews and his transport minister are refusing to answer the Whitehorse Leader's questions on when it will release the long-awaited report into the Box Hill interchange.
And Box Hill state Liberal MP Robert Clark has joined the Leader's fight, promising to force the report's release using the Freedom of Information Act.
"It's disgraceful the Andrews Government made an election promise to hold this review, spent public money doing it, and yet is now keeping its findings secret," Mr Clark said.
"Since the Government won't do the right thing voluntarily, I will be applying to have the report released under the Freedom of Information Act.''
The State Government and Premier Daniel Andrews have remained largely silent about the fate of the interchange since a report into the issue was completed earlier this year.
The Whitehorse Leader has emailed a list of questions to the Andrews Government, including:
WHY has the report not yet been released?
WILL it be released? If not, why not?
WHAT does the report recommend as the best way to upgrade the interchange?
WHAT does the Government plan to do with the information and recommendations in the report?
WILL the Andrews Government be the one to step up and commit to fixing the mess that is the Box Hill interchange?
Apart from listing some minor work done at the interchange, the Andrews Government's single line response is: "The Government is continuing to look at future options to improve public transport in Box Hill".
Two weeks ago, the Whitehorse Leader ran an editorial on the front page urging Mr Andrews to release the report, however since then all of the Whitehorse Leader's questions to the Premier have been handballed to Transport Minister Jacinta Allan, who has also refused to answer questions.
Opposition Public Transport spokesman David Hodgett said the Andrews Government has no long-term to solve public transport woes.
"As Melbourne's population continues to grows, infrastructure like the Box Hill interchange is vitally important for those living in Melbourne's east,'' Mr Hodgett said.
"Melburnians are sick of delays, overcrowding and cancellations on our public transport network - they just want to get home to their families."
Have your say on the Andrew's Government's refusal to release the report at whitehorse@leadernewspapers.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehorse Leader</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedom of Information</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew's Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Hodgett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP Robert Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hodgett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews Government</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Jacinta Allan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melburnians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
