<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399386286377815</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/reality-tv/now-its-xrated-survivor-hunk-locky-goes-naked-for-challenge/news-story/aa31a63d313bdfcc9f1756c4e28f0036</url>
  <title>'Now it's X-rated': Survivor hunk Locky goes naked for challenge</title>
  <content>
Survivor turns x-rated
0:35

Survivor turns x-rated when Locky loses his short during a challenge.

July 31st 2017
4 minutes ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/Television/

May the nudes be ever in your favour. Picture: NIGEL WRIGHT

Share

WE'VE barely begun the current season of Australian Survivor, but viewers are about to be treated to something you just don't see enough of on Aussie TV: A nude wrestling match.
In tonight's episode, the two tribes - Asaga and Samatu - go head to head in a reward challenge, competing to win a simple tool that'll make life much easier on the island.
One member from each tribe had to get themselves wet then tear down a slip-and-slide, trying to grab a ball at the end of the track. The first contestant to grab hold of the ball and bring it to their team's square on the course would win a point.
Two of this season's most physically impressive competitors, 195cm tall mountaineer Locky and former SAS commander Mark, are paired off to compete against each other.

Mark (left) and Locky go head to head.Source:Channel 10
As they careen down the slip-and-slide - Locky clad only in his jocks - Mark reaches for his competitor's sole item of clothing in an attempt to hold him back. All at once, off come the undies.

Who needs clothes at a time like this? Picture: Nigel Wright.Source:Supplied
"Locky gets there first! He loses his shorts! It's now X-rated! Locky's completely naked!" shouts host Jonathan LaPaglia.
The poor Ten censor certainly earns their pay in this scene, struggling to keep up with a very large man squirming his naked frame this way and that:

Uh, Locky - you're naked and you're nowhere near the ball.Source:Channel 10

A face full o' butt.Source:Channel 10
As the ugly wrestling match continues, Locky's team mates go through a variety of emotions at the sight of their fellow competitor in his birthday suit:

The varying reactions to a large naked man.Source:Channel 10
In the end, Locky wins - thank god - and his team mates rushed to congratulate him. None seem to be in that much of a hurry to fetch him his underpants, though.

He won! But in the end, aren't we all winners?Source:Channel 10
As Locky lies in the sand exhusated, LaPaglia has the final word: "Nice cheeks."

Very strategically placed logo there. Picture: NIGEL WRIGHT.Source:Channel 10

Locky (left) and Mark. We'll assume they're bonded for life after that little encounter. Picture: Tim Hunter.Source:News Corp Australia
Check out a preview of the challenge below - WARNING - CONTAINS LOTS AND LOTS OF BUTT.
See Locky's Nudie Run when Australian Survivor 7:30pm tonight on Ten.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Hunter.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaPaglia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Locky</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor 7:30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOTS OF BUTT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Locky's Nudie Run</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CONTAINS LOTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Wright.Source</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan LaPaglia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIGEL WRIGHT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samatu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
