<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399429236051380</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/b1-million-tattslotto-win-for-broadmeadows-retiree/news-story/a09e0c50f356781612c2392976d2632c</url>
  <title>Broadmeadows retiree celebrates $1m windfall</title>
  <content>
A RETIRED Broadmeadows man will partly spend his $1 million TattsLotto win on buying a second-hand car.
The man, who wishes to remain anonymous, claimed $1,052,631.58 in last weekend's TattsLotto $20 million Superdraw.
The retiree bought the winning 18-game QuickPick entry from Broadmeadows Lucky Lotto in Pascoe Vale Rd.
He said he checked his numbers several times before he was able to let the news sink in.
"Checked the numbers three bloody times and called my daughter and got her to check it as well," he said.
"I then checked it at the newsagency just to check that I hadn't stuffed it up, bought the wrong day's ticket and just to check I wasn't dreaming."
The man said he would spend the money wisely, preferring to buy a second-hand car before sharing the rest with his family.
"I've got a few renovations around the house and I do need a new car," he said.
"I'll give some money to my daughter and granddaughter so they can go to England to visit some family."
The winner said he only entered draws with a big prize pool, and it was his late mother who inspired him to buy a ticket.
"My mum used to play all the time before she passed away last year," he said.
"I thought maybe mum's looking down and I'll try and win some money back for her."
Broadmeadows Lucky Lotto owner Hasan Chandrakirana said the win came as a big surprise when the man checked his ticket in the outlet.
"We have sold three other division one winning entries at our store and we thought it was about time for another one," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tattslotto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QuickPick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RETIRED Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TattsLotto $20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows Lucky Lotto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasan Chandrakirana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superdraw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pascoe Vale Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
