<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399433531018721</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/pm-says-back-benchers-have-right-to-cross-the-floor-as-increasing-number-of-his-mps-call-for-parliamentary-vote/news-story/532f341d1ade5b10de18a005db43c5ec</url>
  <title>MP's 'torment' foreshadows marriage vote</title>
  <content>
MALCOLM Turnbull today cleared the way for a Liberal bill legalising same-sex marriage by endorsing the right of back benchers to offer their own legislation.
The Prime Minister moved from a strict insistence that Coalition policy was to hold a plebiscite on the Marriage Act change before any legislation entered Parliament.
An increasing number of Liberal MPs are calling for the matter to be settled in Parliament - possibly through a private member's bill which could be introduced mid-August - and the Prime Minister indicated to block them would be authoritarian.
"In our party, backbenchers have always had the right to cross the floor," Mr Turnbull told reporters in Perth.
"In the Labor Party you get expelled for doing that, but it has always been a fundamental principle in the Liberal Party and indeed the National Party.
"It's a very different political culture to the very authoritarian and centrally controlled culture of the Labor Party."
Marriage equality campaigners argue the Government tried to get the national ballot through Parliament and failed, so the next step is to consider legislation.
The matter is expected to be raised at party-room meetings when Parliament returns next week after the long winter break, and to cause a vigorous debate.
A Liberal private members bill would be opposed by Immigration Minister Peter Dutton, who has proposed a national postal ballot on the matter.
Former Prime Minister Tony Abbott backed that idea last week, saying, "I certainly think that will be better, much better, than just trying to ram this thing through the Parliament".
The number of pro-SSM Liberals speaking out include backbenchers Victorian Tim Wilson, Queensland Trevor Evans, and West Australian Senator Dean Smith. The move could also have the support of veteran Warren Entsch, minister Christopher Pyne, and North Sydney MP Trent Zimmerman.
Tim Wilson told Sky News: "It's in our best interests to move on from this issue so we can focus on the sorts of things I think people voted for me and for my party to deal with - tax reform, fixing the budget, national security.
"I also have a personal conflict which torments, frankly, and challenges me on a daily basis and I'd like to see this issue resolved."
Trevor Evans has called for a conscience vote as the "quickest and most likely course".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sydney MP Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SSM Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
