<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399472185724808</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/breaking-news/tough-airport-security-to-stay-for-now-pm/news-story/21f926782eb20beb6ad8eacb57ea89dd</url>
  <title>Beef up airport staff to ease lines: Labor</title>
  <content>
Federal Labor has made a pitch to passengers stuck in long queues at the nation's airports by calling for extra money and staff to manage tighter security measures.
The government says tougher screenings will remain in place until authorities believe they are no longer necessary to address a terrorism threat.
Domestic passengers are being advised to arrive two hours before their flights, and international passengers three hours before, to allow for the extra security checks imposed after police foiled a Sydney-based plot to bomb a passenger plane.
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten believes Australians are willing to wait a bit longer if it means keeping them safe.
"But I think it would be a bit frustrating, understandably, if the government doesn't upgrade the amount of money they're spending so the passengers are not unduly inconvenienced," he told reporters in Melbourne on Monday.
If the extra measures remained in place for some time the government should seriously consider putting in additional resources.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has been assessing the new arrangements with police, domestic intelligence agency ASIO and the Office of Transport Security.
"I want to thank the travelling public for their forbearance, having to get to the airport earlier and wait longer to get through security," he said in Perth.
"(Security measures) will be required for as long as the threat is assessed as requiring them."
Mr Turnbull was later asked why the government hadn't beefed up resources along with stepping up security.
"The heightened security measures ... have been done on the advice of our security agencies, which are the best in the world," he told reporters.
Transport Minister Darren Chester acknowledged that one of the challenges was avoiding large crowds waiting in areas where they could be put at risk.
"We're constantly evaluating the most appropriate way to move a crowd through the airport to get them safely to their destination," he told reporters at Melbourne airport.
Four Sydney men were arrested over the alleged bomb plot on Saturday.
With an investigation underway, the prime minister was reluctant to comment on details or speculation including whether it involved a bomb or gassing passengers.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Darren Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
