<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399266027292141</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/movies/article/2017/07/28/erica-glynn-talks-teaching-literacy-changing-lives-my-own-words</url>
  <title>Erica Glynn talks teaching literacy, changing lives in 'In My Own Words'</title>
  <content>
By

31 Jul 2017 - 1:36 PM  UPDATED 4 MINS AGO

Tell us how the film came together

I was interested in the subject of adult literacy and I'd sort of been thinking of ways to deal with it. I looked into who was working in the space and it literally took me a ten second Google, which brought up the , who are of course are the people who are behind all of this amazing work.

Was it hard to negotiate access to the classroom?

I went out and did some research with them for a couple of weeks, the year prior, and watched the last four or five classes towards the end of an intake, and based on that and talking to the community and elders, and the foundation members, we we thought let's see if we can make this happen and get it moving, and they were all in agreement. It was a difficult thing - imagine asking to shove a camera in people's faces as they're trying to learn to read and write, but they agreed. There was a way to get it happening we'd try, so that's what we did!

Part of the difficulty, tackled in the the program, of course, is to get people to come at all - let alone come and be filmed during this challenging time..

Yes. it was a very tricky one! Proper filmmaker dilemma. If you were in, you were going to be filmed, because there's no way we could shoot around people, so when signing up, they had to be aware that there were cameras there and they had to be told that they would be filmed. It was awful for me, because i didn't want to rob anybody of an opportunity, and there were some people who did make the choice not to join that intake and come at a later one. So we did and we rode along with it, but they got used to us pretty quickly!

The program co-ordinator Mary is the heart and soul of your film, reassuring the classmates and sharing her own struggles to give them hope that they too can grow. Tell us about how first encountered her, and got her faith.

She's one of the people i met in Brewarrina, obviously because she's one of the co-ordinators of the program. She's a very special person and that's kind of instant. She plays a pivotal role in the organisation obviously because she's coordinator, and kind of like the conduit between the on the ground, grassroots people who are there, and the foundation. Mary herself is so dedicated, a very, very special human being and very very wm and genuine, so i think that audiences respond to people like that, they love that kind of company which is hard to find! She just rose to the top because of her very special qualities.

The film premiered at the Sydney Film Festival -

. Was that the first time they'd watched the film?

Oh, no, we took it out for them to look at, and say what they liked and didn't like - it's all part of the process. I don't want them to feel bad about it. It's been a real process of involvement. I don't want to lie - that's what i had to say to them, 'I don't want to lie but I don't want you to feel bad about it either'. There's not been any huge conflict or tension around that stuff because of the process and their understanding of what we were doing - and trying to do.

It must have been special to witness the change upon someone you've watched struggle, then suddenly realise they can write.

Well, we cried! Yeah, I cried quite a few times! All of us, watching it happen and you see them just go, "What?". It's how it happens, you know, just one day a light bulb just goes on.

Watch 'In My Own Words' at SBS On Demand

 

You sort of leave it with Mary not knowing what's going on and whether the program will continue. Do you have an update?

They did have another intake - they've just finished that in Brewarrina. I'm not sure that they'll do another one, but I think there would be room to do another one there. I think there's still plenty of people in Brewarrina that need it, but the Foundation - part of the Cuban method of doing it - is about a spread of intakes across the country. It's up to them and where they put their focus next.  There's another one in Bogabilla, or Permulla.

Hopefully the film can show what's possible

Yes, that's the hope.

You've got a real skill for telling intimate stories - here, a person literally learning how to read and write,but in a way that touches on the wider themes stories about communities, access, opportunities. How do you draw the line from something individual and touch on those bigger issues?

Well, that's the trick isn't it? I don't think there's one formula, it depends on they way into the story, you know? But that for me, is the point of it all. Those big, broad issues affect people in a very micro way, and micro issues affect people in a very broad way, you know? For me that's what i think is worth discussing in the country.

What's next for you?

Doing a little bit of Little Jay and Big Cuz, and apart from that just a lot of research and development, looking into my next project, which isn't confirmed so I can't talk about it.

 

YOU MIGHT ALSO LIKE

We say goodbye to some great movies this month. Catch them while you can.

MIFF returns with a Cannes-tastic line-up and outstanding Australian movies too. We caught up with artistic director Michelle Carey to get her top tips.

American audiences are rejecting this summer's procession of tired sequels, and international grosses won't be enough to keep studios afloat forever.

Mahershala Ali has become the first Muslim to win an Academy Award in an acting role for his performance in the film 'Moonlight'.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Jay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jul 2017 - 1:36 PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Film Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erica Glynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 4 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS On Demand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Permulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bogabilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cannes-tastic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIGHT ALSO LIKE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brewarrina</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIFF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahershala Ali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Cuz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
