<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399472185724773</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/seven-common-myths-about-pet-cats/8759166</url>
  <title>Seven common myths about pet cats</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Cats are enigmatic creatures to many, appearing in fairy tales and old religious stories as things of mystery.
But in reality cats are just animals, like humans.
Here are some of the more common misunderstandings about cats you may have grown up firmly believing.
1. Cats always land on their feet and have nine lives

While it sometimes appears cats have near magical powers to land on their feet and get out of trouble, they can, and do, hurt themselves by falling off things.
They also get colds and .
Even indoor cats should have their vaccinations to protect them from serious illnesses such as feline immunodeficiency virus.
2. Cats can't be trained

External Link:

Cats are trainable, just like dogs
The meows cats make to communicate with their owners are learned behaviour they use to interact with you. You've trained them without even knowing.
Some cats are easier to train than others, but through persistence and finding what reward your cat prefers - treats or play - you can teach an old cat new tricks.
3. Feed cats milk and let them play with wool

Many cats do love to get their paws on a saucer of milk as they love the fat content, but their digestive systems are not as pleased.
Kittens can drink a little cow's milk without too much of a problem, but adult cats cannot digest the lactose properly and it upsets their stomachs. If you give milk to your adult cat, you're likely to regret it.
Cats love to chase and pounce on strings, too, but if that string is a fuzzy, fibrous woollen type, it can cause harm to the cat.
Their tongues are rough and they can end up digesting a heap of little woollen flecks as they play and chew on a string. This can cause blockages in their digestive tract.
4. You should let a female cat have a litter before she's desexed

in Australia leading to overflowing cat shelters and feral cat issues.
There is no health benefit to a female cat from giving birth, especially if she's a young cat. Desexing not only avoids unwanted kittens, it also prevents uterine cancer, and helps prevent mammary cancer and ovarian cysts.
The RSPCA recommends both male and female cats are desexed at about eight weeks old.
5. Cats need to roam and aren't happy if kept indoors

External Link:

Training a cat to walk on a lead is a good way to get them exercise while keeping birds safe
A cat that's used to coming and going as it pleases will certainly make its displeasure known if you stop that access.
But as long as a cat has access to space to play and exercise, an indoor cat can be very happy and often healthier than a free-to-roam cat.
A secure cat run is a great way to give your cat access to the outdoors without risks to the cat, and of course, protecting other wildlife from a little hunter.
6. They are solo creatures, preferring to be left alone

Every cat has its own personality and some are more interactive than others, but cats are social creatures.
A study at Oregon State University found that if given the choice, most cats would choose to socialise with humans rather than eat.
If possible, it is often better to have two cats at home than a solo cat, so they have company while the people are away.
7. Pregnant women shouldn't touch cats and cats hate babies

External Link:

Kids and cats can and often do get along just fine
Toxoplasmosis is a real thing and it can be found in cat faeces, as well as in soil, raw eggs and meat, and some unpasteurised dairy products.
Toxoplasmosis is generally not a problem for a healthy human, but there is a risk of miscarriage or health problems for pregnant women if they are exposed to it.
Pregnant women should avoid emptying the litter tray, and wash their hands after snuggling the pussycat, but there is no need to get rid of your pet.
Once the baby has arrived, it is advisable to keep the cat out of the baby's room. A cat might want to snuggle up close to the warm little bundle, and a tiny baby is not going to like having a face full of fur.
If you are worried about your cat's behaviour near the baby or toddler, just make sure you are always there when they interact and teach a grabbing toddler to respect the cat's space and to be gentle when patting.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toxoplasmosis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oregon State University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
