<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399343336704313</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/coroner-clears-police-over-death-of-numan-haider/8757632</url>
  <title>Numan Haider inquest: Police cleared over death of teen who stabbed officers outside Endeavour Hills station</title>
  <content>
A Melbourne policeman acted appropriately when he shot and killed teenager Numan Haider as he attacked him and another officer with a knife outside a suburban station, a coroner has found.
Coroner John Olle made no criticisms of the police officers in findings handed down almost two years after Haider was killed outside the Endeavour Hills police station, in Melbourne's south-east, in September 2014.
Haider was shot as he used a knife to attack the officers, who had called him to the station to discuss what police believed was an escalation in his radical behaviour.
Mr Olle found no "reasonable basis to criticise" police officers for meeting with the 18-year-old, including after he posted extremist statements on social media.
"On the available information there is no reasonable basis to believe that Numan had intent to carry out an edged-weapon attack [during the meeting]," Mr Olle said.
"[Outside the police station] Numan exhibited no signs of imminent danger, he displayed no level of agitation, no change in posture, no defensive stance, no verbal indicators.
"It's been established that Numan's death was not preventable other than at the expense of [an] officer's life from the time he produced a knife and stabbed officers."

How it unfolded:

Police visit Haider's home on September 23, 2014 to speak about his behaviour and the rejection of his passport application
His family allows the police to search his bedroom while Haider is out with friends
His mother tells him about the visit, his father says he was "very upset and agitated"
Haider agrees to a police request to meet at Endeavour Hills station
When he arrives, he calls the officers and asks to meet in the car park
Two officers, from AFP and Victoria Police, find Haider sitting on his car bonnet
They ask to search him, and he pulls a knife from his pocket and stabs the Victoria Police officer in the arm
He then stabs the AFP officer in the face and shoulder before crouching over him and aiming for his stomach
The Victoria Police officer fatally shoots Haider in the head

Mr Olle said officers had only moments to react to the attack, which lasted less than a minute in a poorly lit area.
He said Haider's early arrival at the station prevented officers from taking positions outside.
"Given the ferocity and speed of the attack, support officers would have unlikely have altered the outcome," he said.

Mr Olle's findings supported earlier evidence given by a .
A week before the attack, Haider had been seen by police waving a Shahada flag, which is often misappropriated by Muslim extremist groups, at a Dandenong shopping plaza.
Haider told officers on that day that he was "not going to blow up the shopping centre today", but said he was angry about recent terrorism raids in Sydney and Brisbane.
After the incident, Haider told a friend, "If I had a knife I would have stabbed them", referring to police
Mr Olle said the officers who met Haider outside Endeavor Hills station had not been informed about that comment.
"[The information] may likely have altered the manner in which police approached Numan and possibly abandoned the planned approach," Mr Olle said.
The court heard that, before his death, Haider had accessed websites containing "radicalised Islamic ideology" which showed executions and beheadings, and contained recruitment propaganda.
Mr Olle said Haider had accessed material on his phone with graphic instructions from the Islamic State group on how to kill and maim people.
Haider had also attended the Al Furqan Islamic Centre in the months before the attack, which an earlier inquest heard was linked to extremism.
"I accept that the evidence strongly indicates that Numan was minded in the days before his death to carry out some form of attack, albeit that his choice was an opportunistic response," Mr Olle said.
Mr Olle recommended the establishment of a new social services network, which could quickly respond to people deemed at risk of carrying out a terrorist attack.
The coroner also praised Haider's family for their cooperation during the process.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shahada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Furqan Islamic Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coroner John Olle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Numan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Endeavour Hills</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Numan Haider</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haider</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Olle</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
