<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399429236051337</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/law-order/christopher-lavery-racked-up-huge-gambling-debts-before-murdering-james-russouw-court-hears/news-story/eb2fe91f545df95f769db1a9bd816df1</url>
  <title>Court hears of alleged killer's debt</title>
  <content>
A MAN charged with fatally stabbing a mate then torching his body was a problem gambler who slept with a knife under his bed before turning into a killer, his trial has heard.
Chris Lavery is on trial in the Supreme Court for the murder of 24-year-old James Russouw who was fatally stabbed in the neck as he sat in his car in a Burwood carpark in March 2008.
He is also charged with incitement to murder the prosecution's key witness, and has pleaded not guilty to both charges.
A string of Mr Lavery's former friends have been called as prosecution witnesses and have told the court he was a frequent drug user and cannabis dealer.
One witness gave evidence that Mr Lavery kept a knife under his bed, while another said he had confessed to amassing massive gambling debts prior to Mr Russouw's murder.
Michael Gronn, who said he stopped associating with Mr Lavery because of his drug use, said that in about 2007 Mr Lavery told him he had racked up about $21,000 of debt playing blackjack.
The court heard Mr Lavery told Mr Gronn that he had opened a number of credit card accounts, used the money on the cards to gamble, and lost it all.
"It was a pretty clear conversation I remembered quite vividly," Mr Gronn said.
"(It was) quite a significant amount of money."
Mr Lavery wasn't charged over the murder until last year, shortly after a $1 million reward for information about the killing was announced.
In light of the announcement, the prosecution's key witness came forward with new information about Mr Lavery's movements on the night of Mr Russouw's murder.
Mr Lavery's lawyer, Scott Johns, has repeatedly suggested that the evidence has been made up because of the reward on offer.
But the key witness, who cannot be named, repeatedly denied the allegation while giving evidence over two days.
He denied even knowing about the million-dollar reward until after he made his police statement.
In it the witness, known as Witness A, said he was paid $150 to go to the movies with Mr Lavery on the night Mr Russouw was murdered.
He told the jury Mr Lavery later confessed to the killing and promised to murder his family if he ever told anyone.
"He said 'I set up a deal, sat in the back of the car and slit his throat, and if you ever tell anyone I'll kill you and your family'," he said.
Witness A said Mr Lavery had asked him to go to the movies with him to see Rambo at Forest Hill Chase shopping centre in exchange for $150.
Ten minutes into the movie, the two men exchanged clothes, with Lavery leaving about half an hour after that, he said.
The witness was spoken to by police shortly after the murder, but didn't make a statement until last year following the announcement of a $1 million reward.
The court heard any reward could only be claimed if the information helps secure a conviction.
The jury has been told Mr Lavery had discussed killing the man with a prisoner while being held on remand following his arrest last year.
Following Mr Russouw's death, police conducted a search of his bedroom at his parents' house, finding about $60,000 cash.
The trial, before Justice Mark Weinberg, continues.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lavery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Russouw</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Gronn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gronn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rambo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Russouw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Mark Weinberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forest Hill Chase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Witness A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Lavery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lavery</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
