<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399343336704305</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/leadership/top-higher-education-achievers-named-in-afr-awards-20170727-gxk5d0</url>
  <title>Top higher education achievers named in AFR awards</title>
  <content>
The finalists in the 2017 Australian Financial Review include a critical thinking program for marginalised youth, a gamified learning app for mobile devices, a service program for students in Indigenous communities and an augmented reality module for teaching physiology and anatomy.
Over 100 entries were considered by the judging panel, the most ever entered in the awards, which are presented by UniSuper.
Now in their third year, the prestigious awards recognise innovation and achievement in Australia's higher education sector.

Nick Moir

Winners in each category will be announced at a gala dinner on August 29, during The Australian Financial Review.

Community engagement

University of Melbourne - Teddy Bear Hospital: The university's largest community engagement project involving nearly 2000 volunteer students a year, helping medical students relate to kids and helping children understand health.
Central Queensland University - Choices, an applied theatre project: It reaches over 3000 year-12 students from Townsville to Rockhampton with safety messages around alcohol, drugs and sexual activity before they go to Schoolies Week.
Macquarie University - National Indigenous Science Education Program: The program gives Indigenous students the confidence to harness the power of education, realise their potential and become future leaders. It now also involves Charles Sturt University, Edith Cowan University and partner schools.

University of Sydney - Service Learning in Indigenous Communities: Indigenous communities host university students who work on projects selected by the community in multi-disciplinary teams, which contributes to student assessment and gives them the opportunity for personal growth.
Education Technology

UNSW and University of Queensland - BEST Network's Slice: A collaborative biomedical image repository used for teaching with easy access for multiple teaching institutions and advanced features including an annotation tool.
University of Melbourne - My eQuals: Enables students and graduates of universities in Australia and New Zealand to access digital versions of their academic documents and share them with universities, employers and other parties. 

Bond University - Augmented Reality: A suite of innovative physiology and anatomy augmented reality modules for health, science and medicine at Bond University, which have improved student learning and increased class engagement and lecture attendances.
Swinburne University - Quitch: A content-neutral, gamified, mobile learning platform for instruction and assessment, which includes a motivational feedback system and robust data analytics. 
Emerging leader

Sponsored by Perrett Laver

UNSW - Angela Moles: Professor Moles is an internationally leading figure in the field of 'big' ecology with an exceptional record in research and scholarship, who has been successful in a broad range of leadership, mentoring and outreach initiatives.
Deakin University - Emma Kowal: Through her cross-disciplinary research in anthropology, medicine and public health, Professor Kowal has pioneered approaches to reversing Indigenous disadvantage and ensuring Indigenous people can benefit from advanced health care.
University of Sydney - David Reilly: Professor Reilly was instrumental to establishing the university's $150 million Nanoscience Hub and his work underpins Australia's progress in the race to build a quantum computer. 
Employability

Sponsored by Pearson
Deakin University - Graduate Employability Program: The program builds the learning of employability skills into the curriculum and helps students explore career options, build work experience and connect with prospective employers.
Macquarie University - Professional and Community Engagement: The PACE program is a whole-of-university work-integrated-learning program which enhances employability and citizenship capability by enabling all undergraduates to engage in practical learning experiences with industry and community. 
ANU - College of Business and Economics Internship Program: The program gives students the opportunity to strengthen their employability skills in the Australian professional workplace, placing interns with employers for course credit.
Equity and opportunity

La Trobe University and Federation University Australia - Higher Education for Care Leavers Strategy: The program provides outreach, academic and financial support to assist people who have spent time in foster, residential, or kinship care (care leavers) to succeed at university.
University of Wollongong - Outreach and Pathways Team: The team engages with individuals in targeted schools and communities to build aspirations for, awareness of and attainment in higher education. 

University of Queensland - Critical Thinking Project: Assists teachers and schools to move to a 'teaching for thinking' pedagogy and promotes higher education aspirations among marginalised youth, building their capacity for critical and innovative thinking.

University of Newcastle - Building Clarity Through Simplicity: A targeted and personalised communications campaign to help course students make the transition to university, leading to increased enrolments.
St Catherine's College, University of WA - Dandjoo Darbalung: A program which supports Indigenous students transition from school to university and into employment with a retention rate over 90 per cent.
Industry engagement

Sponsored by TechnologyOne
University of Queensland - Boeing Brisbane Technology Centre: Boeing research and technology staff are embedded with university researchers, sharing research infrastructure and inspiring students to seek aerospace careers.
Federation University Australia - Partners in Learning: A deep, long-term partnership with IBM which led to an IT degree offering real industry experience, scholarship funding for students and support for the recently established P-TECH pilot school.
University of Adelaide - Future of Photonics Innovation: A partnership with Trajan Scientific and Medical which lead to a photonics research and development and manufacturing hub.
Monash University - Monash Industry Team Initiative: Embeds high-performing, multi-disciplinary students at bachelor, masters and PhD level in industry to solve real problems leading to commercial outcomes. 

University of Canberra-Ducere Global Business School - Master of Business Administration: An MBA delivered by Ducere in partnership with the University of Canberra, based on industry project work with a high level of practical learning and industry engagement.
International education

Sponsored by Top Education Institute
Monash University - IITB-Monash Research Academy: A research collaboration with the Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, with 400 researchers, nearly 200 research students and 400 research projects to date.
Deakin University - Deakin India Research Initiative: Enables top Indian students to pursue PhD study and research national problems in collaboration with Australian researchers and with access to Australian research facilities.
University of Adelaide - China Career Ready Plus: An initiative to boost Chinese international students' career outcomes with programs to increase students' readiness for employment and offer placements with employers.
University of Notre Dame - Doors of Opportunity: A program which offers service learning opportunities for education, medicine and arts students in Kenya, India and Timor Leste.
Learning experience

University of Notre Dame - Beyond Memorising: The Notre Dame Anatomy Approach has been highly successful in teaching anatomy to medical students with multi-modal techniques including self-directed learning, collaborative problem-solving and senior students supporting junior students.
La Trobe University - Digital Identity: Making Your Mark!: An adaptive e-learning module on digital literacies that empowers students to evaluate the impact of their e-reputation and the power of social media on their academic, professional and social lives.
Western Sydney University - PASS (Peer Assisted Study Sessions) Online: An online, weekly, peer-led collaborative learning program which has successfully led to higher grades for participants.
UTS - Hatchery: The university's Innovation, Entrepreneurship and Creative Intelligence Unit's programs in the Hatchery start-up incubator are in high demand from students, helping them engage with industry and the innovation ecosystem.
Other categories

Two other award categories are still to be announced. The Lifetime Achievement Award - which honours an individual's outstanding contribution to Australian higher education over a lifetime of leadership, innovation and service - will be announced on August 14.
The winner of the Facilities Innovation Award will be announced on August 29 at the gala dinner. The judges decided not to select finalists in this category.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Career Ready Plus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>College of Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IITB-Monash Research Academy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UniSuper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin India Research Initiative</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swinburne University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ducere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Indigenous Science Education Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IBM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Industry Team Initiative</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Notre Dame Anatomy Approach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TechnologyOne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future of Photonics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Moles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Moles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Service Learning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Sturt University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation University Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ducere Global Business School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Queensland University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peer Assisted Study Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyond Memorising</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Economics Internship Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graduate Employability Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing Brisbane Technology Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin University</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Digital Identity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Notre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Catherine's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandjoo Darbalung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bombay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Trobe University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doors of Opportunity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P-TECH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Higher Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perrett Laver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PhD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facilities Innovation Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEST Network's Slice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bond University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Clarity Through Simplicity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teddy Bear Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dame</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanoscience Hub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trajan Scientific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Kowal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Reilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Institute of Technology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Engagement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schoolies Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master of Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Critical Thinking Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Augmented Reality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Kowal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top Education Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Moir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 29</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care Leavers Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Creative Intelligence Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Reilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Technology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timor Leste</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pathways Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Communities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edith Cowan University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifetime Achievement Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
