<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399300387030852</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/lifestyle/fashion/why-kate-middleton-proved-once-again-she-is-the-duchess-of-outfit-repeats-20170731-gxm4ew.html</url>
  <title>Kate Middleton proves once again she is the duchess of outfit repeats</title>
  <content>
In the age of social media, it seems many people cringe at the thought of wearing the same outfit again. But perhaps it's time for all of us to take note of the Duchess of Cambridge's style files, with the royal unapologetically recycling many of her outfits at various official events over the years.
Apart from accessories that have become staples during official outings and royal tours, she is renowned for repeating outfits with sentimental value, including most recently wearing the white Alexander McQueen coat-dress she donned at Charlotte's christening in 2015 to the official commemorations marking the 100th anniversary of the Battle of Passchendaele in Belgium over the weekend.Photo: Joe Giddens
For Middleton the success of her outfit repeating is all in the variation of her accessories, with the duchess pairing the coat-dress with a Lock & Co white hat (which she also wore at her Trooping the Colour appearance in 2015), and a pair of grey pumps and matching clutch bag with pearl earrings and a brooch.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
This joins the countless instances she has pulled from her wardrobe archives. As well as many of her Jenny Packham gown repeats, one of her favourites is a Michael Kors fit-and-flare coat which she wore this year to the unveiling of a new memorial for armed services of the Iraq and Afghanistan wars. She also wore the coat with different accessories to a 2014 Anzac Day service in Canberra, and an event at the Magic Garden, London, last year.
While her outfit repeating is a great budgeting move, it also proves the duchess has the confidence to know the silhouettes and designs that are both comfortable and suit her best. Which is, of course, the secret to looking good in any situation. 

The duchess is a fan of her Michael Kors coat. Photo: Alastair Grant

Her outfit-repeating ways also reflect her priorities are as a mother, wife, official royal in diplomatic efforts and philanthropist, basically - she's busy. Yet her place as both a powerful woman and fashion icon, in a similar fashion to Princess Diana, is well and truly cemented. 
Recycling fashion is not a technique she is using exclusively for herself either, with Middleton dressing Prince George and Princess Charlotte in repeat outfits of their own, and other items that are part of the royal family archives.
Just last week during their  Princess Charlotte was captured wearing red Mary Jane shoes that once belonged to a young Prince Harry, some 30 years on. And like many parents, Middleton has dressed Charlotte in sibling hand-me-downs, including the blue cardigan Prince George wore to the hospital when the now two-year-old was born. Only a few weeks ago the Duchess of Cambridge also wore one of , the Lover's Knot, to a state dinner at Buckingham Palace.
In a time where sustainability is at the forefront of fashion conversations, the duchess proves that purchasing versatile staple pieces, including statement accessories, means spending less, and experimenting more by mixing and matching combinations in your wardrobe.
We'd call that a win. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alastair Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Packham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battle of Passchendaele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lover's Knot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlotte</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middleton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Giddens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Middleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Kors</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duchess of Cambridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander McQueen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince George</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary-Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Charlotte</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
