<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398995444349036</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/breaking-news/sa-court-hears-of-sociopathic-killing/news-story/2a3fc9c7cbad4d465b590f22841969a9</url>
  <title>SA court told of 'sociopathic' killing</title>
  <content>
A Brisbane woman who killed her Adelaide grandfather went to his home wearing rubber gloves and armed with a knife, a court has heard.
In a killing the prosecution said was "almost sociopathic in style" Brittney Jade Dwyer, 19, has pleaded guilty to the murder of 81-year-old Robert Whitwell in August last year.
A co-accused, Bernadette Burns, has pleaded not guilty to murder and will go to trial next month.
In sentencing submissions in the SA Supreme Court on Monday, prosecutor Jim Pearce objected to the proposed tendering of a psychiatric report prepared about Dwyer because it raised issues that had not come out in any other material, including the 19-year-old's police interview.
Mr Pearce described those issues as insidious and said they came at "one minute to midnight".
The court was also told that Dwyer had intended to rob Mr Whitwell of at least some of his life savings.
She believed the pensioner, who lived alone, kept hundreds of thousands of dollars hidden in his shed.
The prosecutor said there was an element of preparation in the killing, including the long drive from Brisbane to Adelaide.
He said she also took a knife with her and wore rubber gloves, and told people in Brisbane that her grandfather "might have to die".
However, the exact details of the killing have not been revealed.
Counsel for Dwyer, Craig Caldicott, said the issues raised in the psychiatric report were not pressed by the defence.
He said Dwyer had a history of self-harming and drug problems.
"She's clearly a young, very mixed-up woman," Mr Caldicott said.
Dwyer has been remanded in custody to return to court on August 29.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernadette Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwyer</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Whitwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brittney Jade Dwyer, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Caldicott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Caldicott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
