<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399399171279913</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/team-calls-in-back-up-for-states-top-bowler/3207008/</url>
  <title>Team calls in back-up for state's top bowler</title>
  <content>
LAWN BOWLS: Darren Muir is eager to have a tilt at the club champion of champions pairs state title but will have to get through the next round without his playing partner, Queensland's top-ranked bowler Kurt Brown.
The duo squeezed through the final at Kawana to be crowned top team there before winning the Sunshine Coast district crown.
Next is a clash against the best team from the Fraser Coast, at Coolum Beach, on August 14.
But Brown will be overseas so he is set to be replaced by Lewis Stumbris.
"I'll have to skip this next game and Lewis will lead for me but he's been playing well for the club so hopefully we can get though that game," Muir said.
A victory there would propel the team into the state final, which Brown would be able to contest.
"He's number one in Queensland at the moment so he's a big asset to the side obviously," Muir said.
Brown's influence has proved telling in the competition so far.
His shot on the third extra end of the Kawana club final was decisive.
Muir said the pair trailed 22-10 after 14 of 21 ends but battled back into contention against Mike Stevenson and Tony Bush.
Then when the game was on the line, the skip turned what looked like a two-shot deficit into a one-shot gain with a neat draw which sealed victory.
"It was a massive bowl in the context of us getting through," Muir said.
Muir and Brown then progressed through the district section, beating Australian Open round of 16 pair, Caloundra's Wade Mutzelburg and Joel Anderson in the semi-finals, before toppling Nambour Heights 37-4 in the decider last week.
Celebration after Coast gym snapped up in last minute sale
More than 300 people nominate their favourite vet
Did your cat make the list?
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
Police hunt firecracker thrower at Shannon Noll concert
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LAWN BOWLS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Noll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Muir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Stumbris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra's Wade Mutzelburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muir</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Stevenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
