<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399300387030885</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/funniest-thing-ive-seen-bottle-rapists-spend-first-night-in-jail/news-story/88b094124f5d4d228be3a11bf06bd4ec</url>
  <title>'Funniest thing I've seen': Bottle rapists spend first night in jail</title>
  <content>
Bailey Hayes-Gordon arrives at the District Court in Brisbane. He's now in jail. Picture: AAP

AAP

Share

THREE Queensland men have spent their weekend behind bars for raping an unconscious friend with a glass bottle at an Australia Day party.
Family and friends cried inconsolably as Bailey Hayes-Gordon, Nicholas Jackson and Jacob Watson were found guilty by a Brisbane District Court jury of raping the 18-year-old man.
Their week-long trial had heard the victim was held down while passed out drunk in a bedroom and repeatedly penetrated in the anus by the bottle. The 2015 incident committed by the then-teenagers was also filmed and distributed on Snapchat and in Facebook chats.
Judge Anthony Rafter noted while Hayes-Gordon was the one who penetrated the victim, Jackson's action of holding down the man while Watson filmed it had encouraged each other.
"None of you were appalled or disgusted by what had taken place," Judge Rafter said on Friday.
"This can't be classified as harmless high jinks."
All three were sentenced to two years' jail, suspended after six months spent in custody.
A fourth man, 21-year-old Frazer Eaton, was given a wholly suspended 18-month jail sentence in February after he pleaded guilty to holding the young man's shoulders and spreading his buttocks.
Eaton testified against the other men and denied he gave evidence in exchange for a lighter penalty.

Frazer John Eaton testified against the other men and was called a "liar" in court.Source:News Corp Australia
Nicholas Jackson, 19, held the victim down while Jacob Watson, 18, filmed the incident on his phone and shared parts of it on Snapchat.
In a Facebook conversation the next day, Hayes-Gordon posted screenshots of the video and wrote: "(He) passed out so we stuck a bottle up his arse and he just took it".
"Funniest thing I've ever seen, legit. The whole end of the bottle disappeared". Watson and Jackson also made crude Facebook comments.
All three were sentenced to two years' jail, suspended after six months spent in custody.
The victim, who was not physically injured, had no memory of the 2015 incident and described it as "f***ed up".
He complained to police several months later after the video was shared in separate Facebook conversations that included his younger brother and girlfriend.
Hayes-Gordon, who at trial denied actually penetrating the victim, told the man's sibling the video was "your brother getting analled".

Jacob Watson has spent his first weekend behind bars. Picture: AAPSource:AAP
Frazer Eaton, 21, was given a wholly suspended 18-month jail sentence in February after he pleaded guilty to holding the young man's shoulders and spreading his buttocks during the incident.
Eaton testified against the other men and denied he gave evidence in exchange for a lighter penalty.
After hearing four days of evidence in the Brisbane District Court it took the jury only a few hours on Friday to find Hayes-Gordon, Jackson and Watson guilty of rape.
Family and friends howled inconsolably as each verdict was handed down, with one woman crying: "I'm going to kill myself".
Judge Anthony Rafter warned people in the public gallery to contain their emotions and not to shout out after a person had been heard calling witness Eaton a "liar".

Nicholas Jackson held down the victim. Picture: AAPSource:AAP
"The verdicts can't come as any surprise to anyone who has seen the evidence in this case," Judge Rafter said.
Hayes-Gordon and Jackson wept openly in the dock as they were sentenced while Watson pursed his lips together and looked back at distraught supporters.
Judge Rafter said it was unusual for a rape to involve no sexual gratification, but that was "cold comfort" to the victim whose body had been violated.
Judge Rafter said he was not confident the men fully appreciated the impact their actions had had on the victim, despite apologising to him through their lawyer in November last year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane District Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas Jackson, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Anthony Rafter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas Jackson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Rafter</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bailey Hayes-Gordon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAPSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frazer Eaton, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frazer Eaton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapchat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Watson, 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eaton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayes-Gordon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frazer John Eaton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Watson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
