<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399605329712492</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/queensland-police-commissioner-ian-stewart-reappointed-for-three-years-20170731-gxm9do.html</url>
  <title>Queensland Police Commissioner Ian Stewart reappointed for three years</title>
  <content>
Queensland Police Commissioner Ian Stewart has been reappointed for another three years.
The new contract could have been a minimum of three years or up to five years, but Police Minister Mark Ryan said Mr Stewart was happy to take three years.Photo: Harrison Saragossi
"The Commissioner's original contract was a three plus two contact," he said.
"And we've had discussions with the Commissioner and the Commissioner is happy to accept a three year contract."
Mr Ryan said the Commissioner was doing a great job and there was no need to open it up to a full recruitment process to other applicants.
The announcement was made following a cabinet meeting on the Gold Coast on Monday.

Mr Stewart said for Queensland to stay at the front end of contemporary policing, there was a range of strategies and "things we need to do".
He has commissioned an internal review of the QPS counter-terrorism framework, which he said would be finalised "shortly".

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But Mr Stewart would not be drawn on whether the QPS needed more resources.
"It's now up to me to talk to the Premier and to the minister to ask for their support in helping us move forward, perhaps to enhance our capability and our capacity to deal with the sorts of threats that are coming over the horizon," he said.
"I'll certainly be talking to the minister and then ultimately the Premier about my plans as we move forward. We can always do with more, there's no doubt about that, but I'm also mindful that we have to do the very best with what we've got."
Mr Stewart has been a member of the Queensland Police Service for more than 44 years, including the past five years as Commissioner.
Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk said Mr Stewart had done extraordinary work, including dealing with cyclones and flooding.
"But also too in the lead up to the Commonwealth Games, I think it's incredibly important that we have a clear sense of stability for our state and also in this heightened era of counter-terrorism," she said.
"The leadership the Commissioner has shown is extraordinary. In fact, I have received reports from our intelligence agencies in, federal agencies, that Queensland is leading the way when it comes to elements of dealing with violent extremism."
Mr Stewart said he was "absolutely humbled" by the announcement. 
Earlier this year, Senior Sergeant Phil Notaro , which he said was "failing the people".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senior Sergeant Phil Notaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stewart</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QPS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Commissioner Ian Stewart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrison Saragossi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Minister Mark Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
