<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399515135398260</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/sydney-couple-to-face-terrorplot-trial/news-story/166c6e97637cb76e02a2535b2e35e18d</url>
  <title>Sydney couple to face terror-plot trial</title>
  <content>
A young Sydney couple accused of plotting a terrorist attack kissed and hugged in the dock after being ordered to stand trial in the NSW Supreme Court.
Magistrate Susan Horan referred to evidence including messages sent on their wedding day when Alo-Bridget Namoa wrote: "I can't stop crying. I have to remember you don't belong to me, you belong to Allah".
Namoa, who married Sameh Bayda on December 30, 2015 when they were 18, also allegedly referred to the couple as a jihadi Bonnie and Clyde.
The 20-year-olds are charged with conspiring between December 13, 2015 and January 25, 2016 to do an act in preparation for a terrorist attack.
Bayda also is charged with three counts of collecting terrorist-related documents - instructions on how to carry out a successful stabbing, how to make an explosive device and tactical advice on preparing for a terrorist attack.
Namoa is charged with one such count - instructions on how to make a detonator - and to possessing a thing connected with a terrorist act, being a hunting knife found wrapped in a Shahada flag in her handbag when she was arrested.
In the Downing Centre Local Court on Monday, the magistrate committed them to stand trial in the NSW Supreme Court where the matter will be mentioned on September 1.
The prosecution case involves 12 volumes of material with most of it relating to electronic evidence, including downloaded extremist material.
In relation to the conspiracy charge, the Crown particularly relied on a "goodbye note" and lengthy detailed SMS messages exchanged between the new bride and groom on their wedding day.
"Be happy, I want to know you are smiling before you jump out of the car," Namoa wrote in the goodbye note, also saying she wanted to have his child as a memento.
"I am going to miss your face, I am going to miss your hugs and kisses."
In the text exchanges, she allegedly said: "I know you wanted this for a long time and I am really proud of you" and "I love that you are not scared".
The magistrate also was told the couple took selfies giving the one-finger IS salute with their faces covered.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clyde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shahada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alo-Bridget Namoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sameh Bayda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonnie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Susan Horan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Namoa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 25, 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downing Centre Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
