<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399558085071740</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/five-of-the-best-nick-riewoldts-finest-games-in-light-of-his-retirement-announcement/news-story/c1ab9a129abe3250639afe6778a3c60b</url>
  <title>Five of the best: Nick Riewoldt's finest games</title>
  <content>
ST KILDA star Nick Riewoldt has called time on one of the great careers of the modern era.
While the gun forward was unable to claim an elusive premiership, Riewoldt made his name as one of the finest players of his generation, with his courage, athleticism and pure power setting him apart from his contemporaries.
Foxfooty.com.au takes a look at five of the St Kilda champion's best performances from across different stages of his career.
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 19 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
1. The big-game player: 2009 Preliminary Final v Western Bulldogs
RIEWOLDT enjoyed one of his five All-Australian guernseys in 2009 - and was captain of that year's side.
He also did everything he could to will his side to its first premiership since 1966.
In that year's preliminary final - off the back of five goals against Collingwood the week before - the St Kilda captain delivered an inspired performance to help his side overcome the Western Bulldogs.
That included a dominant performance up forward, where Riewoldt recorded 18 disposals, took 11 marks and booted four goals - including the game sealer - to will the Saints to a seven-point victory.
2. The star of the competition: Round 2, 2010 v North Melbourne
OFF the back of grand final heartbreak, the Saints entered 2010 with a point to prove.
The team who felt their wrath? North Melbourne in Round 2.
That came off the back of another star turn from Riewoldt, who produced a performance that put him in the conversation as one of the best centre-half forwards of the modern game.
Riewoldt collected 23 disposals, recorded 15 marks and booted seven goals as the Saints thrashed North Melbourne by 104 points.
Pure dominance.
3. The breakout game: Round 22, 2002 v Melbourne
HAVING played six games in his first season, the former No. 1 draft pick played every game of his second, in 2002.
In a season where he won the Rising Star, Riewoldt averaged an astonishing eight marks per game - showcasing his strength and athleticism.
But 21 games in, he had just 15 goals to his name.
Then, the 19-year-old exploded.
In the final round of that season, the Saints lost to Melbourne by 18 points - with their young star showcasing his wares.
Riewoldt booted a career-best six goals, took 12 marks, recorded five inside-50s and had 19 disposals in an excellent individual performance.
In just his second year of senior football, it was a warning shot to the rest of the competition.
4. The arrival of a genuine star: Round 15, 2004 v Melbourne
IF 2004 was the year Nick Riewoldt announced he'd arrived as a star of the AFL, this was the game that underlined his potential.
With Fraser Gehrig out injured, the Saints copped a 57-point thrashing at the hands of Melbourne.
But Riewoldt's effort in that game simply couldn't be faulted.
The St Kilda spearhead - forced to step up in Gehrig's absence - took 10 marks and booted nine goals, well above his previous career-high of four.
It was a milestone he's since achieved twice more.
5. The reminder of a veteran's powers: Round 23, 2016 v Brisbane Lions
JUST when Riewoldt looked to have reinvented himself as a winger for the closing scenes of his career, this game happened.
Riewoldt tore the Lions to shreds with a sublime individual performance, showcasing the gutrunning, marking ability and forward line potency that's defined his AFL legacy.
At 34, Riewoldt ran rings around the Lions' defence.
The star forward recorded a career-best 21 marks, collected 26 disposals and booted an equal career-high nine goals.
In the process, he showed there was plenty of life left in those old legs yet.
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rising Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxfooty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preliminary Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Gehrig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gehrig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 19 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 22, 2002</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
