<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399609624679852</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/luc-besson-keen-to-make-debicki-his-star/news-story/e88a96dbb86c358684a431eaaafa38fe</url>
  <title>Luc Besson keen to make Debicki his star</title>
  <content>
Australian actress Elizabeth Debicki has caught the eye of acclaimed director Luc Besson, and could follow in the footsteps of Scarlett Johannsson and Natalie Portman as a lead in one of his future classics.

The director behind cult favourites such as The Fifth Element and Leon cast Debicki as an alien in his upcoming film Valerian and the City of A Thousand Planets.

Top billing in the film goes to model-turned-actress Cara Delevingne and actor Dane DeHaan, but after seeing what Debicki can do, Besson hinted that she could play a lead in one of his future projects.

"I met Elizabeth who I love and I think I will shoot with her something for sure," Besson told AAP in Sydney.

The French director seemed impressed by Debicki's versatility as she took on the role of a male alien - the emperor of a compassionate alien race known as Pearls - in his epic space adventure set in the 28th Century.

"We pitched her voice just a little bit so you don't even know if it's a man or a woman. He (the character) is an emperor in fact, but she's a wonderful actress."

It's not the first other-worldly role for the star of The Kettering Incident, who recently played the golden villain, Ayesha, in Guardians of the Galaxy Vol.2.

Besson has a habit of putting women front and centre in his movies, believing it's more realistic to have women playing strong, powerful characters.

"This is the image of women I have since I was a little guy - my Mom raised me by herself and she had to work and to find the money, we were living in a 10m square apartment and that's the model I have," he said.

"For me, woman is not the James Bond girl, crying on the back of the hero saying 'Oh when are you coming back?' So I just try to recalibrate the thing, to give real roles to women and real roles to men."

* Valerian and the City of a Thousand Planets releases in Australian cinemas on August 10.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Besson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara Delevingne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardians Of The Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Bond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debicki</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifth Element</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luc Besson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thousand Planets</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vol.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Portman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane DeHaan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Debicki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarlett Johannsson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kettering Incident</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayesha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
