<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399562380039064</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/renewed-call-to-fix-tullamarine-intersection-death-trap/news-story/1c9317f7e67d9081330b4c7e11961250</url>
  <title>Renewed call to fix intersection 'death trap'</title>
  <content>
A  CAR ploughing through his front yard within metres of his home was the last straw for Greg Failla.
Mr Failla says the corner of Broadmeadows and Sharps roads in Tullamarine is a death trap and must be urgently fixed.
He said he was "sick and tired" of cars speeding along Sharps Rd and drivers screeching their tyres after turning left into the street from Broadmeadows Rd to perform a U-turn. There is no right-hand turn option on Broadmeadows Rd at the intersection.
Residents have been calling for change since being featured in the Leader last year.
In the latest incident a vehicle knocked over Mr Failla's brick letterbox.
He said residents wanted the speed limit on Sharps Rd lowered from 70km/h to 50km/h, speed cameras and a right-hand turning lane on Broadmeadows Rd at the intersection of Sharps Rd.
Hume sustainable infrastructure and services director Peter Waite said the council had consulted with the community and police and its traffic engineers found that motorists could safely perform a U-turn at the traffic lights just 140m east of the intersection.
VicRoads metro north west regional director Vince Punaro said the current speed limit on Sharps Rd was appropriate.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharps Rd</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Failla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U-turn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Waite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tullamarine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince Punaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Failla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows Rd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
