<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399519430365628</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/palace-letters-on-whitlam-dismissal-should-be-made-public-court-urged-20170731-gxm01c.html</url>
  <title>'Palace letters' on Whitlam Dismissal should be made public, court urged </title>
  <content>
More than 40 years after Gough Whitlam was dismissed as Prime Minister, his eldest son has appeared in court to fight for the release of letters that would shed light on what Buckingham Palace knew in the lead-up to the Dismissal.
Antony Whitlam, QC, headed a legal team appearing in the Federal Court in Sydney on Monday for Professor Jenny Hocking, a Labor historian and Monash University academic who is seeking access to letters between the then governor-general Sir John Kerr and the Queen.
The National Archives of Australia has refused to release the correspondence - which also includes letters between Sir John and the Queen's private secretary, as well as Prince Charles - on the basis they are "personal" letters rather than Commonwealth records.
Mr Whitlam said medical records and other documents unrelated to the performance of Sir John's official duties would be classified as "personal records" but it would not extend to correspondence with Buckingham Palace before he dismissed the Whitlam government in November 1975.
It could not be suggested that there was a "personal relationship" between Sir John and the Queen, he told the court.
Classifying the documents as personal records means they are embargoed until at least 2027, as stipulated by Sir John's estate, with the Queen holding a final veto over their release.

Professor Hocking said it was "a point of national humiliation that we should have to ask the Queen whether we can look at these key records in our own history - records which are held in our own National Archives".

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Mr Whitlam said the Archives Act set out a "comprehensive regime of accountability and publication" in respect of Commonwealth records.
If the court ruled the letters are Commonwealth records, the National Archives would have to consider if an exemption applied that would also keep the documents secret.
Tom Howe, QC, for the National Archives, said the Archives Act drew a sharp distinction between the governor-general "him or herself" and "the official establishment of the Governor-General".
The "personal and private records" of the governor-general were "owned by him or her as opposed to being transferred into the records of the official establishment", he said.
Mr Howe said previous governors-general had taken with them correspondence with the Palace with they left office.
The court heard Sir John's official secretary, Sir David Smith, lodged the letters with the director-general of the Commonwealth Archives Office in 1978.
Mr Howe said he was "lodging them as agent for Sir John Kerr ... on the instructions of Sir John Kerr" and if they had been Commonwealth records they would not be subject to his orders.
"It was not a transfer of ownership; it wasn't a gift of ownership of the records," Mr Howe said.
"Sir John Kerr had the ultimate constructive custody of the records."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Archives of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Howe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Archives Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gough Whitlam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antony Whitlam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitlam Dismissal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitlam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Howe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Jenny Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Archives</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir David Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archives Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 1975</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitlam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir John Kerr</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir John</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
