<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399609624679834</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/litchfield-national-park-grassfire-causes-hikers-to-shelter-in-burnt-patch-of-ground/news-story/b1dd2690ac159dd38acc567ccb6deaef</url>
  <title>Hikers have close call with Litchfield fire</title>
  <content>
HIKERS were left with no choice but to turn around when they turned a corner and discovered a wall of fire in Litchfield National Park.
Susan Burns and Russell Smith were on a hiking adventure through the national park when they came across the flames on Friday afternoon.
"We could see the smoke but we figured if there was a big fire the rangers would have closed the path," Ms Burns said.
"Then we came around the bend and we saw this wall of flames, about 100m from us."
The group was about 2km from Walker Creek when they reached the fire.
"We were surrounded by grass so we decided to get out of there quick," Mr Smith said.
"The whole day we'd been walking through patches of long grass and recently burnt out areas."
On their return trip, the group ran into other hikers who had faced similar -problems.
"We met some other hikers who told us they'd walked into a fire area, turned to go back and realised the fire was there too," Mr Smith said.
"They had to sit in a burnt patch for two hours while they waited for the fire to go around them."
The group ended up finishing their three day weekend early and returned to Darwin.
"Getting around the fire to the next campsite would have been too hard and we would have had to hitchhike," Mr Smith said.
Despite the lack of signage and warnings about the fires, Mr Smith said he didn't blame rangers for the misadventure.
"Hikers do have some responsibility to be aware of the dangers," he said. "The rangers could have closed the track off, but hikers need to decide what risks they're going to take themselves."
The fire was managed by Parks and Wildlife, who didn't respond to media requests.
It's not clear whether it was part of a planned burn, or if it was unexpected.
Bushfires NT were called by multiple park neighbours but were not involved in the fire management.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Litchfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Litchfield National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
