<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399558085071752</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/nick-riewoldt-retires-saint-nick-hangs-up-his-halo-20170731-gxm7ae.html</url>
  <title>Saint Nick hangs up his halo</title>
  <content>
The incidental perspectives of two other footy lifers act as bearings to provide a fix on Nick Riewoldt's exceptional career.
One is Bob Murphy, who as his Bulldogs slipped down the ladder in 2013 wrote a touching column for The Age in which he said he accepted that his window had closed and that his job now was to smooth the path for the next generation to a premiership beyond his time.

Up Next

Cloke kicks a cracker

00:28

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

Riewoldt, the same age as Murphy, read it and empathised, but said he had not given up yet, that all it took was a couple of boom recruits and a good run with injuries, that you never knew. The Saints were 16th at the time and about to sack another coach.
That was and is Riewoldt all over. From the day he walked into the club, to this day, he has been prepared to give until his last breath, and you can be sure it will be so for the few days that now remain. Sometimes that breath was the last left after a series of lung-busting leads, up, and back and then up again, until the ball was his. Generally, ageing footballers retreat to the confines of back or forward lines. Riewoldt went to the wing.

Sometimes, it was the breath jolted out of him by another kamikaze leap into a pack, one time to meet the ball, the next to follow its flight into the maw of an oncoming stampede. One mark in Sydney comes immediately and vividly to all minds, and in the absence of a premiership cup will live on as the quintessential image of Riewoldt.
Sometimes, in a lower key, it was the last breath that remained after another address to the players, asking for more, or to the media, spruiking for more. Riewoldt did not just play for the Saints, he lived and embodied them. Jointly and then alone, he was captain for 11 seasons. Others came and went, including five coaches, until the whole club had been turned over several times, but Riewoldt was the constant. He says he never seriously gave thought to a change of address.

As he shouldered his burden, Riewoldt presented to the world an earnest face, as Teutonic as his name, a short-back-and-sides footballer playing a short-back-and-sides game. "Don't try to be funny," fellow veteran Leigh Montagna advised him before he announced his retirement to the St Kilda players, "because you're not." Doubtlessly, he was not nearly so stern in private, but publicly, he was always on duty, keeping vigil over St Kilda's cause. And he was and is loved for it.
As best as one man could, Riewoldt shaped St Kilda. In turn, he was shaped by the Saints. For a club with so little success to brag about, so few laurels on which to rest, they inspire a staunch and singular loyalty, among players and fans.Photo: Getty Images
Critics used to concentrate on the wastrels and dilettantes as if to explain the dearth of premierships, but how do you explain Robert Harvey and Nathan Burke and Stewart Loewe and Danny Frawley and Nick Dal Santo and Lenny Hayes? Not many truer or straighter men have played the game.
This is the tradition in which Riewoldt walked, then furthered and gilded. Early in his career, he and a handful of others made an unofficial pact to stick fast until the Saints won a premiership. They were 15th on the ladder then, and there were days when it seemed all they had going for them was the flaxen-haired youth playing footy way above his age at centre half-forward.Photo: Jack Atley
So Riewoldt led the way, collecting best and fairests and All-Australian guernseys as he went, and the Saints coalesced and hardened around him, and grew in his image, and in 2009 and 2010 they came so agonisingly close, denied by a toe-poke one year, an infamously screwy bounce the next. But it didn't come to pass.
Was this St Kilda's unique and forever destiny, no matter how many times it reinvented itself? You had to thinks so. You still do.Photo: Mal Fairclough
Riewoldt said he reconciled it to himself by believing that there was nothing the club could have done better or differently in those two seasons. There was nothing more he could have done. Reflecting some years later, Riewoldt said premierships were no guarantee of a happy and prosperous life, and sometimes even were a curse, then added: "But I would say that, wouldn't I?"
Riewoldt has played another half a dozen seasons of redoubtable footy since that peak, his spirit finding a way even as his flesh weakened to the point where he often could not train between games. But his Saints have receded from September sight, and now that he is going and Montagna is likely to exit with him, the pact is officially dead.Photo: Vince Caligiuri
Meantime, there was a lowly team that found a couple of boom recruits and had a bit of luck with injuries, and thought to itself that you never knew, and then suddenly and gloriously did know, and much even to Murphy's surprise, it was his own Bulldogs.
So here is the other context for Riewoldt's career, and it is particular to St Kilda. When Harvey retired after a vast St Kilda career in 2008, he said in full consciousness that he was cutting himself down to size: "So many players fail to win a premiership. Now, I'm just one of them."
Soon, incongruously, Nick Riewoldt will be another. But don't say so to him, not while he is still wearing a St Kilda jumper and the footy is coming and he has breath to draw.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saint Nick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teutonic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Frawley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Montagna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lenny Hayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mal Fairclough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Atley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murphy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart Loewe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Dal Santo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montagna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince Caligiuri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
