<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399558085071705</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/queensland-leads-gains-in-financial-comfort-but-not-all-are-winning/news-story/fd7256b88e9f27947c6c8071e6043450</url>
  <title>Queensland leads gains in financial comfort, but not all are winning - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Queensland reported the greatest gains in household financial comfort over the past six months, the latest ME report found.

QUEENSLANDERS have had the country's biggest gain in household financial comfort in the past six months, but not everyone is winning.
The latest ME House Financial Comfort report found that Queenslanders were feeling 4 per cent better about their household finances in the last six months.
"Queensland reported the greatest gains in household financial comfort over the past six months to June 2017, up 4 per cent to 5.42 points (out of a possible 10 points), reflecting significant increases with most drivers, notably 'anticipated standard of living in retirement' (up 11 per cent to 5.13)," the report said.
Worryingly, despite the current lowest interest rates on record, 2 per cent of Queenslanders were not meeting the current minimum repayment on their home loan. The only bright side of that result was that it was better than the national figure (3 per cent).

The report also found that 5 per cent of Queenslanders paying mortgages or rent were "a great deal" worried or stressed about their household's ability to meet scheduled payments over the past month.
Almost a third of respondents in Queensland (32 per cent) also said they would be worse off if the RBA raised the cash rate by 1 per cent. The figure was just above the national average of 31 per cent.
According to the report, "both Queensland and Western Australia reported significant gains over the past year, recovering from the mining downturn and recent weather-related events".
Queensland's financial comfort level was below the national average (5.51 points), a figure that was lifted by real estate-fuelled financial prosperity in Victoria (up 2 per cent to 5.70) and New South Wales/Australian Capital Territory (up 3 per cent to 5.65).
* AND
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales/Australian Capital Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Financial Comfort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland (32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
