<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399570969973737</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-07-31/nic-nat-not-ruling-out-fairytale-comeback</url>
  <title>Door open for fairytale Nic Nat comeback</title>
  <content>
Nic Naitanui fronts the media on Monday. Picture: @Westcoasteagles Twitter

NIC NAITANUI is keeping the door open for a last-minute AFL comeback this season in case West Coast makes a fairytale run towards the Grand Final.

The star ruckman last week returned from an intensive two-week camp in the US where he tested his reconstructed left knee in a series of agility exercises under the eye of renowned specialist Bill Knowles.

Naitanui has since met with coach Adam Simpson to discuss his football comeback and is ready to return to main training with the intention of playing this year.

"The last thing I want to do is focus on my little rehab stuff and then we make it to a Grand Final and I'm not a chance or I've talked myself out of it because I haven't trained the way I want to do," Naitanui said.

"I'm going to give myself every opportunity because hopefully the team can keep progressing along as well and give me more time, which is what I need.

"If it happens it happens, if it doesn't I'll be pretty happy coming into pre-season knowing I've got a fair workload out this last part of the year."

More to come

Learning the art of flight again...I'm comin'

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Naitanui</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naitanui</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westcoasteagles Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Knowles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Nat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
