<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399064163826809</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:54</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/07/dont-expect-a-performance-trim-tesla-model-3-until-the-middle-of-next-year/</url>
  <title>Don't Expect A Performance Trim Tesla Model 3 Until The Middle Of Next Year</title>
  <content>
Now that the  will begin to slowly roll out to deposit holders, we're finally getting answers to questions like, "" and, "" and, "" and, now, "when will the fast one be available?"

Instead of announcing when a performance model would be revealed to the thousands watching the Model 3 launch livestream, Tesla CEO Elon Musk later took to Twitter to reveal that we can expect a faster Model 3 by "probably middle of next year."

Currently, the best performance trim available to order is a Long Range Battery optioned car, which is rear-wheel-drive only and goes 499km on a charge with a 0-60 mph time of 5.1 seconds and a top speed of 225km/h, which is no slouch.

We can only speculate on how a "Ludicrous" (or whatever they end up calling it) Model 3 would perform, but keep in mind Tesla is angling very hard to prevent any direct overlap between the new car and the Model S.

This means we could probably expect a dual motor car with all-wheel-drive, a sub-four-second 0-60 mph time and a top speed not likely higher than around 249km/h, if we took at what the Model 3's competitors are doing. Due to the size restrictions of the car, it's possible a performance model would still utilise the Long Range trim's battery pack.

It's still not exactly clear how reservations holders who aren't expecting the car until late 2018 or later will be able to update their orders for different models introduced down the line, but I doubt Tesla will be rejecting anyone who can pay the premium cost of a performance model, which could get the Model 3's price up to well above $US50,000 ($62,582) or $US60,000 ($75,098).

So far, all we know for sure is that a go-faster version of the Model 3 is coming, maybe by the middle of next year, and it will probably aim to at least outperform those boring, normal performance compact sedans.

WATCH MORE: Car News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Car News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla CEO Elon Musk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Of Next</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50,000 ($62,582</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Range Battery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US60,000 ($75,098</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model 3</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Expect A Performance Trim Tesla Model 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
