<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399519430365617</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/rendezview/our-music-industry-is-a-sexist-mess-time-for-a-reality-check/news-story/22e0678071cae19d65162261a601dfe6</url>
  <title>Australia, our music industry is a sexist mess</title>
  <content>
THE Australian music industry is a sexist mess.
While a new report Skipping A Beat prefers to call it gender inequality, their stark findings cast a damning spotlight on the endemic sexism within the industry.
Female artists do not get the same level of support or airplay at radio.
Of the 100 most played songs on commercial radio in 2016, only 31 were by a female artist or act with a female lead.
On the non-commercial airwaves, Triple J's Hottest 100 last year featured 34 per cent female voices - but those were collected across not only solo artists, but acts with at least one woman member and songs which featured a lead female voice.
The lack of female representation onbecame a lightning rod for the gender disparity debate in the industry last year.
Several promoters have since taken proactive steps to book- and there are plenty out there.
But it is disconcerting to read in the report that last year, two of our biggest music events - and showcases of artistic excellence - featured such out-of-whack imbalances.
Splendour in the Grass had 74 per cent male-only acts and Groovin The Moo had 79 per cent male-only acts.
And that's just the tip of the iceberg of bias when it comes to female artists.
Take a look at the music labels and publishing companies and the lack of gender equality in Australia's entertainment industry is staggering.
There is not one woman running a major label in Australia.
We came close earlier this year when it appeared a fait accompli that Warner Music general manager Mardi Caught would be elevated to run the local division of the multinational company.
There was widespread shock when she was not appointed to the role. Not only is Caught celebrated as a champion of Australian artists, she is an astute operator who is hugely respected within the international music community.
There is not one woman on the ARIA board, which represents the Australian music industry at a government and business level and oversees the annual ARIA awards.
They also decide who is inducted each year to the ARIA Hall of Fame. I served on the committee to recommend candidates for this recognition for several years. And every year I would have to argue for a female artist to join her male counterparts on the list.
It took too many years for artists including Little Pattie and Tina Arena to be given their rightful place in the Hall Of Fame, where only 11 out of 75 inductees are women.

Tina Arena, Jessica Mauboy and The Veronicas singing Chains live at the ARIA Awards 2015

Tina Arena, Jessica Mauboy and The Veronicas
Pick any other awards, ARIA, AIR or APRA, and generally female nominees run at about a third of the total list.
For many years, myself and a handful of women who were regularly invited to speak at music industry conferences referred to ourselves as the "tokens".
While there are certainly many more female voices at these events now, it was usually the case that most panels would feature one or no women.
When I worked as the A & R Manager aka talent scout at EMI/Virgin in the mid 1990s, I was the only female working in the role at a major label.
There is not one woman running that department at a major label in 2017.
"When we look at the gender breakdown for more technical roles such as sound engineering and music production, the gap becomes even wider," the report's lead author Associate Professor Cooper of the University of Sydney said.
"Women in the music industry are not only confronted with the 'glass ceiling', but also 'glass walls', where women congregate in occupations and sectors where the majority of employees are women."
The Skipping A Beat report, funded by the Media Entertainment and Arts Alliance, doesn't have any earth-shattering quick fix to the gender inequality so rife in the music industry.
But it does suggest gender equality criteria should be considered when deciding on public funding of the industry.
Unfortunately, the inequality is so ingrained that sending a few extra grants in the direction of female artists or music industry professionals is unlikely to make one iota of difference.
The change has to start at the top and it is up to the industry bodies and the gatekeepers at media, whether radio, television or print and online, to promote the work of female artists and elevate their colleagues at labels, publishers, concert promoters and associated sectors.
Kathy McCabe is News Corp Australia'snational music writer.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skipping A Beat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Veronica</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple J's Hottest 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Mauboy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Pattie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mardi Caught</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Media Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMI/Virgin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R Manager</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APRA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy McCabe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIAs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associate Professor Cooper of the University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIA Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tina Arena</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIA Awards 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
