<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399691229059860</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/07/31/14/22/isis-fighters-bride-describes-horrors-of-life-under-jihadi-rule</url>
  <title>ISIS fighter's bride describes horrors of life under extremist rule</title>
  <content>
The wife of an ISIS fighter has recalled the horrendous life she was forced to live as a jihadi bride in Syria under brutal extremist rule.

Islam Mitat, 23, told  how she went from being a fashion blogger and physics student in Morocco to live in an ISIS controlled region after her husband become a radicalised jihadi fighter.

Speaking from a safe house in northern Syria, the young mother-of-two detailed her day-to-day life living in "Little Britain" - a home in Syria where she lived with British women who had fled the UK.

Shortly after she arrived in Syria, Mitat's husband, Ahmed Khalil, was killed in the battle of Kobane. Her son was born a few months later.

Mitat told the US media outlet she met her husband on a Muslim dating site where he told her they needed to move to Turkey for his work. However, when she arrived she was forcibly smuggled into Syria for a "holiday".

"He was in Dubai and he told me he have job in Turkey, so he told me to come with me, he going to do his job and we go for holiday," she told CNN.

Mitat said she met Sally Jones, the infamous "White Widow" from the UK who is one of the most wanted female terrorists in the world.

Related Articles

The young mother was eventually remarried to an Afghan fighter known as "the German" who forbid her from going outside until she divorced him and was married again to an Australian fighter, Abu Abdallah al-Afghani.

She then moved to the Syrian capital of Raqqa where she lived for two years under violent ISIS rule.

"(It's) like you're dead, it's not life," she said.

"Always scared, always hearing bombs, guns, shooting."

Mitat said her predicament seemed less traumatising compared to the Yazidi sex slaves in her camp who the jihadi fighters would regularly have "a bit of fun" with.

She said she attempted to buy one of the young abused women's freedom but did not have enough money.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yazidi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kobane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raqqa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam Mitat, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Khalil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morocco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Widow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Abdallah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitat</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
