<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399648279386188</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-07-31/coniston-station-sold-pending-settlement/8759906</url>
  <title>Central Australian cattle station sold for $13 million</title>
  <content>
A family-run Central Australian pastoral property is under contract to sell for $13 million, pending settlement.
Coniston Station, north-west of Alice Springs, went under the hammer last week, but was passed through the auction at $12.5 million.
Days later contracts were signed to sell to a local pastoralist.
The property runs more than 5,000 cattle but owner Jacquie Lines said there were times where it had turned off more than that.
She said the family was very happy with the result.

"It's a bit of a relief now at this stage. I think it's a pretty good price and we probably had the best time to sell," she said.

"It wasn't planned. It all happened very quickly actually [when] we decided that we'd move on.
"We were lucky it's a good season, cattle are good, and everything is set up at the station, I'm very pleased."
Ms Lines said the property was currently under contract pending settlement.
Ready to move on

"They will have to put a deposit down and then we are virtually at the mercy of the administrator's consent as to when the settlement is.
"We've done the regrets and the tears and had a look at it from both angles, but we're ready to move and as soon as they're able to organise settlement we'll just hand over and go."
She said the family was also happy with who bought the property.
"I think it's going to good hands, and that was my main concern.
"I wanted it to go to somebody who I would think would look after the country, you know we still have a lot of feelings for this country and it's just such a pretty place."

Coniston Station runs more than 5,000 cattle currently.

Coniston Station runs more than 5,000 cattle currently.

Supplied: Landmark Harcourts

Long history

According to Ms Lines her family bought Coniston in 1976, and moved onto the property in 1978, which was quite bare at the time.
"We came out to a caravan and tent and no power, fridges or that sort of thing, and we worked up from there.
"It was an adventure, the whole hurricane lamps, the works.
"It just progressed as we went, and looking back over time it doesn't seem that long ago."
The family had seen hard years on the property, including when Ms Lines' husband
According to Ms Lines the property also struggled during the national brucellosis and tuberculosis eradication campaign (BTEC).

"We went through the BTEC program by the skin of our teeth at times, [we] didn't know how we would come out the other side.

"It had been quite a tough run for us. Finally prices have picked up and things are looking a lot better.
But despite the difficult times, Ms Lines said through it all the family had very fond memories of the station.
"We had a lot of good things happen, and I don't think I'd ever change what had happened.
"I'd do it again if I had my life over, it was a challenge and we rose to the challenge and here we are.
"I think with most things you know it's not going to be easy, and we had it in our minds that we could beat it and get through it and we did."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BTEC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landmark Harcourts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lines</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacquie Lines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coniston Station</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coniston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
