<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399308976965586</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/hoon-drivers-targeted-by-road-spray-that-burns-through-rubber-of-tyres-20170731-gxm38x.html</url>
  <title>Hoon drivers targeted by road spray that burns through rubber of tyres</title>
  <content>
Are you tired of hoons speeding down your street? A Melbourne council has a solution that they say will stop dangerous drivers in their tracks.
Hume City Council workers have laid a coarse spray seal on bitumen, which can burn through rubber tyres, to stop dangerous driving in hooning hot spots.Photo: Kirk Hargreaves/Fairfax NZ
Sustainable Infrastructure and Services director Peter Waite said the seal did not affect vehicles "driving appropriately".
"If a driver attempts to drive dangerously on this type of road, it would be difficult for a driver to spin their wheels," he said.
"If they did manage it, they would burn through the rubber of tyres faster than on a smooth road surface."
He said seal was applied by spreading an aggregate spray over the top of bitumen. The surface would need to be re-applied every 10 to 15 years depending on the amount of wear.

But tyre experts say the coarse surface could impact the wear and tear of some wheels.
Don, a tyre specialist at Camp Rd Tyre and Auto Service in Broadmeadows, said locals driving over the surface would not be affected, but if they had driven a long distance their tyres could burst.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It depends on how hot their tyres are. For example driving from Shepparton, when the tyre gets hot it gets sticky, and then there's friction with the road and that affects the tyre pressure," he said.
The surface was laid in April this year, but he said "so far" he had not repaired any tyres that had been affected by the seal.
Another tyre expert said the surface could increase the wear and tear of the tyre, but said he would have to test the new surface himself to be sure.
Hume police inspector Anthony Brown said the locations of the new surface were top secret.
"We chose sites that had high-risk driving activity, and known hoon gathering areas," he said.
The new surface would only shred the rubber on tyres "when the wheels lost traction on the road", he said.
"Normal driving speed it's not going to affect you but if you're engaging in intentionally high-risk behaviour, it would reduce the life cycle of your tyre dramatically."
Inspector Brown disputed reports that Hume was the hooning capital of Melbourne, and said police in that area were just very good at catching dangerous drivers.
"We have maintained a focus on it, so we impound more vehicles than other areas," he said. "It's a problem across Melbourne, and we're addressing it as a local issue here."
He said social hoon gatherings led to "people being seriously injured or killed".
"It's a serious risk of death or serious injury to both the drivers and the bystanders, and it's not just them having a fun time, it poses a serious risk to themselves and other people," Inspector Brown said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirk Hargreaves/Fairfax NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auto Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Waite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shepparton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Rd Tyre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
