<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399648279386133</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/east-hills/new-lenzerheide-owners-chefs-tim-pearson-and-mark-gaston-plan-to-breathe-new-life-into-hawthorn-restaurant/news-story/9270fef924d02dc108f6753b6e98d953</url>
  <title>New owners plan Lenzerheide revamp</title>
  <content>
AFTER working in the Lenzerheide kitchen for more than 15 years, chef Tim Pearson wanted another challenge at the landmark Belair Rd restaurant.
When the opportunity to take over the business came around, he and fellow chef Mark Gaston jumped at the chance.
Mr Pearson, who was handed the reins last week, plans to breathe new life in to the Hawthorn restaurant, but retain its fine-dining experience.
"Mark and I have been working here for so long ... it means a lot to us because we have worked really hard to get Lenzerheide to where it is today," Mr Pearson, 31, of Trott Park, says.
"It felt like the right thing to do and we wanted to keep Lenzerheide going, because we had concerns it would not if someone else came along. Things could have changed.
"We are looking at enhancing the dining area with a capital investment in the near future, while still respecting the 1800s historic building as is sits."
Lenzerheide is based at a locally heritage-listed property called Ardmeen House.
Medical practitioner Arthur Gault migrated to Australia from England and built the home, which had an adjoining surgery, in 1890.
The property was transformed in to Lenzerheide in 1989.
It has since won 30 awards, including being named Restaurant & Catering SA's Best European restaurant five times.
Some of its more notable diners over the years include former prime ministers Bob Hawke and John Howard, while artist Thomas Gleghorn remains a regular and, aged 93, still paints pieces for the dining room.
Mr Pearson, who will still work in the kitchen occasionally, and Mr Gaston also plan to start a Lenzerheide at Home range to sell from the restaurant and in local supermarkets.
"Part of our vision is to start a Lenzerheide at Home retail line offering our premium house-made truffles, Lenzerheide's soups and our superior sauces, and also offering in-office catering," Mr Pearson says.
"It is about quality food and produce."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ardmeen House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearson, 31, of Trott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Gaston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Gault</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gaston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Gleghorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belair Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lenzerheide</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catering SA's Best European</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
