<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399729883765993</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/investors-wary-as-cochlears-ceo-chris-smith-quits-after-two-years-20170731-gxm1dn</url>
  <title>Investors wary as Cochlear's CEO Chris Smith quits after two years </title>
  <content>
The sudden retirement of homegrown hearing implant maker Cochlear's American chief executive Chris Smith has left investors puzzled and chastened but not - so far - rushing for the exits.
News of Mr Smith's departure will come just over two years after and only a few months after new chief financial officer Brent Cubis took the reins from another Cochlear long termer, Neville Mitchell.
Cochlear cushioned the blow by confirming its full year earnings guidance at $210 million-$225 million, a solid increase from 2016's $189 million net profit.
Mr Smith will officially retire on 2 January 2018 but is being paid en extra $1.45 million in lieu of 12 months notice. He will also receive short term incentives for the December 2017 half year - worth $1.4 million to him in 2016 - but no long term incentives for the period.

Supplied

Dig Howitt will be CEO

He will be replaced by Dig Howitt, who became chief operating officer a year ago as part of what Cochlear described as "a succession process". Mr Howitt will earn $1.64 million base salary and short and long term incentives worth up to $3.2 million short term incentives, giving a maximum total pay of $4.94 million. 
Andy Gracey, portfolio manager at Australian Ethical Investments, said Cochlear was one of a handful of healthcare companies with strong growth and "priced to perfection" as a result.
He said the sudden news of a chief executive's departure after just two years "makes you scratch your head" and is disappointing and puzzling coming so soon after the change of chief financial officer. 
But he said it would probably take an earnings setback to put a big dint in Cochlear's $8.2 billion market capitalisation, even though the company's shares are priced at a heady 37 times next year's earnings.

Cole Bennetts

Issue is earnings

Cochlear shares slipped just over 1 per cent to $143.90 by lunchtime, down from a peak of $161.14 on 21 June.
"Whether it's $144 or $160 this thing is still priced for perfection. But even when it's on that type of multiple the issue is not so much news of the CEO departing - it's around earnings and delivering," Mr Gracey said.
"Trading at 37 times next year's earnings you don't need much of a blip or a disappointment to see 20 per cent knocked off (the market value). We have not had an earnings disappointment, you could say, but a CEO two years and one month in and he's leaving, and we have got to get used to a new CEO and his take on things might be different." 

Mr Gracey said he heard Mr Smith hadn't wanted to relocate to Australia, where Cochlear is based despite four fifths of sales revenues being in the Americas, Europe and the Middle East. 
He said investors were "just getting used to his new take on the company and new strategy and he is gone - but it's disappointing". 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neville Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dig Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear's $8.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear's CEO Chris Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear's American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Cubis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Gracey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News of Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ethical Investments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January, 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cole Bennetts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gracey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
