<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399171538010501</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4822162/university-of-wollongong-academic-wins-2017-chemeca-medal/?cs=2388</url>
  <title>University of Wollongong academic wins 2017 Chemeca Medal</title>
  <content>
University of Wollongong Professor Judy Raper has won the prestigious 2017 Chemeca Medal. Picture: Paul Jones

Professor Judy Raper was humbled to become only the second woman to win the prestigious 2017 Chemeca Medal since it started back in 1982.
But the University of Wollongong Deputy Vice-Chancellor (Research and Innovation) said there was a lot still to do to bring greater diversity to engineering.
''I don't just mean greater representation and opportunity for women,'' Prof Draper said.

''I mean diversity across the board: racial diversity, cultural diversity, diversity of backgrounds, diversity of experiences.''
A chemical engineer by training and research, Prof Draper said it was humbling and gratifying to win the most senior award for chemical engineers in Australia and New Zealand.

- Professor Judy Raper
She was presented the award, for her outstanding contribution to the practice of chemical engineering, at the  in Melbourne on July 23-26.
Prof Raper used her keynote speech, "Mind the Gap: Addressing the Innovation Gaps", to talk about how the representation of women in chemical engineering had improved since she began her career, and how it could benefit from further change.
''We can't drop the ball. There are more girls coming through but there are still fewer women than men in engineering leadership positions,'' she said.

As a young academic in 1983, Prof Draper was asked to give a presentation at the Chemeca conference on 'The untapped sex', about women in the industry.
''At the time, only about six to 10 percent of chemical engineering students were female,'' she said.

''It's now 35 or 40 per cent women, so chemical engineering has done really well. However, in engineering overall it's gone from six per cent women to 18 or 20 per cent, and if you look at senior positions, it's only 15 percent women on company boards or in senior roles. So there is still a lot to be done to bring greater diversity to engineering.''

Prof Draper also took the opportunity to highlight what UOW was doing about innovation and gaps in innovation, pointing to the success stories including the  initiative and winning the  entry for energy efficient housing.

''Innovation comes about through thinking differently, so we encourage innovation by doing things differently.''

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Judy Raper</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Vice-Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Raper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chemeca Medal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chemeca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovation Gaps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Draper</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
