<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399081343696145</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/hunting-the-ghosts-of-the-grand-hotel/8752610</url>
  <title>Ghost hunting in the Grand, one of SA's most haunted hotels</title>
  <content>
"We don't believe in ghosts."
It seems an unlikely statement from a trio of 40-something blokes spending their nights in one of South Australia's most haunted hotels, but this group of amateur ghost hunters bring a healthy degree of scepticism to their hobby.
"I believe in something but what it is, I do not know," Darren McPhail said, sitting in the dark upstairs corridors of Millicent's Grand Hotel, in the state's south-east.
"Hence why I do this, to try to find out.
"I'm not out there to try to convince anyone else that there is or isn't ghosts. This is for me."

Whatever your beliefs, haunted tourism is big business.
Top-rating paranormal reality television series are inspiring new generations of ghost hunters, all keen to find definitive evidence of the supernatural, happy to spend their hard-earned cash for a good experience.
For Grant White, Darren McPhail and Chris Kenny, who have dubbed themselves the Mount Paranormal Group, investigating the supernatural world is both an entertaining and consuming pastime.
They have filmed in the morgue of Ballarat's Aradale Asylum, scared radio journalists silly at South Australia's haunted Struan House, and toured Melbourne's Pentridge Prison, where the spirit of ex-con Chopper Read supposedly lurks.

Late on a cold and stormy Sunday night, the men unpack thousands of dollars worth of equipment and gadgets in the Grand Hotel's rabbit warren of rooms and corridors.
Full-spectrum cameras, electromagnetic detectors, laser light grids, and a curiously named spirit box, a device which contacts spirits through radio frequencies.
Also in their investigative armoury is a teddy bear dressed as a firefighter, a lure for any lurking child spirits.
"Just in case," Mr McPhail says, with a smile. "Who can resist a firefighter?"
Tonight, the trio are hoping to have an encounter with Mary - a former publican of the hotel more than a century ago - who has been sighted numerous times in years past.
As the men switch their audio recorders on and flick the light switch off, Mr McPhail calls on the Grand's spectral guests to make themselves known.
"Is there anybody with us tonight?" And so the night's ghost hunting begins.
The resident ghosts

"I didn't just inherit one ghost. We're known for up to 10," the Grand's new publican Steve Thomas said.
When the Thomas family took over the hotel in late 2016, the venue was a frequent mention on Australia's most haunted hotel lists and websites such as

For Mr Thomas, who had worked at many historic and supposedly haunted pubs across the United Kingdom, the hotel's spectral reputation was no big deal.
"We knew there was something here. I never disbelieved but I never believed until I came here," he said.
"This pub has made me a believer. A few things have happened upstairs."
The stories and sightings over the years, by multiple staff and visitors alike, have occurred in many rooms of the hotel and contain a cast of different characters.
A little boy who plays around the pool table, a woman who appears in the old service quarters, and an elderly man who wanders up the back stairs late at night and leaves a lingering smell of cigar smoke.
Those stories often emerge years later, Mr Thomas said, for fear of the teller being seen as a "kook".
Mr Thomas, who sees the comical side of the situation, has also had the pleasure of debunking a few strange hotel happenings.

Wardrobe doors that have swung open on their own has occurred, Mr Thomas has discovered, because the floor was on a slant.
Excited staff pointing out light 'orbs' on night cameras he has dismissed as mere dust.
But other occurrences, Mr Thomas cannot explain.
During the nine months he has lived upstairs, doors have banged in the middle of the night, furniture has been moved in the dining room, quilts have been lifted from guests and a woman, believed to be Mary, has been spotted standing facing the wall.
Despite those incidents, Mr Thomas said he was still reluctant to use the word "ghosts".
"I am a cynic. I'm not going to say 'Oh, that is a ghost'. I'm going to say 'Well, I don't know what that is. I think there is something there but I don't know what it is and I can't explain it'."
Promoting the supernatural

When a paranormal group advertised a full moon investigation tour of the Grand Hotel this year, the online tickets were snapped up in just 20 minutes.

It was a shock for the new publican, who said he was sceptical about promoting the hotel's haunted status, despite being urged by fellow hoteliers.
"Everyone said 'You have to do it; it's a really interesting thing', but I wasn't really convinced," he said.
A night at the Grand is a hot ticket for ghost hunter groups and paranormal investigators and on the quiet, Mr Thomas has opened the hotel's doors to several groups.
"We're not advertising it but if they approach me, I'm happy to accommodate them," he said.
"It keeps things interesting and at least it lets us know what's around."

A reputation for spirits might not turn away a thirsty beer drinker in the daylight hours, but would a haunted reputation scare away a weary traveller looking for a bed for the night?
Mr Thomas, who sleeps upstairs in the manager's quarters, said he was warming to the idea of living and working alongside his fellow spectral hotel dwellers. After all, they were here first.
"The hotel has a history," he said, simply.
"We've sort of inherited it and just run with it.
"It's big enough up there so they can have their space if they leave my space alone."
Beliefs and sceptics

"Everyone has their own beliefs," said Chris Kenny, as midnight ticks closer in the Grand Hotel.
"If we capture anything, we will let people draw their own conclusions from that evidence."

Ghost hunting is pretty hit and miss at the best of times and Mr McPhail said you had to trust your mates not to contaminate the scene for a laugh.
At a time when photographs, audio and video can easily be faked, the trio know a die-hard sceptic will not be convinced, no matter what they find at the hotel.
Tonight, despite three separate pieces of equipment going "nuts" for most of the night, the many ghosts of the Grand keep their silence.
The three men take turns lying on the bed in a room where another paranormal investigator reported an encounter with a ghost believed to be Clifford, related to Mary.
But ghost hunters have day jobs too. One of the trio admits he may have fell asleep at one point, his snores picked up by all the ultra-sensitive equipment.

The fact is, hunting for ghosts is a pretty entertaining way to spend a night.
"The second we stop having fun, we won't do it anymore," Mr McPhail said.
"We laugh all the time. We really don't take it too seriously."
After the actual visit, hours and hours of footage has to be examined closely and the members of the Mount Paranormal Group will decide for themselves what is evidence or not.
As to the ultimate question - are there ghosts in the Grand Hotel - Mr McPhail's answer is simple.
"Undefined," he said matter-of-factly.
"We've certainly got some unexplained audio and unexplained pictures. We've heard whispers while we've been communicating that has come across as a clear 'go away'."
But he doesn't believe in ghosts. Right?
"Evidence can be manipulated and your mind can play tricks on you. So until I get that definitive, 100  per cent proof, I'll keep looking."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Thomas</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren McPhail</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millicent's Grand Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Paranormal Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Kenny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McPhail</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Struan House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballarat's Aradale Asylum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Hotel</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chopper Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Pentridge Prison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
