<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398875185262492</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/viral-tinder-couple-finally-meet-after-three-years/news-story/96dbdb4524ba73711b720936c5068a98</url>
  <title>Tinder couple's highly unusual first date</title>
  <content>
IN A 21st Century true love story, a Tinder couple who matched nearly three years ago and went viral have finally met on Good Morning America.
Two Kent State University students, Josh Avsec and Michelle Arendas, swiped right on each other back in 2014 and have been messaging ever since. Well, kind of....
When the two matched all those years ago, Avsec sent a simple, "Hey Michelle," but her eagerly awaited replied did not slide into his inbox for two whole months.
Arendas' reply, "Hey sorry my phone died!" kicked off a three-year-long game where the two messaged each other increasingly creative excuses for their delayed responses.
Earlier this month, Avsec shared two screenshots of their conversation on Twitter saying, "Hahahaha one day I'm going to meet this girl and it's going to be epic."
Twitter users went crazy over the couple's "fateful" encounter, leading Arendas to be tagged by a friend of a friend in the comments of the post.
Breaking her usual two-month reply streak she responded, but only to say, "Sorry I'd reply but I need to give it a few months."
Almost 36,000 retweets and 110,000 favourites later the two finally came face-to-face on Good Morning America.
With a wall dividing them so they stillcould not see each other, Avsec and Arendas were sat on the set of the ABC series each taking turns to answer typical first-date questions.
Avsec admitted he could binge watch The Office and Arendas quickly jumped in saying, "Exact same for me. I think I've watched it through like eight times now."
After what seemed like forever and with encouraging cheers from the audience, the two were given the go ahead to stand up so they could finally come face-to-face.
"This is a dream come true. I can't believe I'm seeing her right now," Avsec gushed after embracing Arendas in a big hug.
The "first date" did not end there either. After the couple's conversation initially went viral on Twitter, Tinder decided it was time to intervene. The company promised to send the two on a free trip to any city they wanted so they could finally see each other in real life.
Arendas and Avsec chose Maui, which is where they said they were heading after the interview.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sorry I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAUI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Arendas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Good Morning America</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kent State University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avsec</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinder</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey Michelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arendas</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Avsec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
