<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399686934092429</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/prime-minister-malcolm-turnbull-downplays-gst-woes-on-perth-trip/8760194</url>
  <title>Malcolm Turnbull downplays GST woes as WA Government requests urgent meeting</title>
  <content>
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has brushed aside fears the Liberal Party will be punished at the next federal election if Western Australia does not get a better GST deal, amid concerns of another hit to the state's revenue.
Mr Turnbull's first visit to Perth since February coincided with the WA Government seeking an urgent meeting over fears its GST share could take another hit, due to changes in population estimates.
- a share much lower than any other state.
WA Treasurer Ben Wyatt has now written to federal counterpart Scott Morrison, warning changes in population estimates derived from the latest census could cost the state $1.9 billion in GST revenue over the next four years.
"I'm calling on [Mr Turnbull] to rule this out. West Australians can't take any more," WA Premier Mark McGowan said.
"Our schools, hospitals, roads and police will all suffer if this write-down is put in place."
A spokesperson for the Prime Minister said Mr McGowan and Mr Turnbull would meet during his visit.
But Mr Turnbull - who visited students at Swan View Senior High School on Monday morning - said he could not comment on the population issue because he had previously been unaware of it.
The Prime Minister again defended his Government's actions over the GST issue, insisting any change to the distribution system needed to be fair to the whole country.
"It's got to past the pub test, not just in Mindarie but around the rest of the country too," Mr Turnbull said.
Mr Turnbull last week said he had spoken "frankly" to other states about a proposed GST floor - below which no state's share of revenue from the tax could fall.
However, what that change could look like and when it may occur remain unclear.
The floor proposal was , but the idea is yet to progress.
The distribution system is now the subject of .
Turnbull claims warm Perth welcome

Mr Turnbull insisted he was doing what he could to ensure WA got a better deal.
"I'm the first Prime Minister to acknowledge that Western Australia is not getting a fair deal out of the GST," Mr Turnbull said.
His visit comes after polling suggested the Liberals could lose five or six seats in WA at the next federal election, amid ongoing anger over the GST.
But Mr Turnbull brushed aside those fears, saying he had been "warmly welcomed" to WA so far.
"I'm concerned about good government for all Australians and a good government for Western Australia," he said.
Mr Turnbull will remain in WA for the rest of the week and will visit regional centres Albany, Busselton and Broome.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Treasurer Ben Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan View Senior High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mindarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Busselton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
