<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399515135398276</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/gisborne-29lot-apartment-plans-knocked-back/news-story/76b37af73d9ce5e85fa6ae582146588d</url>
  <title>Gisborne apartment plans knocked back</title>
  <content>
MACEDON RANGES Council has knocked back plans for a 29-lot apartment and townhouse-style development in Gisborne, reiterating a February decision on the same proposal.
Applicant G2 Urban Planning presented plans for 10 townhouses, one single-storey dwelling and 18 apartments at 22 Calthorpe St.
The nature and style of development failed to impress a majority of councillors despite the original council report, made after subsequent discussions with the applicant, recommending approval of the plan.
Those discussions had been ordered by VCAT where the final decision on the proposal is now likely to be made.
South Ward councillor Helen Radnedge told the meeting she had investigated whether similar style developments were appearing in communities such as Sunbury, Melton and Bendigo and found none.
"I believe an apartment block is not in line with the neighbourhood character of Gisborne," she said.
South Ward councillor Mandi Mees also concluded the "bulk, volume and density" of the proposal did not constitute a "medium density" definition of residential development in Gisborne as outlined in strategic planning documents such as the Gisborne Outline Development Plan.
Several objectors attended last Wednesday's council meeting.
Wendy Black told the meeting parking and car movements would be "disruptive and dangerous", while fellow speaker Simon Pinder said the amount of movements, up to 400 with 95 per cent stemming from one driveway, could lead to pedestrians being struck.
Fiona Corke had told the meeting council's decision on the proposal would risk being a precedent for similar developments elsewhere in Gisborne and the Macedon Ranges.
While councillors chose to back their earlier decision in February, two told the meeting the compromise offered by the developer was worth accepting.
West Ward vouncillor Roger Jukes said inevitably VCAT would rule in favour of the original plan, while East Ward's Henry Bleeck said the type of housing on offer, gave first home buyers and downsizers options.
The notice to refuse the proposal was made by 6-3 majority.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedon Ranges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Pinder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G2 Urban Planning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Ward</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCAT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calthorpe St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bendigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Jukes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Corke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Radnedge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gisborne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gisborne Outline Development Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Ward's Henry Bleeck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandi Mees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MACEDON RANGES Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
