<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398961084610197</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/recap-game-thrones-s7-e3-queens-justice/3206885/</url>
  <title>RECAP: Game of Thrones s7 e3 - The Queen's Justice</title>
  <content>
THEY finally meet.

In the most highly-anticipated scene of season seven of Game of Thrones, the 'Mother of Dragons' Daenerys Targaryen and King of the North Jon Snow came face to face for the first time.

It wasn't exactly a warm and fuzzy introduction, as Jon refused to bend the knee and Daenerys found his story about an army of the dead hard to believe.

As expected, Tyrion Lannister was the go-between trying to help the two parties together. With Daenerys's eyes still firmly on the Iron Throne to the south and Jon's on The Wall to the north, their priorities don't currently align.

But some headway was made as Daenerys agreed to allow Jon to start mining the dragonglass for his weapons

The fan theory that Jon is actually Daenerys's nephew wasn't addressed, but Emilia Clarke did have some great dialogue as Daenerys asserted herself:

"I spent my life in foreign lands. So many men have tried to kill me, I don't remember all their names. I have been sold like a brood mare; I've been shamed and betrayed, raped and defiled. Do you know what kept me standing through all those years in exile? Faith, not in any gods, not in myths and legends, in myself - in Daenerys Targaryen. I was born to rule the seven kingdoms and I will."

But today's episode wasn't named after this all-important meeting. Cersei, the current occupant of the Iron Throne, continued to show her cunning as she out-maneuvered Daenerys and Tyrion's forces.

She also tasted sweet revenge against Ellaria Sand, the woman who killed her daughter Myrcella, after she was apprehended and delivered to King's Landing by a smug Euron Greyjoy.

Here are some key points from today's episode, The Queen's Justice:

Dragonstone
Liam Cunningham and Kit Harington in a scene from season 7 episode 3 of Game of Thrones. HELEN SLOAN / HBO

It's been years since Jon Snow and Tyrion Lannister were together so it was absolutely fantastic to see them share a few words to start the episode.

For Davos, it was a homecoming of sorts. He was one of Stannis Baratheon's trusted men when the man some argued was the rightful heir to the throne after King Robert's death in the first round.

The long-awaited meeting between Daenerys Targaryen and Jon Snow lived up to expectation.

While most of us wished for happy families (are they related? Nothing's confirmed just yet), we got the opposite.

Daenerys flexed her dragon-led muscle from the Targaryen's home of Dragonstone.

She regaled Jon and Davos with powerful stories from her past, most of which we have witnessed. How she conquered Essos, led the Dothraki and Unsullied across the ocean, and, in case you hadn't noticed, had three dragons.

She was overwhelming, but Jon still stuck to his guns.

He was there to request help from Daenerys to take out the White Walkers, and he wasn't about to bend the knee to the rising Targaryen ruler.

With no impasse, Jon Snow became a virtual prisoner on the island, but Tyrion could have provided the way forward.

The Queen's Hand returned to Daenerys with a possible solution: allow Jon Snow to mine the dragonglass he came to request.

The Lannister's words of wisdom paid off, but it remains to be seen how their relationship will change in future.

"I did my part. I brought ice and fire together."
Conleth Hill and Carice van Houten in a scene from season 7 episode 3 of Game of Thrones. HELEN SLOAN / HBO

Melisandre and Varys' interaction atop a Dragonstone cliff as Snow and his entourage arrived was interesting purely for the final words of the conversation.

While Melisandre opened with the line above, it was her final words a future return to Westeros that was most interesting. After Varys' advised Melisandre not to return, she said it was where she must die, and where Varys will as well.

King's Landing
Indira Varma in a scene from season 7 episode 3 of Game of Thrones.Foxtel

Ellaria Sand killed Myrcella, Cersei's only daughter. In last week's "Stormborn" episode, Euron Greyjoy took the first steps towards providing Cersei's "gift" as he attacked Yara Greyjoy's fleet, killed a Sand Snake and captured Ellaria.

We first see Euron leading his prisoners, most notably Yara and Ellaria, through the streets of King's Landing.

"This is the life," Euron said as the crowd lavished him with praise and pelted the prisoners with whatever was within reach.

His gift for Cersei was justice for her murdered daughter.

In return, Cersei regarded him the best captain on the 14 seas, and said he would get what he wanted - her hand in marriage - once the war was won.

With Cersei on the throne, Euron commanding the naval fleet and Jaime Lannister commanding the armies, it is a powerful triumvirate that will take some beating.

In the cells, Cersei lifted her evil genius to another level.

She toyed with the chained Ellaria, talking about how the Dornish took away her only daughter. The long, drawn-out scene was tough to watch, but it showed just how cerebral Cersei has become.

Her choice of revenge - poison, applied via her lipstick in the same fashion as Ellaria killed Myrcella - was poetic justice. It just would've been easier to take if she wasn't so evil.

Winterfell
Sophie Turner and Aidan Gillen in a scene from season 7 episode 3 of Game of Thrones. HELEN SLOAN / HBO

Sansa Stark has encountered a major problem: there is only enough food to last a year.

While she deals with that, and unwanted advice from Lord Baelish, they are interrupted by an urgent request to go the front gate.

Those who watched Stormborn expected one reunion, but nobody could have expected Bran's arrival.

The last we saw of Bran, he had just passed under The Wall.

His reunion with Sansa was not exactly straight-forward. While the first moment was heart-warming, they have clearly disconnected over the years.

Bran's evolution into the Three-Eyed Raven, which he found extremely difficult to explain to Sansa, has fuelled that disconnect.

His comments about Sansa's wedding night in Winterfell proved too much for Sansa, which led to her quick departure.

It was obviously too much for her to hear, but will they be able to repair their relationship?

Lannisters at war
Peter Dinklage in a scene from season 7 episode 3 of Game of Thrones.Foxtel

Tyrion Lannister strikes again, but was he outsmarted by Jaime?

The lowly position in which the late Tywin Lannister has played directly into Daenerys's hands.

Tyrion built the sewers, allowing the Unsullied, led by Grey Worm, a secret passage to take Casterly Rock.

Except there were a few problems.

Casterly Rock didn't house as many troops as expected, so the Unsullied easily took the Lannister home. Euron Greyjoy's fleet arrived right on time, destroying the Unsullied's fleet, essentially trapping the Targaryen force.

While Daenerys could claim a minor victory, the real Lannister force, led by Jaime, marched on Highgarden: the home of the Tyrells.

Most of the Tyrell family was wiped out when the Sept of Baelor was destroyed, but Olenna Tyrell had managed to avoid the worst.

Until now.

In what we can assume as her final words on-camera in this series, Olenna told Jaime of how she was shocked to see Joffrey die. Joffrey was killed in season four, poisoned at his wedding to Margaery Tyrell.

She took a similar way out.

Jaime said he convinced Cersei not to hang, parade, or kill the oldest Tyrell at King's Landing, instead opting for a small vial of poison.

Where do we stand?
Pilou Asbaek and Nikolaj Coster-Waldau in a scene from season 7 episode 3 of Game of Thrones.Foxtel

"The Queen's Justice" was a particularly brutal episode for Cersei Lannister's enemies.

While Jon and Daenerys looked to have found some common ground, the rest of the Targaryen's force is in trouble.

Cersei enjoyed wins courtesy of Euron Greyjoy's fleet's destruction of Yara Greyjoy's fleet (in Stormborn last week), the capture of Ellaria Sand, the smart play at Casterly Rock, and the successful march on Highgarden (the end of House Tyrell).

Her mission is to consolidate her power and unite Westeros under her rule, which could me a clash with the North is on the horizon.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indira Varma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yara Greyjoy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aidan Gillen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Cunningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euron Greyjoy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Tyrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Justice</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casterly Rock</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kit Harington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dinklage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bran</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna Tyrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highgarden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conleth Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winterfell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tywin Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrells</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellaria</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stormborn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Targaryen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dornish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joffrey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sand Snake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myrcella</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey Worm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragonstone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emilia Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dothraki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Three-Eyed Raven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Sloan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikolaj Coster-Waldau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys Targaryen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Hand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mother of Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sept of Baelor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King of the North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellaria Sand</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Baelish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Walkers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaery Tyrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Landing</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stannis Baratheon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Throne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melisandre</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion Lannister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unsullied</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilou Asbaek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
