<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399734178733332</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/15/16/courier-giant-questions-security-checks</url>
  <title>Courier giant questions security checks</title>
  <content>
One of the world's leading courier companies says it's "unbelievable" Australia still relies on paper documents such as birth certificates for security checks.
A parliamentary committee is investigating improvements to Australia's border arrangements including the security of parcel and freight services.
DHL security manager Margaret McCormack told a hearing in Canberra on Monday her workforce was required to go through stringent security checks including Aviation Security Identification Cards (ASICs).
But she said there was a flaw in the system, which would require a change in the law to implement.
"Things like a paper birth certificate being a primary method of identification - I find that unbelievable," Ms McCormack said.
"There's biometrics everywhere in the world now and biometrics should be introduced with ASIC cards and perhaps facial recognition as well."
Biometrics include unique identifiers such as fingerprints, retina and iris patterns, voice waves and DNA.

Related Articles

Ms McCormack said police and ASIO checks were routinely conducted on her workforce but there was "some intelligence which doesn't show up on a police check".
The biggest challenge was the company's temporary workforce and contractors.
When asked whether any DHL employees or contractors had fallen foul of the law, the committee went into a private session.
Ms McCormack said keeping illegal goods out of the network was a "difficult job" and the company worked closely with Australian Border Force and Australian Federal Police to keep tabs on the more than 15 million shipments handled each year.
The key focus of x-raying air-freighted parcels was looking for explosives.
She gave the example of a shipment two weeks ago which was cleared in Pakistan, but DHL customer service later reported some "suspicious lack of information from the caller" about the shipment.
It was referred to the ABF, which discovered it to be a shipment of illegal drugs.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Border Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret McCormack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aviation Security Identification Cards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DHL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McCormack</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
