<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399643984418749</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4822437/unanderra-public-school-students-put-landcare-grant-to-good-use/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Unanderra Public School students put Landcare grant to good use</title>
  <content>
Unanderra Public School students Phoenix and Olivia, with Landcare Australia representative Reeva Badhwar and teacher Meryl Simpson.
Unanderra Public School had some extra cash to help with its National Schools Tree Day activities.

The school was the first in NSW to receive a $5000 grant from the South32 Junior Landcare Grants program.

It will use the funds to restore overgrown and degraded areas within the school grounds with native gardens, engage all students in the planting and ongoing care and provide an outdoor classroom for learning.

Students will be working with local Landcare volunteers on the project and hosting garden parties in the spaces to encourage families to enjoy the native gardens.

The students will also be the driving force behind how the project is undertaken and Landcare will be considered as a sport option at school for interested students.

The South32 Junior Landcare Grants program is distributing 10 grants of up to $5000 to schools in the Illawarra and Wollondilly regions of NSW and Collie and Boddington regions of Western Australia.

Landcare Australia spokeswoman Reeva Badhwar said these grants will fund habitat restoration projects.

The presentation to Unanderra Public School on July 28 was the first in the program to take place in NSW.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>South32 Junior Landcare Grants</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meryl Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unanderra Public School</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollondilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landcare</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reeva Badhwar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landcare Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Schools Tree Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
