<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399661164288335</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:13</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/have-you-seen-the-coasts-car-surfing-magpie/3207040/</url>
  <title>Have you seen the Coast's car surfing magpie?</title>
  <content>
RESIDENTS may have many names for him - Hitch, Ten Ten, Willy, or even simply 'that bird', but there's no doubt that this magpie is ruffling some feathers.
The magpie has been hanging on to cars and going for a ride, much to the shock or joy of motorists.
Golden Beach resident Michelle Reid said she has noticed the bird hopping on cars at the Caloundra roundabout for months now.
Yesterday, her daughter managed to catch the cheeky magpie in the act.
"We see him all the time," Ms Reid said.
"Yesterday it was a fluke that I saw him in the rear-view mirror.
"My daughter, she's 17. So, like a normal 17-year-old, she had her phone in her hand so she flicked the camera on."
The Reids were on their way to the butchers to prepare for a Sunday afternoon barbecue when they drove through the Nicklin Way/Caloundra Road/Pelican Waters Boulevard roundabout.
This was when Ms Reid noticed their black-and-white stowaway.
"We've seen him for the last three or four months doing it," she said.
"We live at Golden Beach so we come down Pelican Waters Boulevard regularly - he's always there.
"He just hangs on and will wait until the next car comes along.
"He's just a little bird hitching a ride."
Ms Reid shared the video on social media, with some criticising the bird for his dangerous antics while others saw the joy in the joyriding magpie.
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
Celebration after Coast gym snapped up in last minute sale
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Reid</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pelican Waters Boulevard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicklin Way/Caloundra Road/Pelican Waters Boulevard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
