<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399643984418756</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/community-rallies-to-save-boinga-bobs-warburton-house/news-story/0439ca0b9c08d774cb675d03f58a1ee1</url>
  <title>Push to save famous sculpture house</title>
  <content>
THE community has rallied around the owner of a Warburton sculpture house who says he can't "physically or financially" carry out safety repairs.
An online crowd-funding campaign has raised $US570 ($780 Australian) to help Robert Prudhoe, otherwise known as Boinga Bob, repair the Tibetan-inspired home he has lived in for more than 20 years.
It comes ahead of a meeting between Mr Prudhoe and Yarra Ranges Council on Wednesday to discuss safety issues at his property.
The property's ageing and "dilapidated and unsafe" structure has been an increasing concern for the council, which engaged a structural engineer in March to determine the work needed to meet its building code and regulations.

In a statement, the council's social and economic development director Ali Wastie said some structures couldn't be made safe "due to the unconventional and non-compliant method of construction" and the way they had weathered and deteriorated over time.
The recommendations included fencing off certain sections of the house until they could be rebuilt, and removing sections that were fire-affected and deteriorating.
The engineer also found "critical" requirements included making the balustrade and stairs safe, and addressing weatherproofing and electrical safety issues.
Mr Prudhoe said the council was aware he couldn't "physically or financially" carry out any repairs and he would feel "unfairly victimised" if he was told to demolish his house.
"I'm 77 years of age now," Mr Prudhoe said.
"I've had heart surgery, I'm ready to get hip surgery - I don't want any more trouble.
"I would like to be living in my own home under peaceful circumstances, and promote and help the arts and tourism in Warburton and the Yarra Valley."
Mr Prudhoe said he was hopeful of an "optimistic and positive resolution" which would be "good for me and the whole community".
"I always try to do my very best for Warburton," he said.
"I look forward to a good outcome to resolve the situation, and I hope the council values my considerable contribution to tourism in the town.
"I don't want to keep living here if the council want to make my life a misery."
Mr Prudhoe's home encroaches on council and State Government land.
Yarra Ranges Council refused to answer further questions relating to public liability, a deadline for completing the work and a course of action if they weren't completed.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US570 ($780 Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Ranges Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Prudhoe</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Prudhoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tibetan-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boinga Bob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warburton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Wastie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
