<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399691229059820</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/residents-slam-sunbury-visitor-centre-move-from-historic-site-to-new-complex/news-story/22d10704d30ccbe9bf5d9588567bff1c</url>
  <title>Anger over Sunbury visitor centre move</title>
  <content>
A DECISION to relocate the Sunbury Visitors Information Centre to the soon-to-be-built Hume Global Learning Centre-Sunbury has drawn the ire of the Sunbury Residents' Association.
The 1885 former courthouse adjacent a historic bluestone lockup and existing police station has been the home of the centre since a community campaign in the 1980s that rescued the building.
But the future function of the building is now clouded.

SRA president Peter Free, who also sat on a community consultative group looking into the centre, said he was blindsided by the move to change the address of the key tourism post.
A letter has been sent by the association to Hume Council over the decision, urging the retention of the site as a visitor centre.
Mr Free said the SRA believed the centre was ideally located and offered appropriate parking for buses and caravans.
"Hume Council is showing its contempt for the Sunbury community's long history and association with this building by proposing this action without any community notice," he said.
According to Hume Mayor Drew Jessop, the centre relocation will improve visitor experiences.
"The housing of the Sunbury Visitor Information Centre at the HGLC-S is an exciting development and ensures the visitor centre will have access to modern facilities, and provides ease-of-use for residents and visitors by bringing services to the one central location," Cr Jessop said.
Sunbury councillor Ann Potter said moving the visitor centre would bring it under the same roof as the George Evans Museum and interactive library facilities.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HGLC-S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Jessop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ann Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Evans Museum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury Visitors Information Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Frees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SRA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury Residents' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume Global Learning Centre-Sunbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Free</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume Mayor Drew Jessop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
