<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399429236051364</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/western-bulldogs-premiership-forward-tory-dickson-says-dogs-are-building-momentum-20170731-gxm48p.html</url>
  <title>Western Bulldogs premiership forward Tory Dickson says Dogs are building momentum</title>
  <content>
Western Bulldogs premiership hero Tory Dickson says the Dogs are building momentum, with the forward taking a "never say never" approach to the remainder of the season.
After a turbulent premiership defence in which they have been thwarted at various times by injury, illness and poor form, the Dogs have won three in a row, briefly returning to the top eight after their 30-point win over Essendon at Etihad Stadium on Sunday before being dislodged later in the day by West Coast.

Up Next

Cloke kicks a cracker

00:28

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

Like his club, Dickson hasn't been able to regularly find his groove this season. Hampered by persistent groin trouble, he has been limited to just seven senior games in 2017, and was dropped after the round 15 loss to the Eagles.
However the Dogs sharpshooter returned to the seniors on Sunday, kicking three goals as his side piled on 19 majors and posted their biggest total since 2015. Dickson said his two-match spell in the VFL had served him well.Photo: Getty Images
"I've had problems with my groins all year. It was trying to get my body perfect and ideal, and doing everything I can to make sure I'm feeling 100 per cent going into games," Dickson said.
"[The message] was simple, 'go back and do the fundamentals and the easy things that make me play well,' which is obviously pressure and create."

The Dogs face the Brisbane Lions (Gabba), Greater Western Sydney (Etihad Stadium), Port Adelaide (Ballarat) and Hawthorn (Etihad) in their run home, and Dickson said that despite the club's challenges this year - which have included mental health battles for Travis Cloke and Tom Boyd - the Dogs can still have a big say come the pointy end of the season.
"It's been an up and down year, we've obviously had injuries, we've had individuals with not as great form as last year, and obviously the team hasn't played as well as we've wanted to play.
"[But] I think off the back of three really good wins, defensively and obviously attacking, we're building some momentum.
"You never say never. We've got four more games to go, it's a very tight season. We can't take any opposition for granted. Hopefully just keep on building that momentum and see where it takes us."
Playing his first senior game since round 12, Cloke was solid against the Bombers on Sunday, with Dogs coach Luke Beveridge agreeing that a dilemma had been posed as to whether the veteran forward would hold his spot, or whether fellow tall forward Jack Redpath would return following a one-match suspension.
Medium forward Jake Stringer is also closing in on a return from his hamstring injury, while the successful shift forward on Sunday of Jason Johannisen - who kicked four goals - has highlighted an extra string to the Dogs' attacking bow.
The Dogs had 12 individual goalkickers against Essendon, with Dickson suggesting it was a sign things were on the right track. "I think that's what made us so hard to play against last year, you didn't know who was going to kick the goals," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday of Jason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballarat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Redpath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tory Dickson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Stringer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
