<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399734178733360</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/federal-politics/political-opinion/a-trust-problem-bill-shortens-early-policy-a-risk-as-coalition-talks-prosperity-20170731-gxm4vd.html</url>
  <title>A trust problem: Bill Shorten's early policy a risk as Coalition talks prosperity</title>
  <content>
The trouble with releasing policies well ahead of any election - usually desirable - is that you can become welded to ideas that need further work, fine tuning, etcetera.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Labor's 'war on the rich' - not

Bill Shortenas big announcement actually cements the use of discretionary trusts as excellent vehicles for tax minimisation. Michael Pascoe comments.

Post-announcement tinkering to patch unintended consequences, is easily depicted as retreat and worse, confusion. Another problem is that in mapping out large parts of the policy terrain, what's left unsaid becomes the focus.
So while Labor complains of the rich getting richer while everyone else slides, it is increasingly exposed to the charge that via its "inequality" agenda, it has (i) abandoned the task of growing the national economic pie in favour of distributing it, and (ii) proposed a policy that will inevitably affect some legitimate small businesses.

Not that the government has much to crow about here. The Coalition has made little impression on stagnant wages and widespread under-employment in the 13 months since it ran on the gloriously diffuse goal of "jobs and growth". Modelling of its permanently blocked $65.4 billion business tax cut (by 2027) shows its centrepiece policy lever would have only a modest impact on economic expansion. And that, years down the track.
Still, serious parties of government must present a full suite of economic policies. Stubbornly flat wage growth is a core problem in many post-GFC economies. And that in turn, has become the major handbrake on confidence, and on growth overall. So much so that Reserve Bank Governor, Philip Lowe (no less) has begun urging employees to demand wage rises. There are even hints that pay increases need not be offset with productivity gains.

Malcolm Turnbull's company tax plan may not be popular, but at least it allows the government to defend its ongoing pursuit of growth and prosperity.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Labor seems to be getting more vulnerable on this front as the term progresses. Its latest economic prescription is another tax increase. That comes on top of its proposed re-instatement of the now lapsed 2 per cent temporary deficit repair levy on high income earners, and amid signs it will roll back some of the business tax cuts already legislated.Photo: AAP
Doubtless, taxing trust income at a flat 30 per cent rate to stop persons with means arranging their affairs in ways that ordinary people cannot, plays well to the politics of grievance.
It is for the most part, sensible, measured, reform (even if  when ).
But in the absence of another strong policy idea aimed specifically at firing up profit-making and thus growth, Labor risks the impression it has lost its longstanding interest in strengthening the market side of the economy. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shortena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank Governor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Pascoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Post-announcement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
