<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399704113961907</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:23</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/exclusive-take-a-peek-inside-the-sunshine-coasts-m/3207034/</url>
  <title>EXCLUSIVE: Take a peek inside the Sunshine Coast's marijuana farm</title>
  <content>
IN AN Australian first, the media has been granted an exclusive look inside a medicinal marijuana farm.
The Sunshine Coast's MediFarm, which is still under construction, is the first of its kind in the state and is expected to have product on the market by the first quarter of 2018.
Secrecy was key for the operation with reporters' phones required to have aeroplane mode turned on and location services turned off - lest a stray Tweet or Facebook post betray the farm's address.
It's not just in the interest of preventing rubberneckers, MediFarm's licence from the Office of Drug Control is dependent on its ability to keep under the radar.
Founder Adam Benjamin said senior police and military personnel have advised on security for the farm which would be subject to constant monitoring.

"MediFarm is not allowed to... advertise where we are," he said.
"But if someone happens to find out, we believe with our security measures and counter measures, we'll be right."
Speaking from outside an under-construction greenhouse, Mr Benjamin said biological measures in place would allow the cultivation of "strictly controlled medicine", much like traditional medicines on the market.
"This is about having a plant that can be grown identically across thousands of plants day in and day out," he said.
"Much as you would with Panadol, when you go and get something you expect that what you're being prescribed is what you're getting and that's the same with medicinal cannabis."
MediFarm is in the unique position of being able to oversee the marijuana from plant to product with two licences which allow the company to cultivate, produce and manufacture.
Mr Benjamin had to keep mum on the amount of plants to be grown at the facility, but said he predicted there would be enough to supply 5000 patients.
"We'll be importing our first cuttings from overseas, but after that happens we become self sufficient," he said.
"What MediFarm will be doing is producing oils and that's through a process of extraction."
This farm has thrust the Sunshine Coast into an international $200 billion industry, but Mr Benjamin said the first 12 months would be spent tending to local customers.
"Medifarm would like to focus on Queensland in the first year of production," he said.
"We do have inquiries from all over Australia.
"There's huge room for growth, you just have to look overseas."
With the help of Tikun Olam, an Israeli company at the forefront of the industry, Mr Benjamin said MediFarm would be able to offer Australian patients "the best in medicinal cannabis".
The companies are working in exclusive partnership with one another, giving MediFarm access to more than a decade of experience in medicinal marijuana.
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
VIDEO: Car surfing bird ruffles feathers
Celebration after Coast gym snapped up in last minute sale
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of Drug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Benjamin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medifarm</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast's MediFarm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Benjamin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panadol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tikun Olam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
