<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399429236051369</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/port-arthur-massacre-survivor-finds-healing-through-singing/8744540</url>
  <title>Port Arthur massacre survivor finds healing through singing</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Port Arthur massacre survivor Cathy Gordon is using choral music to help her deal with the affects of post-traumatic stress disorder, 21 years after the deadliest mass shooting in Australia's history.
Ms Gordon was working for the Tasmanian Symphony Orchestra in 1996 when she was tasked with escorting a group of singers from Opera Australia on a sightseeing trip to Port Arthur.

The group had just emerged from the Broad Arrow Cafe when Martin Bryant opened fire, .
"I left the group a couple of times and ended up witnessing things I wish I hadn't," Ms Gordon said.
"No one should have to witness anything like that in war or in peace time."
Ms Gordon has spent the past 21 years dealing with symptoms of severe post-traumatic stress.
"For those who survived who were injured, they had a physical injury and they had loss and they had to grieve ... I didn't," she said.
"What I lost on that day was me and yet I was still living.
"Everything that was familiar to me was foreign, in a split second that lasted a lifetime.
"I still looked like me, I still sounded like me, but I had absolutely no idea who I was.
"I felt it was unsafe for anyone to be around me. I alienated my parents and didn't want anything to do with them."

Ms Gordon moved to Ballina on the New South Wales north coast in 1998 with the hope of starting a new life.
She said she would be forever grateful for meeting an empathetic doctor in her new home town.
"My doctor said 'Come to indoor cricket with me, you need to get out' or 'You could go to singing with my wife'," Ms Gordon said.
"So I went and sat on the back pew for four weeks and they treated me no differently, and eventually I started to sing with them."

Ms Gordon said reconnecting with music slowly led to her rediscovering happiness.
"It was like a computer screen - you have all the icons there and you can double click on some of them until the cows come home and it will not open, and then all of a sudden one day one will open," she said.
"I tell you, I've never won lotto, but I would say just having that brief glimpse of normality of what life used to be like, it might last for five minutes and that was what started to happen with my music."
Ms Gordon was recently appointed musical director of the Headliners Chorus, which she said provided much-needed motivation.
"It gives me something every week that I'm committed to that enables me to find that strength inside myself," she said.
"To see the joy on the members' faces as they sing, to hear them improve with the skills that I'm actually giving them, and to have audience members come out from a performance that we have and say 'That really touched me'.
"I think that's unique to the Headliners. There's so much love and care and acceptance of who we are, that through our music we can share that joy with each other and with people whose lives we touch by sharing that in the community."

Ms Gordon now hopes to inspire others who have post-traumatic stress disorder.
"It's not an illness, it's an injury. Don't think of yourself as being sick. Try to get to a place within yourself where you can see it as an injury," she said.
"Find who you are and hold on to that, hold on to that with every bit of life in you.
"Be proud of being a little bit different, because that's all we are, just a little bit different."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Symphony Orchestra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gordon</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Bryant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opera Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Headliners Chorus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Arthur</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathy Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broad Arrow Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
