<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398870890295005</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4822403/time-is-running-out-to-enter-illawarra-business-awards/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Entries close for Illawarra Business Awards in exactly one week</title>
  <content>
Region on a plate: Leanne Shaffer, Warwick Shanks, Marc Swan, Isaac Palmer, Chris Lamont, Robert Ryan & Geoff Jansz are ready to serve up a new treat at the 2017 IMB Bank Illawarra Business Awards at the WIN Entertainment Centre in October. Picture: Greg Ellis.

Nominations for the 2017  close in one week.

The Illawarra Business Chamber is advising that when entries close at 5pm on August 7 there will be no extension this year.

So it is is encouraging businesses in the five local government areas that make up the region to look at the award categories early this week and then start pulling together their award application.
Executive director Chris Lamont said there was something for everyone including new award categories covering tourism, retail and hospitality, social enterprise and the Wollongong City Centre business excellence.
"12 of the 17 award categories are aligned with the NSW State Awards, meaning the winners of these categories will be given the opportunity to compete at State level and bring further recognition and exposure to their business and the region," Mr Lamont said.

Other categories are innovation, employer of choice, export, sustainability, small business, young entrepreneur, young business executive, business leader, outstanding new business, local chamber of commerce, customer service and Wollongong City Centre business excellence.

An Illawarra Business of the Year Award will again be presented. Auditor of judging Warwick Shanks, of KPMG Wollongong, and IMB Bank chief executive Robert Ryan are encouraging as many business as possible to support the event this year at WIN Entertainment Centre on October 20.

who will be presenting his own showcase of the Illawarra is put on a plate.

Jansz is designing a locally inspired menu especially for the occasion at the Diamonds Are Forever themed event.
The star of television shows such as What's Cooking, Fresh and Burke's Backyard said he was designing a three-course meal based on his passion for freshness and originality.
- Geoff Jansz
"I grew up in the Illawarra, with its rich cultural heritage. My father had a business in Corrimal. I am excited because I can feel the memories of my childhood. I want to put some local meaning on the plate because it is the Illawarra awards and it is a great region".

Related story:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIN Entertainment Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burke's Backyard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Business Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMB Bank Illawarra Business Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Business Chamber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leanne Shaffer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMB Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jansz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Business of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW State Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong City Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPMG Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamonds Are Forever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Jansz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Swan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Ryan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Lamont</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lamont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Shanks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
