<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398978264479717</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:34</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/07/mcdonalds-is-bringing-backrick-and-mortys-beloved-szechuan-saucefrom-another-dimension/</url>
  <title>McDonald's Is Bringing Back Rick And Morty's Beloved Szechuan Sauce From Another Dimension</title>
  <content>
Image: Cartoon Network

McDonald's Szechuan Sauce, the limited edition dipping sauce that was briefly available in the summer of 1998 as promotion for Disney's Mulan, is Rick Sanchez's singular reason for traversing the multiverse. Just in time for the show's third season return, a McDonald's chef has brought the sauce back.

At this year's San Diego Comic-Con, Rick and Morty co-creator Justin Roiland  that he'd been in contact with McDonald's after the show's third season premiere prominently featured the sauce. After the episode aired, thousands of fans  for McDonald's to bring it back and a single bottle of the stuff  on eBay. Last night, Roiland took to Twitter to reveal that McDonald's lived up to their promise and sent him a single 1,814.37g jug of Szechuan Sauce from an alternate dimension where it's always 1998.

Along with the sauce was a note from one of McDonald's chefs named Mike (there are a  of ) explaining the lengths they had to go to in order to procure the sauce.

Mike wrote:

While Roiland got the first bottle, Chef Mike added that "a few lucky fans will get to experience the glory" meaning that the fast food giant is probably planning to roll it out for another limited time run.

Update: This morning, McDonalds posted a new picture of three more jugs of the sauce to its Twitter feed along with the time and date of Rick and Morty's return tonight on Adult Swim. It's coming back, folks.

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chef Mike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morty's Beloved Szechuan Sauce From Another Dimension</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eBay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonalds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney's Mulan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Szechuan Sauce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald's Szechuan Sauce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roiland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Roiland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego Comic Con</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald's Is Bringing Back Rick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Sanchez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adult Swim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cartoon Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
