<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399343336704311</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/business/factory-worker-who-sued-powerballwinning-colleagues-for-share-has-a-1m-court-bill/news-story/2ab3dbeb3cc231c3d33a4c0166ce337e</url>
  <title>Lotto loser's eye-watering bill</title>
  <content>
THE broke factory worker who lost a legal fight against his work colleagues for a slice of a $40 million lotto win has moved to the US after being left with an eye-watering $1 million court bill.
Father-of-five Brendan King quit Australia two weeks ago after accepting a two-year transfer to South Carolina from electricity factory Prysmian Group's Cromer plant on Sydney's northern beaches.
He is facing a hefty bill of close to $1 million after being ordered to pay the legal costs of the 14 colleagues he worked with in Liverpool after he sued them when they each won $2.8 million in the Powerball in May last year.
The factory supervisor alleged the group - led by - froze him out of the syndicate.
"It got too much for Brendan, he's a good guy, he transferred with the company to Lexington two weeks ago and will be there for two years," Fahad Saleem, a co-worker from the Cromer plant, said.
"It's a fresh start in life for him and his family."
The Daily Telegraph can reveal the beleaguered Mr King, 44, has lodged a bid, to be heard in the Court of Appeal next month, to appeal the original judgment that he was not entitled to be considered the 15th member of the winning syndicate and claim $2.7 million of the winnings.
As result of the appeal, a NSW Supreme Court hearing earlier this month to decide the costs he faces was postponed.
Mr King's move was described by a spokesman at Shine Solicitors as "a promotion".
This means lawyers for his former colleagues will find it harder to enforce the cost order while he is living abroad.
Several weeks ago, Mr King admitted his bid for the lotto cash had taken a harsh toll on him and his family.
"I've got too many bills," he said from his Yarramalong home on the Central Coast.
"My wife is seriously sick but I will get my day in court. I won't give up what is rightfully mine.
"Whatever happens, my family remains my biggest treasure. But I can't pretend this hasn't been a stress on us."
All but two of the factory workers have quit the plant where they worked in Liverpool after banking their prize money while Mr King was transferred to Cromer to avoid further conflict.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prysmian Group's Cromer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr King</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Powerball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shine Solicitors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lotto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Court of Appeal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fahad Saleem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Carolina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lexington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarramalong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cromer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
