<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398909545001615</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/mining/why-west-australian-lithium-miners-are-exploring-downstream-processing-20170720-gxfnqn</url>
  <title>Why West Australian lithium miners are exploring downstream processing</title>
  <content>
When Galaxy Resources opened the Jiangsu lithium carbonate plant in China in March 2012 it was the only Australian company with a major presence in the nascent market.
Following an explosion that  and operational challenges, the troubled plant was sold for $US173 million in 2015.
But now, with the price for lithium carbonate about triple what it was in 2012, Australian mining companies bringing hard rock lithium mines into production are turning their attention back downstream.
A reinvented Galaxy is now the only major West Australian lithium miner that has not flagged plans to become involved in converting spodumene concentrate from a mine in the state into one of the lithium chemicals used in lithium-ion batteries, demand for which has been  and energy storage systems.

Kidman Resources has  to add a chemical plant to its planned Earl Grey project. Two of the partners in the operating Mt Marion mine, Neometals and Mineral Resources, are studying a local lithium hydroxide plant.

Pilbara Minerals and Altura Mining are exploring Asian converter plants with Chinese lithium companies and the part-owner of the state's massive Greenbushes mine, Tianqi, is leading the pack with  south of Perth.
The plans would be positive for the states resources industry, with the move downstream delivering more investment and skilled jobs. But with the price for spodumene concentrate so strong, some in the market have questioned whether the miners should forgo the risks and just stick to their knitting.
"It is all about margin," Canaccord Genuity analyst Reg Spencer said.
"Today market prices for spodumene are so robust it is a very profitable business just to dig the ore up, concentrate it and sell it to converter plants in China.

"But then when you think about the margins the converter plants are making, it is a very attractive business, even considering they are paying a margin to the miner.
"So if you can have some level of upstream integration where you don't have to pay a margin to the spodumene miner, or downstream integration where you can benefit from the margins presently available to the converters, then you are going to make a lot more money. From that strategic perspective it is a great idea."
All in the execution

But Mr Spencer said whether shareholders would realise value from the costly pursuit would lie in the execution.

"With talk of everyone wanting to build their own refinery, what everyone is a little naive about is that the experience in operating these plants is in China and they are highly capital intensive - the average capital intensity of a converter plant is about the same as the mine itself," he said.
"You need the expertise and the finance."
Lithium hopeful Kidman Resources boasted it had secured both earlier this month when it agreed to sell a 50 per cent stake in its Earl Grey project to SQM for $US30 million cash and $US80 million in project funding.
On top of developing the mine and concentrate plant, SQM and Kidman want to build a plant in Western Australia to convert the 220,000 to 300,000 tonnes of lithium concentrate from the project each year to either 37,000 tonne of lithium carbonate or 44,000 tonne of lithium hydroxide.

Lithium hydroxide sells for more than lithium carbonate but it does not travel or store as well.
After the deal was announced on July 11, shares in Kidman fell from 71¢ per share to as low as 53¢ on Tuesday before recovering to 59¢ on Friday, with concerns in the market about shareholder dilution and the addition of a chemical processing facility slowing the timeline to first production.
SQM has said it plans to produce concentrate from Earl Grey in 2019 before bringing the conversion plant online in the second half of 2020.
Neometals hopes to be on Kidmans heels.

The move downstream

The Perth-based company and one of its joint venture partners at Mt Marion, services company Mineral Resources, are studying the development of a lithium hydroxide plant which, if the studies are positive, they hope to commission before the end of 2020.
Neometals owns 13.8 per cent of Mt Marion, which made its first shipment in February.
"We took the strategy to get the concentrate plant up and running first and decided to let  buy 100 per cent of the concentrate for the first three years before we could then take our share of concentrate and downstream process it ourselves," managing director Chris Reed said.
"To survive in a lower price environment you have to be integrated."
Kidman and Neometals are both considering building their plants in the southern Perth suburb of Kwinana, where China's Tianqi is building a large lithium hydroxide plant, or the state's gold mining centre, Kalgoorlie.
For Pilbara Minerals, which is  in the state's iron ore rich Pilbara region, a local plant isn't an option.
"To install such a facility you really need a critical mass of other chemical activity happening because what you want is a lower cost of the raw material inputs and the ability to deal the by-products," managing director Ken Brinsden said.

"It is unfortunate that at this point in time Port Hedland doesn't really fit into that category. It might in the future but today we don't think it does."
Instead, Pilbara has flagged plans to examine a downstream processing facility in Asia, most likely Malaysia, with China's General Lithium.
But Mr Brinsden said it is a longer term goal.
"Strategically we like the idea there might be an opportunity to participate in that type of facility in the future but it is not a natural place for a mining company and there have been plenty of examples historically where it hasn't worked out as well as could be expected," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US173</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara Minerals</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kwinana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Tianqi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Hedland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neometals</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jiangsu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reg Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Marion</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brinsden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earl Grey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidman</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canaccord Genuity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Altura Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Reed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tianqi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mineral Resource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidman Resources</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's General Lithium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenbushes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Brinsden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
