<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399820078080576</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/wildlife-hospital-struggling-to-find-new-owners-despite-free-offer/news-story/e06f7cae457085158292208272fdc532</url>
  <title>No takers for free wildlife refuge</title>
  <content>
A WILDLIFE carer, who has offered to give away his Tablelands property for free to a worthy successor, says many people who have applied for the gig are afraid of hard work.
Retiring wildlife campaigner Harry Kunz is struggling to find someone to take over The Eagles Nest near Ravenshoe, almost a year after he offered the 2ha of land for free to whoever is willing to continue his life's work.
The wildlife sanctuary, established 30 years ago, rehomes more than 1200 animals each year, including wedgetail eagles, tawny frogmouths, kookaburras, kangaroos, wallabies, peregrine falcons, pygmy possums, masked owls and lesser sooty owls.
Mr Kunz, who initially received more than 6000 applications from people across the globe, said only a dozen applicants actually showed up at the property to assess how it operated.
"They come for 2-3 weeks, but most of them have the wrong idea," he said.
"They think there's only a few birds and they can sit there on the couch and pat a kangaroo."
Mr Kunz had issued each applicant with an information sheet detailing exactly what the role of taking over the wildlife hospital entailed.
This includes not receiving any salary, feeding animals, cleaning enclosures, attending to sick and/or injured wildlife, maintaining the property and being on call 24/7.
Applicants have been warned there are several duties some people may not like, such as having to kill rats, chickens and other prey animals by hand so they may be fed to raptors and dingoes.
He said despite this, he still had not found anyone willing to stay beyond a couple of weeks.
"Some people just came and said 'we're here to take over the business, how long do we have to run it as a hospital - when can we sell it'?" he said.
"I've had maybe 10-12 people come here who I've considered, who have been lovely people and I thought they had a chance.
"But then they had private stuff (back home) and they go away too quickly."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tablelands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Kunz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ravenshoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kunz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles Nest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
