<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399777128406997</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/15/14/court-shown-moment-man-is-killed-by-truck-in-road-rage-death-trial</url>
  <title>Court shown moment man is killed by truck in road rage death trial</title>
  <content>
Graphic footage has been played in court of the moment a father is hit and killed by a garbage truck on a Brisbane motorway, causing some family members of the victim to leave distressed.
The court heard that within 13-seconds of meeting each other, one man would be dead and the other would be facing serious criminal charges.
Tamate Heke is accused of punching fellow driver Shane Merrigan, 50, causing him to fall into the path off an oncoming truck at Rochedale in December 2015, while the two were having an altercation. 
The court heard that Mr Heke, who is on trial for manslaughter of plasterer Shane Merrigan, allegedly told witnesses immediately after he didn't mean it. 
"He pushed me, so I pushed him back. I tried to grab him I didn't mean it." 
The court heard the two men had never met before, but that Merrigan had been driving closely to Mr Heke and gesturing with his middle finger.
Crown Prosecutor Clare Kelly told jurors, "Their paths crossed as they drove on the Gateway Motorway that afternoon." 

Related Articles

Both men had stopped their cars on the motorway at Rochedale to merge. 
The court heard Mr Heke, a New Zealand national, later told police "he was coming, he was coming at me pretty quick." 
Crown Prosecutor Clare Kelly alleged in her opening address that Merrigan's injuries were so bad that a pathologist "was unable to find any injury that would indicate a blow to the head."
Heke has pleaded not guilty to manslaughter and not guilty to the alternate charge of unlawful striking causing death.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateway Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrigan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Merrigan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Clare Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Heke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamate Heke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rochedale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
