<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399257437357412</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/world/moscow-washington-take-down-guard-rails-in-bilateral-relationship-20170731-gxm63b.html</url>
  <title>Moscow, Washington take down guard rails in bilateral relationship</title>
  <content>
Washington: A measure of just how nasty the Washington-Moscow relationship has become lies in the historical comparisons - skipping the Cold War, analysts are reaching back a full century, to the Bolshevik Revolution when the US embassy in Moscow was shuttered for 15 years.
The Cold War imposed a manageable, if at times frightening, diplomatic dynamic. 

Up Next

Scant protection for Cassie Sainsbury

00:58

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Russia to expel 755 US diplomatic staff

Russian President Vladimir Putin says Moscow will expel 755 US  diplomats and could impose additional measures against the United States in response to new US sanctions against Russia.

But Moscow's weekend confirmation that the US must cut its embassy staff by 755 comes as the two powers butt heads in the Middle East, as tension mount on the Korean peninsula and the Ukraine crisis festers. All are unfolding with none of the guard rail certainty that endured for more than four decades after World War II - and with both countries led by unpredictable, headstrong presidents.
As Vladimir Putin warned of possible further Russian measures against the US, the Trump administration was flexing is military muscle over the Koreas - flying two supersonic B-1 bombers over the peninsula with Japanese and South Korean aircraft along for the ride, at the same time as the US responded to a new North Korean missile test with its own missile defence test over the Pacific - which it claimed was a success. 

The US embassy cuts and the closure of two American diplomatic facilities in Russia were a delayed response to the Obama administration's order in December for Moscow to reduce its US-based diplomatic staff by 35 and the seizure of two Russian diplomatic compounds - one near Washington, the other near New York.
But acting days after the US Congress hardened the sanctions regime on Moscow and humiliated Trump with a legislative rider that forces him to seek congressional approval before lifting any of the sanctions, Putin said that Russia had run out of patience waiting for relations with the United States to improve under Trump.

And because Moscow's options for further action against the US in Russia are limited, it's likely that those other global crises could be the theatres in which Putin seeks to test or wrong-foot Washington.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Putin alluded to the recent agreement between himself and Trump for a partial ceasefire in part of Syria as proof that the two countries could still cooperate even "in this quite difficult situation."Photo: AP
But he added: "We were waiting for quite a long time that maybe something would change for the better, were holding out hope that the situation would change somehow. But it appears that even if it changes someday it will not change soon."
In its formal announcement of the cuts at the American embassy, the Russian Foreign Ministry warned that if Washington retaliated with further Russian expulsions from the US, Moscow would match them.Photo: AP
On Sunday, Russian deputy foreign minister Sergei Ryabkov told ABC's This Week with George Stephanopoulos: "I think retaliation [was] long, long overdue. [The new sanctions decision by Congress is a] completely weird and unacceptable piece of legislation - it was the last drop." 
Russian journalist Andrei Kolesnikov, who is close to Putin, described the imposition of new US sanctions as "a landmark moment" that would unleash Putin. He told The Washington Post: "[Putin's] patience has seriously run out, and everything that he's been putting off in this conflict, he's now going to do." Photo: AP
This is not where Putin and Trump expected to be at this stage of the new US administration. Campaigning through last year, Trump boasted of his ability to get along with Putin, and even talked of easing or lifting the sanctions on Russia.
They were first imposed after Russia's annexation of Crimea from Ukraine in 2014 - and later were stiffened in retaliation for Moscow's interference in the 2016 election campaign.Photo: AP
Trump's reluctance to accept the unanimous finding by the combined US intelligence agencies that Russia did meddle in the election, with the objective of helping Trump to win, drove his Republican allies in both houses of Congress to corner him with a tougher sanctions regime and to block any unilateral decision by the White House to lift or ease the sanctions - despite heavy lobbying by the administration.
As recently as a week ago, Trump's pugnacious new communications director, Anthony Scaramucci, restated the president's scepticism on Russian election meddling, explaining that Trump cannot separate the intelligence agencies' conclusion from an emotional sense that "this Russia thing" is being used by his opponents to cast doubt on the legitimacy of his election victory.Photo: AP
And that makes things a bit tricky for Vice President Mike Pence, who is now touring the Baltic States, hoping to assure them of American support amidst their angst over Russian expansionism.
Despite Trump's vacillation, Pence told reporters in Tallinn, the Estonian capital: "The president has made it very clear that Russia's destabilising activities, its support for rogue regimes, its activities in Ukraine are unacceptable. As we make our intentions clear, we expect Russian behaviour to change." 
That remains to be seen.
On Saturday, the Russia embassy in Washington tweeted: "Washington still doesn't get the fact that pressure never works against @Russia, bilateral relations can hardly be improved by sanctions."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltic States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassie Sainsbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergei Ryabkov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's This Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukraine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolshevik Revolution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cold War</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TALLINN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington-Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estonian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian's Foreign Ministry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrei Kolesnikov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crimea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Stephanopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
