<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398999739316351</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4822232/quannes-father-visits-dig-site-as-police-search-for-girls-remains/?cs=298</url>
  <title>Quanne Diec's father visits Cataract dig site as police search for missing girl's remains</title>
  <content>
The father of Quanne Diec has visited a bushland site at Cataract, where police are digging in search of the missing schoolgirl's remains
Detectives led Sam Diec to a site one kilometre north of the Southern Gateway Centre on the western side of Appin Road a short time ago.

He lingered over the dig site a while before departing.
Addressing reporters, Detective Inspector Glen Parks said the search was a difficult time for the family.

Quanne's father visits dig site as police search for girl's remains

Sam Diec, father of missing schoolgirl Quanne, visits the site where police search for his daughter's remains on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Sam Diec, father of missing schoolgirl Quanne, visits the site where police search for his daughter's remains on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Sam Diec, father of missing schoolgirl Quanne, visits the site where police search for his daughter's remains on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Police search for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne Diec on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Police search for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne Diec. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Police search for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne Diec on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Detective Inspector Glen Parks addresses the media as police search for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne

Police search for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne Diec on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Police search for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne Diec on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Police search for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne Diec on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Police search for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne Diec on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Sam Diec, father of missing schoolgirl Quanne, visits the site where police search for his daughter's remains on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

MERCURY NEWS BODY SEARCH
Police search bushland off Appin Rd at Cataract for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne Diec. 31st of July 2017. Story: Angela Thompson. Photo: Adam McLean

Police search for the remains of missing schoolgirl Quanne Diec on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

Sam Diec, father of missing schoolgirl Quanne, visits the site where police search for his daughter's remains on Monday morning. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

exit
"Obviously they're coping as well as can be expected. It's been a very difficult time for them and we would continue to support them in this process," Detective Inspector Parks said.

"As of last Thursday Quanne Diec has been missing for over 19 years and as you can appreciate it's a very difficult time for her family and that is why we're doing all we can to try and locate her remains and bring some closure to her family."

"We're always hopeful and will never give up."

The schoolgirl went missing on July 27, 1998 after leaving her Granville home to catch the train to Strathfield Girls' High School.

In November, . 

"There's been a lot of experienced, a lot of dedicated investigators who have worked on this job from word go and they're doing everything they can to assist us," Detective Inspector Parks said.
"Today... investigators from Strike Force Lyndey along with the assistance of specialist police from the forensic services group are searching several areas of bushland along Appin Road at Cataract in an attempt to locate Quanne Diec's remains."
The search is expected to continue for two or three days. It follows an earlier search on November 23 last year, .
Investigating police have examined aerial photographs of the site from 1998 and today to learn how the landscape has changed over time.
"It's very difficult terrain and we identified that early when we were here in November last year.
There's thick shrubbery, sandy and rocky soil which makes it very difficult for searching these particular areas along with the difficulties with the inclement weather."

"We have returned here on a couple of occasions since November to do a search and to assess the area and as a result of that we're not back here conducting a more systemic and methodical search of these particular areas.

Police search bushland at Cataract on Monday morning for the body of missing schoolgirl Quanne Die. Picture: ADAM McLEAN
"Obviously the terrain has changed significantly over the past 19 years. It has significantly overgrown since then so obviously that has made it difficult for us in identifying exactly where we should be searching.

Detective Inspector Parks declined to comment on Tarantino's mental state or the details he has provided to police as his case is now before the courts.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarantino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quanne</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quanne Diec</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appin Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Diec</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appin Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Granville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MERCURY NEWS BODY SEARCH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strike Force Lyndey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday Quanne Diec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Parks</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quanne Die</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Gateway Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Glen Parks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathfield Girls' High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
