<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399386286377839</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/law-order/widow-shaken-over-theft-of-war-medals-during-kyabram-aggravated-burglary/news-story/b77ba87fd6668933df43b68367397b11</url>
  <title>Widow shaken as war medals stolen</title>
  <content>
A 96-YEAR-OLD widow has been left devastated after precious war medals belonging to her late husband were stolen in a heartless burglary.
The woman woke after midnight on Saturday to find her Kyabram home of more than six decades ransacked.
The offender stole a small amount of cash from the Allan St property.
But it was the loss of priceless war medals and air force log books belonging to the victim's late husband which caused enormous upset.
Campaspe Crime Investigation Unit Detective Sgt Shane Kervin said it was a terrible incident
"It has really shaken the elderly victim, who has lived in the same house for 62 years," Det-Sgt Kervin said.
"While it is a tight-knit community we do unfortunately have opportunistic people who will target those who are vulnerable.
"This is a timely reminder to ensure belongings are kept safe and homes are secured."
Two similar incidents - in Underwood Grove and Drum St - were reported in the central Victorian town last week.
Investigators have released an image of replica war medals and appealed for anyone who came across the stolen medals to contact police.
Anyone with information is urged to contact Crime Stoppers via 1800 333 000 or .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>YEAR-OLD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyabram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Det-Sgt Kervin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campaspe Crime Investigation Unit Detective Sgt Shane Kervin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drum St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Underwood Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
