<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398870890295137</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/mining/iron-ore/liberty-house-triggers-real-estate-flurry-in-whyalla-20170730-gxlxyj</url>
  <title>Liberty House triggers real estate flurry in Whyalla </title>
  <content>
Buyers are piling into the dirt-cheap Whyalla real estate market following the including the Whyalla steelworks by British steel giant Liberty House.
Elders Real Estate branch manager in Whyalla Graham Taylor said on Monday his office had sold 11 properties in the past three weeks, double the average monthly sales rate of the previous few months when the future of Whyalla had still been under a cloud.
"In the last month it has really spiked," Mr Taylor said.
The renewed confidence had largely been focused on the mid-tier and higher end of the market, but hadn't yet translated into better prices because there was still a substantial amount of stock that was being soaked up in the town of 22,000 people, about 380km north of Adelaide.

"It's economics 101. It's supply and demand."

The announcement in early July by Liberty House that the British firm and stablemate SIMEC would acquire the Arrium assets from administrators KordaMentha and invest up to $1 billion on upgrading the steelworks and building a new power generation plant has delivered renewed optimism to Whyalla.
Mr Taylor said a 1940s four-bedroom house on 1011 square metres of land at 40 Broadbent Terrace went under contract for $480,000 last week after initially being listed in December 2016 at above $500,000. It had no takers for months, but there was competition for the house in the past few weeks. It was at the higher end of the market, and had views over the ocean in Spencer Gulf, and was indicative of the rise in confidence.
The upturn in activity in Whyalla marks yet another chapter in the fluctuating fortunes of property markets in regional towns dependent on the mining industry. Investors and owner-occupiers alike have been burnt in towns like Port Hedland in north-west Western Australia and  as the end of the mining boom crunched prices.
Peter Calliss, from Peter Calliss Real Estate in Whyalla, said there had been several commercial and industrial properties sold in the past few weeks on the strength of a more robust local economy. "That's picked up," Mr Calliss said.

More inspections

"There's certainly a lot more optimism around the place," he said. But he predicted it would take some time for prices to respond in residential real estate even though there were a raft of new buyers now kicking the tyres.
"We've certainly noticed a lot more activity, a lot more inquiry. There's new people and new contacts looking around," Mr Calliss said.
Blights Real Estate principal Fiona Quinn said she was noticing a rise in the numbers of people at open inspections in Whyalla.

"There's more inspections and there's more inquiries," she said.
Rental prices for investors were still soft after an extended downturn while the fate of the Arrium business hung in the balance, and she said it would take some time for rents to begin rising.
Figures from the Real Estate Institute of South Australia show that the median house price in Whyalla sunk by 18 per cent to $194,000 in the March quarter of 2017 compared with $237,500 in the March quarter of 2016.
Elders' Mr Taylor said in the early months of calendar 2017 there had still been a steady level of transactions at the lower end of the Whyalla market for properties below $150,000 as some investors took a punt that a buyer would be found for Arrium. "Some people had their fingers-crossed and were hoping," he said.

Liberty House and SIMEC, under the GFG Alliance banner, acquired all of the Arrium assets including the Whyalla steelworks, a nearby iron ore mine in the Middleback Ranges, electric arc furnaces in Victoria and NSW and a national steel recycling and distribution business. It overtook a which had been anointed as the preferred bidder for the Arrium assets after the Korean bidder comprising Newlake Alliance and JB Asset Management missed a crucial deadline, allowing Liberty to come back into the process and deliver more certainty.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIMEC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Calliss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbent Terrace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Hedland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Calliss</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate Institute of South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whyalla Graham Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middleback Ranges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFG Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Calliss Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newlake Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arrium</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KordaMentha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Gulf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Quinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberty House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whyalla</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Taylor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
