<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399794308276481</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:44</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/survivor-turns-x-rated-naked-challenge/3207056/</url>
  <title>Survivor turns 'X-rated' in naked challenge</title>
  <content>
WE'VE barely begun the current season of Australian Survivor, but viewers are about to be treated to something you just don't see enough of on Aussie TV: A nude wrestling match.

In tonight's episode, the two tribes - Asaga and Samatu - go head to head in a reward challenge, competing to win a simple tool that'll make life much easier on the island.

One member from each tribe had to get themselves wet then tear down a slip-and-slide, trying to grab a ball at the end of the track. The first contestant to grab hold of the ball and bring it to their team's square on the course would win a point.

Two of this season's most physically impressive competitors, 195cm tall mountaineer Locky and former SAS commander Mark, are paired off to compete against each other.

As they careen down the slip-and-slide - Locky clad only in his jocks - Mark reaches for his competitor's sole item of clothing in an attempt to hold him back. All at once, off come the undies.

"Locky gets there first! He loses his shorts! It's now X-rated! Locky's completely naked!" shouts host Jonathan LaPaglia.

The poor Ten censor certainly earns their pay in this scene, struggling to keep up with a very large man squirming his naked frame this way and that:

As the ugly wrestling match continues, Locky's team mates go through a variety of emotions at the sight of their fellow competitor in his birthday suit:

In the end, Locky wins - thank god - and his team mates rushed to congratulate him. None seem to be in that much of a hurry to fetch him his underpants, though.

As Locky lies in the sand exhusated, LaPaglia has the final word: "Nice cheeks."

See Locky's Nudie Run when Australian Survivor 7:30pm tonight on Ten.
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
Marilyn Freeman won Toastmasters International Speech district event
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaPaglia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Locky</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor 7:30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Locky's Nudie Run</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan LaPaglia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samatu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters International Speech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
