<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399815783113241</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/markets/debt-markets/pimco-pulls-in-us50bn-active-cash-as-investors-flock-to-new-star-20170731-gxmaz8</url>
  <title>Pimco pulls in $US50bn active cash as investors flock to new star</title>
  <content>
by
Attracta Mooney

Pimco has staged a "remarkable turnround" to become the world's best-selling active mutual fund manager, after investors pulled hundreds of billions of dollars from the investment house following the departure of bond king Bill Gross in 2014.
A revival for the fixed-income specialist also points to a wave of demand for bond funds this year, even as central banks around the world prepare to implement tighter monetary policies which could hit prices for such securities.
Pimco attracted almost $US50bn to its funds in the six months to the end of June, according to figures compiled for the Financial Times by Morningstar, the data provider.
The group manages $US1.6trn, down from $US1.9trn when Mr Gross left in September 2014.

The haul came as fixed income funds pulled in $US355bn in the first five months of this year, putting the sector on course to beat 2016's full-year inflows of $US375bn, according to Morningstar.

In a sign of the dominance of low-fee funds, Pimco remains only the third best-selling mutual fund manager in the world, behind BlackRock and Vanguard, which have large passive fund ranges.
Its turnround makes the West Coast group, a subsidiary of German insurer Allianz, the best-selling active manager ahead of France's Amundi.
New money has been concentrated in just one product: Pimco's $US130bn Income fund run by Dan Ivascyn, who replaced Mr Gross as chief investment officer. Mr Ivascyn's fund became the world's largest actively-managed bond fund earlier this year, prompting fears the company risks again becoming too reliant on a star manager.
Mr Ivascyn, 48, was one of the senior Pimco fund managers who, amid infighting at the company in 2014, threatened to resign if Mr Gross did not.

The Pimco founder's departure that year sparked a wave of redemptions, with assets in Pimco's Total Return falling to less than a third of the $US293bn recorded at its peak.
A cult figure who co-founded the Newport Beach-based fund house, Mr Gross left because of "fundamental differences" with the company.
Mr Ivascyn's fund has returned 9.1 per cent annualised over the past 10 years, compared with 4.7 per cent for its benchmark, and drew in almost $US15bn of flows in the US alone this year.
Total net sales for Pimco's US business were $US12.6bn, as investors pulled cash from many of the asset manager's other funds.

In Europe, the Income fund accounted for €19bn of the fund house's total sales of €27.7bn.
Chris Chancellor, a partner at Mackay Williams, the investment consultancy, said the company faced "concentration risks" because of the rapid growth of the Income fund. But he added: "Given Pimco's experience of the past five years they will be very aware of the dangers."
Pimco played down concerns, pointing to its "diverse array of high-performing strategies that draw upon the expertise of 250 portfolio managers".
Eric Jacobson, Pimco analyst at Morningstar, said the company had rebuilt its reputation in recent years.

"[Mr] Gross was the singular figure and very domineering; that's his style," he said.
"The perception is the anxiety level in the place has come down [since he left].
"The larger-than-life boss isn't looming over any longer.
"Dan Ivascyn is very well respected internally and externally. He is probably just a lighter touch."

Philip Kalus, managing partner at Accelerando Associates, an asset management consultancy, said Pimco had orchestrated a "remarkable turnround" since Mr Gross left.
"It is always about net results and Pimco made it back to delivering. A large proportion of the turnround comes down to Dan Ivascyn," he said.
The company has revamped its business since Mr Gross's departure, overhauling teams and bringing in new staff. These include chief executive Manny Roman, who previously ran Man Group, the listed hedge fund company.
It also scrapped attempts to develop an equities business.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$130</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanguard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US12.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pimco</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morningstar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newport Beach-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gross</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Kalus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ivascyn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pimco's Total Return</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Given Pimco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allianz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Jacobson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pimco's US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manny Roman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France's Amundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Gross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlackRock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US355</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US375</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attracta Mooney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Ivascyn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Accelerando Associates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US293</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ivascyn, 48</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
