<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399785718341701</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/hard-work-pays-off-for-nurse-mum/3207057/</url>
  <title>Hard work pays off for nurse mum</title>
  <content>
ONE mother has proven hard work can pay off after juggling motherhood, study and part-time work to finally land her dream job.
Jimboomba mother of two Kara Bruce fought through moments of overwhelm to achieve her goal of becoming a nurse and was recently selected as one of five nursing graduates in the first mid-year nursing graduate intake at Mater Private Hospital Springfield.
Mrs Bruce said the job was a dream come true and looked forward to being able to care for her patients.
"I always wanted to work in a job where I could make a difference, so that's the main reason why I wanted to become a nurse," Mrs Bruce said.
"When people come into a hospital they are usually very scared or nervous and their experience with the nurses can either make and break their day.
"I also come from a family which has experienced a lot of illness and disability, so have always been around hospitals and am used to that environment."
The 32 year-old originally studied a Bachelor in Management and worked for several years in management at Arnott's Biscuits before deciding to make the career change.
"The whole process of studying while working and being a mum was very overwhelming and I honestly don't how I made it through my degree."
"I applied for the Mater graduate program which was my first preference and a dream opportunity and I didn't actually think it would be possible, so the feeling when I got my results was amazing."
Mater Private Hospital Springfield Education Coordinator Vanessa Edwards said the team was delighted to welcome the new graduates. 
"We have an exceptional team at Mater Private Hospital Springfield and we look forward to working with our new graduate nurses to provide them with a rewarding and enriching career," Ms Edwards said.
"Graduate nurses are our nurses of the future and it is wonderful to be a part of their transition into the clinical setting and to see their nursing skills develop and grow."
Mrs Bruce will join two of the other graduate nurses in the inpatient areas where they will gain experience in medical, rehabilitation, orthopaedics, urology, ENT, gynaecology, among others.
The remaining two nursing graduates have been accepted into the perioperative rotational program where they will spend time in admissions, theatre, anaesthetics, recovery and day procedure.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Bruce</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnott's Biscuits</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kara Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimboomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mater Private Hospital Springfield Education Coordinator Vanessa Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ENT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mater Private Hospital Springfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
