<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399820078080569</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/from-watching-netflix-to-taking-advice-from-an-ex-are-these-acts-actually-forms-of-cheating/news-story/700cf498bcda3c89d4e3a579609f8b42</url>
  <title>The non-cheating acts considered a betrayal</title>
  <content>
WHAT constitutes being unfaithful isn't always black and white - for some couples there are some very grey areas.
But according to a Reddit thread, there are five things people believe are almost equivalent to cheating - even though they don't exactly qualify as being "unfaithful"
1. Taking a recommendation off a friend or colleague, when your partner suggested it first:
This is a classic. You take a friend's advice on a great new restaurant or TV show and give it a whirl - even though your partner has made the SAME suggestion a million times before.
"My ex did this A LOT and it actually made me quite angry,"
"Is my opinion not valid enough? You have to hear it from literally anybody else for it to count?"
Another said this issue comes up in all aspects of his relationship.
"Also have this problem where I am not credible enough," Parshath wrote.
"Bars, TV shows, restaurants, activities, everything is lame when I put it, but friends, peer-pressure and go-along make everything so much more credible."
2. Your partner gets help from someone else when you're completely capable of doing the job:
In this conversation, the Reddit contributor spoke of her hobby as a painter.
"One of my favourite things to do is make pieces for my SO [significant other]," she posted.
"I always tell him that if there is ever a specific thing he wants painted, to let me know and I will make it specially for him.
"Few days ago I found out he commissioned another painter for a painting that I would have LOVED to do for him.
"I know its not cheating in the slightest and I tried not to show my jealousy, but f**k did I feel betrayed."
But very few saw this as a form of cheating:
"That means someone dating a chef needs to ask permission before going to a restaurant where another chef prepares the same food?," a contributor questioned.
I think we'll leave this one alone.
3. Watching a TV show we planned to watch together without me. How rude ...
It's always nicer to watch you favourite TV show with a partner, friend or housemate. But according to a survey dropped earlier this year - we are fond of streaming infidelity.
Defined as secretly watching a TV show ahead of your partner, 41 per cent of Australians admitted to Netflix cheating three or more times - and it's slowly become a huge form of betrayal within relationships.
"It actually ends relationships," one Redditor said.
"I secretly watch GoT without my gf but then have to rewatch the eps with her," another added.
"I did this with Sons of Anarchy and my husband.
"He worked 2nd shift, so I'd watch it live but it'd still appear on our DVR as unwatched. He never caught on, and thanks to this thread I'm feeling bad about it now."
4. Cheating in a dream:
"An exgf caught me cheating in her dream. Woke me up at 3am to argue with me. This is no joke."
They're those dreams that feel so real they could pass as reality. You wake up in a huff, convinced you've witnessed your partner cheating. Most of us can brush it off, but apparently they are a good indicator of betrayal for some people.
"My ex would get her waking life mixed up with her dreams a lot," one person wrote.
"Every once in a while she would have a dream where I cheated on her but she would not let it go for days on end even though I've never met some lady she made up in her dream.
"At some point it becomes an insecurity thing, like do you seriously trust your dreams more than me?"
5. 'Stopping to get food ... only for themselves.'
Eating is cheating, because nothing rattles people like food envy, clearly.
"I almost murdered my ex daily because of sh*t like this," one person commented.
"All it takes is a quick text or a glance at the calendar to know I'm home and starving. He's an ex for a reason."
"My husband will do this with lunch or breakfast," another added.
"He will make food for himself and not even ask me or our daughter if we want some."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redditor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sons of Anarchy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parshath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
