<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399648279386073</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/when-les-murray-claimed-lucas-neill-led-a-socceroos-mutiny/8760358</url>
  <title>Les Murray: When SBS commentator claimed Lucas Neill led a Socceroos mutiny during World Cup</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Les Murray's words always carried significant weight with Australian football fans.
So when the SBS commentator, , claimed then-Socceroos captain Lucas Neill had sprung an uprising against their coach during the World Cup, people listened.
Hopes that the Socceroos would follow on from their brilliant World Cup showing in 2006 with a repeat performance in South Africa in 2010 were quickly deflated when Germany battered Australia in a 4-0 mauling in Durban.

According to Murray, .
In his book 'The World Game', released a year after the Socceroos were ripped to shreds, Murray claimed players took exception to coach Pim Verbeek's game plan before the match.
Murray claimed that Socceroos skipper Neill had asked Verbeek to leave the room before telling players the Dutchman's tactics were "bullshit".
"After the coach, Dutchman Pim Verbeek, had addressed the players, naming his line-up and the strategy, the team captain, Lucas Neill, asked the coach to leave the change room while he addressed his colleagues," Murray wrote in the book.
"Verbeek consented. On closing the door behind the coach, Neill erased Verbeek's scribbles on the whiteboard and told the players to 'ignore this bullshit' and play like we normally play.
"A major bone of contention for the players was Verbeek's failure to include a recognised forward in the named team, with Harry Kewell, Josh Kennedy and Brett Holman all on the sub's bench.
"In the confusion there was so much delay that the point was reached when a FIFA match official knocked on the Australian change room and, pointing to his watch, warned the Australians that if they didn't take to the field immediately they would have to forfeit the match.
"The Aussies went out a mess and were slaughtered."
Naturally, the incredible claims prompted a response from Neill, who threatened legal action against the "scandalous" claims.

"The allegations made about me prior to the Germany game in Durban last year are completely false," Neill said in a statement.
"I was angered to hear such claims in the media at home ... they don't even make sense when you consider them as they have been alleged.
"I have always had a great working relationship with the national team manager and supported them to the best of my ability and Pim Verbeek was no exception.
"If a divide such as the one being claimed existed, it is highly unlikely we would have been able to perform as we did in the next two games."
Neill said it was goalkeeper Mark Schwarzer who gave the team talk before the loss to Germany.
"The irony in all of this and what really highlights how absurd these claims are, is that Mark Schwarzer, as a senior player and member of our leadership group, gave the team talk just prior to taking the pitch for that particular game," Neill said.
"The team is always left to themselves moments before going onto the pitch to generate some final motivational and inspirational words of encouragement."
'Reveal who those sources are'

Neill then called on Murray to reveal his sources or face the centre-back in court.
"My aim now is to ensure that my reputation remains intact, as I have worked very hard over many years to maintain a good and positive image within the sporting landscape and I will fight to the fullest extent of the law to clear my name of this scandalous accusation," he said.
"I will be discussing the matter with my management and lawyers over the coming days.
"Those who are claiming that they have this information provided to them by 'sources' should reveal who those sources are, as I am sure that this information will come to light during the course of due legal process."

Murray stood by his claims, saying he had not meant to paint Neill in a bad light.
Instead, he only wanted to highlight how Verbeek's defensive tactics had stymied Australia's World Cup prospects.
Former FFA chief Ben Buckley also flew to Neill's defence, who he called one of the finest Socceroos captains of all time, dismissing Murray's claims.
"Lucas Neill has demonstrated exceptional leadership over the past five years," Buckley said.
"He stands tall as an Australian sporting leader of the highest quality.
"No-one involved with the Socceroos in South Africa can recall any incident with the slightest resemblance to what has been described in today's press."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Holman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutchman Pim Verbeek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neill</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Schwarzer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucas Neill</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DURBAN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Kewell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verbeek</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pim Verbeek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutchman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
