<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399777128406990</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/numan-haider-inquest-police-had-no-other-option-than-lethal-force-coroner-finds-20170731-gxm8dr.html</url>
  <title>Numan Haider inquest: Police had no other option than lethal force, coroner finds</title>
  <content>
Crucial intelligence on Numan Haider talking to a friend about stabbing police officers was missed due to a technical glitch in the days before he attacked two policemen with a knife, a coroner has found.
Haider, 18, boasted to a friend that he would have stabbed police officer at Dandenong Plaza had he had the chance.
But the call was not transcribed.
Had it been detected, it might have prevented the ultimately fatal meeting between the policemen and the teenager five days later.

Haider stabbed a Victoria Police officer and his AFP counterpart outside the Endeavour Hills police station about 7.35pm on September 23, 2014, before the Victorian officer recovered and shot the teenager in the head. Haider died instantly.
The policemen and Haider had agreed to meet outside the station to discuss the teen's failed passport application and a search at his home that day.

The time between the officers walking out of the station to one of them returning injured to raise the alarm was 53 seconds.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Coroner John Olle​, who﻿ released his findings from an inquest into Haider's death on Monday, said the teenager had been radicalised before the attack.
"I find that Numan engaged in a course of conduct that involved radicalisation and behaviour that was increasingly dangerous, ultimately causing his death," he said.
The coroner said the Victorian policeman - referred to as Officer A - had no other option than using lethal force, as Haider was crouched over the AFP officer - Officer B - and stabbing him in the chest.
"It has been established that Numan's death was not preventable, other than at the expense of Officer's B's life, from the time he produced a knife and commenced stabbing at the officers," Mr Olle said.
Officer B suffered stab wounds to the face and chest and Officer A was stabbed in the arm. Officer B told last year's inquest he thought Haider was going .
No adverse finding was made against members of the Joint Counter Terrorist Team of Victoria Police and the AFP, or ASIO, over the way they monitored Haider or planned to meet him outside the police station.
However, Mr Olle said one element that might have changed the way the officers met Haider was not known at the time and was discovered after the teenager's death.
Five days before the attack Haider was on the telephone trying to call an associate, but told a friend nearby: "If I had a knife I would have stabbed 'em."
The remark referred to Haider's run-in with police at Dandenong Plaza that day, when he waved the Shahada flag at officers.
ASIO telephone monitoring did not pick up the remark at the time because Haider's telephone call never went through, and the system did not monitor unanswered calls. But the remark was recorded and was later heard by a Victoria Police detective assisting the coroner.
Mr Olle said Officer A might have cancelled the meeting with Haider had he known the teen previously spoke of stabbing police.
Haider's family - who cannot be identified and were overseas on Monday - previously said the teenager was not radicalised, and that he just snapped amid the pressures of study and the recent break-up from his fiancee.
Mr Olle said that though it was difficult for Haider's family to accept, the teenager "did fit the stereotype of a dangerous young man motivated by an extreme and non-representative form of Islam".
He passed his condolences to the family and praised their dignity in extending their sorrow to the injured officers, and to the two policemen whose lives were changed "immeasurably".
ASIO and police had concerns Haider was planning politically-motivated violence through his attendance at the controversial Al-Furqan Islamic Centre, his associations and his application for a passport to travel to Afghanistan. His family wanted to visit their native Afghanistan to find Haider a wife.
Mr Olle said that in the months before the attack, Haider went from a "happy-go-lucky" teen to one with new friends who was obsessed with events in the Middle East and had shut himself off from his family.
On the day he waved the Shahada flag at , he told officers he had problems with the Australian government and that it would pay for terror raids in Sydney and Brisbane that day.
That night he posted on Facebook a photograph of him in a balaclava and camouflage clothing and holding the flag, and made derogatory comments about the AFP and ASIO.
Over the following days, Haider accessed Islamic State , which included graphic videos of executions and instructions on using weapons to achieve martyrdom. He also accessed news articles about the movements of .
Police arranged to meet with him in the hope of building rapport.
But the two officers were caught on the back foot when Haider arrived earlier than expected and parked his car away from the station, where the lighting was poor.
They and Haider shook hands, but the teenager produced a knife when asked to turn out his pockets.
The inquest raised questions about information shared between ASIO and the police, as it was unclear whether police knew about Haider's Facebook posts prior to the attack.
But Mr Olle said police likely knew he had access to knives and at least one member of the Joint Counter Terrorist Team had seen the changed Facebook page.
Police felt there was nothing remarkable about his Facebook posts at the time given they coincided with the terror raids interstate, the coroner said.
The attack occurred within days of an Islamic State fatwa, which highlighted the terror organisation's "insidious" ability to radicalise young Australians.
Haider's friends were best placed to have seen the radicalisation he underwent, the coroner said, but "did not act on it for reasons that are not clear".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Counter Terrorist Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shahada</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Furqan Islamic Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Plaza</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coroner John Olle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Numan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Counter Terrorist Team of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haider, 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Endeavour Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Numan Haider</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haider</name>
    <count>21</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Olle</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haider's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officer B</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officer A</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
