<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399790013309067</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:43</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/language-school-on-the-move/3207058/</url>
  <title>Language school on the move</title>
  <content>
LEXIS English school has secured a prime new premises in the heart of Maroochydore overlooking the Maroochy River and Pacific Ocean.
The deal, stuck by Jason O'Meara of Savills, included approximately 760sq m of area over three floors; Levels 4, 5 and 6 in Bryant House, 26 Duporth Avenue.
The tenant had a specific requirement to expand, and lease negotiations included a pre-commitment for Bryant Property Group to build two new floors, of 253sq m each, above existing level 4 on the northern tower.
To enable the deal to transact, Savills who previously occupied Level 4 of the same building for 10 years, relocated in March to 61 The Esplanade, creating an opportunity to accommodate exactly what the tenant was looking for.
The build on the upper floor at Levels 5 and 6 includes spectacular water views and outlook for visiting international students of the school, including wrap around breakout balcony on the top floor.
Lexis College managing director Ian Pratt said he was very pleased with the outcome of their new premises and extremely excited with the location.
"The space is well designed with a specifically designed and functional fit-out for administration, classrooms and excellent view of what the Sunshine Coast is about," Mr Pratt said.
"The new premises will assist our marketing programs in recruiting new students from all over the world."
The first Lexis school, Lexis Noosa, opened in 1989. The group later expanded to Brisbane and Byron Bay, the Sunshine Coast and Perth.
They traded as Global Village English Centres until 2011, when the company was re-branded Lexis English. Today, with five great beach and city locations, Lexis offers a unique study experience in some of Australia's iconic study destinations. Lexis also have schools in Korea and Japan.
Developers John and Brendan Bryant of Bryant Property Group are also pleased about the new development, now completely maximising out the northern tower of the building for the allowable NLA.
"It was always the intent to build on top of Level 4, two more levels," Brendan Bryant said.
"It is great to secure a well-established tenant for the space who is a leader in their field. We are delighted to welcome them to our tenancy mix."
Jason O'Meara of Savills said the lease transaction was an excellent outcome for the landlord and tenant.
MAROOCHYDORE
26 Duporth Avenue
Features: 760sq m of area over three floors, with water views, wrap-around breakout balcony
Result: Seven-year lease with a five-year option
Agent: Jason O'Meara of Savills
Contact: 0408 087 868
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
VIDEO: Car surfing bird ruffles feathers
Marilyn Freeman won Toastmasters International Speech district event
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pratt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Pratt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NLA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Village English Centres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duporth Avenue</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven-year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryant House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Level 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Level 4</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Bryant of Bryant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryant Property Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Ocean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lexis College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason O'Meara of Savills</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lexis Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters International Speech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Bryant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
