<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399686934092427</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/lucy-kellaway-would-have-loved-shayne-elliotts-letter-to-staff-20170731-gxm55m</url>
  <title>Lucy Kellaway would have loved Shayne Elliott's letter to staff</title>
  <content>
Oh Lucy, we miss you already.
Just a week after the wonderful Financial Times columnist Lucy Kellaway , ANZ chief executive Shayne Elliott has sent his staff an eight-page letter explaining his strategy.
It's the sort of document that Kellaway would just love to pull apart.
It starts with a quote from David Bowie, ends with one from William Shakespeare and, in the middle, doesn't exactly provide a lot of details about what is specifically about to happen at ANZ.

Designed like some sort of cross between a scrapbook and a school report - pasted bits out of notebooks, love hearts and scrawls in the margins, every page on a jaunty angle - Elliott says: "this isn't your usual staff message; it's more like the essays I wrote back at high school".

The Kiwi education system has a lot of answer for, it appears.
ANZ's purpose, Elliott says, is that: "By helping people make their money work, we transform ideas, hard work and ambition into reality. It's actually pretty cool when you think of it like that."
No doubt Bowie would agree.
Elliott then rattles through some pretty obvious changes to the business landscape - the rise of Asia (you know, that region ANZ has been retreating from), technological disruption, population changes and regulatory scrutiny - before getting to perhaps the core of the document.

'Help solve society's challenges'

In just two dot points, Elliott lays out where the banks will focus.
"In Australia and New Zealand, our aim is to be the best bank for people who want to buy and own a home and for people who want to start, run and grow a business," Elliott says.
"In our institutional business, we want to be the best bank in the world for customers who move goods and money around the Asia-Pacific region."

Lovely. It says what ANZ will do, and what it won't. While the descriptions sound slightly obvious, they do give staff a pretty clear mission.
Then Elliott explains the three big changes that he believes this new, clear mission demands. The first two are straightforward - improving financial performance and embracing digital technology - but the third is a little more difficult to wrap your head around.
ANZ, Elliott says, will "use our purpose and values to drive change so we help solve society's challenges, strengthen our relationship with customers and inspire our people".
It's a big goal. Fortunately, Elliott has "teams to lead four streams of work" to make it happen - there's a service stream, the culture stream and then streams for "connectivity" and "agility".

Thinking big

The latter is a word that appears frequently in the podcast that accompanies the letter - of course there's a podcast - and its use goes further towards the heart of what Elliott is proposing here.
A bank with a slimmed-down focus - and less revenue - will also need a smaller, cheaper team that can be more "agile".
So as ANZ staff embrace Elliott's call to "build a bank and a brand people love" they should also expect to see some of their colleagues embracing a career change.

"A simpler business also means a smaller revenue base," Elliott says in his letter. "At the same time we need to step up our investment in new technology and absorb the rising cost of regulation and compliance. Facing into this means managing expenses tightly. Finding new and more productive ways of working is part of an ongoing challenge for us and has to be part of our DNA."
It's easy to pick holes in a document like this, but the ANZ chief and his internal communications team deserves a bit of credit for what they are trying to do here.
ANZ is about to embark on 18 months worth of organisational changes that are likely to be at times confusing, difficult and potentially brutal for its 46,000 workers.
The effort that Elliott and ANZ are putting in to explain the thinking behind those changes underlines just how big they are going to be.
Just keep that letter away from Kellaway.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williams Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellaway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliott</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shayne Elliott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh Lucy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy Kellaway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
