<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399820078080574</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/hayden-fenton-granted-home-detention-following-shooting-death-of-young-father-bailey-davenport-in-parawa-forest/news-story/9986938e86f15468378c8f6d8c3be350</url>
  <title>Parawa shooting accused granted bail</title>
  <content>
THE man accused of fatally shooting young father Bailey Davenport during an outing in a forest on the Fleurieu Peninsula has been granted home detention.
Bailey Davenport, 21,  at Parawa - about 40km west of Victor Harbor, while with four friends on the afternoon of July 23.
He later died in hospital.
The man accused of shooting him, Hayden Fenton, 28, was granted home detention during a court appearance on Monday - but under strict conditions.
He has been charged with an aggravated count of endangering life. Fenton was required to post $1000 for bail, as were his two parents acting as guarantors.
In addition:
• He must not be in possession of firearms or ammunition.
• He must not come into contact of anyone with firearms or ammunition.
• He must not contact witnesses.
• He must not drink alcohol or consume drugs.
• He will be subject to electronic monitoring.
• He will be subject to random testing for gunpowder residue, alcohol and drugs.
Both the prosecution and Major Crimes did not oppose the home detention order handed down to Fenton, of Victor Harbor, by Magistrate Brian Nitschke.
The Christies Beach Magistrates Court also heard there had been developments in the case since the last hearing on July 24.
He will be released on Monday and required to stay at his parent's property in Victor Harbour before his next court appearance in October.
After the shooting Mr Davenport was driven by the group to the South Coast District Hospital - a 30-minute journey - where they met with paramedics in front of the emergency room.
He was then flown to Flinders Medical Centre where he succumbed to his injuries on July 24.
At the time, SA Police Major Crime acting officer-in-charge Detective Inspector Greg Hutchins said police were sceptical of the account of events from the four friends - three men and a woman - with Mr Davenport at the time he was shot.
"We do not believe the people who were with this young man at the time of the incident have been fully frank about the circumstances," he said.
"We are not totally comfortable they are telling us the full truth.
"Five young friends go out for the day, woodchopping, having a bit of fun, unfortunately they decided to take a gun with them. One of them is now deceased. Until we unravel what has occurred ... the charge of murder is certainly on the table."
Anyone with information about this incident is urged to call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major Crimes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bailey Davenport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bailey Davenport, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christies Beach Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Brian Nitschke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parawa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Medical Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fenton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fleurieu Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast District Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Police Major Crime</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Greg Hutchins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayden Fenton, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Harbor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Davenport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
