<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399214487683921</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/supreme-court-judge-warns-of-high-risk-game-adjourns-toorak-mansion-battle-20170731-gxm4ke</url>
  <title>Supreme Court judge warns of 'high risk' game: adjourns Toorak mansion battle</title>
  <content>
The judge hearing the  between businessman John McMurrick and real estate agency Kay and Burton warned both sides they were fighting a 'high-risk' game that would publicly rule on their trustworthiness, before ordering them to try and resolve their differences through mediation.
Supreme Court of Victoria Justice John Dixon told the two sides that the outcome of the case that pitted Mr McMurrick's word against that of Kay and Burton director Ross Savas would indelibly mark their reputation and told them to try and end the matter themselves.
If they could not sort the matter in mediation on Monday, he would start hearing witnesses on Tuesday morning, Justice Dixon said.
"It would seem there will be a clear winner and clear loser at the end of the day," he said. "I would urge careful evaluation of the risks that are involved in proceeding with the case."

The  boils down to the question of whether Mr Savas advised Mr Murrick he could sell a renovated house in Toorak for between $7.5 million and $8 million.

With no documents proving Mr Savas gave Mr Murrick that advice, the case that could set a precedent by making real estate agents accountable for the estimates they give, comes down to one side's word against the other.
Mr McMurrick says he would not have gone ahead with the renovation on the property that he ultimately sold for $6.5 million if Mr Savas had not told him he could get more.
Mr McMurrick's barrister Michael Osborne QC said he would call Mr McMurrick's former personal partner, Lynda Noiseux, as a witness of the price estimates Mr Savas had given.
"On our case is that on misleading and deceptive conduct, as a result he entered into a transaction, he lost money as a consequence, and is entitled to recover that money," Mr Osborne said.

Mr McMurrick is seeking about $1.5 million, which he claims is the shortfall between the eventual sale price and the $8 million he says Mr Savas said he could get.
Mr Savas says he only ever gave a price estimate of between $6 million and $6.5 million. His barrister Peter Cawthorn on Monday said the two men had been in the habit of meeting casually on Saturday afternoons at Mr McMurrick's own house in Toorak and that conversations between the two in that context could not be relied up on as formal advice.
"The conversation was simply one between two friends - like a friend saying to me 'What do you think is going to happen to Telstra shares?'" Mr Cawthorn told the court.
It was wrong to suggest such a conversation "over a few drinks" was intended to be relied upon to go out and buy property, he said.

Mr Cawthorn said he intended to call a former owner of the 46 Canberra Avenue home and a valuer as witnesses, in addition to Mr Savas.
If the two parties are able to reach a resolution before court resumes on Tuesday morning, none of those witnesses will need to be called.
The stakes are high for both parties, Justice Dixon pointed out.
"I hope the parties appreciate the view I form of their credibility is discussed and published in a judgment that's forever more on the internet," Justice Dixon said. "That's a high risk strategy."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice John Dixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Murrick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McMurrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toorak</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Savas</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McMurrick</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Dixon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Savas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Osborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynda Noiseux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Osborne QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Cawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
