<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399257437357429</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/highend-family-homes-are-selling-fast-in-this-brisbane-suburb/news-story/c9ddeef27b93038132aa9062035de5c6</url>
  <title>High-end family homes are selling fast in this Brisbane suburb - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
This home at 57 Castile St, Indooroopilly, has sold for $3.2 million.

THE leafy neighbourhood of Indooroopilly has dominated the top home sales in Brisbane this week, with families flocking to the suburb for its good schools, big houses and premier golf courses.
A superbly renovated five-bedroom, three-bathroom home at 57 Castile Street, Indooroopilly, has sold for $3.2 million.

Inside 57 Castile St, Indooroopilly, which has sold for $3.2 million.

The sale was negotiated by Reuben Packer-Hill and Alex Jordan of McGrath Estate Agents, who described the home as "one of, if not the best renovation in the area", with the owner investing more than $2 million.
The property has over 24m of St Lucia Golf Links frontage, facing north.
Mr Jordan said the buyers were a family moving from Paddington.

This property at 13 Nindethana St, Indooroopilly, has sold for $2 million. Picture: realestate.com.au

He has also negotiated the sale of another newly renovated home at 13 Nindethana Street for $2 million.
Mr Jordan said the mid-1960s home had been completely gutted and renovated and was surrounded by some of the most expensive real estate in Brisbane.
The property was snapped up by a professional who loves to play golf.

The outlook from 13 Nindethana St, Indooroopilly. Picture: realestate.com.au

At 27 Isles Road, Indooroopilly, a two bedder owned by a property stylist fetched $1.52 million, with the buyers downsizing from acreage at Brookfield.

This property at 27 Isles Rd, Indooroopilly, has sold for $1.52 million.

And Mr Jordan also sold another home at 34 Castile Street for $1.555 million to a family wanting to move closer to the CBD and good schools.

This home at 34 Castile St, Indooroopilly, has sold for $1.555 million. Picture: realestate.com.au

A property at nearby 53 Castile Street recently sold for $2.85 million through Jason Adcock of Adcock Prestige.

This property at 53 Castile St, Indooroopilly, recently sold for $2.85 million. Picture: realestate.com.au

Mr Jordan said Indooroopilly had become hot property for families with young children because it was in the Ironside State School catchment and the area was full of owner occupiers in big houses on large parcels of land.
He said there was a lot of demand and limited stock available.
"You notice people are really house proud in the area," he said.
"It's also a great position being next to golf courses and along the river."
It comes as Brisbane's auction clearance rate rose to 53.4 per cent from 46.4 per cent last week.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isles Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ironside State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castile St</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isles Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indooroopilly</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jordan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Jordan of McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brookfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuben Packer-Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estate Agents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castile Street</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nindethana Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nindethana St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Lucia Golf Links</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Adcock of Adcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
