<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399918862329709</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/three-more-years-top-cop/3207067/</url>
  <title>Three more years for top cop</title>
  <content>
POLICE Commissioner Ian Stewart has been reappointed for another three years in the role.

Despite internal criticism about his leadership and morale in the police force, Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk today announced Commissioner Stewart's contract was renewed after a Cabinet meeting on the Gold Coast.

"Cabinet has endorsed the recommendation made by (Police) Minister Mark Ryan under the Act," she said.

"It's incredibly important that we have a clear sense of stability in this state."

Ms Palaszczuk also praised Commissioner Stewart's handling of natural disasters such as Cyclone Debbie.

Commissioner Stewart's reappointment comes as he had assured Queenslanders the terror threat remained at probable.

Commissioner Stewart said ensuring stability of command for the Gold Coast Commonwealth Games next year was a key reason he put his hand up for reappointment.

"The main driver for me is that we have the Commonwealth Games almost on our doorstep," he said.

Police Minister Mark Ryan said the reappointment was done under the Act but Commissioner Stewart deserved another three years in the role.

"The Commissioner is doing a great job and in light of those circumstances there was no need to open that up to an open merit process," he said.

"The position of the Government is the Commissioner is doing a great job and we followed the process under the Act and as a result the Commissioner will be hanging around for another three years."

Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
Marilyn Freeman won Toastmasters International Speech district event
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Mark Ryan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Ian Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyclone Debbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Stewart</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters International Speech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
