<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399905977427636</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/womens-domestic-violence-helpline-thrown-a-lifeline-by-last-moment-donation-20170731-gxmbj9.html</url>
  <title>Women's domestic violence helpline thrown a lifeline by last moment donation</title>
  <content>
A "last-minute" donation has saved a women's legal helpline, which helped about 2000 women a year, allowing the Brisbane-based service to continue assisting victims of domestic violence.
Doubts over government funding meant the Women's Legal Service Queensland, an Annerley-based community legal centre that was Queensland's largest provider of free legal and social work for women, was .Photo: Phill Carrick
WLSQ chief executive =Angela Lynch said more women than ever were coming forward to report cases of domestic violence.
"We are facing unprecedented demand in the community for our services because of the public conversation going on," she said.
"We responded to that by setting up a helpline that meant we are able to service many more thousand women a year."
The helpline had not received full government funding and while the Ms Lynch remained hopeful that may change in the future, she said the WLSQ was not confident.

"What we need is guaranteed government funding to keep the helpline open" she said.
Without the funding, the service would have to cut its hours from 30 a week to 12 from July 1.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

However, before the deadline arrived, the charity group Hand Heart Pocket signalled its intention to make a donation.
The $120,000 donation made by the Hand Heart Pocket, a charity founded by the Freemasons of Queensland, was officially submitted on the 31 July and meant the helpline would continue at full capacity for three more months.
"We're very thankful for the HHP coming in at the last moment. It was really a lifeline for us." Ms Lynch said.
The donation also allowed the WLSQ to train domestic violence workers in Rockhampton and Emerald on their legal responses.
However, Ms Lynch made it clear that the donation would only temporarily save the helpline.
The state and federal governments provided the organisation with about $1.2 million in funding each year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freemasons of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hand Heart Pocket</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Legal Service Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emerald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WLSQ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phill Carrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annerley-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Lynch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
