<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399858732786709</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4822265/wollongong-kicks-off-australian-ballet-regional-tour/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Australian Ballet brings 'Giselle' to Wollongong in October</title>
  <content>
Wollongong kicks off Australian Ballet regional tour

ON POINTE: Wollongong is the first city to open The Australian Ballet's regional tour of the landmark production 'Giselle'. Picture: Lynette Wills

Picture: Lynette Wills

Picture: Richard Strong

Picture: Richard Strong

Picture: Richard Strong

Picture: Richard Strong

Picture: Richard Strong

Picture: Richard Strong

exit

The Australian Ballet is returning to Wollongong with a production that has pulled at heart strings for generations.
Giselle will star artists from The Australian Ballet and graduating students from The Australian Ballet School and will kick off its regional tour in Wollongong at the Illawarra Performing Arts Centre in October.
The ballet was created in 1841 and has since captured the hearts of audiences the world over with its heartbreaking love story, famous mad scene, sea of ghostly white tutus and impressive display of ballet technique.

"Regional touring has been an important feature of the company's activities since our very first tour back in 1966," company artistic director David McAllister said.
"This is a ballet that all dancers love dancing and I am sure these dancers will follow in the footsteps of world-famous Italian ballet dancer Carlotta Grisi, who was so well known for performing the role of 'Giselle'."

Picture: Richard Strong
Aligning with the tour, The Australian Ballet will engage with local communities through its "Step Inside" and "Behind the Scenes" programs.

Their education team will also provide innovative, high-quality dance education that aligns with the Australian curriculum using a STEAM approach, and visit schools with interactive workshops.
"Beyond performances, we will also connect with regional communities through a range of activities in theatres and local schools," executive director of the company Libby Christie said.
"Our touring party of 49 is preparing to cover more than 5,000 km this year. We are looking forward to continuing our tradition of presenting unforgettable experiences for our regional audiences."
The Australian Ballet presents Giselle, IPAC, October 4 - 5.  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David McAllister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlotta Grisi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 4 - 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Performing Arts Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ballet School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ballet</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynette Wills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>POINTE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Strong</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libby Christie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giselle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
