<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399734178733384</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/07/31/09/45/protests-mar-venezuela-ballot</url>
  <title>Vote grants Venezuelan govt more power</title>
  <content>
Venezuelan electoral authorities say more than 8 million people have voted to create a constitutional assembly endowing President Nicolas Maduro's ruling socialist party with virtually unlimited powers.
The report more than doubles the estimates of independent experts and opposition leaders who have met the announcement with fury and derision.
National Electoral Council President Tibisay Lucena announced that turnout was 41.53 per cent, or 8,089,320 people. Members of the opposition said they believed between 2 million and 3 million people voted and one well-respected independent analysis put the number at 3.6 million.
The electoral council's vote counts in the past have traditionally been seen as reliable and generally accurate, but Sunday's widely mocked announcement appears certain to escalate the polarisation and political conflict paralysing the country.
"The people have delivered the constitutional assembly," Maduro said on national television.
Across the capital, Venezuelans had appeared to be staying away from the polls in huge numbers in a show of protest against the vote. Venezuela's chief prosecutor's office reported 10 deaths in new rounds of the clashes between protesters and police that have killed at least 125 and wounded nearly 2,000 since protests began in April.
Seven police officers were wounded when a fiery explosion went off as they drove past piles of trash that had been used to blockade a street in an opposition stronghold in eastern Caracas.

Related Articles

"If it wasn't a tragedy ... if it didn't mean more crisis, the electoral council's number would almost make you laugh," opposition leader Freddy Guevara said on Twitter. Maduro has threatened that one of the constitutional assembly's first acts would be jailing Guevara for inciting violence.
A list of nations including Argentina, Canada, Colombia, Mexico, Panama, Paraguay, Spain, Britain and the US say they won't recognise Sunday's vote.
The Trump administration has again promised "strong and swift actions" against Venezuelan officials.
(C)  RAW 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAW 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paraguay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guevara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freddy Guevara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Electoral Council President Tibisay Lucena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
