<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398913839968945</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4822383/slice-of-heaven-for-sale-in-st-pauls-rectory-paterson-photos/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Slice of heaven for sale in St Paul's Rectory, Paterson | Photos</title>
  <content>
Built in 1906, St Paul's Anglican Rectory at Paterson is literally a heavenly home.

Slice of heaven for sale in St Paul's Rectory, Paterson | Photos

exit
A key part of Hunter Anglican Church history, the landmark building will go under the auctioneer's hammer on site on Saturday, September 2.

Charlie Lund of McGrath Real Estate has listed the grand Edwardian property which has been tastefully renovated to honour its timeless beauty.
The rectory was built in 1906 after the former rectory was demolished.
Original cedar from the demolished residence was used in the current building most notably including the cedar skirting and French doors in the drawing room, dining room and master bedroom.
Remnants of the 1840s original rectory sandstone foundations can still be seen in property's garden beds.
The building was used throughout the 1900s as an official rectory accommodating many priests and clergymen between 1924 and 1930.
In the 1970s the building was purchased from the Anglican Diocese by former Tocal Headmaster Cameron Archer AM. He undertook a 12-year restoration project which included the construction of a period barn (three-bay car shed).
After buying the property in the mid 1980s from the Archers, Elizabeth Perrottet and her family lived in the rectory until 2010 when current owners James and Kristy Ashton bought it.

The couple is selling the property with a heavy heart but said the sale will mark a new beginning.
"We're selling because we want to be on a bigger rural holding, a farm," Kristy said.

"The rectory has been great, a fantastic home for us. We are selling with some reluctance but it's time to move on," she said.
The rectory is nestled on a 2015 square metre garden setting.

It is in the heart of the village of Paterson and just a stone's throw away from Paterson River.

Some of the rectory's features include large open fireplaces, 11 foot tin ceilings, French polished Australia cedar joinery, four bedrooms some with original fireplaces and French doors, sandstone and brick front entrance.
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Perrottet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Paul's Rectory</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwardian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Lund of McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paterson River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tocal Headmaster Cameron Archer AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paterson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican Diocese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Anglican Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Paul's Anglican Rectory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristy Ashton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
