<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399824373047928</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/east-hills/welcome-mat-murals-rolled-out-on-one-of-adelaides-main-roads/news-story/030c48e72644588e88376e34b792f1d4</url>
  <title>Welcome mat murals rolled out on one of Adelaide's main roads</title>
  <content>
WELCOME mats of a different kind are waiting to greet visitors to Goodwood Rd as Unley Council puts the finishing touches on a multi-million dollar upgrade of the thoroughfare.
The council is using a special type of asphalt to create permanent murals at the intersections of Rosa, Florence, Lily, Gilbert, Surrey and Victoria streets.
Fullarton-based artist Ellen Schlobohm came up different designs for each street, which contractor Creative Pavement is recreating by pouring coloured plastic onto a pliable asphalt surface.
The first "welcome mat" - a tree-inspired mural on Rosa St - was unveiled last month, with the remaining works to be completed by the end of August.
Schlobohm, who describes herself as a papercut artist, says each of the murals will reflect a different aspect of the Goodwood community.
"Rosa St is opposite Goodwood Primary and they have this beautiful tree," Schlobohm, 26, says.
"The trees are symbols of growth and longevity, while on Florence St we will have a bookcase to encourage people to use the (Goodwood) library."
The council commissioned Schlobohm to design the murals as part of its $5.8 million revamp of Goodwood Rd, between Victoria St and the tramline.
Work to underground powerlines, widen footpaths and install street furniture has been completed, with the Transport Department scheduled to start resurfacing the road in coming weeks.
The council expects the project to be finished in September.
Unley Mayor Lachlan Clyne says the upgrade will make the heart of Goodwood Rd a "destination" for locals and visitors.
"We recognise the benefits of making places more accessible, aesthetic and age-friendly while also encouraging an active community," Mr Clyne says.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodwood Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fullarton-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schlobohm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodwood Rd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schlobohm, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florence St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Creative Pavement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosa St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unley Mayor Lachlan Clyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellen Schlobohm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unley Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Clyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
