<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399863027754056</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/news/state/vic/2017/07/31/bowling-ladies-turn-beyonce-help-save-club/</url>
  <title>Bowling ladies turn to Beyonce to help save their club</title>
  <content>
A Melbourne lawn bowls club at risk of redevelopment is fighting back using the power of dance - and Beyonce.
Three women from Melbourne's Chadstone Bowls Club - Terry Foster, 82, Janine Hall, 82, and Wyn Hewett, 72 - have starred in a video featuring them dancing to Beyonce's hit, Single Ladies, in a head-turning bid to save their club making way for a new stadium.
But instead of singing about break-ups and sisterhood, the trio sing about their love for the club and call on Stonnington Council to "pay attention".
"Cause we're bowlers and you can't take this away from us," the chorus goes.
"Now we're mad and you won't get away with it."

Now this is something to see.... the ladies at Chadstone Bowls Club have had enough of Stonnington City Council wanting to demolish their club....Please watch, help and please SHARE with everyone you know!  It is fantastic! If you would like to know more and help please go to http://chadstonebowls.com.au/allthebowlingladies/  and you can SIGN  the petition  here... https://www.change.org/p/stonnington-council-save-chadstone-bowls-club?recruiter=751532515&utm_source=share_petition&utm_medium=email&utm_campaign=share_email_responsive
Posted by  on 2017年7月29日Since being posted to Facebook on Saturday night the video has been viewed more than 400,000 times and the bowling ladies have attracted plenty of wider media attention for their cause.
Denise Wallish, from the Save Chaddy Bowls committee, rejigged Beyonce's world-famous lyrics, and the performers had some choreography help from two other members of the club.
Despite two of the bowling ladies not being familiar with Beyonce and having to negotiate some difficult dance moves, they managed to film the video within an afternoon.
"If you ask the ladies, they didn't know what they were in for," Ms Wallish said.
Late last year, Stonnington Council nominated the park where Chadstone Bowls Club sits as the preferred site for a proposed new $25-million indoor stadium.
The council has said it was struggling to keep up with increasing demand for sports facilities and was also considering building the stadium in three other locations.
"A new indoor facility is particularly important to meet the needs of women's sport which is currently under-catered for," the council said on its website.
While the Council said they have not made a final decision, the club is determined not to lose its beloved green.
"The bowling club is not just a just sporting outlet, for many people it's their connection with their community," Ms Wallish said.
"We have a man in his '90s who said he would chain himself to the fence to save it."
"This has been our home for 60 years, our sporting home, and we want to be here for the next 60."
- with AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denise Wallish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Chadstone Bowls Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Save Chaddy Bowls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wallish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janine Hall, 82</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyn Hewett, 72</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadstone Bowls Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
