<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399863027754048</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/breaking-news/nz-dollar-treads-water-ahead-of-key-data/news-story/b4075ad239c2f506abc16a4df80ad067</url>
  <title>NZ dollar treads water ahead of key data</title>
  <content>
The New Zealand dollar inched higher on Monday as the greenback remains out of favour and investors await key data later in the week.
The kiwi traded at US75.06c at 5pm versus US74.99c at 8am in Wellington, having reached 75.23c in New York on Friday from 74.75c in Asia last week.
"It hasn't moved a lot. We are still of the view that it's going to be a struggle up here for the kiwi but certainly calling it meaningfully lower against a backdrop where the US dollar is struggling is a hard one. That's the opposing tension right here, right now," said ANZ Bank New Zealand senior economist Phil Borkin.
He said there are some key developments this week that will help determine direction, pointing to the Reserve Bank of Australia's rate decision Tuesday, followed by domestic jobs data Wednesday and US manufacturing data and jobs data.
Investors are also awaiting speeches by Cleveland Federal Reserve President Loretta Mester and San Francisco Fed President John Williams this week for further clues about the Fed's plans.
"You could argue that sentiment is so bearish with the US dollar right now that perhaps the risk is that if we start to see some positive surprises you could start to see some love return to the US dollar but it's a brave call to make at the moment," said Mr Borkin.
The kiwi traded at A94.06c from A94.05c in New York on Friday and traded at 63.95 euro cents from 63.97 cents. It was at 82.96 yen from 83.09 yen, traded at 57.16 British pence from 57.21 pence and fell to 5.0495 yuan from 5.0596 yuan.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Borkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Bank New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland Federal Reserve President Loretta Mester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Borkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US75.06</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US74.99</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco Fed President John Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
