<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399918862329731</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:13</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/07/31/sbs-broadcaster-les-murray-known-mr-football-dies-71</url>
  <title>SBS broadcaster Les Murray, known as 'Mr Football', dies at 71</title>
  <content>
For decades Les Murray was the face and voice of Australian football. He leaves behind a legacy spanning five decades.

By

3 HOURS AGO  UPDATED JUST NOW

Football broadcasting legend Les Murray has died aged 71 of a long illness.

Known as 'Mr Football', he has been largely credited with making the World Game part of Australian culture. 

"It hasn't really sunk in to be honest," friend and former SBS colleague Andy Paschalidis said.

"Les Murray has left a lasting legacy for all of us football fans, and I was one of them. He plucked me out of a cadetship to become a commentator at SBS in 1984 and he became a mentor.

"He spread the message of the World Game better than anyone before him during his time, and dare I say beyond his time."

Les Murray , as his family escaped Hungary amidst communist Russia's occupation. In 2015 he told SBS that people smugglers helped them escape.

The family first landed in Darwin, before eventually arriving at a migrant camp near Wagga Wagga.

Former colleague and close friend George Donikian told SBS World News that Les Murray was dedicated to promoting diversity in Australia.

"The work that Les did to support multicultural Australia was fantastic. Immense in fact," Mr Donikian said.

"His name and his legacy will be that he actually transcended SBS and transcended so many different platforms."

Les Murray began at SBS in 1980 as a Hungarian subtitle writer.

SBS Managing Director, Michael Ebeid, pays tribute to SBS football broadcaster, Les Murray

But his passion for football rapidly brought him into the sports team. By 1986, he was hosting the network's World Cup coverage.

As an SBS football commentator and presenter, he covered eight World Cups, before retiring in 2014. That same year he was also inducted into the FFA Football Hall of Fame.

"I never thought in my wildest dreams that Les would go," Mr Paschalidis said.

Les Murray leaves behind two daughters, Tania and Natalie.

In a statement, Opposition Leader Bill Shorten said he hopes the family is offered a state funeral.

"Les is a national icon who did so much to grow the world game and to champion multicultural Australia. He deserves nothing less than the full symphony of tribute and respect," Mr Shorten said.

"Ultimately it's a decision for Les's family, but I think the offer should be made at least. I can think of few people as deserving of this high honour."

Dateline: Les Murray's Mission

Statement from SBS 

SBS is sad to advise that earlier today Les Murray passed away after a long period of illness.

Les will be remembered not just for his 35 year contribution to football in Australia, but for being a much-loved colleague, mentor and friend who has left a unique legacy. To say he will sorely missed is an understatement.

Many Australians know Les as Mr Football, who began working with SBS when it launched as a television broadcaster in 1980. His role went far beyond being a football commentator. The growth, popularity and success of football in Australia today is absolutely a reflection of his passion and advocacy for the game that he loved.

RELATED READING

We pass on our deepest sympathies to his family, including his partner Maria and his daughters Tania and Natalie. They ask that their privacy is respected during this difficult time.

SBS Managing Director, Michael Ebeid, said: "No one better embodied what SBS represents than Les Murray. From humble refugee origins, he became one of Australia's most recognised and loved sporting identities.

"Not just a football icon, but a great Australian story and an inspiration to many, to say that his contribution to SBS and to football was enormous, doesn't do it justice. This is a devastating loss for all of us at SBS. Our thoughts are with his family and all that loved him."  

Devastated at the news that our dear friend & colleague Les Murray has passed away. A great Australian who really has left a great legacy.
- Michael Ebeid (@michaelebeid)

The world lost a football colossus this morning, Les Murray AM. He fought well into extra time but whistle has blown. His legacy is lasting
- Craig Foster (@Craig_Foster)

Day One stories: Les Murray describes his first day Down Under

SBS Managing Director, Michael Ebeid, pays tribute to Les Murray's legacy at SBS and his impact on Australian football.

RELATED READING

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS World News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Games</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>16</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray's Mission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Donikian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED JUST NOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig_Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dateline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ebeid</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>18</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS Managing Director</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Football Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Paschalidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Paschalidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Donikian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga Wagga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
