<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399042688989965</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/east-hills/15-million-in-urgent-action-to-floodproof-waterfall-gully-homes/news-story/65ff2c457bfb0da2b0eb978294bba8db</url>
  <title>$1.5 million in 'urgent action' to floodproof foothills homes</title>
  <content>
BURNSIDE Council plans to spend more than $1.5 million to floodproof Waterfall Gully in the next three years after an independent audit recommended urgent action to protect dozens of foothills' homes.
Councillors last week approved $570,000 in immediate funding for "high-priority work" to clear and stabilise First Creek and Chambers Gully. A further $1 million has been earmaked for the following two financial years.
The council also agreed to lobby the State Government to help almost 80 property owners pay for a combined $1.6 million in work to safeguard their homes.
Residents have welcomed the news, hoping it will help prevent a repeat of last year's flood events.

The council commissioned the audit after First Creek broke its banks during heavy rainfall last September, flooding dozens of homes and leaving Waterfall Gully Rd inaccessible for almost a week.
The audit recommended work at 78 properties, including excavating silt, removing fallen trees and repairing and building new retaining walls.
The consultant's assessment of Chambers Gully also recommended $270,000 be spent to stabilise erosion at six sections of the creek's banks.
The council had already finalised its 2017/18 budget, meaning savings from other projects would have to be found to fund the work. Cr Grant Piggott said while that was not ideal, the council had "no choice".

Evacuation centres have been set up near Old Noarlunga and Waterfall Gully. Courtesy Sunrise Seven News

Flooding at Waterfall Gully last year
Cr Henry Davis agreed: "Clearly this is going to mean a lot of additional spending, but it will be good to make the area safer."
Waterfall Gully Residents' Association chairman Peter Mochakis, who was left with a $300,000 damage bill after last year's storms, welcomed "progress" on the issue.
"We do not have clarity on exactly where the money will be spent, but this is welcome," Mr Mochakis said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Grant Piggott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Henry Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Noarlunga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chambers Gully</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gully Residents' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunrise Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterfall Gully</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mochakis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterfall Gully Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Mochakis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnside Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
