<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399948927101130</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/no-bbl-but-townsville-in-wbbl-mix/news-story/9fd936ea6a1f61234f971eba99a32b96</url>
  <title>No BBL, but Townsville in WBBL mix</title>
  <content>
A LACK of suitable lighting continues to hinder Townsville's goal of hosting a Big Bash League match, but the city is in contention to stage a WBBL game this summer.
Brisbane Heat is yet to confirm a venue for two of its Women's Big Bash League home fixtures on Sunday, January 7 and Friday, January 12, and Queensland Cricket is considering Townsville as an option.
However, it is understood Townsville will likely be overlooked for a Sheffield Shield game this year given Tony Ireland Stadium has already been allocated an Ashes tour match between England and a Cricket Australia from November 15-18.
Townsville hosted a Queensland-Western Australia Shield game last year, and it is believed Cairns and Mackay will are the frontrunners to host the match.
Given Mackay hosted the first Queensland Sheffield Shield home game to be played out of Brisbane two summers ago, Cairns looks to be favourite.
The lighting at Tony Ireland Stadium isn't yet up to a standard suitable for TV broadcasting at night, when the vast majority of Big Bash League games are played.
"The regional centres like Townsville are definitely in the forefront of our thinking when it comes to scheduling matches," a Queensland Cricket spokesman said.
"It's certainly very much in the frame for future matches, the Memorandum of Understanding (standoff) has slowed down the decision making for a few things."
Every Big Bash League team was allocated an extra home game in the 2017-18 schedule released on Monday, and Queensland Cricket have previously expressed their desire to eventually play games at regional venues.
Queensland Cricket boss Max Walters told The Townsville Bulletin in January the city was originally being considered as an option to host the extra home game.
"Townsville's definitely in the mix, we'd love to take it to regional Queensland," Walters said.
"Townsville, Mackay and Cairns have excellent facilities, and they'll all be in the mix.
"Obviously the Gabba is going to be hard to leave because we'll have to financially model what our profit from a game at the Gabba is, compared to a smaller venue.
"But we'd love to take it to the regions and spread the games around."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Sheffield Shield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Ireland Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memorandum of Understanding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBBL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Cricket</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash League</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Big Bash League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheffield Shield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Heat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland-Western Australia Shield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Walters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
