<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399948927101176</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/domain/domain-news/latest-news/former-lions-skipper-michael-voss-continues-to-cut-real-estate-ties-with-brisbane-20170730-gxlymz.html</url>
  <title>Former Lions skipper Michael Voss continues to cut real estate ties with Brisbane</title>
  <content>
Former Brisbane Lions great Michael Voss is forging ahead with offloading his Brisbane real estate, placing a vacant block of land at Mount Gravatt East on the market.

Voss, who joined the Port Adelaide Football club as midfield coach in 2014, has made the permanent move to South Australia with his wife, Donna, and their three children.

Earlier this year the triple premiership captain and Brownlow medallist sold his sprawling family home at Marriott Street, Coorparoo, for $2,575,000. Known as "Nu Haven", the single-level corner residence situated in one of Coorparoo's most sought-after pockets was the most expensive property sold in Brisbane that week.

Voss subdivided the block prior to listing it. Photo: Supplied

Now he's listed a vacant hill top , which selling agent , of , cites as one of Mount Gravatt East's iconic addresses.

"It's the best street in Mount Gravatt East and this is a highly prized front row position," he says.

Interest in the already subdivided block, located about 8 kilometres from the CBD, has been strong after only one week on the market, Mr Crawford says.

Former Brisbane Lions great Michael Voss is offloading more of his Brisbane property. Photo: Supplied

"We've had interest from buyers looking to build two houses but just as much interest from buyers wanting to build one big house. The prestige of the street means that's feasible here," he says.

The block is positioned at the end of a quiet cul-de-sac backing onto private bushland in a street with northeast views that span over Mount Thompson and out to the bayside.

The block has recently been split into two parcels of land by Voss - one 450 square metres and one 688 square metres - but it's being sold as one plot and will go to auction on site, Saturday August 18, at 1pm.

Voss bought the block of land during his tenure as captain and when the Lions won three straight premierships in the early 2000s. He paid $235,000 and was living in another property nearby at Mount Gravatt East at the time.

Domain reports the median price for a three bedroom house in Mount Gravatt East is $590,000.

Quarterly house price report

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nu Haven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voss</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Voss</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Gravatt East</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriott Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday August 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Crawford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coorparoo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
