<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399643984418713</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/oil-spills-on-bike-paths-in-melbourne/8759742</url>
  <title>Police investigate multiple incidents of oil poured onto Melbourne bike paths</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Police are investigating a series of incidents on Melbourne's bike paths, in which they believe oil has been deliberately spilt on the paths so cyclists lose control.
It is understood a female cyclist had to have emergency dental surgery at the Royal Melbourne Hospital, after coming off her bike last night in the latest incident on the Dynon Road path, in West Melbourne.

External Link:

Twitter ABC Melbourne: Oil has again been poured on the Capital City Trail bike path, prompting safety fears for cyclists
Victoria Police spokeswoman Natalie Savino said the issue had been going on for weeks.
"Investigators have been told the Dynon Road path, particularly on the bend between Dynon Road and Arden Road, has been subject to oil spills over the past three weeks," she said in a statement.
"The Capital City Trail has also been affected.
"The incidents are believed to be deliberate acts, with the latest occurring overnight."
Debbie, in North Balwyn, told ABC Melbourne her daughter had been off work for a fortnight after falling off her bike last time oil was poured on the track.
"She broke her right elbow. She said the guy following her also fell, so they both went over one after the other," she said.
"Whoever's done that, I mean it affects not only the person who's fallen but she's a medical professional who works both with children and with cancer patients. It impacts them as well.
"She's then unable to go to work for two weeks and she's still not [well]. She was hoping to go back to work this week but it's still not right. It's her right elbow. She can't write up notes for clients."
'More pressure' on police

The ABC has previously
Twitter user Matt Vicars called on police to investigate after the Metropolitan Fire Brigade had to cover oil with sand on the Capital City Trail three weeks ago, tweeting the spill was "a premeditated act of aggression" that "could seriously injure people".
Responding on Twitter, Victoria Police suggested he contact the local council.
President of the Australian Cycling Alliance Edward Hore said there was not enough pressure on police to properly investigate acts of aggression against cyclists.
"Why isn't there more done about these things? We know we've had injuries on the path. We've got to actually do something about it," he told ABC Melbourne.
"We can't just sit there and wait for someone to die to do something about it."
During peak hours, 924 cyclists an hour use the stretch of bike path, according to Melbourne City Council.
Debbie said the oil was being poured in places where it was more likely to catch cyclists unawares.
"[My daughter] said it was right on the bend of a path to make it more likely, I suppose, that somebody would fall," she said.
"I just don't know what sort of person would decide to do that and why they would do it. It's a shocking thing really."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dynon Road</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debbie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan Fire Brigade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Balwyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Vicars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital City Trail</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter ABC Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Melbourne Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Savino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cycling Alliance Edward Hore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arden Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
