<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399987581807401</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/reality-tv/seven-year-switch-couple-brad-and-tallena-split-after-15-months-of-marriage/news-story/154d31a1369c5f5084d3c8811a0c55c6</url>
  <title>Seven Year Switch couple Brad and Tallena split after 15 months of marriage</title>
  <content>
Tallena drops a bombshell on Brad
0:28

Tallena tells Brad about how Tim got naked in the spa with her during the switch, and Brad can't believe what he is hearing. Courtesy: Channel Seven

May 10th 2016
a year ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Tallena experience tears and tantrums on the controversial show Seven Year Switch.

Share

ANOTHER Seven Year Switch couple has called it quits.
After just 15 months of marriage, Tallena has revealed she has split from husband Brad.
"I had to be selfish and put myself first," the 29-year-old told New Idea.
She added: "I realised I'd been sacrificing my own happiness to make Brad happy, so in the end I had to be selfish and put myself first."
"It was a really hard conversation for us to have, but we both knew it wasn't working."

Brad and Tallena try to make it work on the 2016 series of Seven Year Switch.Source:Supplied

Fights over finances prompted the couple to seek help on the show.Source:Channel 7
The former flight attendant said problems with "communication" and "compromise" were big factors in their split.
The Brisbane couple appeared on the first series of the controversial Channel Seven relationship show in 2016. The pair, who were only engaged at the time, experienced tears and fiery clashes as they tried to work through their problems on the show.
While many viewers thought they would decide to part ways at the end of the series, the couple surprised everyone by staying together - and getting married soon after.
While Tallena told New Idea the decision was mutual, she also suggested Brad, 32, struggled with the decision.

Happier times ... Brad and Tallena split after 15 months of marriage.Source:Facebook
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tallena</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year Switch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Idea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Year Switch.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Year Switch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
