<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399948927101125</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/tv-show-on-late-princess-dianas-sex-talk-betrayal-to-her-memory/news-story/8759049f7ed02eec867f2fc977d9f9a1</url>
  <title>TV show on Diana's sex talk 'betrayal to her memory'</title>
  <content>
AIRING intimate details of the late Princess Diana's sex life is a betrayal to her memory, her brother Earl Spencer has angrily- claimed.
Pleading with a British TV station not to broadcast Diana's "video diaries" - which include claims she stopped having sex with Prince Charles after son Harry was born in 1984 - Earl Spencer said they would cause enormous distress to her sons.
But Channel 4 is believed to have told the Earl that the 90-minute Diana: In Her Own Words is an "important contribution to the historical record".
Channel 4 plans to air the program - based on the tapes recorded by Diana's voice coach in 1992 and 1993 - next Sunday, three weeks before the 20th anniversary of Diana's death in a Paris car crash.
Dubbed the "dynamite diaries", they contain candid- and intimate details of Diana's marriage and her turmoil-, including her admission that she considered running off with her bodyguard, with whom she was "deeply in love".
Diana also reportedly details how she only had sex with her husband "once every three weeks" before Harry was born, and says that Prince Philip had told Charles he could have an affair with Camilla Parker-Bowles if his marriage failed.
The Channel 4 program - based on seven of the original 12 tapes, five are said to be missing - comes after the BBC shelved plans to broadcast the tapes in 2007, in deference to the palace.
However, parts of the tapes have been aired in the US.
Channel 4 is already running promos, in which Diana talks about Camilla Parker-Bowles, now Prince Charles' wife, saying: "I said to my husband, you know, 'Why is this lady around?' And he said 'I refuse to be the only Prince of Wales who never had a mistress'."
She also talks about dating Prince Charles, and how he was "like a bad rash", and her affection for one of her royal protection officers, whose death in a motorcycle accident was the "biggest blow of my life".
Britain's Mail on Sunday reported- Earl Spencer had pleaded with Channel 4 not to air the program, which would cause deep distress to Princes William and Harry.
But The Mail reported that Channel 4 argued its controversial program gave Diana a voice.
"The excerpts ... have never been shown before on British TV and are an important historical source," Channel 4 said.
"We carefully considered all the material used ... the subjects covered are a matter of public record. This unique portrait of Diana gives her a voice and places- it front and centre at a time when the nation will be reflecting on her life and death."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla Parker-Bowles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earl Spencer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British TV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince of Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
