<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398913839969052</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/qld-premier-probed-on-watchdogs-workload-as-corruption-allegations-mount-20170731-gxm1pm.html</url>
  <title>Premier probed on watchdog's workload as corruption allegations mount</title>
  <content>
Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk has insisted the state's corruption watchdog has enough resources to deal with the mounting allegations arising from local government.
It comes after Fairfax Media  used his mayoral car for chauffeur-driven trips to brothels and visits to backstreet massage parlours.Photo: AAP
When asked if a special inquiry into local government was needed, as suggested by member for Cairns Rob Pyne, Ms Palaszczuk said the matters were being dealt with by the Crime and Corruption Commission.
"It would be inappropriate for me to comment about those," she said.Photo: Tammy Law
When asked if the CCC had enough resources to deal with the growing number of complaints against local governments, Ms Palaszczuk said it did.
"I'm sure that the CCC has the resources that they need for the job that they are undertaking," she said.

Queensland ministers are governing from the Gold Coast this week, with cabinet due to meet at the Gold Coast City Council chambers on Monday morning.  

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Ms Palaszczuk could not say exactly how many of her ministers would stay on the Gold Coast for the entire week.
"I don't have the exact number but there will be a large number of ministers here, of course they have other duties across other parts of the state, but the majority of the ministers will be on the Gold Coast here during our governing from this region," she said.
"It's a very important part of Queensland and one I'm absolutely committed to."
The Gold Coast is home to a string of sitting LNP MPs, including John-Paul Langbroek and Jann Stuckey.
But Ms Palaszczuk denied her week on the Gold Coast was not just a pitch to win seats for Labor at the next election.
"Not at all, it's about governing from the regions, governing here from the Gold Coast, highlighting as I said previously that we've got the Commonwealth Games coming in April, highlighting the great work, the investment that my government has put in," she said.
On Monday, the government announced $5 million to develop a business case for stage three of the Gold Coast Light Rail, with Ms Palaszczuk, Deputy Premier Jackie Trad, Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate and federal MPs Steven Ciobo and Murray Watt witnessing the "golden spike" final weld on stage two.  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John-Paul Langbroek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Light Rail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tammy Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Watt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Rob Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jann Stuckey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corruption Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Premier Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs Steven Ciobo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
