<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399386286377821</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/ex-brambles-cfo-zlatko-todorcevski-to-develop-in-bowral-20170727-gxk4yv</url>
  <title>Ex-Brambles CFO Zlatko Todorcevski to develop in Bowral</title>
  <content>
has emerged out of retirement to become a property developer.
In line with his plans to move his family to a more idyllic country life in the NSW Southern Highlands town of Bowral, he and his family including his brother have acquired the 1800sq m corner redevelopment property at 421-425 Bong Bong Street with plans to turn it into a $15 million mixed-use commercial and hospitality development.
Mr Todorcevski told The Australian Financial Review he was considering a combined restaurant, retail and either a boutique hotel or luxury apartment project.
It is understood the price paid for the land with a 300sq m brick and iron showroom building was about $3 million, purchased from private owner Paul Edwards.

The property is said to front the "busiest roundabout in the Southern Highlands". It was initially listed on market but was sold in an off-market transaction.

"Bowral has a bunch of new estates, the schools are full. Now all it needs is a rejuvenation," Mr Todorcevski said.
Bowral is 114 kilometres south-west of Sydney, and half way between Canberra and Sydney. There has been increased development activity in the town in recent times, with estates like former John Fairfax chairman James Fairfax's Redford Park Estate emerging.
but opened up the wider land for a 170-home masterplan community.
near Bowral, was also listed for sale last month, tipped to fetch more than $12 million.

Mr Todorcevski said he was talking to designers following the purchase of Bong Bong Street two weeks ago and was likely to lodge a development application in the first quarter of next year.
He retired from full-time executive life last year but has maintained non-executive directorships in several companies including ASX-listed manufacturer Adelaide Brighton.
His family has acquired a block of land in Bowral to build a new house.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Southern Highlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-Brambles CFO Zlatko Todorcevski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowral</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Fairfax's Redford Park Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Todorcevski</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bong Bong Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Highlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
