<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399648279386153</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/calls-for-reinstatement-of-afp-officers-at-hobart-airport-increase/news-story/12b0b567a89b10427e10966f9db1e4a1</url>
  <title>Airport security row escalates</title>
  <content>
THE Federal Government is coming under increasing pressure to justify why Hobart is the only capital city airport without an Australian Federal Police presence as security screening is ramped up around the nation in the wake of a foiled terror plot.
The Federal Opposition, the State Government and Tasmania Police have reiterated calls for a permanent Australian Federal Police presence to be reinstated at the airport in the wake of the alarm.

Hobart lost its 27 AFP officers in 2014 and the constant calls for that decision to be reviewed have escalated since the Sydney incident.

Denison MP Andrew Wilkie has gone as far as warning Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull he will have "blood on his hands" if people are hurt in an airport terrorist attack in Hobart.
However, Tasmanian Liberal Senator Eric Abetz said risk assessments should drive security decisions until the airport caters for international flights.
"I am on the record saying when the Hobart Airport extension is done and when we get international flights in, hopefully very soon, then of course, the relevant authorities such as the Australian Federal Police presence would be needed," Senator Abetz said.
"Thankfully, fingers crossed, thus far Tasmania has not been one of those hot spots and in fact I just asked the AFP at a parliamentary inquiry whether there had been any real need for the AFP at Hobart Airport since the decision to remove their presence. The answer was very simple no, there was no need for that."
Security screening has been stepped up at all Tasmanian airports - except Burnie, where there is no screening until passengers arrive in Melbourne - in the wake of the terror scare.
Passengers have been advised to arrive two hours before their flight to allow for the tighter security focus.
So far, there have been no delays to flights into and out of Hobart.
Tasmanian Labor Senator Carol Brown and Federal Labor MP for Franklin Julie Collins said the new international freight link to China increased Hobart's case for an AFP presence and she called on Tasmania's Liberal senators to pressure their Federal colleagues to review the situation.
"The Government needs to explain the factual basis for its decision to withdraw those police and outline the steps that it is taking to ensure safety and security at Hobart International Airport is not compromised," Senator Brown said.
Federal Infrastructure Minister Darren Chester said airline passengers would face some delays.
"There will be some delays and it may be frustrating for them, but it's better to be safe in these difficult circumstances," Mr Chester said.
"And we need to work with our security personnel at the airports, with staff involved in checking bags, operating the X-ray machines, and just encourage people to allow a little bit more time for their travel."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart International Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin Julie Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Labor MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denison MP Andrew Wilkie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania's Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Liberal Senator Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Labor Senator Carol Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Infrastructure Minister Darren Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
