<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399996171742189</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4823600/seminar-to-tackle-abuse-and-the-bible/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Seminar to tackle abuse and the Bible</title>
  <content>
SAFER COMMUNITIES: Pastor Wayne Forward from Nelson Bay Baptist Church is hosting a free domestic violence seminar on Thursday. Picture: Ellie-Marie Watts

A Port Stephens pastor is taking proactive steps to address recent reports criticising the church for condoning domestic violence.
Pastor Wayne Forward from Nelson Bay Baptist Church is inviting the community to attend a seminar on Thursday centred on domestic violence, the church and interpreting the Bible.
"The seminar is open to all people and will seek to debunk some of the myths surrounding domestic violence including any suggestion that that the Bible condones abuse," Mr Forward said.

"The one hour seminar will conclude by considering ways in which we can make our community safer and provide support for victims and survivors."
Mr Forward said he was prompted to hold a seminar following an ABC investigation into domestic violence and religion.

As part of the investigation, ABC journalists Julia Baird with Hayley Gleeson . 

"Research shows that the men most likely to abuse their wives are evangelical Christians who attend church sporadically," the introduction to the essay, published on July 24, states.

"Church leaders in Australia say they abhor abuse of any kind.

"But advocates say the church is not just failing to sufficiently address domestic violence, it is both enabling and concealing it.

"Despite criticism from some quarters of the media and the church regarding the research that was used as the basis of essay it serves as a timely reminder of the scourge of domestic violence which statistics continue to show plagues of communities," Pastor Wayne Forward said.
"Abuse of the Bible" is one aspect of the essay that will be addressed in Thursday's seminar.

Ms Baird and Ms Gleeson wrote that abusive men commonly refer to several different parts of the Bible to condone their actions.
These verses include:

- Ephesians 5: 22-23
And;
- Timothy 2: 11-12
Mr Forward said Thursday's seminar would include discussions about what a healthy interpretation of scripture looked like.

"The essay has promoted significant discussion about the churches response to victims of abuse," he said.

"Despite criticism from some quarters of the media and the church regarding the research that was used as the basis of essay it serves as a timely reminder of the scourge of domestic violence which statistics continue to show plagues of communities."
According to the latest data by the NSW Bureau of Crime Statistics and Research, domestic violence-related assault within the Port Stephens local government area has risen in the past year.
In the year to March 2017, there has been 347 instances of domestic assault reported to police.
This is on par with 2015, and higher than in 2016 where 325 incidents were reported.
The seminar will be held at the church in Government Road, Nelson Bay from 7pm on August 3.
Mr Forward, a former registered nurse with experience in supporting domestic violence survivors, will speak as will Gill Fletcher, a clinical counsellor and accredited mental health practitioner from the Yacaaba Centre.
Ms Fletcher has also been working closely with the Anglican Diocese of Newcastle in responding to the Royal Commission into Institutional Responses to Childhood Sexual Abuse.
Family and domestic violence support services

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gill Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley Gleeson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bible</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellie-Marie Watts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Forward</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Childhood Sexual Abuse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gleeson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican Diocese of Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Bays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Bureau of Crime</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Bay Baptist Church</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yacaaba Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Institutional Responses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pastor Wayne Forward</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
