<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399953222068493</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/from-the-unley-renovator-that-went-120000-over-reserve-to-the-quarter-acre-that-went-to-developers-our-auction-wrap/news-story/1c5b23496e0b277d6f66e300ad9737de</url>
  <title>From the Unley renovator that went $120,000 over reserve to the quarter acre that went to developers - our auction wrap - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
9 Thomas St, Unley sold at auction for almost $120,000 above reserve.

ADELAIDE'S auction market continues to shine with 78 properties sold under the hammer over the past week. Clearance rates sit at 66.7 per cent with the total number of homes scheduled for auction higher than this time last year. Here's our wrap of some of last week's more interesting auction sales.
UNLEY
It may have needed work but the prospect of a little elbow grease didn't put buyers off this Unley renovator, which sold almost $120,000 above its reserve price.
Auctioned by Belle Property Unley, the three-bedroom bungalow-style home sold for $813,000, a result that even surprised sales agent John McRostie.

9 Thomas St, Unley

"We had 18 registered bidders and plenty of interest throughout the campaign, including first home buyers and investors," he said.
"The home definitely needs some work, but I did tell the owners to polish the floors and clean up the garden.

9 Thomas St, Unley

"But even I was surprised by the result. I put it down to a significant shortage of stock on the market, especially close to the city.
"The sellers are certainly excited. They live in the country and had this as an investment property but decided they no longer had use for it."
KURRALTA PARK
LOCATED on a quarter acre (1011sqm) block, this three-bedroom Austerity-style home proved so popular it sold days before auction.
The original family home, at 36 Garfield Ave, Kurralta Park, sold to a local developer for 756,000 after only 18 days on the market.
Listing agent Sarah Sheppard of Harcourts Sheppard, said the home's prime city-fringe location attracted a total of 10 offers before auction, prompting the owner to an early sale.

36 Garfield Ave, Kurralta Park

"We had offers from $500,000 to the mid $700,000," she said.
"What attracted so much interest was that the home had subdivision potential so I think we'll see a couple of units going up on the land, I'm sure.
"In terms of the sale price, the value was determined on what could be built on the land. The property backs onto a waterway which creates extra challenges for developers as the land needs to be filled up before it can be built on.
"(But) I think we got a good result and in the end."
BEAUMONT
LOCATED in easy driving distance to some of Adelaide's top private schools, this generously sized family home ticked all the right boxes for a sole bidder.
Spanning across two levels with five bedrooms, three bathrooms and expansive views across the city, 4 Dashwood Rd, Beaumont sold to an Adelaide couple for more than $1 million.
A good result, according to listing agent Suellen Salt of Harris Real Estate.

4 Dashwood Rd, Beaumont

"We only had one very keen bidder on the day but I think we achieved a great result," she said.
"The buyers were attracted to the home because of the size and school district it falls into."
Ms Salt said the property had been a well-cared-for family home for the past 18 years.
"The sellers raised their children in this home which have now left. So they are looking to downsize and decided to sell.
"Most homes in the suburb are much like this tightly held and family owned."
WEST
BUILT in 1971, this neatly-presented home proved popular among young homebuyers, selling above its reserve price at auction.
Purchased by a young local couple, 58 Pine Ave in Novar Gardens sold for $565,000 with five active bidders competing for the three-bedroom home.
Listing agent Judy Myers of Ouwens Casserly Real Estate said the home's location - 15 minutes to the CBD, five minutes to the beach and 10 minutes to the airport - was a driving factor of its auction success.

58 Pine Ave, Novar Gardens

"All registered bidders were young people in their twenties to mid-thirties as this property was the perfect for first home buyers at that price," she said.
"We had nearly 100 groups through the home in 17 days which only shows how popular this area is."
With a median house price jump of 6.4 per cent recorded for the suburb between May 1, 2016 and April 30, this year, Ms Myers said Novar Gardens was becoming increasingly popular.
"Novar Gardens, in my opinion, is undervalued and these young buyers saw the value for money and jumped on it," she said.
"(But) the suburb is tightly held, we don't see a lot of homes come to the market that often so when they do, they tend to sell quickly."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austerity-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pine Ave</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dashwood Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McRostie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy Myers of Ouwens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suellen Salt of Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Novar Gardens</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belle Property Unley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garfield Ave</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Sheppard of Harcourts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casserly Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Salt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KURRALTA PARK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaumont</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheppard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
