<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399944632133805</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/paramedics-share-harrowing-tales-in-hope-of-ptsd-compo-changes/8760510</url>
  <title>Paramedics seeking burden of proof changes to PTSD compo laws share tales of job stress</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Tasmanian paramedics are sharing harrowing tales of life on the job as part of a push for changes to workers' compensation laws.
The Health and Community Services Union (HACSU) wants post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) to become presumptive under compensation claims, putting the burden on proof on employers rather than those experiencing it.
The union said PTSD could be debilitating, and workers were "made to feel like criminals" when claiming workers' compensation.
Paramedic Steve Hickie has PTSD, and is one worker to tell his story in a submission to the Government.
He said people outside his profession thought "blood and guts" was the trauma paramedics were exposed to.
"Blood and guts is normal to us - that's what we're trained for, we work with that all the time," he said.
He said the trauma could often stem from the loss and grief that surrounded the job.
"The trauma for us is when you go to someone who's lost their loved one of 50 years," he said.
Mr Hickie recalled two particularly distressing jobs:
"A 35-year-old with stage four melanoma, his wife's there and his two little kids are running around.
"And I know he's going to start a tonic-clonic seizure and I know I'm not going to be able to stop it and I know he's going to die. And there's kids, their two little kids. And you have to tell his wife 'It doesn't look good, I'll do everything I can'.
"I went to a job with a little four-year-old, she was seizing too. She was really sick. I picked her up, and she looked like my daughter. I lost it. Gone."
He said workers' compensation laws did not properly recognise those types of trauma.
"If I fell over and broke my leg, I could point to the gutter and say: 'I tripped over that and that's where I broke my leg'," he said.
"That's easy. A psychological injury doesn't often just happen. It's an accumulation thing."
'It's appalling'

Paramedic Lauren Hepher has also retold traumatic experiences in her career, but said she would not make a compensation claim.

"I think the concept of having to prove that you've got a psychological injury while you're already unwell is appalling," Ms Hepher said.
"I see my workmates, my friends try to navigate the workers' compensation process, and some of the stories are pretty bad.
"The system seems to have no appreciation of the human side of it.
"You just seem to get labelled as a troublemaker, it's up to you to prove to the system that you're injured or unwell while you're trying to navigate your own experience of mental illness.
"It's not right."
Under current laws, workers who apply to claim post-traumatic stress disorder under workers' compensation laws have to prove their case.
HACSU secretary Tim Jacobson said the burden of proof should be shifted to the employer or insurer, and wants tri-partisan political support for the changes.
"We are working very closely with Ambulance Tasmania around minimising the effects on individuals exposed to trauma, but we can never eliminate it completely," Mr Jacobson said.
"We know there will always be another workplace accident, or vehicle crash, or paediatric death.
"PTSD is an insipid disease - if the focus is shifted from who is to blame to what is the best way to manage the treatment it will be beneficial to all Tasmanians."
The shifting of burden of proof is a policy supported by Labor, and will be taken to the election.
Health Minister Michael Ferguson said the Government would consider HACSU's submission.

External Link:

Paramedics PTSD submission

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hepher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HACSU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hickie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Jacobson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Hepher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PTSD</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hickie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jacobson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambulance Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Michael Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
