<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400000466709517</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/victorian-households-australias-most-financially-comfortable-me/news-story/398ef826fbeb269ad4918a044cc4fcbb</url>
  <title>Victorian households Australia's most financially comfortable: ME - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Victorian households have the highest level of financial comfort of those in any state.

VICTORIAN households are the country's most financially comfortable, according to new research.
The latest ME Household Financial Comfort Report showed that Victorian households had experienced a 2 per cent increase in comfort over the past 12 months.
RELATED:
RELATED:
"Overall financial comfort rose most notably due to comfort with savings, income, and investments, reflecting some improvements in the labour market, rising house values and investments," said ME consulting director Jeff Oughton.
"The cost of necessities remains the biggest concern for Australians and when combined with stagnating or falling income for up to 70 per cent of households, expected further rises in the cost of necessities like power prices, as well as rises in mortgage rates, the future doesn't look as bright for some."
However, Sydney overtook Melbourne as the most financially comfortable city for the first time since 2014, with Sydney reporting a 4 per cent rise in financial comfort in the first half of 2017.

Sydney overtook Melbourne as the most financially comfortable city for the first time since 2014.

"While Melbourne has fallen behind Sydney they are both leading the rest of the country," Mr Oughton said.
"Both city's have seen strong increases in household worth, largely through property prices, while they have also experienced much stronger income gains than the rest of the country."
Speculation the Reserve Bank will lift the cash rate caused households concern because it could impact monthly cash flows, ability to pay off debts, save and spend, ME identified.
"Gen Xers (41 per cent), single parents (36 per cent), and couples with young children (35 per cent), expressed the most concern about potential rate rises," Mr Oughton said.
Mr Oughton said one of the big takeaways from the report was the fact the comfort divide between rich and poor households was widening.
"Over a quarter of all households (27 per cent) reported income cuts in the past year, rising to almost half of households earning less than $40,000 (45 per cent), while households earning more than $100,000 were least likely to report income cuts (17 per cent), and the most likely to have seen an income rise (46 per cent)," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Oughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Household Financial Comfort Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Xers (41</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Oughton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
