<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399433531018725</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>04:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/three-girls-aged-12-to-15-have-been-arrested-in-new-zealand-after-a-man-was-stabbed-to-death-2017-7</url>
  <title>Three girls aged 12 to 15 have been arrested in New Zealand after a man was stabbed to death</title>
  <content>
New Zealand police have confirmed three girls aged 12, 13, and 15 have been arrested following the fatal stabbing of a man in Hamilton last Friday night.

Norman Kingi, 54, died in Waikato Hospital after being stabbed on Ranui St on Friday night. Police said the avid rugby player was believed to have interrupted the teenagers attempting to break into a vehicle on his way home from a sports club.

He was taken to Waikato Hospital in a critical condition, but died soon after arriving.

A 15 and 13-year-old were arrested and appeared in the Hamilton Youth Court on Saturday charged with aggravated wounding and unlawful interference with a motor vehicle.

They have been remanded in custody to reappear in Hamilton Youth Court on Wednesday.

A 12-year-old has been referred to Youth Aid for unlawful interference with a motor vehicle, while the enquiry continues to establish what happened, Detective Inspector Graham Pitkethley of Waikato police said.

"Police are seeking any person that has seen or had contact with a group of three female juveniles wearing dark clothing walking together in the area ... between the hours of 10pm and 1am Friday night and Saturday morning.

"If you or someone you know had your vehicle broken into overnight, please contact police as soon as possible."

Detectives continue to investigate the homicide and no further information will be released on the offenders due to their age, he said.

Kingi played centre for the Fairfield United Yellow Bellies over-50 rugby team, club president John Cruickshank said.

This article first . Read . Follow .

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Cruickshank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waikato Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman Kingi (54</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield United Yellow Bellies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Graham Pitkethley, of Waikato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton Youth Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth Aid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ranui St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
