<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399991876774717</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4823485/council-push-for-light-rail-in-broadmeadow/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Council push for light rail in Broadmeadow</title>
  <content>
NEXT STOP: Newcastle City Council want the government to back an extension of light rail to Broadmeadow as part of an overhaul of the area.

NEWCASTLE City Council will seek to put pressure on the Berejiklian government to push ahead with planning for a light rail extension by making transport the focus of its discussions about the Broadmeadow sport and entertainment precinct.
The council is due to begin talks with Venues NSW about a plan for a "new look" Broadmeadow precinct which includes .

While light rail was not mentioned in the draft concept plan, Newcastle Lord Mayor Nuatali Nelmes and the council's interim general manager Jeremy Bath plan to use the discussions as a way of pushing for a commitment to making Broadmeadow the first destination in a wider light rail network.

While the government is on the record as supporting an extension to the network, it has been slow in progressing with plans.  

In June when the Transport Minister Andrew Constance was asked about the council's push for a light rail extension he delivered a spray to Cr Nelmes, . 

POSSIBILITIES: A map of a proposed extension of the light rail network.
On Monday Cr Nelmes accused the government of sending "mixed messages" about its commitment to extend the mooted line from Wickham, and said planning for a transport corridor needed to begin in order to prevent possible routes being built out.

"We can see a huge boom of development happening throughout the city at the moment, we have $1 billion worth of DAs approved in the last 12 months alone and as the city grows and as this precinct is planned and developed we need to make sure that these proposed transport corridors are zoned out," she said.

She said she welcomed Premier Gladys Berejiklian's comment earlier in July that she wanted to see the line extended. 

The quote from Ms Berejiklian is included in an updated version of the council's Connecting Newcastle document, also released on Monday.

The document -  - includes a map of possible light rail extensions first released by the government, which Cr Nelmes said was aimed at making it "really easy" for the government to support the plan.

Mr Bath said he would push for light rail to be part of the redevelopment of the Broadmeadow site.
"It's crucial that we don't make the same planning mistakes made at Homebush, where sporting venues have been built in isolation and where the only realistic way of moving from one site to the next is to get in your car and drive," Mr Bath said.

"Equally important to the overhaul of Broadmeadow is ensuring it links light rail with the Newcastle CBD."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venues NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Andrew Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Lord Mayor Nuatali Nelmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday Cr Nelmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Bath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connecting Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homebush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wickham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bath</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Nelmes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
