<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400077776122005</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/16/11/robert-whitwell-murder-brittney-dwyer-claimed-victim-had-abused-her</url>
  <title>Teen who murdered elderly grandfather 'invented' claim he had molested her</title>
  <content>
A Queensland teenager awaiting sentence for the murder of her grandfather in South Australia has made an eleventh-hour suggestion that her victim had sexually abused her.
Brittney Dwyer, 19, has pleaded guilty to the stabbing murder of her grandfather Robert Whitwell, 81, inside his home in Adelaide's northern suburbs in May 2016.
The court has heard Dwyer had murdered Mr Whitwell in an attempt to steal a large sum of cash from his property.
She was arrested three months later, after "grieving" with family members who unknowingly comforted his killer at his funeral.
Dwyer has made frank admissions to police on a number of occasions, but this is the first authorities and the court have heard about claims of sexual abuse.
Prosecutors in Adelaide's Supreme Court today slammed Dwyer, accusing her of fabricating a story that she was molested in an attempt to excuse the brutal killing and asked the judge to reject the assertions.
"At one minute to midnight she's claiming to have flashbacks (about being molested) ... it is simply an invention, a version that's completely at odds with every other version she's provided," prosecutor Jim Pearce said.

Related Articles

"It's insidious that a man who was murdered in that way should have his reputation besmirched like this.
"This was a pre-meditated, pre-planned, sociopathic killing."
Dwyer's lawyer Craig Caldicott conceded there was no factual basis for the allegations of sexual abuse and the motive for the murder was the large amount of cash Mr Whitwell kept at his house.
"She admits she's not sure (the flashbacks) were real or not ... she doesn't press that as being the motivation for the murder," Mr Caldicott said.
"Clearly she's been a troubled young woman over a long period of time."
As well as the murder charge, Dwyer has pleaded guilty to trespassing on her grandfather's house in the months before the murder.
Her co-offender in the trespass, Shelby Holmes, 19, was today given a suspended sentence.
The Queensland woman had travelled with her friend Dwyer to "scope out" Mr Whitwell's house in the planned robbery, but the pair left with nothing after a failed attempt to break into the property.
Justice Kevin Nicholson was satisfied that Holmes was remorseful and committed the offence "out of friendship" to Dwyer, who was "a domineering influence" on the young woman.
But he said he didn't understand how she could be so naive.
"I remain at a loss as to how you became involved in such morally repugnant, criminal conduct," he said.
"That you could be persuaded so easily into this conduct is really quite baffling."
He ordered Holmes be of good behaviour for three years or risk returning to South Australia to serve her 17-month suspended head sentence.
Earlier, Holmes' lawyer Andrew Culshaw had asked the judge for leniency, asserting the young woman was in no way associated with the murder.
He said she only ever intended to steal cash and she was remorseful for the trespass on Mr Whitwell's home.
"My client did a monumentally stupid thing," Mr Culshaw said.
"She is well aware that she could have potentially become involved in the tragic events of some months later."
A third Queensland woman, Bernadette Burns, 21, is charged alongside Dwyer over the murder.
She has pleaded not guilty and is due to stand trial next week.
Dwyer will return to court for another pre-sentencing hearing in August.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernadette Burns, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelby Holmes, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwyer</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brittney Dwyer, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Whitwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Culshaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holmes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Kevin Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Caldicott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Caldicott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitwell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Culshaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
