<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398875185262509</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/chanticleer/lessons-in-cochlears-longdistance-ceo-strategy-20170731-gxm0w8</url>
  <title>Lessons in Cochlear's long-distance CEO strategy</title>
  <content>
by
Michael Smith

It was the endless travel that prompted .
The departure of Smith after just two years in the job should be a lesson for Australian-headquartered companies with chief executives based on the other side of the world. The tyranny of distance means it often just does not work.
Smith, an American who had been working for Cochlear out of Denver, Colorado for 10 years, moved to Sydney when he landed the top job in September 2015.
That arrangement did not work as Smith's family was in the United States and he found himself spending his entire life on a plane.

Supplied

Holliday-Smith agreed to let him return to the United States and run the hearing implant maker from there but that did not work either. At the time, H and the company was committed to its Australian headquarters.

At the time, the board decided it would work because as chief executive of a global company, Smith would have to spend as much time in the United States as in Australia anyway. While Smith was the best man for the job at the time, the experiment has failed.
"Co-location" is the industry jargon for a growing trend in corporate Australia to allow chief executives to live offshore for a big chunk of the year.
This is usually for strategic reasons such as Boral chief Mike Kane's decision to spend half the year in his native United States to bed down a major acquisition.
Treasury Wine Estates chief Mike Clarke is also based in California for a large part of the year to oversee US brands acquired from Diageo.

Brambles' new chief Graham Chipchase has also been allowed to remain based in London. It is too early to determine whether that arrangement is working or not.
The problem for Australian companies trying to attract the best global CEO candidates is the distance.
While the lifestyle of Sydney or Melbourne is a selling point, spending more time on a plane than on the ground is not.
Letting a chief executive live where they want simply for personal reasons is also a luxury that investors should not tolerate unless there are strategic advantages.

Cochlear announced on Monday that Smith was stepping down. He will be replaced by chief operating officer Dig Howitt who will remain based in Sydney.
Cochlear shares were trading 0.9 per cent lower shortly after opening. Howitt joined the company in 2000 and oversaw the decision earlier this month to develop a manufacturing plant in the western Chinese city of Chengdu.
Smith, who will receive a retirement payment of $1.5 million, became chief executive in September last year.
This followed the retirement of Chris Roberts who ran the company for 11 years. Cochlear has reaffirmed net profit forecasts of of $210 million to $225 million.

michael.smith@fairfaxmedia.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Kane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brambles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diageo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chengdu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colorado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury Wine Estates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dig Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-location</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Chipchase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holliday-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-headquartered</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
