<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400086366056789</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65443/bmw-slashes-m140i-price-as-part-of-1-series-range-revision</url>
  <title>BMW Slashes M140i Price As Part Of 1 Series Range Revision</title>
  <content>
has adjusted the price and specifications of its entry-level  range, resulting in a cheaper price for the flagship M140i, but price rises for most other variants.
The range opens with the 118i, which goes up in price by $2000 and now starts from $39,990 plus on-road costs.
The 118i is powered by a turbocharged 1.5-litre three-cylinder petrol engine producing 100kW and 220Nm, matched to an eight-speed automatic transmission. Standard equipment extends to 16-inch alloy wheels, LED headlights, DAB+ digital radio, reversing camera, sports steering wheel, and BMW's latest iDrive 6 infotainment system plus Sport Line trim including cloth upholstered front sports seats.
The BMW 118d matches the 118i's standard features list but is instead powered by a 2.0-litre four-cylinder turbo diesel engine producing 110kW and 320Nm. Pricing for the 118d also goes up by $2000 for a price of $43,990 plus on-road costs
The next step up, the BMW 120i suffers a larger price hike, up by $3000 to start at $45,990 for the 135kW/270Nm 2.0-litre four-cylinder turbocharged petrol-powered model.
The 120i comes loaded with BMW's Urban Line trim, and adds standard features like 17-inch light alloy wheels, LED fog lights, front and rear parking sensors, Dakota leather upholstery, a self-dimming rear vision mirror, and an interior lighting package.

BMW M140i

Next in line is the 125i which BMW has held steady price-wise at $49,990.
Moving up the 125i also brings a more sporting feel thanks to 18-inch light-alloy wheels, an M Sport pack with M suspension and brakes, anti-dazzle exterior mirrors and high gloss Shadow Line exterior trim. On the inside the 125i scores an M leather steering wheel, cloth and Alcantara upholstery, an 8.8-inch touchscreen and a dark grey roofliner.
A more powerful version of the 2.0-litre turbocharged petrol four-cylinder engine from the 120i brings outputs up to 165kW and 310Nm.
For $59,990 the  is the sole model to come down in price, and on top of the features of the 125i also includes adaptive suspension, Harman Kardon premium audio, black 18-inch light-alloy wheels, Dakota leather upholstery, electric seat adjustment, and adaptive LED headlights with auto high beam.
As the sole six-cylinder model in the 1 Series range the M140i brings a serious step-up in performance with 250kW and 500Nm from its 3.0-litre turbocharged engine and a no-cost choice of eight-speed automatic or six-speed manual transmission.
Pricing

BMW 118i - $39,990
BMW 118d - $43,990
BMW 120i - $45,990
BMW 125i - $49,990
BMW M140i - $59,990
Manufacturer's list price excluding on-road costs. Overseas model shown.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nm</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M140</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Series Range Revision</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW 120</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW 125</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW 118</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW Slashes M140</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dakota</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW M140</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iDrive 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alcantara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sport Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shadow Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW's Urban Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harman Kardon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
