<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400077776122013</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/reality-tv/too-good-to-sell-inside-the-mornington-peninsula-beach-house-reno-of-the-blocks-dea-and-darren/news-story/4ef3bde62dfd8d3560c6fe970a3061b4</url>
  <title>'Too good to sell': Inside the Mornington Peninsula beach house reno of The Block's Dea and Darren</title>
  <content>
The Block's Dee and Darren and their winning bathroom
2:36

The Block's Darren and Dea Jolly talk to Prue Miller about their award winning bathroom.

February 24th 2015
2 years ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Lifestyle - syndicated/

Dea and Darren Jolly are keeping the 1900 Sorrento beach house.

Share

THEY'VE made big bucks flipping rundown homes. But The Block winners Dea and Darren Jolly have finally met their match.
"Everything we've ever done, we've sold. But because it's a beach house, we're keeping this one," Mrs Jolly told news.com.au about their recently purchased 1900 Sorrento cottage. "A white weatherboard Victorian, it's really hard to find down that way. It's walking distance from the beach. It's too good to sell. It's a hard one to find."
The Jollys bought the unrenovated home on Victoria's upmarket Mornington Peninsula in November for $1.8 million. The home - named Franklin by its first owner when it was relocated from Point Franklin near Portsea in the 1890s - boasts a wraparound porch with glimpses of Port Phillip Bay, 3.5m-high ceilings and sash windows.

'Franklin' ... the white weatherboard beach house on the Mornington Peninsula.Source:Supplied

The character-filled home has remained relatively untouched since the 1940s.Source:Supplied
And while the cottage has been relatively untouched since it was last renovated in the 1940s, Jolly said they're not in a rush to give it an overhaul. Instead, they've been "chipping away at it" and don't plan to "overdo" it.
"It will be done in stages and the first stage will be more of a makeover because we love the house as it is, so we just want to freshen it up," she said. "We want it to remain a bit undone. It's a beach house, we want it to be relaxed."

A post shared by D+D Home (@deanneanddarrenjolly) on

A post shared by D+D Home (@deanneanddarrenjolly) on

Since the purchase, Mrs Jolly has been sharing glimpses of the home with fans on social media - and teasing design inspiration as well as plans from her architect Jane Merrylees.

A post shared by D+D Home (@deanneanddarrenjolly) on

A post shared by D+D Home (@deanneanddarrenjolly) on

"Everything that's original we'll keep. Period houses are our thing," she said. "Particularly this one. We just want to bring it back to what it would've been originally - before it was renovated in the 1940s.
"We're reinstating the original old fireplace in the living room that we found the footings for.
We've got the archways and the beautiful windows. We found beautiful hardwood floors under the carpet that was put in the 1940s. It's just a matter of polishing it up really - it's all there."

A claw-foot bathtub will be the first addition to the beach house.Source:Supplied

A post shared by D+D Home (@deanneanddarrenjolly) on

While the mum-of-two is hesitant to give away too many details about her design plans, she did reveal the one addition she can't wait for.
"I'm very excited about putting a claw foot bath in the bathroom," she laughed. "The house we're living in at the moment in Melbourne doesn't have a bath and we've really missed it. The bathroom itself will be really pretty - it's got a big beautiful old window."
On Instagram, Jolly has shared photos of a tribal-style sideboard she will use as the vanity in the bathroom as well as pictures of "bathroom inspo".

A post shared by D+D Home (@deanneanddarrenjolly) on

A post shared by D+D Home (@deanneanddarrenjolly) on

The beachside purchase came soon after the couple pocketed $2.908 million from the sale of their Kew East renovation project. They spent one year and close to $1 million renovating the rundown 1920s California bungalow, which they purchased for $1.395. The controversial renovation , with the couple facing fines of up to $180,000,  despite being required to leave the facade of the house intact. Their company DJJ Promotions was placed, without conviction, on a two-year good behaviour bond by the Melbourne Magistrates Court.

A post shared by D+D Home (@deanneanddarrenjolly) on

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Jolly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Block's Darren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Block's Dea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Block's Dee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jollys</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prue Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Phillip Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sorrento</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Jolly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Point Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D Home</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJJ Promotions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Merrylees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dea Jolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kew East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Lifestyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
