<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400047711350489</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/07/31/well-played-old-friend-full-time-called-colossus-les-murray</url>
  <title>'Well played old friend': Full time called on 'colossus' Les Murray</title>
  <content>
Commentators, politicians and punters alike have expressed their sadness over the loss of veteran football broadcaster Les Murray.

By

Georgina Cooke

2 MINS AGO 

In , Les Murray delivered the kind of signature insight for which he best known since starting his post at SBS in 1980.

Murray, who has died at the age of 71, reflected on a time before the FFA and warned that if the national governing body were to ignore the clout of the clubs, the game risked being fractured again, as it was 60 years ago.

Related reading

"I spent much time being amongst the people who administered football and its clubs between 1957 and the ultimate demise of the NSL in 2003. Most of them worked hard, for no salary or financial reward," he wrote.

"All these people, most of them immigrants, had one over-riding mission: to make football accepted and popular among all Australians. For this effort they were labelled, as Johnny Warren recalled, sheilas, wogs and poofters.

"Yet their legacy is golden and one we should all cherish ... there would be no new football without old soccer which was kept alive and breathing mostly by immigrants."

Beyond his passion for the game that sustained a career spanning more than half-a-decade, Murray was an outspoken advocate for diversity.

It was this trait - and his encyclopaedic knowledge of the sport - for which he became revered as he beamed into homes across Australia, perhaps most memorably on weekend afternoons for the ''World Soccer' and later, 'The World Game' programs.

"No one better embodied what SBS represents than Les," Managing Director of SBS Michael Ebeid said.

"From humble refugee origins, he became one of Australia's most recognised and loved sporting identities. Not just a football icon, but a great Australian story and an inspiration to many, to say that his contribution to SBS and to football was enormous doesn't do it justice.

"This is a devastating loss for all of us."

Devastated at the news that our dear friend & colleague Les Murray has passed away. A great Australian who really has left a great legacy.
- Michael Ebeid (@michaelebeid)

Colleague and fellow commentator Craig Foster said Murray's impact on the game would endure.

"He fought well into extra time but whistle has blown," Foster tweeted. "His legacy is lasting.

"Well played old friend. Extraordinary performance.

The world lost a football colossus this morning, Les Murray AM. He fought well into extra time but whistle has blown. His legacy is lasting
- Craig Foster (@Craig_Foster)

Les left family that loved him, colleagues adored him, futbol community that revered him. Well played old friend. Extraordinary performance
- Craig Foster (@Craig_Foster)

Politicians also rallied around the memory of one of football's most iconic figures.

"Very sorry to hear of Les Murray's passing," Greens leader Richard Di Natale tweeted. "A football legend, advocate for people seeking asylum and an amazing personality."

Very sorry to hear of Les Murray's passing. A football legend, advocate for people seeking asylum and an amazing personality.
- Richard Di Natale (@RichardDiNatale)

"Les Murray brought the world game to Australian homes. He was the voice of famous victory and heartbreaking defeat, of joy and despair. Vale," Bill Shorten wrote.

Les Murray brought the world game to Australian homes. He was the voice of famous victory and heartbreaking defeat, of joy and despair. Vale
- Bill Shorten (@billshortenmp)

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull posted a video message tribute to Les Murray.

"You championed the beautiful game, the World Game in Australia over so many years."

When Murray announced his semi-retirement from SBS in 2014,  that spanned more than three decades with the broadcaster.

"I have been lucky, of course, and whatever it is that I did for football has been reciprocated by what football did for me," Murray wrote

"Most of all, as the end of the journey nears, I must pay gratitude to the viewers, the true believers who stood by football, SBS, and me, and shared the journey with me as members of my family.

"I will never forget them."

On Monday, generations of fans returned that gratitude tenfold as social media was flooded with tributes for the beloved icon, proving the spirit of Mr Football's legacy will certainly live on.

Les Murray is the reason I wanted to be a football reporter. Watching  and World Cups with him. Football will never be the same
- Loukas Founten📝🎥⚽️ (@loukasfounten)

Impossible to put into words how much Les Murray helped grow & shape football in this country. Spent many, many Sundays watching TWG. RIP.
- Matt Bungard (@TheMattBungard)

Grew up watching les Murray on sbs, he elevated soccer in Australia with his commentary, knowledge and passion. Condolences to his family
- Bill Hayek (@BiLLyBoiiiiii)

The ache in my heart is so profound that no tribute can quantify what you meant to me. You were, and will forever be, my no. 1, maestro.
- Lucy Zelic (@LucyZelic)

I can't remember football without Les when the game needed someone to champion he was always there spirit passion a great man a great loss
- David Basheer (@Bashola66)

Les Murray's career highlights

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bashola66</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Games</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig_Foster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Soccer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Di Natale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TWG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ebeid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LucyZelic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgina Cooke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Hayek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Basheer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RichardDiNatale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy Zelic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TheMattBungard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BiLLyBoiiiiii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Bungard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Foster</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loukas Founten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director of SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
