<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399863027754073</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/more-sports/australian-triathlon-pioneer-garth-prowd-dies-in-spain-after-bike-accident/news-story/0b948719d29624d85467ccfcad596658</url>
  <title>Triathlon pioneer Garth Prowd dies</title>
  <content>
TRIBUTES are pouring in from around the world following the death of a man who helped put the sport of triathlon on the map in Australia and the brains and passion behind the biggest race in the Southern Hemisphere.
The much-loved and admired triathlon pioneer Garth Prowd, OAM, died in Spain on Sunday following a bike accident in Barcelona last week.
The man behind the famed Noosa triathlon and multiple world championship events and great friend to numerous high profile triathletes, swimmers, cyclists and Olympic athletes, was in Spain on a family holiday and passed away surrounded by his family.
He was a beloved member of the triathlon and sporting community at large and widely considered one of the sports great trailblazer both in Australia and overseas.
In a statement, the family said while they mourned the loss of a "remarkable man", his life and contribution to Australian sport would be remembered.
"Garth passed away peacefully surrounded by his family - his greatest love - wife Robyn, daughters Sally, Megan, Katie and son-in-law's Matt and Ben,'' the statement said.
"He was a loving husband, father, grandfather, brother and friend to many and his loss will be felt by all who knew him.

I cry as I write this most difficult note No words can describe my sadness 2 lose my gr8 friend Garth Prowd Vale mate we will never forget u

"While we mourn the loss of a truly remarkable man, we will remember his incredible life and his contribution to Australian sport.
"He was a man who revolutionised triathlon, running and cycling events in Australia, who was himself an enthusiastic sportsman.''
Prowd's death at 65 was greeted with shock on social media by those who knew him, including multiple world ironman champions Mirinda Crafrae and Craig Alexander.
"Garth was a legend and always a smiling face. Will be missed terribly. Thoughts with his family,'' wrote triathlete Liz Blatchford on Twitter.
"Just terrible news,'' wrote Alexander.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirinda Crafrae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Hemisphere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz Blatchford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
