<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400082071089401</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/royals/theres-a-morbid-reason-the-royals-always-pack-a-spare-outfit/news-story/206dca25cce1a7c97710332c80def96b</url>
  <title>There's a morbid reason the royals always pack a spare outfit</title>
  <content>
Andrew Morton: 'She ain't Diana, and never will be'
1:09

Journalist Andrew Morton compares the difference between Diana and Catherine, the Duchess of Cambridge.

July 28th 2017
3 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

It's tough work choosing one outfit for each public appearance, let alone two. Picture: Christian Charisius

Jennifer NewtonThe Sun

Share

NARROWING down your wardrobe to pack for a holiday is never easy.
But for the Royal family, their outfits for overseas trips are planned in advance so they never have to worry if they have enough shirts or pairs of shoes.
However, there is one outfit that all royals must take with them abroad, no matter where they are going, and the reason for it is disturbing.

The Duke and Duchess of Cambridge, and Prince George and Princess Charlotte, all took a special set of clothes on their recent visit to Germany. Picture: Patrik StollarzSource:AFP
Every time they leave the country, they must take a black mourning outfit in their luggage - just in case a family member dies while they're away, reports .
And in the sad event of the Queen passing, it is Royal protocol that all of her family members must wear black during a mourning period.
This means that when they return to the UK, they will be seen wearing a respectable, dark outfit to fit the no doubt sombre mood of the nation.

It all started when Princess Elizabeth was caught without an appropriate outfit upon hearing of the death of her father in 1952, while she was on tour in Kenya.Source:Supplied
So last week when William and Kate toured Poland and Germany, a suitable black outfit for the pair would have been packed just in case.
However, there have been times when the Royals haven't been quite prepared with a mourning outfit.
In February 1952, the Queen was on a royal tour with Prince Philip in Kenya when the sad news broke that her father George VI has died following a long illness.

A suitable black dress hadn't been packed for her and she had to travel back to the UK in regular clothes.

It's important for royals to wear black during each official mourning period. Picture: Jeff J MitchellSource:AFP
After her plane landed back in the country, a black dress was taken on to the aircraft for the Queen to change into before she emerged down the steps.
But its not just the royals who have to have a black outfit on standby in case of a death in the family.
Newsreaders also have to have black suit prepared in the event they have to announce the death of a senior royal.
This article originally appeared in and was reproduced with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer NewtonThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Charisius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 1952</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George VI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrik StollarzSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff J MitchellSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duchess of Cambridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Charlotte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Morton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
