<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400034826448440</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/wheelers-hill-charcoal-chicken-serving-fresh-chooks-and-souvlakis/news-story/da4b703ce9d74e05dcf20edb3360431c</url>
  <title>Chicken shop ruling the roost</title>
  <content>
A CHARCOAL chicken shop in Wheelers Hill is ruling the roost when it comes to fresh chooks.
Wheelers Hill Charcoal Chicken owner Angelo Nicou said people were queuing up for their schnitzel burgers and souvlakis.
"We took over the business in April and we've completely changed the menu," Mr Nicou said.
"We use free range La Ionica chickens and lightly charcoal them to make sure they taste to perfection."
He said their souvlakis were a hot item on the menu.
"We use a Greek-style marinate for the souvas and they are so delicious that people keep coming back for more."
"We also have scallop potatoes and fresh salads made daily."
Mr Nicou said feedback from customers had been phenomenal.
"We've had people say they love our fresh food and it's been really good to see several regular customers come through our doors now."
He said they also served up South Melbourne Market Dim Sims.
Mr Nicou said he has lived in Wheelers Hill for 22 years and was thrilled to be working nearby.
"The Wheelers Hill village has a great community feel and it's such a treat to work with my family in a job that I really love."
Monash Leader readers receive a free medium salad when they spend $20 or more until July 31.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wheelers Hill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelo Nicou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wheelers Hill Charcoal Chicken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Ionica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Melbourne Market Dim Sims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nicou</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
