<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399867322721405</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Defence Magazine</source>
  <url>http://www.australiandefence.com.au/news/thales-and-sydney-uni-to-work-on-new-technologies-and-capabilities</url>
  <title>Thales and Sydney Uni to work on new technologies and capabilities</title>
  <content>
In a memorandum of understanding (MOU) the University of Sydney and Thales Australia have committed to work closely together over the next five years to develop new technologies and capabilities.

The MOU covering a more enhanced relationship was signed by the University of Sydney Vice-Chancellor and Principal Dr Michael Spence and Thales Australia Country Director and CEO Chris Jenkins.

"Thales Australia's long-term relationship with the University has contributed to breakthrough technology in underwater sensing and Thales's sovereign capability in fibre laser sensors," Jenkins said.

"Recognising the pace of innovation, especially in digital technologies like big data, machine learning and artificial intelligence, it is critical for Thales to partner with leading universities.

"The future applications of these technologies will require a holistic and integrated response, moving beyond individual disciplines and creating the next generation of careers and technological and industrial capabilities."

Dr Spence said the signing would see the university's researchers offered new opportunities to collaborate on transformational industry projects and Thales to obtain access to world-class research.

"We have made great gains in increasing our engagement with industry in 2017, which is a major priority in our 2016-20 Strategic Plan. Thales has a long and established track record of successful collaboration with a number of academic institutions around the world and we are proud to partner with them formally," Dr Spence said.

Under the terms of the MOU, the partners will initially work on research activities within the Faculty of Engineering and Information Technologies, in the areas of autonomous systems, artificial intelligence, data analytics, advanced sensing and processing, and materials science.

Dean of the Faculty of Engineering and Information Technologies Professor Archie Johnston said the MOU builds on a positive existing relationship between Thales and the faculty. This notably included a 2015 Australian Research Council Linkage Project between Thales and researchers from the University's Australian Centre for Field Robotics, looking at new ways to increase the effectiveness of underwater survey operations.

"By collaborating, exchanging ideas and sharing best practice with Thales, our engineering and IT researchers will gain new ideas about how to translate their research into practical solutions for industry," Professor Johnston said.

Over the longer term, the partners also intend to explore other research, education and training pursuits which may include events, industry development programs and student mentoring opportunities.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Research Council Linkage Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Principal Dr Michael Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faculty of Engineering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean of the Faculty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University's Australian Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thales Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strategic Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Uni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Chris Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Information Technology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thales</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Spence</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Field Robotics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Information Technologies Professor Archie Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thales Australia Country Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
