<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400077776122070</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/south-australian-government-releases-draft-regulations-on-growing-and-processing-industrial-hemp/news-story/b4018787226e95ba2fba57f38f508ca4</url>
  <title>Want to grow hemp? Here's the new rules</title>
  <content>
NEW rules for growing and processing hemp in South Australia would require licence holders to prevent theft or loss of the crop in transit and to notify authorities if they were convicted of a drug offence.
The State Government has released draft regulations for public feedback, which also restrict the level of tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) present in an industrial hemp crop to one per cent.
Industrial hemp is produced from cannabis plant leaves, flowers and stems but provides no psychotropic effect from consumption at that low level.
South Australian MPs passed the Industrial Hemp Act in April, putting in place laws similar to Tasmania, Victoria, Queensland and New South Wales.
The proposed regulations will enable the cultivation of industrial hemp crops and the establishment of a hemp processing industry in SA.
They are being developed by the Primary Industries and State Development departments, SA Health and SA Police.
Industrial hemp is currently cultivated for fibre and seed production and used in products such as textiles, paper, rope, fuel, oil and stock feed.
It will be able to feature in food in Australia from later this year.

A newborn "pinkie" wombat is cute, but when they don't have a mother's pouch to snuggle in life can be difficult. In their furless state, their skin is incredibly delicate, and, if they are being hand reared, they require massage with a lubricant several times a day to keep their skin from drying out. For this adorable young one, in a video taken on June 28 at the Sleepy Wombat Sanctuary, in Gundaroo, New South Wales, hemp oil is the carer's choice. Credit: Sleepy Burrows Wombat Sanctuary via Storyful

Baby wombat gets hemp oil massage
The proposed regulations suggest a licence fee for growing or processing industrial hemp of $1080 and would require a police background check ($250) and inspection fee ($145).
Licence holders would have to be 18 years of age or older and notify authorities if they, or any associate, had been convicted of a drug-related offence.
Unprocessed hemp plants and seeds must be protected from "theft or spillage" while being transported and any "failed" crops would have to be reported to authorities.
Manufacturing and Innovation Minister Kyam Maher said the new laws "allow farmers to decide for themselves if it is economically viable to introduce a hemp rotation to their crops".
"Industrial hemp, which has very low psychoactive properties, can be manufactured for a wide range of products, from cosmetics to textiles and construction materials," he said.
Feedback on the draft regulations closes at 5pm on Friday August 25.
For further information and or to book to attend an information session visit the .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sleepy Wombat Sanctuary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Development</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sleepy Burrows Wombat Sanctuary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Industrial Hemp Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primary Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gundaroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovation Minister Kyam Maher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
