<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398913839969044</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/obituaries/doctor-who-assistant-deborah-watling-who-confronted-daleks-and-cybermen-20170731-gxm0ql.html</url>
  <title>Doctor Who assistant Deborah Watling who confronted Daleks and Cybermen </title>
  <content>
Doctor WhoPhoto: BBC
Deborah Watling, the actress who has died of cancer aged 69, was best known as Victoria Waterfield, the petite and doe-eyed assistant to the second Doctor Who (played by Patrick Troughton) in 40 episodes of the series, which ran from 1967 to 1968.
She was only 19 when she was cast as the "young Victorian miss" who was whisked away in the Tardis after the death of her mother and the slaughter of her father by the Daleks.
"At first, I was very prim," Watling recalled, "in this long frock with big sleeves. But I thought, 'I can't stay in this for a year if I've got to climb mountains'. So gradually Victoria got her own character and the frocks changed: she became stronger and stronger."
 Along with another of the Doctor's companions, the Highlander Jamie McCrimmon (Frazer Hines), Watling appeared in some of the best-loved early episodes of the series and encountered some of its most memorable monsters, at whose appearance she would react with such a piercing shriek that she became known to fans as "the screamer".
"I enjoyed being the damsel in distress and getting all that attention," she said. "I worked with so many monsters: the Daleks first, then the Ice Warriors and the Cybermen - they were horrendous. And I killed the Seaweed Monster with my scream."
The Tomb of the Cybermen, originally aired in 1967, was one of several early episodes that were lost for many years, although it was recovered in 1991 and is now seen as one of the classic Doctor Who stories.

For Watling, however, the monsters provided even more fun off set. "I went out with a Yeti," she recalled, "and a Cyberman, but only for one night. I couldn't take it. The height of him!"
Deborah Patricia Watling was born on January 2, 1948, and brought up in Essex. Her parents, Jack Watling and Patricia Hicks, were actors, and her two sisters and brother, Giles Watling, also went into the business, although he is now the Conservative MP for Clacton.
Deborah made her first television appearance aged 10 in an episode of the ITV series The Adventures of William Tell, after which she played Sally Wilson in the 1958 adaptation of H. G. Wells' The Invisible Man.
She also made several stage appearances, and after leaving school at 16 she spent less than a term at stage school before landing the role of Alice in Dennis Potter's television version of Alice in Wonderland. It was after she appeared as Alice on the front cover of the Radio Times that she was approached by the producers of Doctor Who.
In 1969, after leaving Doctor Who, she joined her father in the BBC soap opera The Newcomers, which was followed by starring roles in two rock 'n' roll musical movies, That'll Be The Day (1973), with David Essex and Adam Faith, and Take Me High (1973), opposite Cliff Richard.
In the 1970s she appeared on stage in several productions including, in the West End, a revival of JB Priestley's Laburnum Grove with Arthur Lowe. But after playing Norma in Danger UXB (1979) she retired from acting and moved to Essex where she set up a gardening business.
In 1993 she played Victoria again for the film Dimensions in Time, which was made for Children in Need.
A familiar face and gracious presence at many Doctor Who conventions, she did admit that her role in the series had dominated her professional life. "Once you've been in Doctor Who," she explained, "you"re never allowed to forget it."
She was married briefly to the actor Nicholas Field, after which she married Steve Turner. He survives her.
Telegraph, London
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tardis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daleks</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giles Watling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adventures of William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Take Me High (1973</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seaweed Monster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Hicks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ITV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highlander Jamie McCrimmon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deborah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Troughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Faith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Watling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H. G. Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Priestley's Laburnum Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wonderland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cliff Richard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyberman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ice Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomb of the Cybermen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clacton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Waterfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watling</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WhoPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day (1973</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doctor Who</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deborah Patricia Watling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essex</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danger UXB (1979</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conservative MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Essex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deborah Watling</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invisible Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frazer Hines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
