<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400034826448456</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/opinion/missing-people-sad-for-families/news-story/bd0e1ba8f2a09c5b0aab53ab54fd4488</url>
  <title>Missing people sad for families</title>
  <content>
DEALING with the death of a loved one is always difficult, but what happens when there's no body to bury, and no real opportunity to mourn?
That is the reality for the friends and families of the 24 missing people featured in our story today. These are 24 Territorians or people visiting the Territory who have disappeared, never to have been seen or heard from again by those who love them.
It's heartbreaking for the people left behind, who are left always wondering what happened.
Rebecca Hayward's three children still ask where their mum is and when she will be coming home, six months after she disappeared near Alice Springs.
Her sister, who is now caring for her young nieces and nephew, can't answer those questions and can't provide any closure for them. It must be agonising.
Carl Herdman, whose brother Jamie went missing from Daly Waters in 2006, said the disappearance as a "hole" in his life. "You think about it all the time and wake up thinking about it"," he said.
More than a decade on, he hasn't given up on finding his brother and closure at last.
"It just leaves a hole, you think about it all the time, and wake up thinking it."
More than 38,000 people are reported missing in Australia each year. Happily, most are found within hours or days. But some aren't.
Ms Hayward is just one of about 2000 long-term missing people in Australia.
If you can help solve the mystery of what happened to any of these people, and help their families heal their hurt, please, contact police.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daly Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Hayward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territorians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hayward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carl Herdman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
