<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399257437357424</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/sport/football/les-murray-australian-football-broadcasting-legend-and-sbs-presenter-dies-aged-71/news-story/f0c9aed7353ae6740bb05f2651d79652</url>
  <title>Les Murray dies aged 71</title>
  <content>
THE world of Australian football is in mourning after the news that SBS presenter and broadcasting legend Les Murray has died aged 71.
The country's most prominent presence on TV screens covering the sport, he was a passionate advocate for the game and a much loved figure both in sport and the media.

SBS football broadcaster Les Murray has died at the age of 71 after a long battle with illness. Tributes tonight on SBS World News at 6.30pm

Murray, born in Hungary with his family emigrating to Australia in 1957, began working in journalism in 1971, spending a time with Network Ten before joining SBS at its foundation in 1980. It was there that he made his name, his face and voice now synonymous with football in this country, his knowledge and humour a feature of football fans' experience of the sport.

Vale, Les Murray.
Football in this country wouldn't be where it is without him.
That's a legacy.

He is survived by two adult daughters, Tania and Natalie.
"Les Murray was 'Mr Soccer' and devoted his life to the game and did so much for the game," said former Socceroo and friend of Murray, Robbie Slater.
"Les was someone we all looked up to; he did so much for the game.
"Les is not only a great loss to his family and friends, but a great loss to the game."
Murray was appointed a Member of the Order of Australia in 2006 and was also a member of Football Federation Australia's Hall of Fame.
Les Murray Tribute

He was also presented with the Lifetime Achievement Award for Contribution to Sports Journalism at the 2009 Australian Sports Commission Media Awards.
"This is the biggest honour the Australian sporting family has ever given me. I am thrilled by it and am very proud of my country," he said at the time.
"That I, who came here as a penniless child refugee over 50 years ago, should receive such an award says a lot about this country and about what a welcoming, open and receptive society we are.
"But I accept this award not just on behalf of myself but of many others with whom and with whose help I did my work and played out my dreams and continue to do, including those who are no longer with us, such as the late Johnny Warren who'd be sharing my immense pride.
"I accept it on behalf of SBS whom I must thank for giving me the licence and the platform, to do what it was that earned me this honour, and for paying me to do it."

The world lost a football colossus this morning, Les Murray AM. He fought well into extra time but whistle has blown. His legacy is lasting

Les left family that loved him, colleagues adored him, futbol community that revered him. Well played old friend. Extraordinary performance

Having stepped back from a full time role following the 2014 World Cup finals, he continued to play an active role with SBS on a part-time basis, as recently as earlier this month penning a column on the broadcaster's website to .
"No one better embodied what SBS represents than Les Murray. From humble refugee origins, he became one Australia's most recognised and loved sporting identities," SBS Managing Director, Michael Ebeid said.
"Not just a football icon, but a great Australian story and an inspiration to many, to say that his contribution to SBS and to football was enormous, doesn't do it justice. This is a devastating loss for all of us at SBS. Our thoughts are with his family and all that loved him."
Through his television work and public advocacy of the game, Murray is widely recognised as a pioneering champion of football during it's rise in popularity in Australia in the 1980s and 90s, and is known to most who will miss him quite simply, and appropriately, as 'Mr Football'.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS World News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Network Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray Tribute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports Journalism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia's Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ebeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS Managing Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Member of the Order</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sports Commission Media Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifetime Achievement Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Soccer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
