<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399128588336913</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/holden-production-line-exhibit-for-national-motor-museum/8759682</url>
  <title>Holden production line exhibit to be built in National Motor Museum</title>
  <content>
Despite Holden closing its car production line in Adelaide soon, a spectacular replica will live on suspended from the ceiling of the National Motor Museum.
"We're looking at suspending six cars from the ceiling in the museum, so it's going to be quite a big display - it will be quite striking I think," Holden corporate affairs manager Sophie Milic told ABC Radio Adelaide.
"We're going to focus on the cars that we've built over the last few years."
She said there would be a Cruze and various Commodores, one of them with a very special significance.
"The last car on the [suspended display] line will be the 50,000th VF Commodore that we built in 2014," she said.
"That's covered in signatures of our employees who built that car."

The museum is at Birdwood in the Adelaide Hills and the display will be in a space which has very high ceilings, museum director Paul Rees said.
"This is history in the making; this is a moment in time and we're there to help document it," he said.
"It's going to be quite spectacular when people walk in."
Exhibit to open in late September

Mr Rees said it was a fantastic opportunity, but the museum staff were tempering their excitement because the closure of Australian automotive production was the reason it has come about.
Although , Mr Rees said the museum would be ready to launch its new display in late September, to coincide with the weekend the annual  is held.
The ambitious project is expected to cost about $600,000, and funds are being contributed by Holden, Arts SA, the National Motor Museum and construction support from some of the Adelaide companies which have been Holden suppliers.
The State Government's Automotive Transformation Taskforce is giving $110,000 toward the cost of the permanent display.

SA's Automotive Transformation Minister Kyam Maher said the exhibit would be enjoyed by generations who worked in vehicle production in the state and their descendants.
"South Australia has a very proud history of car manufacturing and it is appropriate that we support a lasting legacy to ensure future generations understand how important automotive manufacturing is to our state's history," he said.
"For over 50 years, generations of South Australians have worked in the automotive industry and we should be proud that we are one of only 13 countries who can build cars from scratch."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Milic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cruze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA's Automotive Transformation Minister Kyam Maher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rees</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Rees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Motor Museum</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government's Automotive Transformation Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VF Commodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
