<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399085638663452</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/12/47/aboriginal-man-disappointed-at-mining-snub</url>
  <title>Aboriginal man disappointed at mining snub</title>
  <content>
Organisers of Western Australia's annual Diggers and Dealers mining conference have been accused of being "condescending and patronising" towards an Aboriginal elder after they dumped the traditional Welcome To Country ceremony he had been asked to give.
Trevor Donaldson says he was approached to open next week's conference in Kalgoorlie, but organisers later claimed the schedule was too tight for him to perform the 15 to 30 minute ceremony.
But Mr Donaldson told AAP on Monday that his ceremony would likely only be about five minutes and that he's disappointed not to be able to conduct it.
"I'd be pushing 10 minutes to the maximum," he said.
"I am bitterly disappointed."
Mr Donaldson said he would be happy for any traditional custodian of the land to perform the ceremony and said it was not a personal issue, but a matter of reconciliation and mending bridges.
It is a sensitive time in Kalgoorlie after a 56-year-old man who ran down and killed 14-year-old Aboriginal boy Elijah Doughty was acquitted of manslaughter in the WA Supreme Court and was instead jailed for three years for dangerous driving causing death.

Related Articles

Elijah's death in August last year sparked a violent riot, exposing racial tensions in the Goldfields town, but a more peaceful march was held this month when the verdict was handed down.
Conference organiser John Langford insisted last week there was no disrespect meant towards the Aboriginal community and the Welcome To Country would return next year.
One Nation upper house member Robin Scott has urged the conference organisers to reconsider their decision for this year and described it as a gratuitous snub.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Donaldson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Langford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Welcome To Country</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Donaldson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elijah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldfields</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elijah Doughty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
