<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400077776122077</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/bail-granted-parawa-shooting-accused/8760556</url>
  <title>Parawa forest shooting death accused granted home detention bail</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A man facing charges over the shooting death of a friend in a wilderness area at Parawa, south of Adelaide, has been granted home detention bail.
Hayden Dove Fenton, 28, was charged with acts to endanger life after the death a week ago of 21-year-old Bailey Davenport, of Hayborough, a suburb of Victor Harbor.
The young man died after receiving a gunshot wound to the head while at a forest with mates, where police said they had been chopping wood.
Defence lawyer Stacey Carter told the Magistrates Court at Christies Beach that Fenton was hardworking and had been regularly in employment since leaving school at the end of Year 9.
"One could describe him as a very hardworking young father," she told the hearing.
The court granted bail with strict home detention conditions, including a ban on firearms possession or being near anyone else who possessed a firearm.
Fenton was banned from making any contact with a woman and two other men who are part of an ongoing police investigation.
Detective Inspector Greg Hutchins told a previous hearing that five friends had gone to a wilderness area, 40 kilometres west of Victor Harbor, to gather wood and "have some fun".
After the shooting, Mr Davenport was driven to South Coast District Hospital by his friends, then transferred to an Adelaide hospital where he died.
Fenton is to appear in Adelaide Magistrates Court in October.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bailey Davenport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parawa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fenton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stacey Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayden Dove Fenton, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.25</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast District Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christies Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Greg Hutchins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Harbor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Davenport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
