<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399686934092465</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/world/china-unveils-vast-military-weapons-tells-troops-march-wherever-the-party-points/news-story/8ca09353a855f6d7c816e28a486855f6</url>
  <title>China parades its terrifying military might</title>
  <content>
CHINA launched an awesome show of its military might - just hours after warning Donald Trump about his involvement in North Korea.
Tens of thousands of Chinese troops marched alongside tanks and nuclear weapons as stealth fighters and attack helicopters roared overhead.
President Xi Jinping, wearing his military fatigues, inspected his troops personally just hours after the latest North Korea crisis.
The Americans were warned by Beijing after stepping up the deployment of its THAAD missile defence system in South Korea.
The move was in response to Kim Jong-un's .
But a stern China warned Washington: "The Chinese side is deeply concerned about the situation."
And Beijing's show of military might in Inner Mongolia - celebrating the 90th anniversary of the army's foundation - proved it now possesses the force to back up its words.
Xi told his troops they should be ready to defeat all "invading enemies" as he told them they were "closer to the goal of the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation."
On display were a new Dongfeng-31AG nuclear-tipped ballistic missile and the Dongfeng-21D "aircraft carrier killer."
Several nuke-ready H-6K bombers were shown flying overhead.
Xi has invested billions into the Chinese military in a bid to overtake the US as the world's most powerful force.
Despite cutting 300,000 from the army, he has overseen investment in aircraft carriers, nuclear submarines and stealth fighters.
The strongman added: "Always listen to and follow the party's orders. And march to wherever the party points to."
This article first appeared in and is republished with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>XI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dongfeng-31AG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H-6K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Xi Jinping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dongfeng-21D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inner Mongolia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THAAD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
