<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400094955991523</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:54</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/07/31/calls-state-funeral-sbs-football-legend-les-murray</url>
  <title>Calls for state funeral for SBS football legend Les Murray</title>
  <content>
For decades Les Murray was the face and voice of Australian football. He leaves behind a legacy spanning five decades.

By

3 HOURS AGO  UPDATED JUST NOW

There are calls for a state funeral for football broadcasting legend Les Murray, who has died aged 71 after a long illness.

Known as 'Mr Football', Murray has been largely credited with making the World Game part of Australian culture.

He leaves behind two daughters, Tania and Natalie.

RELATED READING

Opposition Leader Bill Shorten said the family should be offered a state funeral.

"Les is a national icon who did so much to grow the world game and to champion multicultural Australia. He deserves nothing less than the full symphony of tribute and respect," Mr Shorten said in a statement.

"Ultimately it's a decision for Les's family, but I think the offer should be made at least. I can think of few people as deserving of this high honour."

Murray began at SBS in 1980 as a Hungarian subtitle writer.

But his passion for football rapidly brought him into the sports team. By 1986, he was hosting the network's World Cup coverage.

As an SBS football commentator and presenter, he covered eight World Cups, before retiring in 2014. That same year he was also inducted into the FFA Football Hall of Fame.

Tributes have flown from all circles for the football commentator.

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull issued his condolences in a Facebook post, saying the Socceroos and Matildas never had a more devoted fan than Murray. 

"You championed the beautiful game - The World Game - in Australia over so many years," Mr Turnbull said.

"You and Johnny Warren really made The World Game Australia's game. Rest in peace."

SBS Managing Director, Michael Ebeid, pays tribute to SBS football broadcaster, Les Murray

SBS Managing Director Michael Ebeid said it was a sad day not just for the multicultural broadcaster, but sports broadcasting and the football community at large.

"Les was certainly an iconic football presenter, and he did an amazing job for us over 37 years," Mr Ebeid said, paying tribute to Murray's passion to nurture and develop up-and-coming writers and broadcasters.

"Les has mentored many young journalists and young commentators in football over the years," Mr Ebeid said.

"And the one thing he often used to say is 'it's not about us hosts, it's not about us in entertainment, it's always about the game'."

Friend and former SBS colleague Andy Paschalidis said Murray left a lasting legacy for all football fans.

"He spread the message of the World Game better than anyone before him during his time, and dare I say beyond his time."

Murray , as his family escaped Hungary amidst communist Russia's occupation. In 2015 he told SBS that people smugglers helped them escape.

Day One stories: Les Murray describes his first day Down Under

The family first landed in Darwin, before eventually arriving at a migrant camp near Wagga Wagga.

Former colleague and close friend George Donikian told SBS World News that Les Murray was dedicated to promoting diversity in Australia.

I hope the state govt offer Les Murray's family a state funeral. He deserves nothing less than the full symphony of tribute and respect.
- Bill Shorten (@billshortenmp)

"The work that Les did to support multicultural Australia was fantastic. Immense in fact," Mr Donikian said.

"His name and his legacy will be that he actually transcended SBS and transcended so many different platforms."

Dateline: Les Murray's Mission

Devastated at the news that our dear friend & colleague Les Murray has passed away. A great Australian who really has left a great legacy.
- Michael Ebeid (@michaelebeid)

The world lost a football colossus this morning, Les Murray AM. He fought well into extra time but whistle has blown. His legacy is lasting
- Craig Foster (@Craig_Foster)

RELATED READING

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS World News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ebeid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Games</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>16</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray's Mission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Donikian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED JUST NOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig_Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Game Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dateline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ebeid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS Managing Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Football Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS Managing Director Michael Ebeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Paschalidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Donikian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga Wagga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
