<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399910272394989</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/business/what-to-expect-from-your-winter-bill/news-story/89a82c1e4ebc906cd3f9f49395c00ec9</url>
  <title>Maths equation to stop bill shock</title>
  <content>
Why do your power bills keep going up?

ONE of the major electricity retailers has finally released details of what consumers should expect from their winter bill.

News.com.au was  but one of them has now provided details for those worried about what  could mean for their next bill.

EnergyAustralia has estimated the charges for an average customer over the winter months from June to August.

The figures provided are an estimate only, as individual bills can be impacted by which distribution zone a customer lives in, their tariff and actual consumption.

The winter bill, which is generally due in October, is traditionally the biggest bill households face.

"Historical consumption records show households use almost a third of their annual electricity demand in winter and could be paying around 40 per cent more for electricity during winter compared with summer," EnergyAustralia chief customer officer Kim Clarke said.

The EnergyAustralia figures show usage and price increases appear to vary widely depending on which state people live in, with the average customer in NSW looking at a 24 per cent increase in their winter bill, while those in South Australia face a 16 per cent increase and Victoria just 8 per cent.

The calculations differ slightly from the estimated yearly increases EnergyAustralia released, which suggested a 19.6 per cent rise in NSW and South Australia, and a 7.3 per cent in Queensland.

The other two companies have refused to provide similar calculations.

Origin spokesman Ryan Auger told news.com.au it would not be calculating estimated winter bills because price changes vary "from household to household, based on factors like the customer's network supplier, individual usage patterns and weather".

AGL did not provide any response despite repeated calls and email requests.

But worried consumers can check their estimated yearly costs and search for a cheaper provider using the government-funded  website, which allows people to compares electricity providers.

It comes as iSelect today released the results of a national Galaxy Research study that suggested nine out of 10 Australian households were concerned about their upcoming winter bill.

The Galaxy survey revealed more Australians were worried about the bill than last year.

It found an extra half a million households (or an additional 5 per cent of homes) were likely to be concerned about their winter energy bill compared to 2016 figures.

"More Australian households are worried about their energy bill this winter than last year, no doubt partly due to the latest price hikes in July which will see customers in NSW, South Australian and parts of Queensland paying up to 20 per cent more," iSelect spokeswoman Laura Crowden said.

About 50 per cent of households surveyed said they were dining out less to budget for their energy costs and a further 43 per cent were cutting back on holidays.

About 27 per cent may even be cutting back on groceries to pay their energy bills, an increase of 10 per cent on 2016 figures.

Almost 70 per cent of households surveyed said they believed their energy bills had increased in the past year, with less than a quarter of respondents saying they are able to pay their energy bills easily.

"These figures confirm our beliefs that Aussies are struggling more and more with energy prices and are having to cut back around the home in order to pay their energy bills," Ms Crowden said.

Last week NSW Shadow Minister for Resources and Energy Adam Searle slammed the lack of response from electricity and gas retailers in providing estimated bills.

Mr Searle said these companies should be able to give customers a ballpark figure.

"This is not rocket science, the energy companies would know what the percentage increase people would pay for their winter bills," he told news.com.au.

"There is huge anxiety among households, families and businesses about what these staggering price hikes will mean to their cost of living."

News.com.au readers were also scathing of the energy companies, with many taking to Facebook to share stories about errors in bills and huge increases.

One woman said: My bill has gone from $175 to $298 in 2 months with just 2 of us here... Can understand why so many people are becoming homeless as you just cannot survive anymore... Shame on this government"

Another post said: I vacuumed a house twice that's been empty for 5 months and received a $287.56c bill".

EnergyAustralia's Kim Clarke acknowledged that price increases were bad news for families and businesses.

She said recent rises made it even more important for consumers to understand how to reduce their bills.

"Wholesale costs - what it costs to buy electricity on behalf of customers - have increased 120 per cent since July 2015. I would love to be proved wrong but we see no sign pressure on retail energy prices are about to ease in the short term," Ms Clarke said.

"Customers shouldn't have to sacrifice their comfort and wellbeing while industry and governments work out a long-term, sustainable solution. There are some things people can do to save money on their winter energy bills," she said.

The ACCC is currently investigating energy prices Queensland, NSW, Victoria, South Australia, Tasmania and the ACT, amid accusations of price gouging by retailers.

It is holding  to speak directly with customers.

.

EnergyAustralia's home heating hints:

1. Heat a room according to use. If possible, transit areas like kitchens or hallways can be heated to 16 degrees celsius and where people spend more time, such as lounges, are generally comfortable at 20 degrees. Close the door to rooms you're not using.

2. Up to 10 per cent of your power use could be from gadgets left on standby; turn them off at the wall when not in use.

3. Take advantage of the sun this winter, no matter how sporadic, by letting in natural light particularly through north-facing windows. The sun is most intense from 10am to 3pm; let in as much light as possible during that time. At other times, keep the blinds closed.

4. Draught-proof around the bottom of external doors with door snakes and install weather-stripping along door edges.

5. Ensure walls, ceilings and beneath floorboards are properly insulated; this can reduce heating costs by up to 20 per cent.

6. Run ceiling fans in reverse during cooler months. Set to clockwise, the fan creates an updraft that sends warmer air pooled near the ceiling back down to living areas.

7. Use a warmer doona so heating can be turned down or off while everyone is asleep. If possible, don't leave the heater on overnight.

8. A cosy home in winter is a joy. But every degree above 20 degrees Celsius can add around 10 per cent to the running cost of your heating.

9. We all love a hot shower. But keep it to around 4 minutes, and you'll be surprised how much water and energy you'll save.

10 If you have a storage hot water system, keep the tank at 60 to 65 degrees Celsius for safety and efficiency.

|

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Searle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Shadow Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EnergyAustralia's Kim Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iSelect</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Auger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Crowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Crowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Adam Searle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EnergyAustralia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celsius</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
