<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399661164288251</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:13</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-boys-24-hour-wait-for-arm-snapped-in-half/3207043/</url>
  <title>Coast boy's 24-hour wait for arm snapped in half</title>
  <content>
A SUNSHINE Coast boy has waited for more than 24 hours for treatment after breaking his arm clean in half.
Doonan's Christian Cameron, 9, was playing with friends yesterday morning when he fell from his skateboard, snapping his arm at 10am.
Christian was raced to Nambour Hospital in an ambulance.
From there, Christian and his frantic mother Lieke Cameron were forwarded to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital where they would wait more than 20 hours for treatment for the break.
Ms Cameron said she was appalled by the lack of communication between doctors, nurses and wards.
"There was only one student doctor (who visited last night)," she said.
"He promised he was going to come back to tell us what time the surgery was and he didn't even come back."
Ms Leike said her son didn't eat until late into the night as nurses weren't sure if he'd be going into surgery.
"It's no service and miscommunication," she said.
Ms Leika also questioned if the newly built hospital was understaffed.
At 11.15am this morning Christian finally went under the knife, with surgeons manipulating the bone into a position so it could heal.
Ms Cameron said she was "relieved" to see her son treated after sitting up all night with him.
Christian woke from his surgery at about 2.30pm and is on the road to recovery.
Sunshine Coast University Hospital have been approached for comment.
VIDEO: Car surfing bird ruffles feathers
In an Australian first, the media has been granted access
Celebration after Coast gym snapped up in last minute sale
LATE footballer James Ackerman's legacy will forever live on.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
He won the heart of Georgia Love and now, Lee's heading back to TV
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ackerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Leika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Leike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Cameron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieke Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doonan's Christian Cameron, 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
