<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400086366056753</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/more-sports/australian-coach-jacco-verhaeren-not-happy-with-james-magnussen-over-relay-comments/news-story/ac240ec8aeb909eaa126a18d94b3b7dd</url>
  <title>Aussie coach slams Magnussen relay spray</title>
  <content>
DUAL world champion James Magnussen can expect a phone call from national head coach Jacco Verhaeren to reprimand him for publicly criticising Australia's relay strategy at the Budapest world championships.
Verhaeren is clearly annoyed that  rather than talking to the head coach directly.
"I do think he has my phone number and when he has a question _ I think he's a good guy and we have a pretty good relationship _ so if he has a question I think he should talk to me and not through the media,'' Verhaeren said.
"I'll definitely have a conversation with him about this because I'm actually very comfortable and happy with the process we had for our relay strategies.''
The Australian men did not win a medal in their three relays in Budapest, but the women won a silver and two bronze medals and the mixed medley relay claimed the silver medal.
Magnussen, who opted out of the national team this year to focus on next year's Commonwealth Games, said that the Australian teams should go back to their former strategy of leading with their fastest men.
But Verhaeren said the decisions on relay strategy were being made by very experienced coaches.
"I do think athletes within the team should trust the coaches to make those decisions,'' he said.
"We have in our team structure a team leadership group (for relays). In this case it's Michael Bohl, Simon Cusack, Glenn Beringen and myself, together with a relay coach on the day. That's about 100 years of relay experience.''
Verharen suggested that Magnussen had breached the team's trust by speaking publicly on the matter.
"I think the trust within is very important and I think James knows better than to make comments on the outside. On the inside it's great, but (his comments are) not a reflection of what this team is made of.''
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magnussen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verharen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Beringen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacco Verhaeren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verhaeren</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Cusack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bohl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Magnussen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
