<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400292524490648</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/shock-and-anger-at-closure-of-castlemaine-gallery-20170730-gxlpyd.html</url>
  <title>'Tell me this is a bad dream': Anger at closure of Castlemaine gallery</title>
  <content>
A 104-year-old tourist attraction in the goldfields town of Castlemaine is closing, with little notice, next week in what has been described as a "kick in the guts" to the Australian arts community.
Paintings by Australian masters including Frederick McCubbin and Arthur Streeton will be placed in storage when the Castlemaine Art Museum closes its doors, and five employees will be laid off.
Shocked and saddened supporters have started a campaign to save the museum after its board announced it has insufficient funds to operate.
The town will be without one of its major tourist attractions for at least two years, and even then, it's not guaranteed it will be back at that time.
The gallery has hosted exhibitions by big name artists such as Ben Quilty, Bill Henson and Patricia Piccinini​, exhibits many local artists' works, and holds priceless gold rush heritage items.
Quilty said the closure was "another kick in the guts" to the Australian arts community.
"Tell me this is a bad dream," he wrote on Facebook.

"Castlemaine Art Museum is one of Australia's oldest art galleries. It was built at the tail end of the glittering gold rushes of central Victoria. It also hosted my After Afghanistan exhibition in 2013." 
Sources pointed out that a major review in 2015 warned the gallery was not financially sustainable.
They said costs have mounted, including $60,000 to publish a centenary book in 2013, and $40,000 in 2014 to pay staff entitlements and back pay.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Complying, for the first time, with museum maintenance and climate control guidelines had added more costs.
Recently a major annual philanthropic endowment, worth $30,000 per year over the past 13 years, was lost.
In 2015 the gallery members voted for the gallery to become incorporated because it would bring a greater accountability and compliance regime. But a condition of the endowment had been that the gallery be unincorporated.
Art consultant Louise Smith, from the Facebook group , is horrified at the closure of "one of the lifebloods of the town". The group is seeking white knights to save it. 
"We're so lucky. Our forebears worked so hard to get this going," Ms Smith said. "And for these people just to close it, because they've suddenly woken up to the fact that they haven't got enough money, is just crazy."
Ms Smith said the gallery should stay open to generate revenue. "I don't know whether they've got any sense. Any business plan," she said. "You work on a plan. You don't just say, 'oopsie daisy, there's no money coming in, [so] we'll close the shop and see what we can do'."
Castlemaine printmaker Catherine Pilgrim said she was "incredibly saddened" at the loss of "an integral part of the local arts community" that had been revitalised since Jennifer Kalionis​ became director. 
The board cited revenue reductions, rising compliance and maintenance costs and "deep-rooted vulnerabilities in financial structures" as reasons for the closure.
It promised to review operations and to develop a blueprint for the future.
Board chair Jan Savage said the gallery could reopen for the Castlemaine State Festival in March 2019.
The board has said the gallery will remain secure and items will be stored to museum standard during the closure. It said there would be staff to monitor the collection.
The board will host an information session for members this Wednesday at 6pm, at Castlemaine Town Hall, to explain the closure. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlemaine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jan Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlemaine Art Museum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlemaine State Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Henson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Piccinini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Kalionis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Streeton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frederick McCubbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Pilgrim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlemaine Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
