<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400292524490725</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/energy/electricity/accc-says-extra-power-generators-would-help-cut-power-prices-20170731-gxm4sv</url>
  <title>ACCC as mythbuster on how Aust's power prices stack up against other countries.</title>
  <content>
Extra power generation from new competitors needs to be injected into the electricity grid to deliver better prices for large electricity users and go some way to stop any "gaming" of prices which has allegedly occurred, the Australian competition regulator said on Monday.
Roger Featherstone, one of the commissioners from the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission, said on Monday that a number of submissions to the ACCC's retail electricity pricing inquiry had claimed that too few power generators was one of the big drags on competition in the sector.
"In our preliminary thinking, we would agree with them," Mr Featherstone said.
He was speaking after a forum in Adelaide for large electricity users to air their grievances and give their opinions in Adelaide, in the latest step of the inquiry which is due to hand down a preliminary report to Federal Treasurer Scott Morrison by late September this year, and a final report by June, 2018.

If more generators were in the market offering power to customers, there would be less chance of "gaming" by particular operators who may be deliberately trying to enhance their profits by using strategic bidding under existing market mechanisms. are in the spotlight over allegations of price gouging and the ACCC will investigate those allegations as part of its inquiry.

Mr Featherstone said the ACCC was also examining power prices in overseas countries in a broad fashion because it wanted to establish once and or all whether claims made about Australia having some of the highest power prices in the world, and South Australian having close to the most expensive electricity in the world, were factual or not.
South Australia, which has been pursuing aggressive renewable energy targets and last month announced a deal with  for the construction of the world's biggest storage battery near Jamestown, has come under fire for an unreliable energy grid from a range of critics.
"It's important to separate the facts from the myths," he said. "Some of these claims do result in a fairly misleading picture.
"Although its early days, we think the truth may lie somewhere between the two," he said, referring to the likelihood that some of those claims may have been exaggerated.

But he said there was no doubt that Australia's competitive position had weakened in the past few years because of rising power costs, making it harder for exporters to compete against rivals from other countries.
The vast land mass in Australia was one of the factors which power generators had to deal with, along with the relatively small population of 24 million. "We have long stretches of wires, lots of poles," Mr Featherstone said. "They are very relevant factors."
The cost of building and maintaining poles and wires made up close to half the cost of power bills.
Mr Featherstone said the ACCC was using its statutory powers to seek extensive documentation from energy retailers about their pricing decisions and profit margins over the past decade. A decision had been made to use the 10-year timeframe because it would give a broad picture, while going further back may present some difficulties for power companies in accessing that documentation.

He said the ACCC had been in discussions with  about his report into Australia's energy sector as part of its own retail inquiry.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Featherstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Featherstone</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
