<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400210920110493</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/will-power-settles-for-second-in-ohio/3207124/</url>
  <title>Will Power settles for second in Ohio</title>
  <content>
Australia's Will Power was forced to settle for second behind American teammate Josef Newgarden at the Indycar race in Lexington, Ohio.
Newgarden overtook early leader Power on the 13th lap and was never headed to claim his third win of the season for Team Penske - and the series lead.
"We didn't have the machine to stay with him today," said Power of starting on pole for the fifth time this year.
"It wasn't my race today. I'm very happy with second."
The 26-year-old Newgarden now leads the drivers' championship on 453 points after 13 of the 17 races, seven points clear of fellow Team Penske driver Helio Castroneves with Power fifth on 401 points.
"We had an awesome race. It's what we needed," Newgarden said. "This was a good day for Team Penske."
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Marilyn Freeman won Toastmasters International Speech district event
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OHIO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Will Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josef Newgarden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helio Castroneves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IndyCar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newgarden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Penske</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lexington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters International Speech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
