<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400163675469405</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/red-tape-closes-darwin-shows-chung-wah-sartee-stand/8760844</url>
  <title>Red tape forces Chung Wah Society's sartee stall to close at Darwin Show</title>
  <content>
In 1965 the Chung Wah Society began selling marinated beef on skewers at the Royal Darwin Show, which over the years became something of an institution.
Some people have said they went to the show just to buy the sartees - thought to be named sartees because of difficulties some Chinese people who sold them had pronouncing satays - which were not available for sale at any other time of the year.
But red tape meant that after more than half a century of tradition, the society, which aims to foster better relationships between Darwin's Chinese community with other groups, had to scrap its annual event.
The death of the Chung Wah sartee stand at this year's show has saddened both show organisers and the president of the society, Austin Chin.
Mr Chin said stricter occupational health and safety rules meant his group would have had to spend more than $500 to get more professional cookware if they wanted to have their stall this year - too much for a community group.
"We have never had an incident, or anyone die from it," he said.
"It is getting all too expensive to do what we do now.
"We used to cook the sartees on half a 44-gallon drum and use skewers made from a bit of old wire," he said, recalling the early days when the stand started.
Although over the years the equipment was upgraded, it still fell short of the current regulations.
'We have to comply,' says show boss

The recipe the sartees used has remained a secret, but Mr Chin said the skewers were put together by a team of volunteers ahead of the show, in what was a community event in its own right.
"That is the side that everyone liked. The profit wasn't the motive," he said.
Show chief executive Cherry Court said she was also sad to see the sartee stand go, but the rules could not be bent.
"At the end of the day we can't change environmental health rules, and we have to comply," she said.
On social media people have lamented the end of the sartee stand.
"No reason to go if I can't get my Chung Wah Society sartee," Shane Stringer wrote on the ABC Darwin Facebook page.
"I searched and searched and searched and had a truly horrible lunch as the much anticipated sartee was not available ... please can we have it back by popular demand next year???" said Belinda Davis on the Chung Wah Society's Facebook page.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Stringer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin's Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austin Chin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chung Wah Society</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Darwin Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chung Wah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chung Wah Society's Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Darwin Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherry Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
