<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651398918134936391</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>02:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/technology/seek-exec-simon-rosenberg-poached-by-nz-whizzkids-startup-crimson-20170727-gxjwjr</url>
  <title>SEEK exec Simon Rosenberg poached by NZ whizz-kids' start-up Crimson</title>
  <content>
New Zealand education mentoring technology start-up Crimson has poached long-time SEEK executive Simon Rosenberg, as the company's young founders look to push ahead with rapid international expansion plans.
Mr Rosenberg has been with the online recruitment firm for 17 years and most recently led its Chinese operations. He was a board member of Zhaopin, which is currently being taken private by a consortium of SEEK, Hillhouse Capital Management and FountainVest Partners.
Despite his relative seniority, Mr Rosenberg told The Australian Financial Review he was not concerned about joining a company where his bosses - founders Jamie Beaton and Sharndre Kushor - are still in their early 20s.
"I thought a lot about that, but it was actually an important driver and positive factor for me. I thought the combination of their youth, passion and achievements, combined with my experience, would make for a unique position to be in," Mr Rosenberg said.

"While clearly there is an age gap, I don't see that as a barrier and Crimson is a company that values diversity. I think I will complement their skills with the experiences they haven't necessarily had."

Both are high achievers, with Mr Beaton starting to build the company while completing an undergraduate and master's degree at Harvard in only three years (the undergraduate program alone usually takes four.)
In high school, rather than take three or four British A-level subjects, which is normal, Mr Beaton finished 10, and came top of the world in A2 English Literature. Finishing with a perfect score, he was accepted into every university he applied for including Cambridge, Yale, Princeton, Stanford and Columbia.
Matching students with mentors

This inspired him to start Crimson, which is an online platform that uses carefully developed algorithms to match students to mentors who coach them and help them decide which university courses to apply for and what they need to do to get in.

Last year the business  from New York-based private equity giant Tiger Global and Tiger Global Management, valuing the company at over $205 million.
The business now has offices in 12 cities around the world including Auckland, Melbourne, Moscow, Shanghai, Nanjing, Bangkok and London, with plans to expand operations into 10 more cities in the next three months.
Mr Rosenberg said he had been looking for a "special" company to join for a new challenge, having already seen SEEK through its fast-growth years.
"My most enjoyable time at SEEK was when we were in hyper growth mode and disrupting the industry. That exists very much at Crimson and it's making an impact on students' lives," he said.

"The broad themes I will be focused on are across people, process and operations and how we take the product to market. It will be dynamic as we evolve and because of my broad commercial experience at SEEK I feel comfortable navigating through that."
Team's 'smooth' growth

In the past 12 months Crimson has grown its team from 30 to 140 people, a process Mr Beaton describes as "fairly smooth", as many of the hires have come on the back of recommendations from the company's team of mentors.
The business is adequately capitalised from its last funding round and Mr Beaton said the start-up's current focuses were on entering new markets, especially in Europe and China, and further developing its matching algorithms.

"In high school you have a teacher or a few teachers that you think back to and remember who were pivotal in your pathway. What I'm focused on at Crimson is to ensure that every match is like that," he said.
The company has been working with Galen Buckwalter, who was responsible for dating website eHarmony's matching algorithm and in the past year has developed four psychometric tests that are now used in the matching process.
"Our goal is to help any student anywhere find the best possible career and university for them."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Beaton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEEK I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillhouse Capital Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanjing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhaopin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crimson</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Columbia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiger Global Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eHarmony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FountainVest Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiger Global</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangkok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Literature</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rosenberg</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Rosenberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharndre Kushor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British A-level</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galen Buckwalter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beaton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princeton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
