<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400245279849441</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4824011/stingrays-peaking-at-the-right-time/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Stingrays 'peaking' at the right time</title>
  <content>
Erica Halloway. Picture: Sylvia Liber

Illawarra coach Brett Wallin believes his side have hit top gear after the Stingrays made it five straight victories in the NSW NPL Women's 1 over the weekend.
The Stingrays were at their dominant best as they beat North West Sydney Koalas 3-1 at ELS Hall Park to maintain their winning run. The strong performance couldn't have come at a better time, with just one match remaining before finals football takes centre stage.
"I really do think we are peaking," Wallin said.
"We have consistently worked hard over the course of the season and I think it has happened on the back of that effort.
"We haven't had a bad game in the last month or so."

Making matters even better for the Stingrays is the return of Matildas striker Michelle Heyman from injury.
She played her first game of the season in their win over Koalas, in a match that Illawarra always held the upper hand in. 
Two goals midway through the first half from Erica Halloway had Illawarra well and truly on their way to another three points.
When Michelle Carney dispatched a penalty, Illawarra would move 3-0 up. 
Natalie Tobin pulled a goal back for the hosts in the shadows of half time, but the damage was already done by that stage. 

"Ultimately we were always in control," Wallin said.
"We shifted well in midfield and had great movement. 
"When we scored those goals, it was nothing less than we deserved.To go away and get that result at Koalas is massive for us."
Illawarra can still win the regular season title on the final day of the season if they win and Macarthur and Manly United lose.

Illawarra host North Shore Mariners at JJ Kelly Park to round out their campaign. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW NPL Women's 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Shore Mariners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Carney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Heyman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Tobin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Wallin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Liber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ELS Hall Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JJ Kelly Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erica Halloway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MacArthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
