<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400163675469401</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65444/2018-mercedes-benz-e-class-cabriolet-price-and-features-for-australia</url>
  <title>2018 Mercedes-Benz E-Class Cabriolet - Price And Features For Australia</title>
  <content>
Mercedes-Benz has revealed Australian details for the final variant to join its E-Class range confirming the price and specifications of the E-Class Cabriolet.
The two-model E-Class Cabriolet range will arrive just in time for the Southern Hemisphere summer, due to land in showrooms this October.

Buyers will have a choice of the E300 powered by a 180kW/370Nm 2.0-litre four-cylinder turbocharged petrol engine driving the rear wheels via an nine-speed automatic transmission, or the more powerful E400 with 245kW and 480Nm and the added surety of all wheel drive - a first for the E-Class Cabriolet.
Styling for the new E-Class cabriolet follows the cues established by both the smaller C-Class and larger S-Class convertibles, complementing the most up-to-date Mercedes drop-top range in years.

Compared with its predecessor the new E-Class Cabriolet features a longer wheelbase for added rear seat space, with a redesigned acoustic soft top that can be opened and closed in 20 seconds at speeds of up to 50 km/h.
Standard kit equipment for both models includes twin 12.3-inch digital displays, air suspension, leather seat trim with heated front seats and Airscarf neck-level heating, LED headlights, 20-inch AMG alloy wheels, and AMG exterior styling.

The E400 adds standard metallic paint, head-up display, and a 13-speaker premium Burmester audio system
Pricing

E300 $123,500
E400 $157,500
Manufacturer's list price excluding on-road costs. Overseas model shown.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C-Class</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S-Class</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E400 $157,500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E-Class</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E300 $123,500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Hemisphere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E-Class Cabriolet</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burmester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz E-Class Cabriolet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Features For Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E400</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airscarf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
