<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400202330175740</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-07-31/gm-canola-planted-south-australia/8760744</url>
  <title>Genetically modified crop unknowingly planted by SA farmer</title>
  <content>
A canola grower in South Australia's mid-north has accidentally planted genetically modified (GM) canola in contravention of a statewide ban.
South Australia is the only mainland state to ban GM crops, and fines of up to $200,000 can apply to anyone who breaks the law.
On Monday the Government confirmed a farmer had accidentally planted GM canola seed, bred to be resistant to the chemical Roundup, or glyphosate.
The farmer became aware of the outbreak when some canola plants did not die after they were sprayed with glyphosate.
"A number of self-grow, or volunteer canola plants, survived a spray of glyphosate while others had died," Biosecurity South Australia executive director Will Zacharin said.
"We will continue to monitor that site, and it is also being monitored by the agronomist of the seed company.
"The farmer agreed to spray the crop with an alternative herbicide to control the volunteer plants."
GM seeds mixed up in batch

Biosecurity South Australia said only a small number of GM plants had been detected, and the crop in the affected paddock had now been completely destroyed.

Rural Newsletter

Rural news in your inbox?

for the national headlines of the day.

Mr Zacharin said it was not uncommon for small amounts of GM seeds to get caught up in batches of seed sent to farmers in South Australia.
"We do see these year on year, and we do assist those people who may have problems," he said.
"It comes down to seed quality. These companies provide seed all over Australia, and of course we make sure they've got appropriate sampling regimes in place and quality assurance in place."
Mr Zacharin said the farmer would not be held responsible, but the seed company had been warned to be more careful.
"While we believe that no offence was created against the act in this instance, the seed company has been advised of the potential implications of South Australia's market and trade advantages gained by our policy prohibiting the cultivation of commercial GM food crops," he said.
South Australia strictly bans the growing of GM crops, arguing the state's farmers get paid more for their crop because of the GM-free status.

South Australia is the only mainland Australian state to ban the growing of genetically modified crops.

South Australia is the only mainland Australian state to ban the growing of genetically modified crops.

Landline: Marty McCarthy

SA remains GM-free after incident

South Australian Premier Jay Weatherill has previously said allowing grain growers to plant GM canola would ruin the state's ability to call itself GM-free.
"If they take that option they destroy the opportunity for everyone else, because one exception completely destroys our capacity to represent ourselves as GM-free because it travels beyond the boundaries of farms," he said.
However, the outbreak is not expected to change the state's GM-free status because only a small number of genetically modified crops were planted.
"South Australia's GM-free status is an important part of the state's reputation for producing premium food and wine," a Primary Industries and Regions South Australia spokesman said.

"The State Government works closely with the local grains industry to protect the GM-free status and preserve our reputation for producing clean grain."

Opposition agriculture spokesman David Ridgway said he was disappointed the Government had only revealed the outbreak when forced to in Parliament.
"Clearly it is not something Biosecurity SA or the Government talk about publicly, and so it was only through budget estimates we could tease out that this has happened," he said.
"It's a concern."
Farmer frustrated with GM ban

Some  are calling on the State Government to legalise GM crops, arguing the ban is preventing the growth of their industry.
Wayne Hawkins owns a sheep property in South Australia and a grain property across the border in Victoria.
He said he wanted access to genetically modified canola so he could grow it on his South Australian farm.

"That's the thing that makes us mad here, because we can grow them in Victoria but if we grow the same varieties in South Australia we would just about go to jail for it," Mr Hawkins said.

"We are on the wrong side of the border, so we're worried that we're going to be left standing still.
"It's disappointing really. We're all part of one state. We contribute to the revenue."
Mr Hawkins said many consumers were opposed to genetically modified technology without realising it was already in their diets or daily use.
"Ninety-something per cent of cotton grown is genetically modified, cotton shirts," he said.
"A lot of the oil that cooks the chips [in fast food restaurants] is cotton oil, [even] diabetic insulin," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GM</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Zacharin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biosecurity SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marty McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hawkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia's GM-free</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regions South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Ridgway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biosecurity South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Premier Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GM-free</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Zacharin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primary Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
