<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400167970436789</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/fulwoods-spinning-bullets-in-pursuit-of-finals-ber/3207113/</url>
  <title>Fulwood's Spinning Bullets in pursuit of finals berth</title>
  <content>
WHEELCHAIR BASKETBALL: Jake Fulwood's Queensland Spinning Bullets are shaping up for a final-round clash with Adelaide Thunderbirds in the National Wheelchair Basketball League.
The team's fourth after 15 games and with only four teams making play-offs, it looms as a crucial clash in South Australia on Saturday.
Fulwood, 22, has played 12 matches for the team during a stellar season, averaging more than eight points per outing.
The Mooloolah Valley prospect played a key role for the Australian team at the under-23 world championships in Canada in June, when the team captured bronze.
He was player-of-the-match in an overtime win over Italy during that tournament.
Also a member of the Suncoast Spinners Wheelchair Basketball team (University of the Sunshine Coast), the Matthew Flinders Anglican product has spina bifida.
He's had more than 15 major operations but they've hardly dented his determination.
A regular on the representative scene, since he started playing basketball at 10 years of age, Fulwood's been invited to train with the Australian men's team the Rollers.
He's also a university student.
Steven Elliott was also part of the national team which fared well at Toronto and as a result he was recently named Gympie's latest Sunshine Coast Sports Federation development winner for June.
"The talent of some of the guys over there was crazy," he said.
"The way they were moving the chair was unbelievable."
He said the world titles experience had fuelled his Paralympic dream.
"It definitely inspired me," he said.
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
Celebration after Coast gym snapped up in last minute sale
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fulwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paralympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Flinders Anglican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fulwood, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Thunderbirds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Wheelchair Basketball League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Sports Federation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fulwood's Spinning Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncoast Spinners Wheelchair Basketball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolah Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Fulwood's Queensland Spinning Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
