<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400202330175737</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4824291/peoplecare-recognised-nationally-as-an-employer-of-choice/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Peoplecare has been recognised as one of the best employers in Australia and New Zealand</title>
  <content>
Best of the best: Peoplecare chief executive Michael Bassingthwaighte and head of people and culture Maree Morgan-Monk. Picture by Greg Ellis.

Peoplecare credentials as an employer of choice is being boosted this week with news the Illawarra based not-for-profit health fund has been ranked as one of 16 leading Australian and New Zealand organisations on the Aon Best Employer list for 2017.

Peoplecare is listed alongside big companies such as Nova Entertainment and SEEK Limited.
The Best Employers program is run annually by Aon Hewitt to recognise the elite group of organisations that record high employee engagement scores and deliver outstanding people practice.

Organisations are assessed as part of a study that measures employee engagement, effective leadership, aligned employer brand and high-performance culture.

Peoplecare is the only health insurance provider to ever be listed in the Aon Best Employer list.

The achievement is seen as a confirmation of he success of its unique approach and commitment to engaging and motivating employees, guided by the philosophy 'personal is best'.
The survey results see Peoplecare sitting above both the benchmark of Australia and New Zealand insurance companies and at the top of all organisations surveyed in the top quartile.

Peoplecare also exceeds the top quartile in work/life balance, effective leadership, a high-performance culture and safety.
Chief executive Michael Bassingthwaighte said the national recognition demonstrates the commitment that all employees have to Peoplecare.

"The culture within Peoplecare is what sets us apart," he said.

"A positive, inclusive culture that strives for continuous improvement, exceptional customer service and positive workplace relations is a clear driver of outstanding performance. From the initial recruitment and induction phase to ongoing learning and development, mixed with a fun and engaging work environment, plus spontaneous recognition of work well done, the employees at Peoplecare are genuinely our most precious asset and the positive culture is emphasised and encouraged every working day".

Head of people and culture Maree Morgan-Monk said Peoplecare's appearance on the list of best employers in Australia and New Zealand validated the health fund as an employer of choice. And that helped it continue to attract the best people to the organisation.
"Being recognised as an Aon Best Employer is great recognition for our leaders and confirms for our chief executive and board that the strong commitment to our Peoplecarers is the right organisational focus. We are glad that our wonderful Peoplecarers appreciate their work environment, the opportunities given to them and the teams they work with," she said.
"This recognition also provides our members with confidence that Peoplecare is an organisation that invests in the people that are servicing and helping our members often during difficult times in their life. We have a high-performance culture and that is undoubtedly reflected in the way we help our members, deliver exceptional customer service and be a secure, financially healthy organisation".

Related story:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bassingthwaighte</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aon Hewitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nova Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEEK Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aon Best Employer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peoplecare</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>18</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Employer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peoplecarers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maree Morgan-Monk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
