<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400240984882122</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/more-brisbane-bus-strikes-set-for-this-week/news-story/bd21c45f1d59849bc2c17af1ced784e5</url>
  <title>More bus strikes on the cards</title>
  <content>
MORE Brisbane bus strikes have been planned for this week as the union feud with council continues to escalate into rolling industrial action.
Bus drivers plan to strike from 10am to 2pm on Wednesday this week as part of the protected industrial after enterprise bargaining agreement negotiations with council reached a stalemate.
A council spokesman said services were expected to return to normal after 2.45pm but "no major impacts" were anticipated across the network.
The low-impact industrial action follows a major peak-hour strike across all seven depots on Friday last week after tensions with council came to a head.
The RTBU have been demanding a 3.5 per cent pay rise and input into the rostering system to help better manage driver fatigue.
But council has maintained its offer of a 2.5 per cent pay rise to all employees, while refusing to cede any control of the rosters to the union, citing fears it would turn into a similar fiasco that consumed Queensland Rail.
The union has also asked for greater security on buses after ongoing assaults, which culminated in the death of driver Manmeet Alisher last year.
After refusing to meet the demands, council recently offered an olive branch on security measures but the union have asked for it to be written into the enterprise agreement.
The RTBU have been contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manmeet Alisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Rail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
