<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651399605329712469</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/14/42/keep-out-of-the-headlines-sainsbury-warned</url>
  <title>Keep out of the headlines, Sainsbury warned</title>
  <content>
"Keep quiet, learn Spanish and stay out of the headlines."

That's the advice Australian author and expert on the South American drug trade Rusty Young has for mule Cassie Sainsbury.

"Cocaine Cassie" as she has been dubbed in the media, looks set to spend years in a Colombian jail even if a plea deal her lawyers have agreed to with prosecutors goes ahead.

The plea deal hit a hitch in a Bogota court last week when Sainsbury admitted to attempting to traffic almost 6kg of cocaine, but told the judge she only did so because a man threatened to kill her family and fiance.

Having the judge accept the plea deal which would see her sentenced to six years' jail appears to be the best case scenario for the 22-year-old former personal trainer and sex worker from Adelaide.

Young, who wrote the bestselling book Marching Powder and today released a new book Colombiano after living in Colombia for seven years, told nine.com.au that
Sainsbury would not win any favours from Colombian authorities by speaking out about her troubles.

"Certainly trying to claim that she was set up by Colombians or to be playing guilty in court but innocent in the media is not a strategy that's going to work," he said.

On the flip side there was the possibility that Sainsbury could have her sentence reduced by as much as 25 percent if she kept her head down and behaved while serving time in the El Buen Pastor Prison women's prison.

That meant avoiding journalists, and also trying to keep her family out of the media too, Young said.

"Colombians hate international headlines in which their country is associated with cocaine," he said.

"Every time Cassandra Sainsbury or a member of her family or even her lawyer speak to the press, that just reinvigorates the news cycle."

Studying while in prison was also looked upon favourably, and Sainsbury would do well to learn Spanish as not knowing the language would be a big stumbling block for her in prison anyway, Young said.

Young said several things pointed to Sainsbury being caught up in an Australian or UK based drug smuggling operation, rather than a Colombian one, so naming her dealers as part of a plea deal shouldn't put her in danger of reprisals in prison.

"It was such an unsophisticated means of concealment and she was actually up on the Colombian police radar before she even picked up the drugs. So that says to me that there was a network behind her back in Australia or the UK," he said.

"It says to my mind that there was no Colombian cartel behind this operation. And that means her telling the truth about who was behind the operation is not going to put her in any danger in the Colombian prison."

While she was unlikely to be in physical danger, Young said Sainsbury would no doubt have to deal with prison guards and fellow inmates trying to take advantage of her status as a "wealthy foreigner".

"There is an assumption that every westerner is wealthy and that means guards and other prisoners might be looking to chisel some money out of her but they won't be doing it in a violent manner. It will be just making friends and then asking for money or asking for a loan," he said.

It's a scenario familiar to Young, who spent three months voluntarily living in a Bolivian jail in order to tell the story of UK drug smuggler Thomas McFadden in Marching Powder.

Young then went on to spend four years working for the US government in Colombia as part of an anti-kidnapping squad, a dangerous role which he was forced to keep secret from his closest friends and family.

Young's novel Colombiano is told from the point of view of a child soldier and is based on his interviews with child soldiers and research into Colombia's terrorist organisations.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rusty Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassie Sainsbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marching Powder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombiano</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sainsbury</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>El Buen Pastor Prison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolivian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bogota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassandra Sainsbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas McFadden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombian</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
