<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400292524490745</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-07-31/deledio-a-chance-to-make-giants-debut-against-dees</url>
  <title>Deledio 'a chance' to make Giant debut against Dees</title>
  <content>
Brett Deledio is a chance to make his debut this week

GREATER Western Sydney is yet to make a call on whether they'll pick Brett Deledio for his first senior game for the Giants when they take on Melbourne in Canberra this week.

Deledio has been battling persistent calf problems since February, but has now made two appearances in the NEAFL without any setbacks and is a huge chance to face the Demons on Saturday.

The 30-year-old gathered 25 possessions in the Giants' 31-point loss to Gold Coast on Saturday and pulled up well from his second game in a row, after playing the second half against Sydney University the previous week.

GWS head of football Wayne Campbell told AFL.com.au on Monday that Deledio has done everything asked of him in recent weeks, but no decision has been made in regards to team selection for round 20.

"He played about three quarters then came off in the last, but that was because he'd covered the amount of kilometres we wanted him to do," Campbell said.

"He played in the midfield for the first half and then went to half-back in the third quarter, whereas last week he spent most of his time across half back.

"He hasn't been selected as of yet, we'll know more after training on Wednesday but he'll be a chance."

If he does board the plane for the nation's capital later in the week, Deledio will bring a wealth of experience and outstanding foot skills to coach Leon Cameron's team.

With star forward Jeremy Cameron already ruled out with a hamstring strain, club champion Toby Greene suspended, and Steve Johnson (knee) and Shane Mumford (ankle) battling their own injuries, the inclusion of the 243-game veteran would be a welcome boost for such an important game against the Demons. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
