<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400288229523199</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/16/40/jesse-bromwich-kevin-proctor-cocaine</url>
  <title>NRL fan cut lines of cocaine on his phone for idols Kevin Proctor and Jesse Bromwich</title>
  <content>
A man who supplied drugs to two NRL players hours after they'd played an international match has narrowly avoided jail.
Adrian Crowther had hoped to impress Kiwi stars Jesse Bromwich and Kevin Proctor when he spotted them enjoying a night out in Canberra.
But the 45-year-old was captured on CCTV preparing lines of cocaine for them on his mobile outside Cube nightclub
He avoided jail today but was slapped him with a 12-month good behaviour bond.
It was about 5am on Saturday in early May after New Zealand had lost 30-12 to Australia in the ANZAC Test when the incident occurred.
The NRL stars, who both lost their spots in the Kiwi's rugby world squad, claimed they were too drunk to recall what happened.
Today the court Crowther too had lost his job - and since struggled to find employment.

Related Articles

He had apparently bought the cocaine in the nightclub's toilet before speaking to the players.
But Magistrate Bernadette Boss said deterrence was an important factor in sentencing.
He told Crowther: 'Somebody of your maturity should not be encouraging younger men into this sort of behaviour despite them being your sporting idols."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Bernadette Boss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crowther</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Bromwich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Crowther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Proctor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
