<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400326884229665</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/grenfell-tower-prompts-early-revision-of-building-code-to-test-fire-compliance-20170731-gxmdu1</url>
  <title>Building code updated for fire compliance</title>
  <content>
London's Grenfell Tower tragedy has prompted building ministers to update the National Construction Code's fire testing requirements a year earlier than planned.
The Australian Building Codes Board, the governmental agency that oversees the building code that governs construction standards, on Monday said it would amend the code  before its next scheduled 2019 revision to incorporate a new standard for testing the spread of fire within buildings. The AS5113 standard was written following Melbourne's 2014 Lacrosse residential tower fire. 
The early amendment of the code - which is supposed to happen only every three years - comes after the building ministers, at their last meeting in June, promised to expedite processes to prevent the use of non-compliant cladding on Australian buildings. 
The amendment, due to be adopted in March next year, will require suppliers of materials to make sure they comply with the improved standard. However, it does nothing to test whether the supplied materials perform to the standard and will not resolve . 

"Certain products should be independently tested," said Kristin Brookfield, the Housing Industry Association's chief executive for industry policy.

"That's the same today, as after this amendment. What this means doing better is explaining the types of test and types of evidence and bringing in this new test method."
Last week, NSW Minister for Better Regulation Matt Kean said new legislation would be introduced to prohibit the sale and use of unsafe building products.
Many in the industry want independent testing of imported building materials. Last month Kyle Jeavons, the development director of Perth-based Fini Group, said such a testing regime for glass, cladding and structural steel would take away uncertainty around those products.
"I'm sure that the parties that are creating the products know if they have to undertake a certain quality assurance process and that they can get tested continuously and thoroughly by an independent national body, that will ensure the products meet the standard required," Mr Jeavons said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Construction Code</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Industry Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Jeavons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristin Brookfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Jeavons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Better Regulation Matt Kean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Grenfell Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's 2014 Lacrosse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Building Codes Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth-based Fini Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
