<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400013351611641</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>06:35</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/07/heres-how-the-insane-car-stunts-ofatomic-blondewere-pulled-off/</url>
  <title>Here's How The Insane Car Stunts Of Atomic Blonde Were Pulled Off</title>
  <content>
If you didn't get enough of Charlize Theron kicking arse in Mad Max: Fury Road or Fate of the Furious, she's back in theatres this weekend as a badass Cold War spy driving awesome cars and kicking more arse in Atomic Blonde. Here's how the movie pulled off some of its unbelievable car stunts.

If you were a fan of John Wick, but thought that maybe you'd like to see a similar movie with Charlize Theron as an MI6 agent set in the 1980's, you're in luck with Atomic Blonde.

Director David Leitch, who is best known for his stunt coordinating and director work on the John Wick movies, returns here, and sat with Yahoo! Movies to break down the intense getaway scene in the movie:

So we're dealing with Charlize Theron racing around in Soviet-era cars, looking beat to hell and causing all kinds of carnage in a movie utilising practical stunts while "I Ran" by A Flock of Seagulls plays, and it looks pretty spectacular.

If you haven't caught wind of Atomic Blonde's trailer yet, you can  otherwise you could just go see the movie which is in theatres now.

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flock of Seagulls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yahoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fate of the Furious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blonde Were Pulled Off</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cold War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atomic Blonde</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Leitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soviet-era</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MI6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Wick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insane Car Stunts Of Atomic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
