<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400159380501989</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/real-story-of-ice-deaths-isnt-found-in-headlines/8759918</url>
  <title>The real story of how ice is killing Australians isn't found in scary headlines</title>
  <content>
In the past few years, we have been going ice mad, and this is particularly visible in media reporting.
With headlines such as  in the Daily Telegraph, and  in The Age, or a description of the importation of methamphetamine from China as a "" making its way here on a "wave of death boats", you'd be forgiven for thinking we're living in an episode of The Walking Dead.
We now need to ask ourselves - are we being entertained by other's suffering? Are we doing anything about the apparent ice crisis? Where does the truth lie?
Devil is in the detail

The National Drug and Alcohol Research Centre has  that found ice deaths have doubled since 2009. It found 1,649 "closed cases", or cases that have been examined by the coroner and found to have involved methamphetamine.
At first glimpse, it's something to be scared about. Like most things however, the devil is in the detail.
When we think of deaths involving ice, the images that may come to mind are the crazed ice user embarking on a drug-fuelled rampage, with innocent members of the community ending up as collateral damage. However, NDARC's report focused solely on the deaths of those actively using ice, not the average community member.
It found that the majority of deaths were a result of accidental overdose, which can result from consuming an excessive amount of the drug or a dose of extreme purity.
But this isn't the whole story.
Ice is a stimulant, and frequent use of stimulants severely stresses the heart. It is no surprise, then, that NDARC has reported cardiovascular disease to be involved in a fifth of the ice-related deaths it analysed.
Polydrug use - the use of several drugs at once - is another factor you won't necessarily read about in the media. The report found that in more than 80 per cent of ice-related deaths, toxicology reports found other substances aside from ice in the deceased's blood. These mainly included opioids and sedatives, but also psychiatric medications such as antidepressants.
Tough on crime doesn't work

So what can we draw from the NDARC report? Yes, ice deaths have doubled in a seven-year period, and this is definitely a cause for concern. However, the circumstances are often far from what is depicted in the media.
Public attention and concern is often focused on ice and violence, and death resulting from that, however you won't find much media interest in cases of natural disease and multiple drug toxicity.
The report also emphasised that in a majority of cases, those that had died lived outside major cities and most were not in treatment.
Perhaps we need to be focusing more on that, rather than a "tough on crime" approach.
Speaking of crime, what impact has ice had on rates of violent crime? A big one, according to the media. However, the Bureau of Crime Statistics and Research reports a recent downward trend in crimes such as robbery - down by 63 per cent since 2000 - which wasn't the case during the heroin crisis of the 1990s, arguably the last time we were this concerned about an illicit drug.
Further, the media tends to associate ice with other, scarier crimes such as assault and homicide, however ABS statistics show a decline in rates of physical assault between 2008 and 2015. Similarly, between 2000 and 2014 homicide rates have declined, from 1.6 per 100,000 of the population to just 1.
Matt Noffs is chief executive of the Ted Noffs Foundation and co-founder of Street Universities. Shelley Smith works in policy and research for the Ted Noffs Foundation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Noffs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Crime</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted Noffs Foundation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NDARC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walking Dead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Universities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alcohol Research Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Drug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelley Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
