<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400245279849492</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/more-bus-strikes-planned-for-wednesday-20170731-gxmf77.html</url>
  <title>More bus strikes planned for Wednesday</title>
  <content>
Brisbane's bus services will be reduced for four hours on Wednesday as the Rail, Tram and Bus union enter another week of strike action.
On Monday, the RTBU advised Brisbane City Council some drivers would be participating in industrial action from 10am to 2pm on Wednesday.
This follows most union-member drivers offering  last week before Photo: Ruth McCosker
The week earlier drivers on Tuesday and Wednesday.
It is understood this week's strike action is part of the union's ongoing fight for safer buses, a wage increase and rostering changes.

The RTBU met with the council for more than seven hours on Thursday evening, again Friday morning and have a meeting scheduled for Tuesday - but an agreement to stop the strike action is yet to be met. 

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Comment has been sought from the RTBU.
In a statement issued Monday afternoon, the council said major impacts to bus services across the network were expected until about 2.45pm as services returned to normal.
"Commuters who normally travel during these times are advised to plan ahead and make alternative arrangements," it said.
During Friday's strike there were long queues of resident's waiting for buses while the electronic timetables and Translink app showed a majority of services as "cancelled".
Commuters are urged to check the Translink app, or contact 13 12 30 for information on Wednesday afternoon. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TransLink</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth McCosker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
