<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400198035208428</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/retired-stars-nick-riewoldt-luke-hodge-to-kick-along-into-media-roles-20170731-gxm7nr.html</url>
  <title>Retired stars Nick Riewoldt, Luke Hodge to kick along into media roles</title>
  <content>
The football media landscape is set to become even more congested next season as a bevy of the game's stars appear set to move into commentary roles.
Nick Riewoldt, who announced on Monday he would retire at season's end, and Luke Hodge, having already confirmed this would be his final year, are set to enjoy greater media profiles.

Up Next

Nick Riewoldt announces retirement

01:42

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

They have been an intermittent part of Channel Seven's football coverage in recent years but have been restricted because of their club commitments.
Seven had already sounded out Riewoldt about having a greater role even before his retirement was confirmed. The network has retired greats Cameron Ling, Wayne Carey and Matthew Richardson as expert commentators in the prime Friday-night slot, with Ling and Richardson backing up on a Saturday night.Photo: Will Russell/AFL Media
Hodge, a four-time premiership player, including three in a row as skipper, could be used as a way to freshen the coverage. He has also been involved with Triple M's radio commentary and is also a sought-after talent in this field.
Riewoldt, who fell short of a premiership but is second only to Robert Harvey for most games with the Saints, is also expected to be a coveted radio voice.

The champion forward said on Monday his focus was on finishing the season strongly, with the Saints an outside chance to make the finals.
"In the immediate future, I have got four games of footy and, hopefully, finals to play," he said.
"I will prepare the last part of the season as I always have - with a view to playing finals and contribute really strongly.
"In the short-term, I have a good bottle of red to drink. I have a family to take care of but I haven't had any time to look further than that. As I mentioned, I am excited about the opportunities."
Riewoldt's teammate Leigh Montagna is also facing retirement, and has been honing his calling on Triple M into interstate markets.
Western Bulldogs captain Robert Murphy has a weekly slot on SEN radio and could also retire this year. He is seen as a more quirky figure listeners would embrace. His knowledge of the game is also impeccable.
Former St Kilda and North Melbourne star Nick Dal Santo has made an impressive start in his media career this year with his insights on SEN and Fox Footy.
Dual Brownlow medallist Chris Judd has taken on a greater media role this year on Triple M and through his weekly columns with Fairfax Media.
Many of the game's high-profile commentators signed new contracts heading into this season, aligning these with the AFL's new broadcast rights agreement. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Montagna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday-night</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Judd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Ling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Dal Santo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell/AFL Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Hodge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
