<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400417078544586</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/wa-behind-other-states-in-canine-sterilisation/news-story/1167bb24f0e74aa429819b08a8c5783d</url>
  <title>Call for dog owners to sterilise pets</title>
  <content>
WA has the worst rate of dog sterilisation in Australia, according to a national pet ownership survey.
More than a third of WA dog owners (37 per cent) have not had their canine companions desexed, a result that has prompted the McGowan Government to reaffirm its promise to introduce compulsory dog sterilisation.
Last year Premier Mark McGowan vowed to force people to sterilise their dogs, unless an appropriate exemption was requested, if Labor won the election, as part of a planned crackdown to stop "puppy farming" and illegal over-breeding.
"Over-breeding results in hundreds of dogs being surrendered to pounds, shelters or roaming the streets," Local Government Minister David Templeman has said.
Mr Templeman expected an implementation working group of relevant stake-holders would be established in coming months to help realise the policy.
In contrast, WA has the best cat sterilisation rate in the country at 93 per cent, after the Liberal government made it compulsory in 2013.
The Animal Medicines Australia survey, which was conducted by the group representing the nation's animal health industry and canvassed more than 2000 people, also confirmed WA is officially a dog State, with more people owning dogs (33 per cent) than cats (28 per cent), birds (10 per cent), fish (9 per cent), and other pets (8 per cent).
Australians spent $12.2 billion on their animals last year, a huge jump of 42 per cent since the last survey in 2013.
"Our research shows that costs are not rising, pet owners are just spending more to keep their pets happy and healthy," Animal Medicines Australia executive director Ben Stapley said.
WA is not the biggest animal-loving State, with the survey showing we have the lowest rate of pet ownership in Australia. Roughly 494,000 households, or 57 per cent, have a pet compared with 62 per cent nationally.
The biggest barriers to pet ownership in WA were said to be an unsuitable lifestyle, strata rules banning animals and the costs associated with looking after furry friends.
Mr Stapley called for WA's current review of strata laws to relax the rules surrounding pets appropriate for units and apartments, like cats, as having pets had proven health benefits and provided valuable companionship.
The Smillie family of Karrinyup got their "gentle giant" Prince from the Dogs Refuge Home in Shenton Park late last year.
Mother-of-three Philomena Smillie said she and husband David decided to wait until their kids were a bit older to get their first family pet.
Ms Smillie said it was wonderful seeing Prince bond with her children and having a pet had taught her kids to be more confident and responsible.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philomena Smillie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Templeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shenton Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Stapley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGowan Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Minister David Templeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karrinyup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dogs Refuge Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Animal Medicines Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smillie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stapley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smillie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
