<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400502977891956</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/red-for-danger-but-it-should-be-green-20170731-gxmh16.html</url>
  <title>Red for Danger, but it should be green</title>
  <content>
Paddy Dangerfield has been punished because of the AFL's mission to organise chaos retrospectively. There is a difference between minimising accidents, which is laudable, and denying that they happen, which is laughable. In a contact sport, it is an important difference.
That is not to say that Dangerfield did not know what he was doing. Rather, it is to say that he knew exactly what he was doing. He pinned Matthew Kreuzer's arms, as per the textbook. Then, following a more recent dictum, he tried to pull Kreuzer to one side, so as not to fall into his back. He found, as you might expect, that at 101kg, Kreuzer was not easily pulled to aside.

Up Next

Nick Riewoldt announces retirement

01:42

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

But it was not as if there were two conscious actions, the tackle and the effort to take Kreuzer down. It was one action, not the notorious sling tackle. Dangerfield's mistake, if any, was to try to be too correct in his tackling technique.
Under the AFL's guidelines, Kreuzer was deemed to be "vulnerable". So he was, as events proved. Under the AFL's rules, that put the onus on Dangerfield to protect him. This is a reach. The episode lasted perhaps a second. To a hyper-alert AFL player, a second is quite a long time, long enough for Gary Ablett, say, to pick the best of three options, other players two.Photo: Michael Willson/AFL Media
But to see out of the corner of your eye is one thing, to be blindsided is another. Kreuzer did dispose of the ball, but Dangerfield, obscured by Kreuzer's bulk, could hardly have known this, and in case had already laid the tackle that would take them both to the ground. The course was set. It is expecting too much even of Dangerfield's footy instincts to say that he should have sensed the impending accident and released the tackle.
Protecting the head has become an AFL article of faith, reasonably. It means any action that causes a knock to the head is statutarily deemed as high contact. It is why, somewhat obtusely, Dangerfield was assessed to have taken Kreuzer high, though his arms were clamped around the Carlton ruckman's waist. Dangerfield of all people would know this: while playing for Adelaide in 2011, Melbourne's Jack Trengove pinned him, slung him to the ground, knocking him out. Trengove got three matches.Photo: AAP/Julian Smith
But protecting the head does not mean that an automatic penalty for every case of concussion. Cause and effect on the football ground cannot be looked upon in the same way as in civilian life. There, the lights mostly are green and red. On the footy ground, every light is permanently yellow. Simply to set foot on an oval implies acceptance of this risk. It means that accidents sometimes happen. This was one.
The first thing to hope is that Kreuzer recovers quickly, and avoids future mishap, by accident or incident. The second is to say that this has nothing to do with the Brownlow medal. In this, the match review panel has shown itself to be an honest jury. Now it is up to Dangerfield and Geelong to decide if they dare to submit to the double jeopardy of an appeal.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Ablett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/Julian Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Willson/AFL Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Jack Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
