<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400417078544580</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/18/06/wa-s-top-cop-wants-more-forensic-funding</url>
  <title>WA's top cop wants more forensic funding</title>
  <content>
Western Australia's outgoing police commissioner says mandatory sentencing doesn't deter criminals and wants funding to go towards prevention and improving forensic technology.
Karl O'Callaghan says being "tough on crime" by investing in prisons and officer numbers fails to solve the drivers of crime.
"I don't think mandatory sentencing actually solves the problem," he told ABC radio on Monday.
Mr O'Callaghan, who retires in August after 13 years as the state's top cop, says more funding is needed for pathology and blamed a lack of forensic equipment for slow turnaround times in processing evidence.
"They're good scientists, but they haven't got the equipment they need," he said.
"We will need to invest very heavily in forensics and bring ourselves up to world standards."
Mr O'Callaghan also noted that while WA has a reasonably good care program for children in immediate physical or sexual danger, there are thousands more who are neglected and not going to school.

Related Articles

"There's a whole range of problems that we are going to inherit unless we have a next level down strategy for those children, for those families, and it's a very, very big problem."
Mr O'Callaghan admitted he used his position to raise important issues, including squeezing $10 million out of the previous government by threatening to close the PCYC.
"Sometimes you have to make something seismic to make people move now or ... sometimes embarrass people into acting because it's not a priority for them."
Mr O'Callaghan also reflected on being in the spotlight after his son was arrested following a meth lab explosion in 2011.
He says the "most terrible" part was that his son was seriously burnt and he could not visit him in hospital for fear he would be accused of interfering.
"I actually drove to Royal Perth Hospital in my own car and sat outside for half an hour, debating on whether I should go in and provide support that a normal father would provide, and I drove away."
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Callaghan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Perth Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl O'Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCYC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
