<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400369833903423</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:58</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/man-points-pistol-at-fouryearold-daughter-and-pulls-trigger/news-story/a932470c08ca7b4710363366bf847ab9</url>
  <title>Man 'points gun at daughter, pulls trigger'</title>
  <content>
A MAN coldly points a pistol at his four-year-old daughter and squeezes the trigger. She survives - the gun does not discharge.
This is the chilling evidence alleged by detectives charging a man over an illegal firearms cache.

Officers from Strike Force Bowser, a NSW Terrorism Investigation Squad case relating to illegal firearms, today charged the 32-year-old Revesby man with six offences including four counts of illegal firearm possession; allow unauthorised person possess firearm and production/possession of child abuse material.
Police seized a 25 calibre Walther TP-model pistol, two Colt 1911 45 calibre automatic pistols and a Bentley-brand 12-gauge shotgun from addresses at Revesby and Granville as part of their inquiries.
During the investigation, police also accessed mobile phone video footage which allegedly shows the man, sky-larking with one of the Colt .45 handguns, pointing it at his four-year-old daughter and pulling the trigger. The weapon did not discharge.
The images also show the man allegedly pointing the shotgun at the phone camera.
Detectives allege further footage shows the child playing with the automatic pistol and pulling the trigger, without effect.
Senior Police have condemned the alleged behaviour.
"Allowing a child to play with a firearm of any kind is reprehensible and is a serious criminal offence," Assistant Commissioner, Mark Murdoch, said.
The investigation is not terror-related.
The father has been remanded in custody and ordered to appear in Burwood Local Court on Wednesday, August 16.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colt 1911 .45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strike Force Bowser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walther TP-model</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burwood Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Granville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Revesby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colt .45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Terrorism Investigation Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
