<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400412783577257</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/world/vladimir-putins-bet-on-a-trump-presidency-backfires-spectacularly-20170731-gxme9o</url>
  <title>Vladimir Putin's bet on a Trump presidency backfires spectacularly</title>
  <content>
by
David Sanger

A little more than a year after the Russian effort to interfere in the US presidential election came to light, the diplomatic fallout - an unravelling of the relationship between Moscow and Washington on a scale not seen in decades - is taking its toll.
President Vladimir Putin bet that Donald Trump, who had spoken fondly of Russia and its authoritarian leader for years, would treat his nation as Putin has longed to have it treated by the West. That is, as the superpower it once was, or at least a major force to be reckoned with.
That bet has backfired, spectacularly., it was that Trump's hands are now tied in dealing with Moscow, probably for years to come.
Just weeks after the two leaders spent hours in seemingly friendly conversation in Hamburg, Germany, the prospect of the kinds of deals Trump once mused about in interviews seem more distant than ever. Congress is not ready to forgive the annexation of Crimea, nor allow extensive reinvestment in Russian energy. The new sanctions were passed by a coalition of Democrats who blame Putin for contributing to Hillary Clinton's defeat and Republicans fearful that their president misunderstands who he is dealing with in Moscow.

Alexander Zemlianichenko

So with his decision to order that hundreds of US diplomats and Russians working for the US Embassy leave their posts, Putin, known as a great tactician but not a great strategist, has changed course again. For now, US officials and outside experts said Sunday, he seems to believe his greater leverage lies in escalating the dispute, Cold War-style, rather than subtly trying to manipulate events with a mix of subterfuge, cyberattacks and information warfare.

, and presumably expelled, there do not appear to be anything close to 755 US diplomats working in Russia.
That figure almost certainly includes Russian nationals working at the embassy, usually in non-sensitive jobs. And, of course there are many non-diplomats working for the US government in Russia at any given time - experts from departments across the government, from energy to agriculture, and a large station of spies, some working under diplomatic cover.
A senior administration official, who spoke on the condition of anonymity, said the White House had not given up hopes for a better relationship. Putin's interview on Russian television, in which he announced the reduction in staff, was free of bombast, the official noted. Russia seems uncertain about the direction of the relationship, leaving open the possibility of a reversal.
"The Russians would have preferred not to head down this path, but Putin didn't feel he had a choice but to respond in the classic tit-for-tat manner," said Rolf Mowatt-Larssen, who has served in a number of senior intelligence roles for the US, including in Russia. "We've been in a new Cold War for some time now. Any hope for a short-term improvement in relations is gone."

That downturn accelerated in the last days of the Obama administration, he argued, "when emotions took over the relationship". Now, said Mowatt-Larssen, who recently became director of intelligence and defence projects at the Belfer Centre at Harvard's Kennedy School, "fear has replaced anger in dealing with Russia".
Sergey Lavrov, the savvy Russian foreign minister, has struck a measured tone in his conversations with Secretary of State Rex Tillerson. In public, he has blamed not Trump, or the investigation into the Russian influence operation around the election, but Congress. "The latest developments have demonstrated that the US policy turns out to be in the hands of Russophobic forces that are pushing Washington toward confrontation," the Foreign Ministry said on Friday, after the passage of the latest sanctions act.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belfer Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rolf Mowatt-Larssen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard's Kennedy School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>War-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergey Lavrov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALEXANDER ZEMLIANICHENKO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cold War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Sanger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Embassy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Ministry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crimea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russophobic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mowatt-Larssen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
