<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400502977891941</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/football/neymars-dad-the-big-winner-if-psg-move-happens/news-story/cfe9291c32426b557a5e5db414a9f4e7</url>
  <title>Neymar's Dad the big winner if PSG move happens</title>
  <content>
Neymar in Barca bust up
0:32

Footbal: Neymar has been involved in a mid-training fight causing the Brazilian superstar to storm out of training.

July 29th 2017
3 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Football/

Neymar of Barcelona gestures after scoring during their International Champions Cup.

Andrew RichardsonThe Sun

Share

NEYMAR'S father has asked Paris Saint-Germain to delay completing a deal to sign his son until after July 31 so he can earn a whopping $37 million, according to reports.
The Brazilian is expected to leave the Nou Camp for the French capital in a world-record $322m deal.
But, should he still be a Barcelona player on August 1, his father would earn the staggering amount in commission as part of the contract he signed last summer.
And The Sunday Times report that Neymar Snr. has contacted PSG and asked them to ensure any deal is completed after July 31 (August 1st, AEST).
Should he earn the staggering amount, Barcelona will have incredibly paid him more than Lionel Messi since 2013.

FC Barcelona's Lionel Messi, left, and Neymar pose with their new jersey.Source:AP
As well as being easily the costliest transfer in football history, this looks set to be messiest with so many complications.
PSG risk the wrath of Uefa's Financial Fair Play rules as they would need to rake in around £100m in transfers to justify the purchase of Neymar.
But the transfer could be financed by the club's holding company Qatar Sports Investment, who have offered to pay the Brazilian a staggering $88m-A-YEAR to be an official ambassador for the 2022 World Cup - which will amount to $443m over five years until the start of the tournament.
And that would see Neymar pay the fee himself, allowing PSG to bypass FFP regulations as the money is coming out of the player's own pocket.

Barcelona have returned home from their pre-season tour of the USA.
But Neymar is not going back with them regardless of where his future lies, instead moving onto China for a promotional event.
And, while there, it could be he makes a quick dash to Qatar to finalise the move to PSG.
A training spat with new Barcelona signing Nelson Semedo during a pre-season tour in Miami ramped up chatter that Neymar could be about to swap Spain for the French capital.

FC Barcelona football star Neymar could be about to leave the Nou Camp.Source:AFP
Neymar, who has remained tight-lipped about the transfer rumours, posted a message for Chinese fans on Weibo, China's equivalent of Twitter, after arriving for a promotional visit.
"Ni Hao China! I'm Neymar Jr. and I've just arrived in China," he wrote on Monday.
"I'm in Shanghai at the moment. I would like to send a huge hug to all my Chinese fans, thank you very much for your support."
He posted messages in English and Chinese and asked for suggestions as to what he should do while in Shanghai, where he was scheduled to appear at an event for a fashion brand later on Monday.
Separately, China's biggest online travel company Ctrip had said it was cancelling an event with Neymar on Monday in Shanghai because he and his advisers were "busy with transfer issues".
People close to the player subsequently told media there had never been an arrangement with the firm.

Neymar #11 of Barcelona reacts during their International Champions Cup 2017 match against Real Madrid.Source:AFP
Even after the training-ground bust-up in the United States, after which Neymar appeared to storm off, his Barcelona teammates said they wanted him to stay at the Camp Nou.
"Neymar and I, we are very close and I want him to stay and I know the situation," defender Gerard Pique told ESPN FC.
"Right now he doesn't know what to do and we are trying to help him - the ones (on the team) that are more close to him - to take the right decision."
PSG's pursuit of Neymar has angered some in Spain, where football league chief Javier Tebas says he will file a complaint with UEFA for financial fair play breaches by the French club.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weibo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javier Tebas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nelson Semedo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ni Hao China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Champions Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIAMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar's Dad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar Sports Investment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar of Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Madrid.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nou Camp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FC Barcelona's Lionel Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Champions Cup 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nou Camp.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ctrip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FC Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew RichardsonThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar Snr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Pique</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uefa's Financial Fair Play</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Nou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar #11 of Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
