<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400331179197024</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4822932/mayoral-bid-has-liberals-divided/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Mayoral bid has Liberals divided</title>
  <content>
CANDIDATE: David Compton has been preselected to run as the Newcastle Liberals candidate for Newcastle Lord Mayor.

THE Newcastle Liberal Party is divided over plans to run a mayoral candidate at next month's local government election, with senior members privately voicing fears that having two conservative candidates in the race could hand the election to Labor.
The Liberal Party held its preselection ballot last week and, while the results are yet to be formally endorsed by head office, the Newcastle Herald understands the party intends to run a candidate for lord mayor for the first time in recent memory.

In a show of strength for the party's youth wing two of its members - Taylor Wright and Hannah Eves - were preselected in wards one and four respectively.
Incumbent councillors Brad Luke and David Compton will run in wards two and three.
However it's the decision of Cr Compton to run as a mayoral candidate that has ruffled feathers within the party. 
The Newcastle Liberals have traditionally avoided nominating a mayoral candidate to avoid stealing votes from conservative-minded independents, and it's understood that sections of the party had wanted to continue the tradition in a bid to help independent candidate Kath Elliott unseat incumbent Labor Lord Mayor Nuatali Nelmes.
But Cr Compton still nominated uncontested at last week's preselection vote and despite the concerns of some within the party the Herald understands he still intends on running.
Cr Compton said he could not comment on Monday because the ticket had yet to be endorsed.

The emergence of Ms Elliott's ticket has rankled some Liberals because of its close ties to the party.
John Church, the independent candidate in Ward 1, was previously a Liberal Party candidate in Shortland and .
However the conservative-minded independents, including incumbent councillors Andrea Rufo and Allan Robinson, have sought to distance themselves from the Liberal Party.
Ms Elliott denied she was conservative leaning, saying she was "community minded" and a "swinging voter" although she said she "never voted for the Greens".
"I vote on the issues, which is why I wanted to run as an independent," she said.
Ms Elliott's professional website carries testimonials about her firm's campaigns for the coal industry and against the Gillard Labor government's carbon tax.

She said "it was a matter for the Liberal Party" as to whether they ran a candidate, and while she conceded it "may split the vote" she said she hoped her ticket "will take votes from Labor too".
"I haven't spoken to the Liberal Party about that in particular," she said. 

"Last time I spoke to anyone they didn't have [a candidate] but I don't really have an opinion, it's up to them."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Compton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shortland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah Eves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Liberals</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillard Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Rufo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Lord Mayor Nuatali Nelmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Compton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ward 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Elliott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
