<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400498682924625</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/mutual-trust-names-phil-harkness-as-chief-executive-after-myer-family-merger-20170731-gxmc1b</url>
  <title>Mutual Trust names Phil Harkness as chief executive after Myer Family merger</title>
  <content>
The new chief executive of Mutual Trust says he will approach the integration of the firm with Myer Family Investments in a careful way, after the pair completed due diligence and are now only awaiting regulatory for their merger.
"We are very focused on how to put the firms together in a way that capitalises on their relative strengths," Phil Harkness told The Australian Financial Review on Monday.
"Nothing is going to be done in a rushed way. It will be all very considered, very stable and very sensible.
"We are genuinely going to create one firm here and at the moment there are two standalone businesses here in every respect." 

The merger of  in the 1930s and 1920s, respectively, was announced in early June.

The merged entity, which will trade under the Mutual Trust name, will manage $3 billion, with a focus on families, trusts and charities.
Mutual Trust shareholders will own 65 per cent of the merged group, with MFI owning the remainder. It will also be Mutual Trust's biggest shareholder.
Mr Harkness will replace current Mutual Trust CEO Tim Hammon, who had previously announced his retirement and will become a consultant to the company.
'A determination to exceed customer satisfaction'

Mr Harkness previously led the performance improvement practice within EY Advisory, and prior to that was a vice-president for AT Kearney for 11 years.
Myer Family Investments CEO Danielle Press has been squeezed out in the merger; she will leave the business after "assisting with a smooth transition over the coming weeks and months".
The announcement of the merger had already seen the 
Despite the departures, Mr Harkness said staff across both firms were upbeat about the prospect of combining the strengths of both businesses and delivering a better suite of services to clients.  

"Really good professional services firms do create a culture that is characterised by a determination to exceed customer satisfaction."
Myer Family Investments director John Russell said the response from clients since the announcement of the deal had been positive, and they saw the benefits it could bring through greater scale and larger investments in areas such as human resources and technology.
"Most clients see the benefits that we have seen through the combination." 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Harkness</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Harkness</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kearney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myer Family Investments</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myer Family</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EY Advisory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mutual Trust CEO Tim Hammon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mutual Trust</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myer Family Investments CEO Danielle Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
