<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400550222533052</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/special-reports/trailblazers/investing-in-employees-reaps-dividends-20170730-gxlsa8</url>
  <title>Investing in employees reaps dividends </title>
  <content>
by
Melina Gouveia

This content is produced by The Australian Financial Review in commercial partnership with Salesforce.
As leaders introduce rapid and pervasive change to drive new growth, many find that reconfiguring their organisation's staff to keep capabilities up to date is a major challenge.
It is an issue that is very familiar to Danielle Uskovic, head of Digital and Social at Lenovo Asia Pacific. "When I look at how fast technology is changing for us in the ad tech and mark tech space, it's phenomenal. For me, I have to up-scale my existing team because I don't want to lose them."
She was speaking at The Australian Financial Review/Salesforce Trailblazers round table in Sydney. It is a challenge to keep them educated in the new technologies, she says.

"That means bringing technology in-house, owning it, and actually helping those people. If they don't come on that journey and they don't want to learn new skills, then they can go somewhere else. I'm big on investing in the people that you have, because it costs a lot of money for an organisation to bring new staff in," she says.

Attracting, training, and retaining talent is a particular concern when the core skills required for a job become obsolete over substantially shorter time frames. This human resource challenge is complicated by the need to adjust a workforce skill-set frequently, to pivot in sync with shifting strategic priorities.
Then there is the problem of managing the interplay of staff and new technology efficiently and in a way that delivers the best return on investment to the business.
If this makes the task of building future workplace capability seem daunting, it is worth remembering that there is nothing new about change. That was the view expressed by participants in the roundtable.
Participants (mostly) agreed that what remains constant in a digital age work environment - a pre-defined company culture based on a shared vision, purpose, and values - is firmly within management's control.

Precise communication and transparency with employees about new systems and procedures that have an impact on company culture is essential when undergoing transformational, change according to Belinda Vassallo, GE Digital Country Manager for Australia and New Zealand.
"The biggest thing I find is communication," Vassallo said. "Giving employees a long-term vision of where we want to head when everything is always pivoting and adjusting. Or they may not feel comfortable with the lack of communication, and that's occurring.
"We are in a world where we don't know how we're going to navigate, but we know the endgame."
Empowering employees and keeping them united around company culture breaks down the adversarial barriers - real and perceived - between humans and machines. In taking responsibility for transforming an organisation, leaders must also assume accountability for creating a future for their employees, said Andy Bateman, Deloitte's national lead partner, Innovation Strategy.

"People tend to adapt and do new parts of work as long as the work design is done sensitively, and accommodates their ability to learn as well."
Bateman said new technological capabilities, when correctly aligned with people, enhanced decision-making abilities and operational efficiencies. Complications may arise when planning for optimal co-ordination between nascent technologies and future employees - particularly a workforce soon to be dominated by Millennials - to get things done.
will be 60 per cent of the workplace by 2025, claimed Bridget Loudon, co-founder of Expert360. She added that they think differently to Baby Boomers. "If we look at the Millennials, they're looking to choose interesting work. So it's not about money. It's about purpose. It's about 'Does this company's values align with mine?' "
For both generations, Loudon said, a shift towards having choice in the way they work as a priority over full-time employment is increasing, fundamentally altering the workforce.

" who are getting to their 50s and 60s are saying, 'Actually, I want a bit of flexibility. I want a bit of diversity,' " she said.
Leaders will need to adopt a flexible labour framework and be comfortable blending highly skilled freelance employees who are committed to their job - but not the company - with full-time employees, she said.
Firms that get this right will capture significant unrealised gains that help deliver on their long-term vision.
Loudon thinks securing full-time work is increasingly becoming "less valued as a virtue" in the workplace. She predicts that in 10 years the idea that doing exciting work as a valued employee will no longer equate to a 60-hour week year after year.

"I think we will look back and say that was crazy," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Expert360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GE Digital Country Manager</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lenovo Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovation Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danielle Uskovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loudon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridget Loudon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melina Gouveia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baby Boomers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salesforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Bateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vassallo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review Salesforce Trailblazers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Vassallo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
