<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400455733250956</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/ct-letters/canberra-times-letters-to-the-editor-inaction-on-diet-a-big-failing-20170731-gxmic2.html</url>
  <title>Inaction on diet a big failing</title>
  <content>
The comments of Coles managing director John Durkan to the American Chamber of Commerce last week were widely reported for acknowledging that rising cost of living pressures make junk food in his supermarkets relatively more affordable than fresh food, especially for low-income families.
What he failed to recognise was the much bigger issue resulting in part from this observation: the obesity epidemic engulfing wide swaths of the community.
The paradigm he described is a classic example of the structural and cultural factors that conspire to create the "obesogenic" environment in which we all now live. Obesity and its insidious progeny - diabetes, cardiovascular disease, and cancer, to name a few - disproportionately affect people of low socioeconomic status, Indigenous Australians, and those living outside major cities.
Throw in slick and inescapable advertising, misleading food labelling, and low educational attainment, and obesity is almost as inevitable as that feeling of queasy regret after downing a triple cheeseburger.
It is precisely why government must give all Australians an equal opportunity to engage in healthy eating and activity levels, rather than blaming the individual as so many of us are wont to do.
The current level of inaction is a gross moral failing, to say nothing of the ballooning costs of obesity-related disease, for which we all as taxpayers foot the bill. We should be worrying less about the corporate bottom line and more about the wider consequences of poor food accessibility in this country.

Jonathan McGuane, Australian National University Medical School
Bigger is not better

If I have interpreted Jon Stanhope's article correctly ("More houses a priority", Forum, July 29, p. 10) the price of bungalow style housing is being seriously inflated because the government is not releasing sufficient land for the construction of free standing dwellings (as opposed to units and townhouses).
Stanhope's criticism is more or less reflected in Kirsten Lawson's front page article ("Affordable housing lure", July 29, p.1).
In his article, Stanhope emphasises that "the law of supply and demand is quite brutal - if the supply of a product ... is less than the demand, the price goes up ..." and, of course, vice versa.
Having identified these two basic tenets of economics, he then proceeds to ignore one of them in offering his solution. In order to address supply, the government must release more land more quickly.
Not a word does he write on the eminently redeemable issue of demand.
Would not a better, wiser path - albeit over the slightly longer term - be to press the federal government to curtail our unsustainably high rate of immigration?
The ACT might simultaneously reduce, postpone, or terminate its participation in the regional migration component of this.
This would quickly reduce demand for Canberra housing by up to 40 per cent, resolve affordability issues, permit the scaling back of the infrastructure burden upon the current citizenry, arrest the decline in the livability of this city and, most important, give our numerous threatened species a desperately needed respite.
Graham Clews, Kambah
Attack on Queen

Bill Shorten has launched an attack on the Queen, accusing her of being a foreign power. If he truly believes that then what worth is his word when he swore to bear true and faithful allegiance to that very same Queen when he took his seat in the Parliament?
"I, William Richard Shorten do swear that I will be faithful and bear true allegiance to her majesty Queen Elizabeth, her heirs and successors according to law. So help me God."
The Queen is Queen of Australia by right of the Australian constitution. 
The Queen is not a foreign power, she is the Queen and therefore is above citizenship.
Philip Benwell, national chair Australian Monarchist League
Adding up the numbers

Ross Gittins ("Falling for the big scam", July 26, p.16) writes that "intelligence and law enforcement agencies had successfully interdicted 12 imminent terrorist attacks since September 2014. There's no way of checking that claim ...".
Surely the perpetrators of imminent terrorist attacks are either cautioned, charged and brought before the courts or "disappeared" in some Orwellian way.
Presuming the first and last procedures are unlikely, surely the would-be terrorists are brought before the courts.
A simple reading of the charge sheets would validate whether or not those people may have intended to commit acts of terrorism.
Even a cub court reporter would be able to tally up such court records throughout Australia and thus check the claimed numbers of interdicted terrorists since September 2014.
Or is something more sinister going on here?
Penleigh Boyd, Reid
Disappearing water

Why is the enormous dollar value of the water stolen from the Barwon not being mentioned?
We need a police investigation not a political whitewash.
Gerry Gillespie, Queanbeyan NSW
Very bad habit

Are Bill Shorten's chances of becoming PM now likely to go up in smoke because of the latest donation controversy?  ("Labor takes 'illegal' tobacco donations", July 31, p.6)
He needs to give up the habit before it kills his prospects.
M. Moore, Bonython
There are plenty of comrades that are prepared to walk with Barnby

Karen Hardy's article regarding Don Barnby's inclusion in a forthcoming book ("War is hell but the aftermath can be purgatory", July 29, p16), resonated very deeply on a number of fronts.
Don and I joined the ACT Police Force on the same day. His service in Vietnam in 1971 was at the same time as my second tour of duty.
Our instructors, including then Sgt Colin Winchester, were the best of the best, and the lessons learned stayed with me to this day.
Don stayed in the job, I went back to soldiering. It was my first love.
Don has had a stellar career and his service and sacrifice is a credit to himself, the AFP and the nation, and we should all be grateful for that service.
From one soldier to another: "Well done, that man!"
Karen Hardy asked, "Can that door (to what people have seen) ever really be closed?"
Not really. To Don I say this: "Mate, there are many of us who will walk with you and hold your hand to keep that door from opening wider."
Bonne chance, mon ami.
Noel McLaughlin, Macgregor
A carrier choice

Most G20 nations have an aircraft carrier of their own but Australia currently does not - and it should.
The Royal Australian Navy does have two amphibious assault ships, the HMAS Canberra and the HMAS Adelaide, but they carry helicopters and not war planes.
Why not have a "light" aircraft carrier as part of the Australian Fleet?
A new light aircraft carrier could be built based from the USS Tripoli. 
The USS Tripoli is an America-class amphibious assault ship, and it was built by Huntington Ingalls Industries.
The USS Tripoli is an amphibious assault ship that is larger than the HMAS Canberra and Adelaide and it has the capability to launch and carry fighter jets. As Australia and the United State are close Allies, maybe the federal government could purchase an America-class amphibious assault vessel that could be used as a light aircraft carrier for the RAN.
A light aircraft carrier would be a lot less costly to run and operate than a mega aircraft carrier.
Such a vessel would be the pride of the RAN and it would further strengthen Australia's naval capabilities.
Malcolm Webster, Boronia
Quick fix required

What a joke is Section 44 of the constitution and its impact on elected senators.
Why can't something simple and quick be done to fix things?
Our constitution is outdated (a 1901 document) and clearly needs changing, eg, inter alia to recognise indigenous people.
How do we sensibly do this? Constitutional lawyers with commonsense, please step up to the plate!
Also, there is a PhD in this for someone - how many MPs have there been who were not born in Australia?
Graeme Mayo, Hawker
Flying nuisances

Over the past three months there have been drones flying around the suburbs of Banks, Gordon and Conder.
These drones fly at night and shine lights in various homes and at times into windows of these residences. This is not an isolated occurrence and is happening every night like clockwork.
What has happened to our privacy?
I have contacted CASA but to no avail: "Oh, can you get the serial numbers?"
Am I going to chase  drones and take photos at night of tiny serial numbers?
So what do we do? 
Just keep our blinds closed and wonder who is actually behind these drones and what are they looking at?
K.Robinson, Gordon
Ill-befitting manners

Recently I have seen a number of specialist doctors in regards to assessments for insurance companies.
Without exception they have been rude and arrogant.
They have summoned me into their anointed presence without declaring who they are and barely looking up from their paperwork.
If I did that to the clients I see, I would expect them to be as upset as I have been.
The latest one summoned me, no introduction, so when I heard my name, I said "yes?" A momentary silence. He was very surprised when I said "and you are"? He was then forced to tell me his name.
These doctors need a reality check.
Be polite, we are not meat on a production line.
You may see lots of people a day, but you are the only doctor I will be seeing, so get over yourselves and your arrogant self-importance.
Ian Jannaway, Monash
Rustlers in charge

So, our "all hat but no cattle" Deputy Prime Minister, Federal Water Minister and leader of the National Party, Barnaby Joyce, reckons that illegally diverting water intended to rejuvenate the health of the Murray Darling Basin to irrigators is no different to cattle rustling ("Stop 'greenies running the show': Joyce unloads on Four Corners water report", canberratimes.com.au, July 28).
As evidence of just how far our society has really progressed, there was a time when rustlers were certain to face swift and real justice if caught, while these days it seems that the worst that can happen to them is that they wind up wearing a sheriff's badge.
John Richardson, Wallagoot, NSW
Justifying themselves

The idea has been floated of again increasing the ACT's MLAs from the current 25, following the recent increase from 17. The Assembly list shows the following members have no "position": Caroline Le Couteur (Greens), Suzanne Orr (ALP) and Michael Pettersson (ALP). 
The following hold what I judge to be nominal "positions": Tara Cheyne (ALP, government whip), Bec Cody (ALP, Assistant Speaker) and Chris Steel (ALP, Assistant Speaker).
To inform the electorate, I wonder if any of the above would be prepared to put in writing (1) what exactly they have done since the October 2016 election, that is, how they have filled their days, (2) if, and if so, how they think 25 MLAs have improved our government from the time of 17, and (3) if they think the number should be further increased, and if so, how that would benefit Canberrans.
Hugh Dakin, Griffith
TO THE POINT

TROLLEY TRUDGE
Would Coles/Aldi at Jamieson take note of the letter by Paul O'Connor (July 28) and install a trolley bay by the three disabled parking spots in the small parking area at the rear of the centre.
It is a long walk back to a trolley bay for people with a disability.
Mary Robbie, Aranda
JOYCE REALLY A KIWI?
Is Barnaby Joyce a New Zealand citizen? His father came from there.
Pam Cohen, Turner
MOVING THEM ON
I took delight in reading Jack Waterford's words, "I ... rejoice in the opportunity to throw the bastards out as frequently as possible." ("Rightly, s44 is here to stay", Forum, July 29, pp1, 3).
He had deviated from his main theme to deride the suggestion of four-year parliamentary terms.
I'll back Jack on this one.
Gary J. Wilson, Macgregor
LIMPING ALREADY?
After only six months into his term, is Donald already a lame duck president?
Dennis Hale, Beecroft, NSW
CHANGE OF GUARD
The new Department of "Home Affairs" sounds like a headline from a women's magazine. Surely the leader Mr Dutton could have called it the "Home Guard" or the "New Guard" which sounds much more paramilitary.
Adrian Jackson, Middle Park, Vic
CONUNDRUM
Given that HM Queen Elizabeth II is Queen of Australia and Britain, how can it be wrong to hold dual Australian/British citizenship when standing for Parliament in Australia?
Susan MacDougall, Scullin
FANS STAY AWAY
Can I put out there another reason for the small turn out for the finals game at Bruce stadium. I suspect Super Rugby suffers from a lack of a free-to-air presence. I would follow the Brumbies more if I didn't have to fork out for pay TV.
Kim Fitzgerald, Deakin
LOW-PROFILE ROLE 
Has anyone heard what happened to Brendan Smyth since he was appointed as the newly minted ACT Commissioner for International Engagement?
Anyone? Anyone...?
Ian Forno, Waramanga
WELL MATCHED
New White House communications boss Anthony Scaramucci looks like Donald Duck, sounds like Donald Duck and behaves like Donald Duck.
A most apposite appointment for Lame Duck President.
Jon Jovanovic, Lenah Valley, Tas
mail: . Send from the message field, not as an attached file. Fax: 6280 2282. Mail: Letters to the Editor, The Canberra Times, PO Box 7155, Canberra Mail Centre, ACT 2610.
Keep your letter to 250 words or less. References to Canberra Times reports should include date and page number. Letters may be edited. Provide phone number and full home address (suburb only published).
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary J. Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Speaker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Durkan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waramanga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lame Duck President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Police Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Jovanovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Guard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonython</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macgregor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles/Aldi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Forno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Hardy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sgt Colin Winchester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Dakin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Waterford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America-class</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian/British</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Webster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beecroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Gittins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bec Cody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Clews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFILE ROLE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Fleet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Mayo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Mail Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PO Box 7155</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanhope</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOYCE REALLY A KIWI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel McLaughlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University Medical School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberrans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PhD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STAY AWAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aranda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Robbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Pettersson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Monarchist League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan McGuane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Times</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington Ingalls Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT 2610</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Engagement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Duck</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kambah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Barnby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzanne Orr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Stanhope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Steel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K.Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CASA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen of Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orwellian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barwon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HM Queen Elizabeth II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pam Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallagoot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Jannaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Benwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USS Tripoli</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirsten Lawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Water Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Richard Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Cheyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan MacDougall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerry Gillespie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boronia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MONASH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Hale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penleigh Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT's MLAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMAS Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Section 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Smyth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MLAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of "Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Le Couteur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lenah Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scullin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
