<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400378423838269</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/several-players-in-the-hunt-for-brownlow-medal/news-story/1a5f94311ad4c5859073a16335f91242</url>
  <title>Brownlow night could get very awkward</title>
  <content>
THE news could get even worse for Patrick Dangerfield.
Not only could he see his Brownlow Medal hopes evaporate this week after being handed a one week ban from the Match Review Committee, but things could get uncomfortable for the Cats' star on award night.
Given Dangerfield claimed the 2016 Brownlow Medal, it is customary that he present the medal to the 2017 winner. Depending on how he goes at the AFL Tribunal, it could get very awkward.
Even if suspended, Dangerfield will still poll votes until the final round, meaning he can still win the Brownlow - technically. He can still get the most votes from the umpires, but obviously be unable to claim the medal.
Corey McKernan in 1996 and Chris Grant in 1997 are the only other players that have experienced the same fate.
It certainly made for an awkward moment then, as it would for Dangerfield in 2017.

So Dangerfield might poll the most Brownlow votes and then have to present the medal to the winner.
The Geelong star will have to front the AFL Tribunal and hope he can overturn the decision, but will face a two-game suspension if he is found guilty.
The Cats currently sit second on the ladder, a place that comes with a second-chance come finals time and a home final in the opening week.
Geelong hosts Sydney on Friday night and then face fourth placed Richmond the following week.
Losing both could see them slip out of the top four entirely. The stakes are certainly high, meaning the club may choose to accept the one-week ban handed down to Dangerfield, ending the Brownlow dream.
The match review panel took video evidence and a medical report from Carlton into account and assessed the incident as "careless with medium impact to the head".
Dangerfield was charged with rough conduct after he pinned ruckman Matthew Kreuzer's arms and dumped him head first into the turf during the third quarter.
Kreuzer was ushered to the Carlton rooms and wasn't sighted for the rest of the match as the Cats went on to win by 65 points, with the Blues later confirming he had suffered a concussion.
Former St Kilda and North Melbourne star Nick Dal Santo says Dangerfield should expect to remain sidelined and can't see how the AFL will allow the midfielder to escape punishment.
"I think he has to (be suspended)," Dal Santo told SEN.
"I don't necessarily like it. My thought when I saw it was 'Is this where we're at with our footy?'. But, on what we're governing and where the game is now - he has to get a week.
"It's your responsibility not to hurt them and cause a head injury.
"(If their arms are pinned in a tackle) Let them go, any movement after that is your responsibility."
This means Richmond's Dustin Martin has rocketed into Brownlow favouritism. He has become the shortest priced Brownlow Medal favourite in history.
Martin does currently have two strikes (punished by fine, not suspension) against his name this season though. A third strike will automatically roll into a one-week suspension, making the Richmond star ineligible for the Brownlow.
That would leave the race wide open, with Hawthorn's Tom Mitchell suddenly right in the mix.
Adelaide's Rory Sloane, GWS' Josh Kelly and Essendon's Zach Merrett have also seen their odds shortened.
Geelong has until 11am Tuesday to commit to fighting the charge, something AFL legend David Schwarz believes they will do.
"I reckon Chris Scott is a semi crusader and wants to stand up for what is right," Schwarz told SEN.
"If they believe there was no malice intended - they will fight it."
Schwarz said his initial view of the tackle was that Dangerfield would not face a charge, but he admits having watched it closer, he agrees with the penalty, despite Dangerfield arguing that he felt Kreuzer was still in possession of the ball.
"If you've got two arms pinned you know the ball is gone," Schwarz said.
"I looked at it twice and thought he's in trouble."

Dangerfield only been cited once in a 196 game career, a fine of $900 for negligent umpire contact in r1, 2012. Fairest time up in Brownlow

Just means that  will win the Brownlow
Which he deserves 1.
Just a shame he wins it for being the fairest, not the best

Really looking forward to Dustys speech with Bruce at the Brownlow. Going to be a "colourful" interview that's for sure

Tom Mitchell is a Dusty brainfade away from winning the Brownlow.

Those saying Brownlow Medal night is ruined... remember that Danger's presenting the medal to the winner. Might be a little loose...
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey McKernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn's Tom Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Schwarz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schwarz</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond's Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS' Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's Rory Sloane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon's Zach Merrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Dal Santo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Tribunal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dal Santo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
