<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400421373511964</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/crossbench-poised-to-refer-thankful-one-nation-senator-to-high-court-20170731-gxmf52.html</url>
  <title>Crossbench poised to refer 'thankful' One Nation senator to High Court</title>
  <content>
﻿Senate crossbenchers will move to refer One Nation senator Malcolm Roberts to the High Court if the government hesitates, all but guaranteeing his eligibility will be decided by the court.
But Senator Roberts, whose office threatened to report Fairfax Media to police for "stalking" in response to questions over his eligibility, is now delighting in the "unbelievable" increase in his profile the furore has created.

Up Next

Scant protection for Cassie Sainsbury

00:58

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Senator's eligibility concerns

One Nation senator Malcolm Roberts won't release the documents proving when his British citizenship ceased, putting his eligibility to be in Parliament under a cloud.

The Greens party room will discuss the issue next week, while Derryn Hinch said he would move the motion himself, if the government or One Nation itself failed to do so. The Greens and Senator Hinch are pushing for an independent audit of all MPs' citizenship status.
"Our view is there should be a comprehensive audit of all members of Parliament and we would like to see an independent audit - we would support the government conducting an independent audit, but in the absence of that, then each house can conduct an audit, can basically co-opt independent advice and in fact, could proceed to appoint an auditor to do this and make recommendations about any cases that should be referred to the High Court," Greens leader Richard Di Natale said.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
"In the absence of that happening, than there is the capacity for us to refer individual cases and there are big questions around Malcolm Roberts that need to be answered and obviously the High Court is the appropriate place to do that."
Senator Hinch who, like Senator Di Natale has had to prove he is not a dual citizen in recent weeks following the section 44 fall-out that cost two Greens senators their jobs and raised questions over others, said in addition to an independent audit he also wanted questions over Senator Roberts and the LNP's Matt Canavan quickly resolved.

"I think both Canavan and Roberts are in real trouble," Senator Hinch said.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"...If they don't do it themselves [refer the matter to the High Court], I will definitely move one myself, yes."Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
It is understood the government, which has committed to referring 's case to the High Court, will follow suit with Senator Roberts, after the Queensland senator revealed last week he had only received confirmation from British authorities his renunciation was successful six months after he nominated as a candidate. 
But One Nation is standing behind Senator Roberts, who was "choosing to believe that he was never British",  he was once a British citizen.  
Senator Roberts confirmed he had sent emails to British authorities inquiring as to his citizenship status in May last year, following up with another email on June 6 - three days before nominations for the federal election closed - but did not say when he began the proper renunciation process set out by Britain, which includes forms and a fee.
Attempts by Fairfax Media to clarify the situation resulted in Senator Roberts' spokesman Sean Black  journalists to police for "stalking".
But Pauline Hanson's office said Senator Roberts would provide a further explanation to the Senate in the next sitting.
"I too believe in the interest of transparency the documents that support Senator Roberts standing in the Senate should be shown, however it will be through appropriate means which does not involve exclusively giving them to a single news source," Senator Hanson's spokesman said.
"Next week the Senate will be provided with supporting documents that prove Senator Roberts had renounced his citizenship.
"In the meantime, Malcolm Roberts is enjoying the unbelievable spike in public profile. He can't thank you enough."
Senator Hanson and her chief advisor James Ashby have both claimed to have sighted the documents proving Senator Roberts' case, with Senator Hanson saying "hand on heart [she could] assure everyone that Malcolm is not a dual citizen".
"I saw first hand his renouncement of UK citizenship before he became a candidate for the Senate," she said.
But not everyone within the party is as confident.
Two weeks ago Senator Roberts' colleague, Brian Burston, called for "all parliamentarians who were not born in this country to table their documents of revocation of citizenship for the country of their birth prior to the next session of parliament in August".
"It shouldn't be that difficult," he said in a media release from July 18.
"They'd have needed to have it squared away as part of their administration prior to nominating for candidacy.
"Anyone caught having dual citizenship after that should be prosecuted and face a custodial sentence."
Last week, when asked on social media to place a bet on Senator Roberts' eligibility to remain in the Senate, Senator Burston said he was "not confident of anything".
"I say they all (i.e. the elected officials) put their material forward, let the cards fall where they may."
A High Court ruling against Senator Roberts may not be the end of his parliamentary career, with his likely replacement, Fraser Anning, facing bankruptcy proceedings.
If proven, Mr Anning would be ineligible to sit as a member of parliament under section 44.  But if any potential bankruptcy was found to have occurred after the election, ABC election expert Antony Green, said that train of events would create a casual vacancy, which would mean One Nation could fill any vacant senate spot with anyone from within the party - including Senator Roberts.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassie Sainsbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antony Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Di Natale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Roberts</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Anning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derryn Hinch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Burston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Anning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Roberts</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Burston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Di Natale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ashby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hinch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP's Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
