<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400331179197020</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/teams/bulldogs/why-fans-should-be-more-patient-with-canterbury-coach-des-hasler/news-story/229e23ddede20b514d802934ea8ba446</url>
  <title>Why the mob are wrong to hate Hasler</title>
  <content>
PITCHFORKS to the left, torches to the right.
The mob assemble for Des Hasler, whose record at the weekend fell to 11 finals appearances from the past 12 seasons. That's a hanging offence when mob mentality takes over.
And so with a grand flick of the hair Hasler prepares to fight for his job as the great disturbance around the Bulldogs boardroom, with elections in February, threatens his future.
A week ago Bulldogs captain James Graham sat down on NRL360 and spoke with true passion about Hasler's credentials as coach while he wondered about the energy being put into tapping Hasler out of his job after one failed season.
Graham, a thinker, quoted a book called This Is Your Brain On Sports that detailed the ancient phenomena of baseball manager Connie Mack, who managed the Philadelphia Athletics for 50 seasons.
Mack won just five World Series, had a losing record overall, and yet the ball club so appreciated the value of what he did with what he had that they refused to run him out of town even though his last World Series came 20 years before he retired.
At 88.
Nowadays, Graham wondered, everybody wants success instantly.
Nobody is prepared to give the benefit of time or perspective to Hasler's stint, both of which would save his job.
To understand what Hasler has achieved and where Canterbury are can be done only through the full breadth of his tenure.
To isolate the merit of his coaching to merely this season is shortsighted and the kind of narrow thinking that presents a danger the Bulldogs' faithful have not fully considered. Namely, they might actually get worse and not better.
Hasler made the grand final his first season at Canterbury in 2012, losing to Melbourne, after they finished ninth the season before. He was hailed a saviour, a worker in small miracles.
Bulldogs fans clapped their hands and waited.
Hasler got there again two years later, going down to South Sydney this time, and the feeling was the Bulldogs were oh so close.
In hindsight that hope, the small margin of improvement needed, was where Hasler went wrong.
But is that enough to run him out of town?
In the two seasons since that grand final the Bulldogs have made the playoffs both years but got eliminated easily both times in the first round of the playoffs.
Throw in last weekend's loss to Penrith that eliminated the Bulldogs from this year's finals series for the first time since Hasler arrived and the smell of blood drifts through Belmore.
Suddenly, the roster is revealed as stale and lethargic. And it is the coach's fault so surely he must go.
Forget Hasler had every right to believe the Bulldogs were close to a premiership.
The difficulty many fail to appreciate is the whole time coaches are tilting at premierships the salary cap is working against them.
Salary caps create a premiership window, a moment in time when a club has enough quality experienced players there playing, on market value, and enough emerging young players who are under market value to give them a chance to make a charge for the premiership.
Most clubs spend years trying to build such a roster.
When Hasler got there in 2012 he had every right to believe the premiership window was upon the club and a premiership was clear.
It almost came to fruition in 2014 when they again got to the grand final.
With hindsight, that is when Hasler should have looked to reinvigorate his roster.
SUPERCOACH:
VIDEO:
BUZZ:
No club can stay on top forever. The salary cap and changing market values determines they cannot do it.
The Roosters, after three straight minor premierships from 2013-15, fell to 15th in last year's premiership.
Never a club to wait for success coach Trent Robinson realised they needed to reinvigorate their roster, took the lumps and are now second.
South Sydney bent their salary cap all out of shape after their 2014 premiership and are struggling to make it back, having finished seventh and 12th in the two seasons since. They now sit 14th and, like Hasler, coach Michael Maguire will soon begin to fight for his job.
Such is the modern history of success.
Hasler's mistake was trying to squeeze one more premiership tilt from his team after 2014 before turning over his roster.
It failed, the wrong players were let go to keep the high-priced necessities on the list, others had their contracts back-ended twisting the salary cap out of shape, all to keep the band together, and the Dogs got themselves in a small mess.
That does not mean Hasler cannot coach.
It means he made a mistake. It means he need to change.
Bulldogs fans don't like the way they play.
They want Hasler gone and carry the veiled threat that if the board does not boot him out then they will vote them out at February's boardroom elections.
The mob assembles. They do this with no suggestion who better could replace him.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia Athletics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PITCHFORKS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Des Hasler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUPERCOACH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brain On Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasler</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Series</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Maguire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connie Mack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
