<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400417078544593</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4822007/albion-park-man-welcomes-better-access-to-cancer-drug/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Albion Park man welcomes better access to cancer drug Opdivo</title>
  <content>
Gamechanger: Albion Park's Keith Watson had exhausted other cancer treatment options, before trialling Opdivo. Picture: Adam McLean

A 'miracle' drug that stopped Albion Park grandfather Keith Watson's lung cancer in its tracks will give many more Australians another chance at life after its listing on the PBS from August 1.
The federal government subsidy will mean the immunotherapy drug Opdivo (nivolumab) will be available at a heavily discounted price for patients with late-stage lung and renal cancer.
Mr Watson, 71, has been involved in a trial of the drug through Southern Medical Day Care Centre in Wollongong for the past 12 months, under the supervision of renowned oncologist Professor Philip Clingan.
''It's not only kept me alive, it lets me have a good lifestyle,'' Mr Watson said. ''I had six rounds of chemotherapy prior to this which left me very ill, and I lost seven kilograms as well as my hair.
''Since I've started on this I've had no side effects, I can keep doing the things I love like playing bowls, and going out with family and friends. Importantly, the progression of my cancer has stopped.''
After a stage four lung cancer diagnosis in January 2015, Mr Watson was given eight months to live, but now has a new lease on life. 

The government subsidy will bring the cost of Opdivo down from around $5000 per treatment to $38.80, or $6.30 for concession card holders.

''This subsidy means lots of other people will have another chance,'' he said.
Prof Clingan said immunotherapy drugs like Opdivo were revolutionising the way many cancer patients were treated.

Groundbreaking: Professor Philip Clingan runs Southern Medical Day Care Centre which has gained an international reputation for its clinical cancer trials. Picture: Adam McLean
''They work by unlocking the patient's own immune system to attack tumours,'' he said. ''In Wollongong we have a lot of first-line trials underway, where immunotherapy is used along with chemotherapy.
''(Opdivo) is a second-line trial, where patients have failed chemotherapy. We've been running this trial for over 12 months and have treated over 70 people.
''We've found it to be far less toxic than chemo and it's effective with patients living much longer, and with a better quality of life.''

READ MORE: Illawarra cancer patients are taking part in global drug trials
Around 8000 Australians die from lung cancer annually, while about 3500 new cases of kidney cancer are diagnosed each year.

Lung Foundation Australia CEO Heather Allan said the PBS listing was welcome news. ''The lack of treatment options, especially in later stages of the disease, has resulted in a significant unmet medical need that had to be addressed.''
The federal government said Opdivo was more effective and safer than current therapies for these late-stage cancers and could improve and extend the life of patients.
''The hardest part of this role is to witness families facing the most tragic of medical diagnoses,'' Health Minister Greg Hunt said.

''The most uplifting is to see breakthroughs that save lives, transform families and give people real hope - and that's exactly what Opdivo does.''

The drug is administered as an intravenous infusion every fortnight, with treatment able to continue for as long as the patient keeps benefiting from it or can no longer tolerate it.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Watson, 71</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foundation Australia CEO Heather Allan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park's Keith Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Medical Day Care Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Watson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Clingan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Greg Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opdivo</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Philip Clingan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
