<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400210920110525</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4823305/theres-no-place-like-the-ocean-for-fisherman-rocco-ianni/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Why Documentaries captures Rocco's fishing tale for Yesterday's Stories</title>
  <content>
There's no place like the ocean for fisherman Rocco Ianni

exit

There was never any doubt Rocco Ianni would follow the family tradition and become a fisherman.

This despite the fact his first experience on a fishing boat, when just two-days-old, was when his family was fleeing war-torn Italy in 1943.

''All my family was in the boat. They took me under the tunnel until the war was over,'' Rocco said.

''But when the war ended and life returned to normal, we were back fishing quick smart.''
We, soon enough included a young Rocco, who would join his father, brothers and relatives fishing in the seaside town of Bagnara, a province of Calabria.

But when love led his older brother to Australia, the rest of the family followed in 1955.

And, before too long the Ianni men, and women, reverted to doing what they love most in the world, fishing.

Today, more than 60 years later, 74-year-old Rocco still takes his beloved trawler, the San Rocco Star out on the waters of Wollongong Harbour trying to catch ''whatever God sends us''.
Rocco's story is being captured by Why Documentaries film-maker Sandra Pires, as part of the Yesterday's Stories project.

VETERAN FISHERMAN: Rocco Ianni has been a professional fisherman for over 50 years. Picture: Sylvia Liber
Mercury photographer Sylvia Liber joined Pires and her crew on Monday as they filmed professional fisherman Rocco in action.
''Rocco has been fishing the area for over 50 years with his family since they migrated from Italy,'' Pires said. ''Rocco and his crew have been going out pretty much everyday for the past 20 years....his is a wonderful story of the history of fishing and how it began out on the harbour.

''We hope to have 50 Wollongong stories to launch soon.''

Yesterday's Stories is a project involving ,  the  and the University of Wollongong.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ianni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bagnara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calabria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocco Ianni</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra Pires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Liber</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocco</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pires</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Rocco Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yesterday's Stories</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
