<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400502977891989</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/world/asia/construction-still-underpinning-chinas-iron-ore-demand-20170731-gxmgbi</url>
  <title>Construction still underpinning China's iron ore demand</title>
  <content>
China's demand for iron ore is being underpinned by a surprisingly resilient construction sector, although the economy is expected to slow over the rest of the year as the government moves to rein in debt.
While growth in business activity across China's factories cooled slightly in July, according to the latest release of the official Purchasing Managers' Index (PMI), the subindex for the construction sector rose to a three-year high.
The construction gauge jumped to 62.5 from 61.4 in June, boosted by government spending on infrastructure and stronger-than-expected property investment despite new regulations to curb runaway prices.
"At the beginning of the year most people had a pessimistic view on the outlook for the property market but that has changed with the stronger data releases," said Qiu Yuecheng, an analyst at steel trading platform Xiben New Line.

The overall PMI for July was 51.4, down from June's 51.7. The drop was partly attributed to high temperatures and flooding in some areas, which disrupted business, the National Bureau of Statistics said on Monday. A figure above 50 indicates activity expanded compared with the previous month.

The construction sector was the highlight and iron ore futures on China's Dalian Commodities Exchange jumped almost 8 per cent on Monday following the release.
"We think the industrial recovery will last longer than what we had expected," said ANZ's senior China economist Betty Rui Wang in a note to clients.
Xu Xiangchuan, from consulting group Mysteel, said iron ore was catching up with recent gains in steel prices, which have been buoyed by central government efforts to reduce overcapacity.
Chinese Premier Li Keqiang said over the weekend the government was committed to its capacity cuts and would ensure closed mills didn't reopen now the sector had returned to profitability.

Iron ore has surged in recent weeks, to more than $US70, and last week . The three-month forecast was raised to $US70 a tonne from $US55, and the year-end target increased by $US5 to $US60. However, next year, prices are still expected to drop.
Zhao Yang, chief China economist at Nomura, said the current strength in China's construction sector wasn't sustainable.
"Construction is still pretty strong and property investment is quite resilient but I don't think it is sustainable and overall there is a slowdown in growth momentum," he said.
"Growth is likely to slow in the second half due to the unfolding impact of the financial deleveraging in the first half as well as uncertainty over external demand."

Still, for now the property sector is holding up with stronger-than-expected sales in June, particularly in smaller cities.
"Early this year, the government launched regulations and everyone thought the weak property market would be the theme running through the year," said Liu Yuan, an analyst at property consulting group Centaline.
"The government plan was to boost infrastructure spending while calming down the property sector.
"However, property sales are unexpectedly holding up in third and fourth tier cities," he said referring to China's smaller cities.

China's economy grew 6.9 per cent in the first and second quarters, above the government's target of "around 6.5 per cent". However, most economists expect growth to slow as purchase restrictions start to have a bigger impact on property investors and Beijing's crack down on financial risks reins in credit growth.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betty Rui Wang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xu Xiangchuan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nomura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liu Yuan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mysteel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centaline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Premier Li Keqiang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qiu Yuecheng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Dalian Commodities Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhao Yang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xiben New Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Purchasing Manager Indices</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 51.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$70</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
