<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400331179197032</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-advice/flights/arianna-huffingtons-advice-on-how-to-get-a-decent-sleep-on-a-longhaul-flight/news-story/25c9e700b92bcd7a69b054ab5742a3b5</url>
  <title>Arianna Huffington's advice on how to get a decent sleep on a long-haul flight</title>
  <content>
Top 10 tips for surviving a long-haul flight
1:07

Take a look at our Top 10 tips for surviving a long-haul flight.

October 4th 2016
10 months ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Lifestyle - syndicated/

Arianna Huffington's advice on how to get a decent sleep on a long-haul flight.

Share

THIS is the big question when it comes to long haul flights - what is the best way to sleep on a plane? Is it even possible to get a decent rest on a flight?
Well, in a , Arianna Huffington, co-founder of the Huffington Post, shared her best advice for getting a bit of shut-eye on a plane. And you can bet she has flown a lot.
Best of all, her advice doesn't involve any tricks or gadgets, just good old fashioned routine. She said getting a good rest while flying starts before you even step foot on a plane - you need to create a flight schedule that fits around your sleep schedule.
"Before you even set foot on the plane, you can create a schedule that better suits your sleep needs," she said.
"My advice, based on what has worked for me through my many travels across multiple time zones, comes down to arranging my schedule so that I have plenty of time for sleep - even if it means building in an extra day for travel.
"I've talked to many executives who fly around the world and go into meetings exhausted, unable to stay awake; they often end up offending people who may have worked for weeks getting presentations ready for that meeting."

Arianna Huffington said creating a flight schedule that better suits your sleep needs is the best way to make sure you don't get off a flight feeling like death. Photo: Andrew Burton/Getty ImagesSource:Getty Images
And to help you stick to schedule, Huffington said you need to make sure you try and emulate your bedtime routine at home, so your body knows it is time to sleep.
"I'm actually a little bit obsessed with trying to do everything I can to make my flights more sleep-friendly. That's because I travel so much, and I've learned over time that a little preparation goes a long way," she said.
"I have my sleeping gear permanently packed in my carry-on: an eye mask, noise-cancelling headphones, earplugs, herbal teas (including lavender and licorice), and my favourite neck pillow."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Burton/Getty ImagesSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huffington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arianna Huffington</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huffington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Lifestyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
