<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400412783577272</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/the-age-editorial/victorias-teacher-watchdog-fails-to-protect-children-20170731-gxmgb1.html</url>
  <title>Victoria's teacher watchdog fails to protect children</title>
  <content>
The regulator responsible for ensuring children are not at risk of abuse from teachers has failed to meet its duty. The Victorian Institute of Teaching says its purpose as a community safety watchdog is "to regulate the teaching profession in Victoria in the public interest by enforcing high ethical and professional standards for teachers".
The VIT has disregarded its mission in a case that a group of disillusioned parents has forced to be reopened. A month ago, the institute stunned the parents and perturbed the Education Minister, James Merlino, by not revoking the licence of a grade 4 teacher who told students disturbing stories including one revolting example, about a little girl being "urinated" on in a toilet by a priest, as well as tales of incest, murder and persecution.Photo: Quentin Jones
The teacher also paid children for massages in class. A particularly troubling element of the case is that he instructed his students they must not tell their parents or others about the stories.
As The Age's education team, Henrietta Cook and Timna Jacks, revealed, the VIT made its finding even after the Education Department, following an 18-month investigation, sacked the teacher, who had been suspended in late 2015 from Caulfield Junior College. The department's finding that the teacher had acted in a "disgraceful, improper" manner was central to the Fair Work Commission rejecting his claim he was unfairly dismissed.
It is concerning that there is such a divide between the Education Department's views on who is a fit person to teach in state schools and who the VIT deems to be a suitable teacher, as they could still work in non-government schools.
The VIT's failure is not limited to this case. An independent review was ordered this year, for example, into a case involving a teacher it twice declared fit to teach, despite his admission to indecently assaulting a former student. The findings have not been released.

The VIT, which exists under state legislation, publishes key findings from disciplinary hearings and also publishes a list of every teacher who is deregistered and suspended from being able to teach.
But there needs to be more transparency around its decision-making process.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The initial report into this teacher was not published online, so there was no way a school checking references could learn of these serious concerns.
A more transparent and public process would not compromise the reputations of those teachers who are exonerated. But it would provide greater scrutiny of those we entrust with one of the state's most important jobs - teaching our children.

A note from the editor - Subscribers can get Age editor Alex Lavelle's exclusive weekly newsletter delivered to their inbox by signing up here: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Lavelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Institute of Teaching</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quentin Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield Junior College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIT</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Department</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henrietta Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timna Jacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Merlino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
