<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400374128870880</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/soccer/bill-shorten-calls-for-state-funeral-for-football-icon-les-murray-20170731-gxmh6y.html</url>
  <title>Bill Shorten calls for state funeral for football icon Les Murray</title>
  <content>
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten has called for Les Murray to be awarded a state funeral, labelling the football broadcaster a "national icon" for his role in promoting multiculturalism in Australia. 
Murray died on Monday morning aged 71 after a lengthy battle with illness. Shorten has urged NSW premier Gladys Berejiklian to acknowledge his services to the community with a prestigious memorial service reserved for Australia's most distinguished citizens. 

Up Next

Did McGuire intentionally stomp Mannah?

00:29

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

The best of Les Murray

Iconic SBS football presenter Les Murray AM has passed away following a battle with illness. Courtesy SBS

"I sincerely hope the state government offers Les Murray's family a state funeral and I certainly think they should," Mr Shorten said. "Les is a national icon who did so much to grow the world game and to champion multicultural Australia. He deserves nothing less than the full symphony of tribute and respect. Ultimately it's a decision for Les' family, but I think the offer should be made at least. I can think of few people as deserving of this high honour."
Murray rose to fame during a 34-year career with SBS where he worked as a football commentator, pundit and journalist beginning with the 1980 National Soccer League grand final until the 2014 FIFA World Cup in Brazil. 

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull praised his work in promoting the global game in Australia, opening the world to living rooms and using football as a means of telling world stories. 
"Farewell Les Murray," Mr Turnbull said. "You championed the beautiful game - the world game - over so many years. You and Johnny Warren really made the world game Australia's game."

Football Federation Australia chairman Steven Lowy praised the work of Murray who was inducted into the FFA hall of fame in 2003.
"He made an immense contribution to football in Australia through his professional work but above all through his passion ... he literally brought the game to millions and connected us to the biggest sport in the world.Photo: Anthony Johnson
Western Sydney Wanderers will hold a minute's silence in Murray's honour before Tuesday's FFA Cup match against Wellington Phoenix at Campbelltown Stadium. Players, coaches and staff will also be wearing black armbands in honour of a man former NSL and A-League coach Branko Culina says gave the game its greatest respect. 
During decades when the National Soccer League was shunned from the mainstream, Murray continued to tell the story of migrants through the lens of sport. He pushed for the game's acceptance in the broader society and used his role at SBS to tell the world's stories through football. 
Photo gallery
"There were a lot of people who contributed greatly, but nobody at a time who contributed so much when it needed it the most," Culina said. "In difficult times when the game didn't get a great deal of exposure, he was tireless to make sure it got the push it needed."
Murray's passion for the game and the role it played in multiculturalism in Australia was captured best by an article he wrote in 1999. As referenced in The Death and Life of Australian Soccer by author Joe Gorman, nobody prophesied the future of the game and its role with migrants better than Murray. 
"The clubs they will replace will die, some faster than others. Their memories will be the plaques in their honour in community halls. Some will live on as state league or amateur clubs, playing in stadiums built with unselfish passion for a more extravagant future, with a handful of ageing fans, out of sentimental duty, watching them," he said. "The saddest part will be that the new clubs, soccer's new era, will make hay from the foundations these clubs made. And soon nobody will remember them."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Culina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Branko Culina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday's FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney Wanderers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Soccer League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington Phoenix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Lowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIFA World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Gorman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life of Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
