<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400545927565701</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/special-reports/trailblazers/corporate-values-integral-to-longterm-success-20170728-gxl37g</url>
  <title>Corporate values integral to long-term success</title>
  <content>
by
Andrew Birmingham

This content is produced by The Australian Financial Review in commercial partnership with Salesforce. 
You often hear the argument made that values-based is necessary to build sustainable profitability. But does the performance of Uber and some other companies suggest otherwise?
Recently, Uber has come under sustained fire on multiple fronts regarding its values, especially for its treatment of female staff. A number of senior staff have left the business recently.
Yet the alleged harassment occurred during the period when Uber was rapidly building global scale.

So does Uber's success suggest that real disruption means checking your decency at the boardroom door?

Not at all, according to the participants in The Australian Financial Review Salesforce Trailblazers round table discussion on the impact of leaders on growth.
Expert360 co-founder Bridget Loudon said "If you actually dig deep and ask, 'Why? Why did it start costing them money?' It's because their customers were not attracted to those values, right?"
Indeed, as Uber's problems have filtered into public consciousness in the US, its market share has started to fall, dropping from 84 per cent at the start of the year to 77 per cent at the end of May. In many ways rival has positioned itself as a different style of business.
Loudon sees similarities between Uber's troubles and in the backlash against some venture companies who have also have had some high profile resignations.

The message for companies seems to be that consumers, will accept a little bit of lawlessness - but only to a point. There is a threshold of poor corporate behaviour that overrides hip-pocket concerns.
Loudon said values will be important to success in future. "I think values-driven leaders are the leaders who will succeed. Ultimately that's the glue that holds an organisation together Companies are looking for values. 'Do I believe in accountability? Do I communicate well? Do I act with integrity?' All these kind of questions are important.
"I think leaders need to be very clear about what those values are, and set them from the top down," she said.
"The point on Uber was somebody spoke up," says Eileen O'Mara, senior Vice President of Salesforce APAC. "And that's really important. Transparency is a great leadership characteristic. It is really important in ensuring that you create an environment where people feel counted and accountable. "

Jim McKerlie, founder of Bambu Digital, suggested the failings of Uber's leaders hinted at a core weakness at the top: a lack of genuine empathy. "Sustainable change requires empathy," he argued.
He said Uber clearly is very successful at systematising process and knowledge. It had a very good customer-centric system. However, "the company tolerated bad behaviour at the top, and the system seemed strong enough to manage that until it wasn't. Then the behaviour became an abscess and had to be dealt with."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loudon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President of Salesforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridget Loudon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bambu Digital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salesforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim McKerlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eileen O'Mara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review Salesforce Trailblazers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
