<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400331179196992</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/aymen-terkmani-on-trial-for-murder-and-sexual-assault-of-teenager-in-fairfield-20170731-gxmbp7.html</url>
  <title>Aymen Terkmani on trial for murder and sexual assault of teenager in Fairfield</title>
  <content>
The last time a 16-year-old boy ever spoke to his parents, he was "slower and quieter" than usual and whispered down the phone as if  "he was trying to hide something".
The teenager, who rode his bike to meet a friend on the evening of May 16, 2015, gave his mother the address for "Aymen's house" before the phone call cut out.Photo: Supplied
When the teenager didn't return home his family spent all night searching for him, before his body was found the next day, lying in a pool of blood in the hallway of a vacant house in Fairfield East.
Aymen Terkmani, 24, is charged with the murder and aggravated sexual assault of the boy, who cannot be named for legal reasons. He has pleaded not guilty.
Crown prosecutor Adrian Robertson told the NSW Supreme Court the boy was allegedly beaten with implements in the house, including a toaster and a rolling pin.
He suffered injuries including a fractured skull, brain damage, a fractured rib and a collapsed lung.

"The accused inflicted numerous and severe injuries, and he did so with severe force," Mr Robertson told the jury of five women and seven men on Monday.
The boy had asked his father if he could go to McDonald's in Villawood instead of going to a family dinner, and later rang to say he was going to a friend's house for half an hour, the court heard.
CCTV footage from McDonald's showed the teenager and Mr Terkmani sitting in a ute about 6.20pm.
When the boy had not returned to his family's house in Fairfield East after 9pm, his father, mother and brother called him and told him to come home.
During a call at 9.42pm, the boy's mother said she would pick him up, but the call "cut out abruptly" when he told her the address.
The family searched for the teenager, reported him missing to police, and went to Mr Terkmani's house, where a family member saw the boy's bicycle.
Mr Terkmani said he'd been with the teenager, but they parted ways about 7.30pm and he stayed home for the rest of the night.
"The Crown case is that the accused lied about leaving the deceased ... and this was a deliberate lie about a significant matter," Mr Robertson said.
"On the Crown case, this was a lie told with a consciousness of guilt in having killed the deceased."
Mr Robertson said the case against Mr Terkmani was circumstantial, but DNA from the vacant house, bloodied footprints, CCTV footage, and the boy's bike all linked him to the murder.
Defence barrister Mark Austin said Mr Terkmani denied being at the vacant house that night.
"You need to treat [Mr Terkmani] as though he's innocent, until you as a jury find beyond reasonable doubt that he's guilty," Mr Austin said.
The trial continues before Justice Lucy McCallum.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villawood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Lucy McCallum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Robertson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Terkmani</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aymen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aymen Terkmani, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield East</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aymen Terkmani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
