<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400502977892045</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/opinion/columnists/direct-talk-needed-on-terror-threat-not-just-extra-airport-security-20170731-gxm2hp</url>
  <title>We need direct talk on the terror threat not just extra airport security</title>
  <content>
I follow instructions and arrive at Melbourne airport much earlier than normal to catch my flight. But other than the very visible presence of the Australian Federal Police and new signs directing passengers, I notice little difference in procedures in the .
A friendly security guard tells me I have hit a rare midday lull in the queues for screening.
"The lines were winding all over the place and nearly out the door earlier this morning," he says.
And presumably Australians will have to get used to the need for extra time and waiting around at airports. That's supposedly in exchange for feeling less vulnerable whenever they board a flight.

Whether that feeling of greater safety is justified or just another illusion can really only be answered definitively in the worst possible way.

What is clear is the threat can never be eliminated and that there are still plenty of weaknesses in the system. I wonder idly how long it will be that people are still permitted to take computers and phones on board and what that will mean.
Whenever I get on a plane, I do appreciate rationally that the risks of me not getting off at the other end are infinitesimal.
Sense of dread

But with every potential "incident" that occurs in the air or on the ground, I temporarily share in that broader emotive sense of dread about the prospects of random terrorism at home. It's no longer something terrible that happens somewhere else.

Even without headlines screaming "Sky High Evil", the details about the plan to bring down a passenger plane reinforce the Prime Minister's message that "there are no borders".
"Nowhere is far away from anywhere else nowadays," Malcolm Turnbull said on Monday. "In an age of the internet and the age of social media and the age of over the internet messaging applications, Syria is not a long way from Sydney."
The federal government says the security agencies have disrupted 13 serious terror plots in the three years since the threat level was raised to "probable" and that 70 people have been charged as a result of 31 counter-terrorism operations.
This is supposed to be reassuring - as well as alarming. But while Australian security agencies may be good and getting better, they only have to fail once against a threat that is still spreading in passionate intensity if not sophistication. A meat grinder? Knives? Trucks?

That makes international cooperation between agencies to try to thwart this more vital than ever. Although the government won't confirm it, the information triggering the arrests is supposed to have come from a foreign intelligence agency.
Yet that's happening at a time when the Trump era of constant turmoil shows little evidence of coordinated strategy about anything while the British are dealing with their own political confusion on everything from Brexit to the stability of a now fragile Conservative government.
Nowhere immune

Add in what seems to be the now regular testing of intercontinental ballistic missiles by North Korea and the anger of Vladimir Putin about US sanctions leading to unpredictable forms of retaliation. It's little wonder the world seems a particularly dangerous and volatile place - with nowhere immune.

Australians will still focus most on managing the domestic pressures of their daily lives, of course, with little apparent relevance to the chances of being blown up.
The government will sell its new "homeland" style department to coordinate security as helping to "keep Australians safe". But the news of yet another local terrorism plot also demonstrates the reality that "nowhere is far away from anywhere else" affects public sentiment.
And whether it's expanded police powers or Muslim immigration, Chinese investment or promoting local jobs, the result is a national mood increasingly protectionist and risk-averse.
The police explain that when dealing with terrorism threats, for example, they may act before they have all the pieces of the puzzle together. Most Australians are happy for them to do so, no matter the cost to any principles of civil liberties and the presumption of innocence.

With some notable exceptions, however, most political leaders will still be trying to calm community fears rather than exacerbate them.
Donald Trump may have offended large swathes of the Muslim world as well as many American citizens with his various attempts to impose restrictions on Muslim immigrants or tourists from certain countries.
Yet most Western leaders are still trying to hold together their multi-ethnic and increasingly Muslim domestic populations rather than stoke divisions.
Rare unity ticket

Witness the victory of Emmanuel Macron in France, the expectation Angela Merkel will be re-elected Chancellor of Germany and the election of Sadiq Khan, a Muslim, as London Mayor.
So Malcolm Turnbull will be on a rare unity ticket with Bill Shorten in emphasising that radical Islam is a perversion of the Muslim faith and appeals to only a tiny minority, most of them born here.
But even without Tony Abbott prodding from behind, Turnbull knows an Australian government can no longer avoid referring specifically to "Islamic" terrorism and must address head-on the failure of a percentage of Muslims to integrate into Australian society.
This is just one element of the new political fashion demanding more direct talk from political leaders about the concerns of those they seek to govern.

Resigned community acceptance of more politics-as-usual has changed dramatically in Australia as it has elsewhere. Mainstream politicians are belatedly recognising they must adjust to that change to have any appeal to voters.
So when just boarding a plane or attending a concert or sitting in crowded bars can make a lot of Australians apprehensive they could become possible terrorist targets, the political system and its rhetoric must adjust too. The future awaits, impatiently.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sadiq Khan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chancellor of Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky High Evil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emmanuel Macron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Merkel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
