<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400803625608016</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4824521/turnbull-says-mps-have-right-to-cross-floor-on-same-sex-marriage/?cs=4219</url>
  <title>Turnbull says MPs have right to cross floor on same-sex marriage</title>
  <content>
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull in Parliament.  Photo: Alex Ellinghausen

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has indicated he would be comfortable with backbench MPs crossing the floor to legalise same-sex marriage, saying the right to break with party policy is a "fundamental principle" of the Liberal Party.
Mr Turnbull was speaking after two Liberal backbenchers, Trevor Evans and Tim Wilson, left open the possibility of crossing the floor to force a vote on same-sex marriage.
"In our party, backbenchers have always had the right to cross the floor," Mr Turnbull said, when asked if he could prevent Mr Evans from siding with the Labor opposition.
"In the Labor Party, you get expelled for doing that. 
"In our party, backbenchers have always had the right to cross the floor," Mr Turnbull said, when asked if he could prevent Mr Evans from siding with the Labor opposition.
"In the Labor Party, you get expelled for doing that. 
"It's always been a fundamental principle in the Liberal Party and indeed, the National Party.
"So it's a very different political culture to the very authoritarian Labor Party."
Mr Turnbull did not repeat his usual statements that a plebiscite must be held before any vote in Parliament, although government sources say this remains his position.
A Liberal MP who supports same-sex marriage said he was "sure" his colleagues would interpret Mr Turnbull's comments as permission to cross the floor.

Victorian Liberal MP Tim Wilson is one of several Liberal MPs pushing for a free vote on same-sex marriage. Photo: Alex Ellinghausen

The legalisation of same-sex marriage without a plebiscite is seen as a potential threat to Mr Turnbull's leadership because of the fury it would likely unleash among Liberal conservatives. 
The issue could flare up as early as next week when Parliament resumes after a long winter break. 
"We do not support a bill relating to gay marriage being brought on until there was a vote of the Australian people," Mr Turnbull said last month. "We will not support a vote in the Parliament until there has been a plebiscite."
The first preference among moderate Liberal MPs is to use a private member's bill drafted by WA senator Dean Smith as a trigger for the party room to allow a conscience vote on the issue. 
If this fails, three MPs could bring on a vote in the House of Representatives by crossing the floor in support of a Labor motion to suspend standing orders.
Mr Wilson, who is gay, said he wanted to see same-sex marriage dealt with soon. 
"When you look at my party I think it's in our best interests to move on from this issue so we can focus on the things that I think people voted for me and for my party to deal with: tax reform, fixing the budget, national security, making sure that we stop terrorism," he told Sky News on Monday.
"I am going to talk to my parliamentary colleagues, to my community, as well as to my party members over the next few weeks and talk to them directly about the challenge we face, and let's be frank, the personal tensions I have on this issue. 
"I always said politely that the plebiscite wasn't my first preference for a way to deal with this issue."
Mr Wilson said he and his colleagues had "discharged" his responsibility to the plebiscite by supporting the legislation to enact it last year.
Mr Evans, who was elected the Member for Brisbane at last year's federal election, told Fairfax Radio: "I hope we can do this quickly in a business-like fashion so we can refocus on other priorities.
"Lots of people are speaking up and saying, 'We need a new way forward'."
Mr Evans said the election promise to hold a plebiscite was no longer tenable. 
"Our policy wasn't a stalemate," he said. "The point of the plebiscite was to deal with the issue by February.
"When a reform path is blocked for a government you find a new way to get it done. 
"This is a good government achieving real, tangible things - this issue is distracting us from all of those achievements and we just need to get on with it." 
Mr Evans said the time had passed for alternatives such as a postal plebiscite and that a free vote in Parliament was the best option. 
Australian Marriage Equality chair Alex Greenwich said: "There seem to be a number of Coalition MPs - Trevor Evans, Jason Wood, Dean Smith, Tim Wilson - who all seem to have clearly identified that this is now the time to move forward on marriage equality.

"The comments of the Prime Minister should be no surprise - they're in line not only with the Coalition's policy, they're in line with what the former prime minister Tony Abbott said when he said the previous Parliament would be the last one in which MPs would be bound."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Liberal MP Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Marriage Equality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Greenwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Evans</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
