<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400722021228017</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/19/01/coles-boss-says-cost-of-living-crisis-forcing-families-to-choose-between-food-and-bills</url>
  <title>Coles boss says cost of living crisis forcing families to choose between</title>
  <content>
The boss of one of Australia's major supermarket chains has declared Australian families are doing it tougher than ever, with families now forced to choose between food and the household bills.
Coles managing director John Durkan told A Current Affair that families were hurting from increasing costs in utilities and child care, and from stagnant wages.
He said the end result was that families were sacrificing fresh food.
"The worrying thing I'm seeing now is that customers are having to trade off food versus things like utilities," he said.
"They're no longer making decisions (such as) 'do I go on holiday or not'."
New research by the University of Melbourne has revealed the expenses faced by families in a year.
Housing costs such as water and power, rates and mortgage repayments, add up to about $30,000.

Related Articles

Food expenses for an average family of four run to $8700 - more than was spent on cars, and on financial services such as insurance and ambulance membership.
In total, households needed $50,000 a year just to cover the cost of living.
This is coupled with the lowest wage growth on Australia's record.
News Corp cost of living editor John Rolfe said between 2000 and 2010, real wage increases were steady at about three percent.
"And then in 2011 that just stopped, but prices kept rising - albeit moderately," he said.
"And what that's meant is your standard of living is in face going backwards."
In the past five years, it has been households in the outer suburbs of major cities, and in regional areas, that have been most at risk when it comes to cost of living stress.
In Melbourne, families in Wyndham and Dandenong are struggling more than others, while in Sydney households in Fairfield and Cumberland are most affected.
Families in regional Queensland, especially the far north of the state, are also doing it tough.
Mr Durkan said Coles was trying to respond to customer budgeting woes, pouring $200 million into price cuts in the past six months.
He said it was also a priority for the chain to convince consumers that switching from premium brands to Coles's cheaper private label, did not entail a cut on quality.
"We can sell it at cheaper prices and of course the volumes we sell these products at will continue to bring the prices down," he said.
"So our message is, really trust the quality."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Durkan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyndham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cumberland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Current Affair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Rolfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Durkan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
