<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400760675934323</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/world/venezuelan-officials-killed-as-voting-starts/news-story/fc18d965654b5cd284e0df036b9d65a2</url>
  <title>Venezuela's 'new era of combat'</title>
  <content>
VENEZUELA's unpopular president Nicolas Maduro has vowed he will begin a "new era of combat" as his crisis-stricken nation battles in the streets over a controversial vote.
Deadly protests have rocked Venezuela as voters broadly boycotted an election for a constitutional super-body that many fear will herald a move into dictatorship.
Anti-Maduro activists wearing hoods or masks erected barricades on roads, and scuffles broke out with security forces who moved in quickly to disperse demonstrators who denounced the election as a naked power grab.
Authorities said nine people have been killed in the weekend confrontations. The opposition said the true death toll was around 12.TIME OF TURMOIL
The weekend of violence has seen a motorcycle motorcade bombed, leading political candidates and activists shot and riot police opening fire on angry crowds.
"This is war!" Caracas resident Conchita Ramirez exclaimed on television as she described troops firing at buildings and people in the capital.
The fiery unrest confirmed fears over the vote for a new "Constituent Assembly" called by teh beleaguered presidence in defiance of months of demonstrations and fierce international criticism.
He is gambling his four-year rule on the 545-member citizens' body that will be empowered to dissolve the opposition-controlled congress and change laws.
Maduro, widely disliked for overseeing an unravelling of Venezuela's economy, has promised the assembly will bring peace by way of a new constitution after four months of opposition protests in which about 120 people have been killed.
But opposition parties sat out the election, saying it was rigged to increase Maduro's powers, a view shared by governments including those of Colombia, Argentina and the US.
US Ambassador to the United Nations Nikki Haley tweeted "Maduro's sham election is another step toward dictatorship. We won't accept an illegit govt."CARNAGE IN THE STREETS
In eastern Caracas on Sunday, seven soldiers were wounded when an improvised explosive targeted their motorbike convoy. The tightly clustered force of motorcycles was attempting to drive into - and disperse - a crowd of protesters blocking a key avenue.
But the most dramatic incident was the targeted killing of a candidate for the new constitutional body in Venezuela's southeastern town of Ciudad Bolivar.
Jose Felix Pineda, a 39-year-old lawyer, was killed from multiple shots fired by assailants who broke into his home overnight, prosecutors said.
The lawyer was the second candidate to be murdered, after the July 10 death of another, Jose Luis Rivas, as he was campaigning in the northern city of Maracay.
Protesters are also among the dead.
A 13-year-old and a 17-year-old were shot and killed overnight. The first victim was killed in the town of Capacho Viejo and the other in Tucape, both in the western state of Tachira on the border with Colombia, prosecutors said.
A Venezuelan soldier was also shot dead. The victim was shot in the face when clashes broke out between protesters and security forces in the western town of La Grita, near the border with Colombia.
The death toll also included a 30-year-old regional leader of a youth opposition party in the northeast town of Cumana and two protesters in the western state of Merida.
More than 100 people have been killed in the past four months amid unrest triggered by the president's bid to rewrite the constitution.NATIONAL UPRISING
In the west of the capital Caracas, national guard troops have fanned out, using armoured vehicles, rubber bullets and teargas to disperse protesters blocking roads.
Video posted on Twitter showed troops smashing down a metal gate and entering to the sounds of gunfire, and what appeared to be an armoured vehicle on fire.
Soldiers also violently moved against protesters in the second city of Maracaibo, in the west, and Puerto Ordaz in the east.
The opposition has called for a boycott and mass demonstrations against the election, which it calls a bid by Maduro to install a dictatorship with the backing of the military.BATTLE AT THE BALLOT
President Maduro kicked off voting by casting his ballot in a west Caracas polling station.
"I'm the first voter in the country. I ask God for his blessings so the people can freely exercise their democratic right to vote," the president said. He was accompanied by his wife, Cilia Flores, who is a candidate to sit on the new assembly.
Turnout will be key to determining the legitimacy of the election. But that will be difficult to ascertain as most voters will be able to vote twice, as candidates are drawn from social and industry sectors as well as geographically.
Surveys by Datanalisis, a pro-opposition polling firm, show more than 70 per cent of Venezuelans opposed the idea of the new assembly - and 80 per cent reject Maduro's leadership.
Maduro decreed a ban on protests during and after the vote, threatening prison terms of up to 10 years for anyone violating the order.
Maduro has described the election as the most important Venezuela has seen, and the Constituent Assembly a "card that will win this game."
"I have come to vote to tell the gringos and the opposition that we want peace, not war, and that we support Maduro," said voter Ana Contreras.
The head of Datanalisis, Luis Vicente Leon, said the Constituent Assembly was being formed because the uncharismatic Maduro - whose term is meant to finish next year - "can't win elections."INTERNATIONAL ALARM
Fear of Venezuela's violence worsening has rippled across the region, and beyond. The US, the EU and Latin American powers, including Argentina, Brazil, Colombia and Mexico, have come out against the election, saying it would destroy Venezuelan democracy.
Several foreign airlines, including Air France, Delta, Avianca and Iberia have suspended flights to the country over security concerns.
The US has ordered the families of its diplomats to leave after imposing sanctions on 13 current and former Venezuelan officials.
Colombia, Panama and Peru - refuges for tens of thousands of Venezuelans fleeing the chaos at home - have said they will not recognise the results of the election.
The US has suggested further sanctions could follow. The oil industry is worried they could target Venezuela's crude exports, 40 per cent of which are bought by the United States.
Some in Maduro's administration have broken ranks with him, most prominently his Attorney-General. Two diplomats resigned this week in dissent: one at the United Nations and another at the embassy in Panama.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iberia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cumana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BATTLE AT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capacho Viejo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Luis Rivas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puerto Ordaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conchita Ramirez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avianca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Datanalisis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Felix Pineda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATIONAL UPRISING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tucape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constituent Assembly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Vicente Leon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Grita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INTERNATIONAL ALARM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Ambassador</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cilia Flores</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maracaibo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maracay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ana Contreras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ciudad Bolivar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tachira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Nikki Haley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TIME OF TURMOIL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
