<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400717726260649</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/19/09/mum-claims-squatters-locked-her-out-of-her-home</url>
  <title>Mum says she was locked out of her own home as</title>
  <content>
A single mother hoping to rent out some rooms in her house to help pay her mortgage claims it soon turned to hell when a group of squatters kicked her out of her own home.
Homeowner Alesha told A Current Affair that she had advertised for some renters on Gumtree.
She said one respondent, Tania Anderson, claimed she urgently needed a place for her and her daughter to stay.
Alesha agreed to let them rent a room for three weeks, and has received three weeks' worth of rent for two rooms.
However, she said, six weeks later Ms Anderson remained in the house, and had effectively kicked her out.
Alesha said not long after Ms Anderson moved in, she had to go away for a period.
When she returned, she said she found there were strangers in her house, she was refused entry and that the locks were changed.

Related Articles

Alesha said she had been forced to sleep in her car while strangers lived in the property she has owned for seven years.
"I only gave them permission for three weeks to stay," Alesha said.
"They didn't pay me so they have no right to stay on my property."
When A Current Affair attended the property with Alesha, the alleged squatters threatened to call the police.
Real estate agent Grant Stephens sold Alesha the property and is now trying to help get her home back.
"There are a couple of fairly scary customers in the home so it's something that is quite daunting for a lady from China, at her age, with her health and her language limitations," he said.
"It's a harrowing story and not something you usually see in this area."
Another woman who rented a room at Alesha's house, Rachael, said she had also been locked out - but her possessions remained at the property.
She said the alleged squatters were "lower than low".
Alesha has gone to the Queensland Civil and Administrative Tribunal, which normally handles property disputes.
However, QCAT said they were unable to help as it was a dispute over renting rooms, not renting an entire property - thus making it a police matter.
"I don't know how I can meet bad people like this," Alesha said.
Following A Current Affair's visit, the squatters have left the house.
However, Alesha claims there is damage to the property and that some of her belongings are missing.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumtree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Anderson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alesha</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Current Affair</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Stephens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QCAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tania Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Civil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Administrative Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
