<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400593172206801</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4824467/yes-please-wests-members-flock-to-support-takeover-of-knights/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Yes please: Wests members flock to support takeover of Knights</title>
  <content>
FOR the second time in six years, Novocastrians have flocked to the ballot box for a vote that is expected to make or break the city's much-loved but embattled rugby league flagship.
In March, 2011, 97 per cent of Knights members endorsed a privatisation bid by Nathan Tinkler, only for the one-time billionaire to take the club from bad to worse during a now-infamous reign of error.
More than three years after ousting Tinkler and agreeing to fund the Knights on an interim basis, the NRL has struck a deal to hand ownership over to the Wests Group.
All that is needed for the proposal to be signed and sealed is for Wests members to provide the group's directors with an overwhelming mandate.
Between Monday and Sunday (this week), Wests' 90,000 full-membership contituents are being urged to make their vote count at the touch-screen polling booths installed at the group's five licensed establishments.

IN FAVOUR: Wests members Lois Kenny Fogg are supporting the club's plans to take over the Knights.
Wests Group chief executive Phil Gardner said on day one of the ballot a "couple of thousand" members had voted, most pressing the "yes" option.
"It's been really positive,'' Gardner said.

"We've had lots and lots of people coming into vote. Lots of interest. Overwhelmingly it's been positive at this stage."
"I've been surprised at how supportive the regular patrons are. The regular, everyday users of the club have been really supportive. It's been fantastic. 
"I think we'll probably get a couple of thousand votes today, which is good. It's a great representation and we'll certainly get a fantastic sample by the end of the week."
Gardner said Wests had mailed 60,000 houses and sent 38,000 emails to inform members about this week's vote. 
"We've got a line for questions and I've been answering them myself,'' he said. 
"People would probably like more information on where it sits, but there's only so much information you can provide because the information we have with the National Rugby League is confidential at this stage until the next stage is actually taken. 
"The board will have a meeting on Monday, and they'll get all the information and they'll have to make a decision. By Tuesday [next week] everybody will know what's happened."   

Knights coach Nathan Brown said he would "definitely be voting ... and I'll be voting the way that I hope many others do."
"We need the Wests members to get out there and support what Wests want to do,'' Brown said.
"That, certainly, as a club, gives us our best chance to move forward.
"It offers so much stability ... having someone with Wests' credibility, and the ability to build a nice sporting complex, I think all of these things have such a big impact now and on the team in the future.

"I know when you talk to people away from the Knights, if the Wests thing does go through, like we all hope, the credibility it brings the club, players coming here will be much easier to attract.''
New Lambton's Lois and Ken Fogg are both long-time Knights supporters and in favour of a Wests takeover.
"I wouldn't have missed it,'' Lois said.

"We've been going to games here since they first started in 1988 ... a few people have asked questions about it but I think it will be good for Newcastle. Why wouldn't it be?

"I can't see why it won't work." 
It wasn't all one-way traffic with one member, who asked to remain anonymous, questioning the move. 
"There hasn't been much information,'' he said.

"Rugby league clubs are a bottomless pit. 
"I don't understand why that want to do it. 
"It's not as if they are a particularly strong team and It's going to take a lot of money to make them a strong team."
"I worry about how it will affect [Wests] members."
The Herald was told that at Wests Mayfield "hundreds" of members had voted, and only "perhaps only five or six" were against the takeover.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Fogg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Tinkler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gardner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March, 2011, 97</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Lambton's Lois</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lois Kenny Fogg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Novocastrians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Mayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinkler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests' 90,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
