<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400588877239380</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4822961/olyroo-sets-sights-on-winning-starting-spot/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Olyroo sets sights on winning starting spot</title>
  <content>
MOTIVATED: Lachlan Jackson (right) and Nigel Boogaard at Jets training on Monday. Fresh from a successful Olyroos campaign, Jackson is aiming to win a spot in the Jets starting side. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

ERNIE Merrick does his homework.
A former physical education teacher, the Jets coach leaves little to chance. He studies videos, details strengths and weaknesses and makes informed assessments.
When he joined the Jets in May, Merrick had a deep understanding of the players at the club and had identified the areas that needed strengthening.
It didn't take a scholar to determine that the Jets conceded too many goals last season (53) and didn't score enough (28).
Merrick added proven performers Nikolai Topor-Stanley and Daniel Georgievski in defence and beefed up their arsenal with Roy O'Donovan and Dimi Petratos.

Olyroo sets sights on winning starting spot

exit
Lachlan Jackson was one of the contracted players who grabbed the Scotsman's attention. While Topor-Stanley and captain Nigel Boogaard will spearhead the back four, Jackson features heavily in Merrick's plans.
"Lachlan hasn't really impressed me because I have always been impressed by him," Merrick said. "I watched video of him last season. Technically he is good - he has a great left foot - and he is very fast. His pace gets him out of a lot of trouble at the back." 
Jackson, along with Jets teammates Nick Cowburn and Devante Clut, earlier this month helped steer the Olyroos in a successful qualifying campaign for the under-23 Asian Cup to be held in China in January.
The 196cm Jackson partnered captain Jonathan Aspro in the heart of defence in wins over Singapore (7-0) and Myanmar (3-0).
"Singapore was my first national-team cap," Jackson said. "It was a good experience and I am looking to get in the squad for China. Josep Gombau (Olyroos coach) likes to play attacking football, which is good. He likes the centrebacks to get on the ball and create things. It is similar to the way Ernie wants to play. They slot in nicely beside each other."
Buoyed by the Olyroos experience, Jackson, who has made 35 appearances in the past two seasons, is now focused on winning a starting spot at the Jets.
Boogaard will have hit first hit out of the pre-season against Maitland at Cooks Square Park on Wednesday night.
"I need to play well in the pre-season and continue to get as much game time as I can," Jackson said. "It's good to learn and compete against Nigel and Nikolai. After every training you compare yourself to them and strive to be better than them."

Merrick said Jackson performed "really well" in the 2-0 loss to the Mariners last week and has not ruled out using him as a fullback.
"I think he could play left back," Merrick said. "We would play a slightly different system. I don't expect him to bomb up and down, even though he has the pace to do it."

Merrick will use the clash against Maitland as a dress rehearsal for the FFA Cup.
"If it is just about beating a team who are playing at a lower level, that is not good enough," he said. "The eleven that starts are the ones who are training the best. Then it is us to everyone else to force their way in."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Cowburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Topor-Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Aspro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Jackson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dimi Petratos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikolai Topor-Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotsman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Boogaard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devante Clut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrick</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josep Gombau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie Merrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikolai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooks Square Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Georgievski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olyroo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy O'Donovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boogaard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
