<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400597467174160</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/father-of-triathlon-garth-prowd-dies-after-cycling-accident/news-story/63d4c29cb30b9f60b0d0ce4b24e3acd8</url>
  <title>Prowd, father of triathlon, dies</title>
  <content>
The triathlon community is in shock today following the tragic death of the sport's godfather Garth Prowd, the man who turned the Noosa triathlon into the biggest event of its type in the Southern Hemisphere.
Mr Prowd, 65, was cycling alone in Barcelona while on holidays with his family nine days ago when he fell from his bike.
He was critically injured and taken to hospital where he remained in a critical care unit until he passed away yesterday.
His family have released a statement this morning confirming his death.
It said in part: "Garth passed away peacefully surrounded by his family - his greatest love - wife Robyn, daughters Sally, Megan, Katie and son-in-law's Matt and Ben.
"He was a loving husband, father, grandfather, brother and friend to many and his loss will be felt by all who knew him.
"While we mourn the loss of a truly remarkable man, we will remember his incredible life and his contribution to Australian sport.
"He was a man who revolutionised triathlon, running and cycling events in Australia, who was himself an enthusiastic sportsman.
"Garth was widely renowned as 'one of a kind' for so many reasons. He loved music, sport, cars, motorbikes, surfing and most of all his family and friends.''

You get to meet some amazing people in sport. None better than Garth "Mr Noosa" Prowd. Gone way too early.

Mr Prowd was the managing director of USM Events, based in Noosa, for almost 30 years, turning the Noosa triathlon and multi-sport festival into a huge annual event patronised not only by many of the world's top triathletes, but road cyclists, swimmers and runners.
Mr Prowd and his local staff ran the Noosa triathlon almost like an extended family. It was his personal touch that distinguished his organisation from all others and which made him one of them most-loved and successful event organisers in the country.

RIP . Such a loss to family, friends and sport. You will be remembered and you will be missed.

His death will send reverberations through the wider sporting community. He was a friend to many leading current and former athletes, including Mark Webber, Robbie McEwen and Emma Snowsill.
Mr Prowd sold his company in 2009 and the Noosa Triathlon is now run by the World Triathlon Corporation (Ironman) but he was still to be found officiating at the finishing line as recently as last year.
During his tenure USM Events developed and managed a range of triathlon, running and cycling events, both at elite and community level.
Mr Prowd was awarded the Australian Sports Medal in 2000 and was nominated for Australian of the Year in 2004. He also received a Medal of the Order of Australia in 2005 for his services to Australian sport.
Funeral arrangements will be announced in the coming weeks.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth Prowd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Prowd</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medal of the Order</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Prowd, 65</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USM EVENTS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Hemisphere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Snowsill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sports Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Triathlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Triathlon Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Webber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ironman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie McEwen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prowd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
