<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400631826913049</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/policy/industrial-relations/judge-finds-cfmeu-coerced-john-holland-to-defy-safety-policy-20170731-gxmbkf</url>
  <title>'Nothing short of unconscionable': CFMEU coerced John Holland to defy safety policy</title>
  <content>
The Federal Circuit Court has blasted the Construction, Forestry, Mining and Energy Union for taking part in "unconscionable" conduct when it coerced builder John Holland to go against its safety obligations through unlawful industrial action.
The Australian Building and Construction Commission took the CFMEU and one of its delegates to court after the union objected to the builder's new policy at its University of Newcastle site requiring workers to wear long pants to guard against cuts, abrasions and skin cancer.
While stressing "the union does not endorse footy shorts", the CFMEU opposed the policy due to concerns over heat stress and demanded that workers should have a choice of clothing.
CFMEU official Pomare Auimatagi allegedly told a meeting of 82 workers in January 2014 that "we've done it at [Lend Lease sites at] Barangaroo and Tamworth - I'm suggesting that you come to work in shorts and short sleeves and make a stand".

When John Holland's senior HR adviser warned the company would prevent workers from entering the site if they wore short sleeves or shorts, Mr Auimatagi allegedly responded "touch one, touch all" and threatened to stop work at the whole site if any worker was removed.

The next day, after a site manager told a scaffolder to put on some "longs" and come back to work, all subcontractor workers walked off the site in protest and did not fully return to work until four days later.
The workers went on strike despite Comcare inspectors supporting John Holland's policy as a "reasonable" requirement, in part because it included heat management such as structured breaks and rehydration.
'Unconscionable'

Judge Sylvia Emmett found that the workers' action was not based on a "reasonable concern about an imminent risk to health and safety".

Further, the CFMEU provided no evidence to rebut the presumption that its action was taken to "prejudice John Holland directly or indirectly in relation to its building contract" and to force the builder to abandon its policy.
"The [CFMEU official's] conduct in seeking to negate John Holland's choice to enforce its Two Longs Safety Policy, when it had a statutory duty in relation to the health and safety of its workers, was nothing short of unconscionable."
She found the CFMEU and Mr Auimatagi had taken unlawful adverse action because the builder had exercised its workplace right to ensure compliance with its safety policy.
The judge directed the parties to mediation on the issue of penalties with the next hearing set down for September.

The CFMEU faces a maximum penalty of $51,000 per breach and Mr Auimatagi faces $10,200.
The court case comes as the CFMEU's mining division has been organising a three-month campaign in support of a miner who was sacked this year for instigating a controversial  at South32's Appin mine to highlight issues with the supply of work clothes.
A South32 spokesperson deemed the protest was unprotected industrial action but the CFMEU has been urging the company to reinstate him.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forestry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Sylvia Emmett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Construction Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barangaroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Auimatagi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Two Longs Safety Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Circuit Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Holland</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lend Lease</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Building</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pomare Auimatagi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South32</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
