<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400198035208413</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/food/35-aldi-whisky-takes-out-top-prize-for-being-a-phenomenal-drop/news-story/14ca83dce732c7f46232a283eff29110</url>
  <title>Aldi whisky takes out prestigious spirits prize</title>
  <content>
A CHEAP bottle of Aldi whisky has taken out the top prize at the Melbourne International Spirits Competition.
Receiving the Double Gold prize, the Highland Black Eight-Year-Old Scotch Whiskey was judged the top drop of its price category because of its "good body, nice colour and soft finish".
"This whisky is phenomenal for its price," competition judge and founder, Adam Levy told news.com.au.
"For its price point [34.99 for 700ml] it's a wonderful whisky to buy."
, and is the first major international spirits competition in the Pacific Region with trade-only judges.
Consisting of a judging panel of buyers, restaurant owners, distributors and importers - the competition works by placing submissions in its product category but also its pricing category.
Therefore a spirit will be judged in its category along with other spirits in its same price range by its retail price.
According to Mr Levy, while the Aldi whisky received the Double Gold in it's category - if it was $20 more expensive, it probably would've only walked away with a silver medal.
"At its price point, it compares to a good quality mass produced whisky," he said.
"To get the double gold award, it means the spirit is in the top 10% of the whole competition."

It's not the first time the whisky has walked away with a top prize. In May, the same brand was awarded the silver medal in the whisky category at the International Spirits challenge - which has been described as the "most authoritative" competition in the world.
The Highland Black Eight-Year-Old Scotch Whiskey beat some rivals valued three times more in price, with judges claiming it was a "rich blend of the finest grain and malt whiskies from Scotland".
In London this week, Aldi's Oliver Cromwell London Dry Gin won a gold medal at the International Wine and Spirits Competition - meaning it's one of the best in the world.
Earlier this year, the  at the International Wine Challenge - also making it one of the best drops in the world.
Unfortunately, both wine and Gin haven't quite made it to Australian stores.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Levy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Wine Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Levy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highland Black Eight-Year-Old Scotch Whiskey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Spirits</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne International Spirits Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Region</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi's Oliver Cromwell London Dry Gin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spirits Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Wine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Double Gold</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
