<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400498682924619</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/missing-man-perth-family-urge-shaun-black-to-call/news-story/7e37be154d96d2fca59d4e51dee7d9ab</url>
  <title>Family 'still live in hope'</title>
  <content>
IT has been a long and torturous 113 days since Shaun Black's family last saw or heard from him.
When his mystery disappearance reached the 90-day mark, Mr Black was officially listed by police as a "long-term missing person" but his family still hold out hope for answers, although they admit they are preparing for the worst.

The 52-year-old carpenter was said to be in good spirits when he left his parents' home in Gosnells on the morning of April 8 in his white Ford Ranger to return to his home in Southern Cross to finalise a land sale.
CCTV cameras captured him leaving Gosnells but he never made it home.
Mr Black's vehicle, registration number 1DFR 001, has also not been found.
His family is using National Missing Persons Week, which starts today, to renew their desperate pleas for information. They say Mr Black was experiencing personal problems and work stresses in his life.
This week, police will conduct aerial and ground searches of a large swathe of State forest east of Perth in their bid to find Mr Black.
"The family is taking it pretty hard with no sightings ... we still live in hope that they may come across him, it'd be nice. We just want some answers, where he's gone ... just to rest our minds," younger brother Gavin Black said.
"Leading up to it (his disappearance) he was very paranoid about a few things, about what was going on in Southern Cross, he was a bit worried about going back to Southern Cross for some reason. (It was) very out of character, but when I was here (the night before he vanished) he was fine. Work was petering out in Southern Cross he was a bit worried about that.
"It's not looking good, but we just hope for the best and prepare ourselves for the worst."
He had this message for his older brother: "Shaun, if you're out there ... get in contact with someone. Ring the police, let them know you're safe and you're well."
Anyone with information about Mr Black or any other missing person is urged to call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000. If you are experiencing difficulties, you can contact Lifeline on 13 11 14.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Black</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Ranger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Cross</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosnells</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Missing Person Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DFR 001</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
