<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400760675934345</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/19/00/the-10-second-test-that-determines-the-best-diet-for-you</url>
  <title>The 10-second test that could determine the best diet for you</title>
  <content>
An innovative 10-second test using DNA has guaranteed users it will determine the diet most suitable for their body.
The Nutrigenomics test involves taking a non-invasive swab of a person's saliva that is lab tested, then sent away to experts who map out the genetics.
"Weight loss can be very successful if you understand you've got this particular weakness in your genotype," Nutritionist biochemist Christine Houghton from Cell Logic told 9NEWS.
"If you understand your strengths and weaknesses, you can change your diet and lifestyle accordingly," she said.
Brisbane mother Jenelle Povey discovered she needed more protein in her diet after taking the test and working through the results with her naturopath.
"My body craves protein and once I did that, there was no looking back," Ms Povey, who works in the health industry, said.
"Sleep better, more energy, it's done wonders."

Related Articles

Trudy Cadoo from Brisbane LiveWell Clinic told 9NEWS she had seen the benefits of nutrigenomics with her clients, and praised the personalised aspect of the diet.
"So many people will try the next diet that's in vogue, but it doesn't necessarily mean that it's going to work for them," Ms Cadoo said.
The disclaimer for the test is that it shouldn't be done DIY.
While there are home testing kits available, they're not endorsed by health professionals and it's best to consult a doctor, naturopath or dietician.
"It's really fraught with real difficulties if an individual tries to do it on their own," Ms Hougthon advised.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenelle Povey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trudy Cadoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane LiveWell Clinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Houghton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Povey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cell Logic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DIY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Cadoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nutrigenomics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hougthon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
