<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400722021228013</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/players-to-pay-tribute-to-les-murray-at-ffa-cup-matches-as-football-mourns-his-passing/news-story/56735906e963234110f0fc7e4a2349a2</url>
  <title>Players to observe minute's silence for Les</title>
  <content>
FOOTBALL players, supporters and broadcasters have joined to remember the man known as 'Mr Football', after the death of Les Murray was announced aged 71.
There will be a minute's silence before Tuesday night's four FFA Cup ties, with players wearing black armbands, as the game begins to acknowledge its debt to a man who anchored SBS's coverage of football for three and a half decades.
VALE LES MURRAY:
TRIBUTE TO LES MURRAY:
TOM SMITHIES:
Murray passed away on Monday morning after a long illness, just months after he had announced plans to be the face of a bid for a new A-League team in Sydney.
His death came three years after his retirement from SBS at the close of 35 years of senior involvement at the network, during which he presented coverage of eight World Cups and a variety of competitions from the old National Soccer League to the Champions League.
The Prime Minister added his own tribute to a man he said "had made the world game Australia's game", while former Socceroo Craig Foster - for years Murray's companion on screen - said the world had "lost a football colossus".
Murray's final broadcast at the World Cup in 2014 contrasted with his first at SBS in 1980, commentating on the NSL with just two days' notice. But he and his close friend, the former Socceroo Johnny Warren, forged a powerful identity for SBS as the home of football, presenting shows including one, World Soccer, that ran for 22 years.
In 1990 Murray convinced SBS bosses to acquire the rights to the World Cup, sparking audiences in their millions, and in 2006 he proudly presented coverage of Australia's first games at a World Cup in 32 years.
SBS CEO Michael Ebeid had spoken of "a devastating loss for us all" in announcing Murray's passing in an email to staff on Monday morning.

So sad that Les Murray has passed. A pioneer and legend of our game.No words can describe how much we will miss him. Rest in Peace my friend
"His role went far beyond being a football commentator - the growth, popularity, and success of football in Australia today is absolutely a reflection of his passion and advocacy for the game that he loved," Ebeid said.
The longevity of Murray's work could be seen in a stream of tributes from current players remembering watching football as presented by Murray in their own childhoods.
"So sad that Les Murray has passed," tweeted Socceroo Tim Cahill. "A pioneer and legend of our game. No words can describe how much we will miss him. Rest in Peace my friend."
Wanderers captain Robbie Cornthwaite wrote that "Sundays growing up were The World Game and Les Murray all afternoon. Thank you for teaching me about football."
Malcolm Turnbull recorded a video message in tribute, saying that "the Socceroos and Matildas never had a more devoted fan than you. You championed the world game for many years - you and Johnny Warren really made the world game Australia's game. Rest in peace."
Football Federation Australia chairman Steven Lowy called it "a very sad day for football - few people become synonymous with their sport but Les was one of those few.
"I've been seeing his face and hearing his voice since I was a teenager and I am sure I speak for many when I say that football is not going to be quite the same without him around."

The world lost a football colossus this morning, Les Murray AM. He fought well into extra time but whistle has blown. His legacy is lasting

Les left family that loved him, colleagues adored him, futbol community that revered him. Well played old friend. Extraordinary performance
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Cornthwaite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Soccer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ebeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOM SMITHIES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS CEO Michael Ebeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VALE LES MURRAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Soccer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanderers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroo Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Lowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroo Tim Cahill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroo Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
