<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400374128870841</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/kate-mulvany-from-country-to-helpmann-award/8759698</url>
  <title>Kate Mulvany accepts Helpmann award on behalf of all affected by Agent Orange</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Days after Kate Mulvany took to the stage for the opening of Shakespeare's Richard III, her father, a Vietnam veteran, died.
She has since been presented the  for her role as the disfigured historical character.
Mulvany said she used her own disfigurement - the result of her father's war service and her resulting seven-year battle with cancer - to bring the character to life.
"They're all linked, sadly, but kind of beautifully linked," she said.
"My dad was a 10-pound pom who arrived in Geraldton and got conscripted to fight in Vietnam, and then came back from Vietnam with Agent Orange in his system, which many Vietnam veterans did.
"That got passed along to me and turned into a form of cancer that is very common in the children and grandchildren of Vietnam veterans.
"So the weird thing was I was performing using my Agent Orange ailments. I mean I wouldn't have the back I have without Dad's exposure to Agent Orange, so I really was doing it for him every night and doing it for all of those kids every day."
Exposure a liberating experience

Mulvany said she had long hidden her curved spine, but told director Peter Evans she was morally opposed to acting disabled for the role.
"When they  a few years ago I got tingles and got quite teary actually because I saw my spine. There he was and there was what my spine, my x-rays, look like," she said.
"When I got offered the role of Richard the third I said to Peter Evans, the director, I don't want to pretend to have a disability because I don't agree with that.

"Morally I think that's wrong to put someone on stage pretending to have a disability.
"Obviously that meant being very brave and showing people my back, which is something that I've hidden ... now here I was at the age of 40 showing the full curvature of my spine and the abnormalities I guess of my growth and it was really liberating and wonderful.
"For the first time ever ironically I didn't have to pretend."
Hometown support the best medicine

Mulvany regularly returns to her home town of Geraldton, on WA's mid-west coast, for a dose of her godmother's spaghetti and to visit the many people in the community she considers family.
She said growing up in regional Western Australia had helped her cope with the severe effects of cancer treatment.

2017 Helpmann Awards notable winners

Best Musical: The Book of Mormon
Best Play: Drover's Wife
Best Ballet: Ballet Preljocaj's Snow White
Best Dance: Attractor
Best Australian Contemporary Concert: Nick Cave & The Bad Seeds
Best International Contemporary Concert: Patti Smith
Best Comedy Performer: Hannah Gadsby

"Being in a country town there weren't that many kids around me that were bald and scarred and very, very sick," she said.
"But the community of people that surrounded me, Sicilian and Yamatji and Noongar and Greek and Vietnamese, they were all around me and just surrounded me with love and just their own form of healing I guess."
Her developing years also helped form her career as a playwright with a number of credits to her name.
"I wrote a lot about home. I was homesick, so I wrote a lot about Geraldton and Western Australia and the incredible, amazing amount of cultures that I didn't realise at the time how lucky I was to be growing up amongst such incredible diversity of cultures," Mulvany said.
She was also a finalist in two other categories of the Helpmann awards, for best new Australian work and best play for her .
Mulvany had one day off after Richard III wrapped before filming began on a new series for Foxtel in which she plays the wife of a returned soldier from Afghanistan, and in another month begins shooting a new feature film.
"Until then I'll just be writing and writing and writing," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnamese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helpmann</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah Gadsby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare's Richard III</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helpmann Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agent Orange</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bad Seeds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noongar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Evans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Contemporary Concert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballet Preljocaj's Snow White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Contemporary Concert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drover's Wife</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sicilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yamatji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patti Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comedy Performer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Mulvany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geraldton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulvany</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard III</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Book of Mormon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Cave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
