<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400726316195361</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/07/31/report-finds-federal-service-providers-hostile-refugees</url>
  <title>Report finds federal service providers 'hostile' to refugees</title>
  <content>
A jointly authored report by the Refugee Council of Australia and the Fairfield Multicultural Interagency finds refugees are being treated with hostility and stigma by federal service providers.

By

Marese O'Sullivan

3 HOURS AGO  UPDATED 10 MINS AGO

The federal government says it's unware of claims refugees are being mistreated by its welfare-to-employment agencies after a report alleged some were being direspected and unfairly penalised.

The Refugee Council of Australia and and the Fairfield Multicultural Interagency's draft report investigates refugees and their experiences with the government's Jobactive program, which aims to help the unemployed find jobs.

It focused on humanitarian arrival refugees who have recently moved to Fairfield, in western Sydney.

The report found a number of agency staff members were "hostile" and provided little or no support when approached for advice.

Refugees often felt disrespected and were threatened with having their welfare benefits suspended, the report said.

Staff allegedly called refugees 'dirty' and 'shabby'

One immigrant from Syria was told they had come to Australia for "easy money".

"The caseworker when he interviews (sic) me stated that I just arrived in Australia to get easy money from the first interview... upset me a lot. He did not help me with my job plan, he just judged me," a Syrian refugee was quoted in the report.

Another was confronted by a staff member calling them "dirty" and "shabby".

"I felt ashamed and was unhappy and very angry with the provider but I could not do anything due to my dependence on Centrelink payment and my limited English proficiency," the 32-year-old woman was quoted.

'Learn English or look for work'

There were also examples of refugees who were forced to choose between learning English and looking for work, as well as those who claimed their welfare payments were reduced because they were unable to attend routine meetings with employment services, even if they had valid reasons for missing their appointment.

Many did not understand why their payment had been delayed or cut off.

Clients with disabilities also faced being incorrectly assessed or not assessed at all by the Employment Services Assessment.

One interviewee said despite her permanent medical conditions and limited English, she had been told her Centrelink payment would cease if she did not look for work.

She declared the constant stress had taken a significant toll on her wellbeing.

It was also difficult for jobseekers to find Australian work experience through Jobactive, according to the report. 

The Refugee Council of Australia recommended the government should initiate a national multicultural employment strategy to improve the transition for migrants.

Government unaware of allegations

However, the Assistant Minister for Social Services and Multicultural Affairs Zed Seselja told SBS World News in a statement said the government "is unaware of any disrespectful treatment of refugees".

Senator Seselja suggested there were pathways for refugees to learn English while on the Jobactive program saying the Adult Migrant English Program was an approved activity under the service.

"These job seekers can decline to accept offers of suitable work while they are fully meeting their part-time requirements," he said.

In addition, he said refugees could be exempted from looking for work under the Jobactive program for up to 13 weeks to allow them to find housing, childcare and schooling and adjust in their new country.

"Refugees may voluntarily engage with employment services during this time," he said.

A new humanitarian settlement program will start by November and help people with their English, studies as well as creating "linkages" between the two, he added.

A Department of Employment spokesperson said in a statement it had not yet received a copy of the draft report.

"The government recognises that refugees settling in Australia face greater levels of labour market barriers than other job seekers, including lower levels of English proficiency and education."

"Refugees have access to the full range of jobactive employment services and income support from the date of their arrival in Australia.

"The Department considers that nobody should be pulled off an Adult Migrant English Program course to do another activity."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS World News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adult Migrant English Program</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrelink</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 10 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobactive</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marese O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Employment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield Multicultural Interagency</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Refugee Council of Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Employment Services Assessment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Multicultural Affairs Zed Seselja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Seselja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
