<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400640416847728</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/nick-riewoldt-is-one-of-st-kildas-top-five-alltime-players-says-tony-lockett-20170731-gxmhtu.html</url>
  <title>Nick Riewoldt is one of St Kilda's top five all-time players, says Tony Lockett</title>
  <content>
Tony Lockett has lauded the retiring Nick Riewoldt as "a complete player," with the game's leading goalkicker placing his fellow St Kilda champion as one of the top five players in the club's history.
Lockett kicked 898 of his 1360 VFL/AFL goals while at the Saints, and has legend status in the Australian Football Hall of Fame.

Up Next

AFL plays of round 19

02:18

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Nick Riewoldt announces retirement

St Kilda veteran Nick Riewoldt has announced the 2017 AFL season will be his last. AAP

He is also one of just eight St Kilda figures to have been named an official legend of the club. Darrel Baldock, Ian Stewart, Allan Jeans, Trevor Barker, Neil Roberts, Robert Harvey and Ross Smith are the others.
Riewoldt appears destined to one day join that group. He has been named the club's best and fairest more times than any other player (six), holds the record for most games as Saints captain (220), sits behind only Harvey on the club's games record list with 333 appearances to his name, and his tally of 714 goals puts him behind only Lockett and Bill Mohr.Photo: Fairfax Photographic
Speaking on Monday, Lockett - who played with Barker and Harvey, and was coached by Baldock, said Riewoldt clearly belonged in that bracket.
"He's one of St Kilda's greatest ever players in my opinion. He'd have to be in the [club's] top five players," Lockett told Fairfax Media.

"[He's] been a true champion through and through in every way, shape and form of the game.
"I think he'd be very proud in what he's achieved. They don't come much better than that."
Asked at his press conference on Monday how felt when mentioned alongside St Kilda's greatest names, Riewoldt was self-effacing."It is what it is," Riewoldt said.
"That's really for other people to make those comparisons. I can't control any of that. All I've been able to control the last 17 years is the way I've prepared, the way I've carried myself. Football's meant so much to me. I'm just so grateful to have had an opportunity to be able to do it as long as I have."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darrel Baldock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Photographic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Jeans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL/AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Football Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockett</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Mohr.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Lockett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baldock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
