<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400631826913071</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/lynette-daley-died-due-to-violent-sex-act-court-hears/8761048</url>
  <title>Lynette Daley died from injuries inflicted during violent sex act, court hears</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

A woman who died on a remote beach on the New South Wales North Coast suffered fatal injuries from a violent sex act, a court has heard.
Lynette Daley was found dead
A jury of seven women and five men today heard the 33-year-old suffered severe lacerations to her genitals from a violent sexual act involving the use of a hand or fist.
Crown prosecutor Philip Strickland SC told the court Ms Daley had lacerations in and around her vagina.
"The lacerations to the vagina were very significant," he said.
"They caused significant bleeding - a significant loss of blood."
'Boys will be boys,' says accused

Paul Maris, 47, has been charged with aggravated sexual assault in company and hindering the discovery of evidence.
He told the court Ms Daley was "quite all right" with the sexual act which led to her death.
"She didn't say stop it, she was alright with what we were doing," he said.
But Mr Strickland told the court a post-mortem examination had shown Ms Daley had a blood alcohol level of more than 0.3 at the time, and either did not or could not give consent.

Adrian Attwater, 42, has been charged with manslaughter and aggravated sexual assault in company.
The court was played an excerpt from his record of interview with police, in which he was asked how the situation had developed.
"These things just happen, man," he said.
"Girls will be girls and boys will be boys."
The court was told Maris was seen with an apparently intoxicated Ms Daley at a supermarket in the area the afternoon before her death.
The jury was told a witness would testify that Maris asked him: "Hey mate, can you do us a favour and drop this thing [Ms Daley] down the road for us?"
About 50 witnesses could be called in a trial expected to last another five weeks.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Attwater, 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Maris, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Daley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Strickland SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynette Daley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Strickland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
