<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400717726260636</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4824437/brown-orders-double-helping/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Brown orders double helping</title>
  <content>
KNIGHTS coach Nathan Brown has challenged his team to win consecutive games for the first time in almost two years.

Newcastle have not gone back-to-back since rounds 23 and 24 of season 2015, when they scored upset wins on the road against Wests Tigers (24-18) and Melbourne (20-6). After last week's breakthrough 21-14 win against St George Illawarra, the Knights should be full of confidence when they host the enigmatic Warriors on Saturday, who have lost their past four games to crash out of play-off contention.

IT'S A KNOCKOUT: Chanel Mata'utia missed last week's game with concussion.
Asked about the prospect of successive victories on home turf, Brown replied: ""That would be huge.
"It's a good challenge for them. We're playing the Warriors, who are probably in a similar boat to us, in that there's no play-off football for them. "We're certainly going to need to play better than we did on the weekend, and it's a great challenge for us. We'd like to get out there and put our best foot forward."
Brown had no doubt his players would be highly motivated but could not speak on behalf of the Warriors.
Brown said Chanel Mata'utia was in line for a recall to Newcastle's backline after "ticking all the right boxes" in his recovery from a nasty concussion he sustained against the Roosters two weeks ago.

Mata'utia's availability will be timely because senior outside backs Dane Gagai and Shaun Kenny-Dowall were both in doubt with what Brown described as "slight issues". 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>S A KNOCKOUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanel Mata</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Gagai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Kenny-Dowall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
