<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400631826913084</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/it-pro/government-it/robot-to-greet-visitors-to-queensland-government-office-20170731-gxmd80.html</url>
  <title>Robot to greet visitors to Queensland government office</title>
  <content>
Visitors to two Queensland government offices in 1 William Street will be greeted by a robot, as part of a new trial.
The Department of Science, Information Technology and Innovation has partnered with cloud technology company Axalon to develop and trial a Google Home speaker called Eve to greet visitors at the reception it shares with the Department of Communities, Child Safety and Disability Services.Photo: Supplied
Innovation Minister Leeanne Enoch said the government saw an opportunity in Axalon's platform to use the Google Home artificial intelligence system to help visitors in 1 William Street.
Department of Science, Information Technology and Innovation director-general Jamie Merrick said Eve was a voice-enabled speaker, configured to have conversations with visitors.Photo: Tammy Law
Eve can direct visitors to meeting rooms and notify staff via their desk phone or text message when guests arrive at reception.
Mr Merrick said there had been a problem with having a reception area separate to the main office that was constantly staffed but had irregular visitor arrivals.

There have not been job losses as a result of the new robot.
"We are always looking for ways to streamline our work and operate as efficiently as we can, and we saw this as a way of freeing up two people to do more complex and valuable tasks," Mr Merrick said.
The project cost $13,775.
Axalon co-founder Tracey Kay said DSITI was an early adopter, with the Google Home technology only released in Australia recently.
"We use machine learning to understand what users are saying and engage them in simple, smart conversational interactions," she said.
Global technology firm Gartner has predicted that by 2020, 30 per cent of web browsing sessions would be done without a screen, as "voice first" interactions increase with technology such as Google Home and Amazon's Echo.
Ms Enoch said the initiative came about after Axalon worked with the government as part of the "testing within government program", which invited businesses to offer solutions to specific government problems.
During the World Science Festival, Axalon operated an interactive water buoy that relayed water quality data from the Brisbane River.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tammy Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Echo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Science</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disability Services.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Axalon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Leeanne Enoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williams Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Home</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Merrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey Kay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Science Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Information Technology</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gartner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Communities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Enoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merrick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DSITI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
