<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400717726260652</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/southeast/ecommerce-idea-earns-bike-retailers-national-business-award/news-story/f2039c9ddea9f730708136c6a88dd613</url>
  <title>Business riding high</title>
  <content>
THE Camp  Hill owners of online business Mountain Bikes Direct have taken out the 2017 Telstra Queensland Micro Business Award.
With increasing competition from international online retailers, the founders of Annerley's -ForTheRiders bike shop decided to take the competition head on and set up e-commerce operation Mountain Bikes Direct.
The business was so successful they sold the Annerley store last year to focus on the e-commerce trade.
Owners Michael Geale and Tim McCullough first came up with the idea for their business as teenagers riding bikes around the streets of Camp Hill and went into business -together at the end of high school.
Co-owner Jen Geale said the e-commerce business met demand from riders wanting to buy from an Australian retailer at a globally competitive price. The company's aim was to counter issues customers faced when purchasing from an overseas retailer, by stocking products backed by local warranty support and offering next-day delivery.
Mrs Geale said the win was an -unexpected surprise.
"You never really expect to walk away the winner from something like that, with so many other amazing businesses in the room," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ForTheRiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annerley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim McCullough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Geale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Geale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-owner Jen Geale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountain Bikes Direct</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra Queensland Micro Business Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
