<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400417078544629</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/a-league/teams/melbourne-city/melbourne-city-to-start-ffa-cup-defence-without-tim-cahill/news-story/a724d1abe630ff37465929b17f7d07a3</url>
  <title>Cahill on ice for City's cup defence</title>
  <content>
TIM Cahill will not play in the FFA Cup on Tuesday night as he builds in to his pre-season.
But new Melbourne City coach Warren Joyce says an otherwise full-strength side will take on local Queensland outfit Peninsula Power at Dolphin Stadium in Brisbane as it begins its FFA Cup defence in earnest.
Tonight's match is also the first competitive game Joyce has coached since taking over at City in June, following on from friendly wins over Oakleigh Cannons and Bentleigh Greens in the past couple of weeks.
Coming from England, he admitted to it feeling a little "strange" playing a fully-fledged Cup match in the depths of pre-season.
Not that it will change his approach to the game in any case.
"All games are competitive as far as I'm concerned," Joyce said.
ROTATION:
MERRY-GO-ROUND:
NET KIT:
"I know we've had two friendlies, but any game - whether it's the grand final or a friendly - you approach them exactly the same.
"You want that consistency in training, games, you're striving for perfection all the time.
"The fact that this is billed as the first competitive game is immaterial for me."
Joyce said he and his fellow City coaches have studied up on Peninsula, but admitted to not knowing anywhere near as much about the NPL Queensland side as it would an A-League opponent.
Socceroos star Cahill has a month to ready himself for crucial World Cup qualifiers against Japan in Saitama and Thailand at AAMI Park.
But having only just returned from his off-season break, Joyce was adamant there was no need to rush the 37-year-old into match action.
"He was still playing when the a lot of the boys were on holidays," he said.
"We gave him a holiday after he played the Chile game (at the Confederations Cup) and then we'll build him up from there.
"He's only been back a week, but he's the only one we've left behind who's fit.
"He's worked well in training, he's working hard, but in controlled environments rather than games.
"We didn't (play matches) in the first two, three, four weeks for all the other boys, so trying to keep consistency about all the players' preparations going into games so that we've got everybody firing and fully fit for when you need them when the season starts."

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleigh Greens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cahill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MERRY-GO-ROUND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dolphin Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Confederations Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Cahill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh Cannons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saitama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
