<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400717726260627</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/big-business-accuses-bill-shorten-of-lying-20170730-gxly73</url>
  <title>Big business fires back at Labor over inequality</title>
  <content>
Corporate Australia has scolded Bill Shorten for misleading voters about the impact of company tax cuts while the miners have warned the opposition to keep its hands off their diesel fuel rebate as Labor looks for revenue as part of its campaign to tackle inequality.
A day after Labor sent jitters through the small business sector , the Business Council of Australia unleashed on Mr Shorten for his "patently untrue" claim that the company tax cuts proposed by the government will "impede growth".
Sources said the outburst signalled that corporate Australia was no longer going to allow itself to be a punching bag in the pre-election political contest, even though it knows that criticising Labor plays into the opposition's campaign.
"Politicians can have differing opinions in the company tax debate, but they shouldn't mislead the public about the facts," said an unusually animated BCA chief executive Jennifer Westacott.

Ms Westacott essentially called Mr Shorten a hypocrite by pointing out he had once argued in government that cutting the company tax rate would increase productivity and investment, leading to higher growth, jobs and wages.

She said Mr Shorten's new position was at odds with the majority of expert economic opinion, ranging from the Treasury and economists to the government of other nations "that are reducing their company tax rates to lure investment and jobs away from countries like Australia".
"This isn't 'trickle down' anything. There is a straight line from increased business investment to higher productivity, to higher incomes for workers," she said. "When politicians trash the independent evidence, it's our community that suffers. Voters deserve better."
Mr Shorten has made tackling inequality Labor's mission statement and he contrasts that with the Coalition's support for the paring back of Sunday penalty rates, an across-the-board increase in the Medicare levy to fund the National Disability Insurance Scheme, and its company tax cut policy.
The Coalition has a 10-year plan to reduce the company tax rate to 25 per cent for all corporations. So far, the Senate has allowed a rate cut only for companies with an annual turnover capped at $50 million and Labor is threatening to revoke that, too, if elected.

Mr Shorten gave further grist to this theory on Monday when he asked rhetorically whether a company with a $50 million turnover was a small business.
"This is a government who has got a runaway train of national debt. The more that this government gives away money to the large end of town... means is that there's fewer people in the system, fewer companies in the system having to pay a large proportion of a declining budget," he said.
"This corporate tax cut will impede growth, it will accelerate national debt on every Australian and the reason why we say that is because there's no compensating revenue."
When Mr Shorten kicked off the inequality campaign with a speech 10 days ago, he said tax concessions and revenue measures previously considered too hard or off limits would be looked at. The taxation of trusts - a minimum 30 per cent on all distributions to adults - was the first instalment.

While Labor has not suggested it will target the billions paid annually to miners as rebates for the excise on the diesel fuel they use, the industry fired a warning shot on Monday.
The Minerals Council of Australia pointed out a  on levels of subsidy to various industries. The MCA said the report noted the industry receives "negligible" government assistance because the diesel rebate is regarded as a business input not a subsidy.
The report states that the effective rate of combined assistance - the ratio of total assistance to output - is 0.2 per cent, having fallen by half a percentage point since 2010-11, the MCA said in a statement.
"Any attempt to reduce the Fuel Tax Credit scheme would be vigorously opposed." The Greens support paring back the rebate.

Labor was buoyed on Monday given the relatively benign response to its proposal to tax trusts. While the government continued to claim it was another attack on small business, the small business sector was concerned but not hostile.
While 198,000 of the 318,000 trusts which will be hit are classified as small businesses, shadow treasurer Chris Bowen said "in many of those instances they will be doctors, accountants, lawyers - not the sort of small businesses that many people would imagine".
"The vast majority of small businesses, remembering there are 3.2 million small businesses in Australia, actually don't use trusts."
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull said Mr Shorten has "obviously got a determination to do everything he can to kick small business in the guts".

"What does he think is going to drive economic growth? Other than entrepreneurship and enterprise and small business," Mr Turnbull said.
"Every way you look at it, from raising taxes on small and medium businesses and family businesses, that's not the way to go.
"We're providing tax relief because we know that that will encourage people to invest and employ and get ahead."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Westacott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fuel Tax Credit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Westacott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minerals Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Disability Insurance Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
