<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400889524955300</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/cricket/cricket-pay-war-nearing-end-after-marathon-talks-say-players-20170731-gxmgyo.html</url>
  <title>Cricket pay war nearing end after marathon talks, say players</title>
  <content>
Players are quietly confident Australian cricket's damaging pay war is on the verge of resolution with marathon talks set to avert the need for arbitration.
There is growing belief an in principle agreement between the governing body and the players union could be reached as early as Tuesday night, .

Up Next

Cricket Australia willing to seek arbitration for players dispute

00:57

More Cricket Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Cricket pay dispute deadline

After a nine month dispute, it's the final day for a deal to be struck on cricket's pay war before arbitration. Vision courtesy: Seven News.

While Cricket Australia is not as bullish, it agrees progress is being made. Any agreement would have to be signed off by the CA board, the ACA executive and the players, which means it's unlikely any announcement will come before Wednesday.
After marathon talks across the weekend, intensive negotiations continued into Monday night as both sides close in on an agreement which had seemed improbable throughout the bitter dispute. So poor have relations been between the two sides nothing can be taken for granted until both parties sign the dotted line.

CA and the Australian Cricketers Association have in the past two weeks both believed they were nearing a resolution only to be blind sided by the other party.
ACA chief Alistair Nicholson sent a draft heads of agreement and tour contracts to CA last week only to be accused of stalling tactics. It came a week after CA rejected a terms sheet sent by the ACA, plunging the game back into crisis.

However, there has been greater urgency in talks since  if a new deal was not agreed by early this week.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Cricket's feuding parties were locked in talks into the early hours of Monday morning, after which the ACA held an internal briefing which did not wind up until 2.30am.Photo: Getty Images
Despite the progress, relations remain tense as seen by both sides' insistence they are responsible for the recent breakthroughs. There is also a feeling the high stakes has expedited progress.
CA says the call for arbitration had brought the matter to a head and believe that its proposal for players to be re-contracted was important. That both parties had not met for four days before the ultimatum was further proof of its effectiveness, CA say.
But the players believe the governing body increased their urgency after being told an arbitrator would not help their case. 
The ACA could have asked for an international sports expert who may have ruled CA needed to share as much as 40 to 50 per cent of its revenue, instead of 22 per cent asked by players, in keeping with major US sports.
Players have stuck firmly to retaining revenue-sharing in a hybrid pay model though it may be termed differently so both sides can be seen to save face.
A resolution this week would mean the upcoming tour of Bangladesh would go ahead.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
