<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400898114890124</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/melbourne-storm-young-gun-jahrome-hughes-embraces-cameron-smiths-350th-20170731-gxmfbb.html</url>
  <title>Storm young gun Hughes embraces Smith's 350th</title>
  <content>
Jahrome Hughes has made a strong impression on the Melbourne Storm and captain Cameron Smith.
The full-back scored his third try in three games for the Storm in their 40-6 win over Manly Sea Eagles at AAMI Park on Sunday as he notched his first win with the club.Photo: Robert Cianflone
Smith set up Hughes for the Storm's first try, one of four assists for , and the pair shared a hug immediately after.
The 22-year-old New Zealander admitted he was more nervous to play his first game with Smith and the Storm's State of Origin stars than his earlier NRL or Storm debuts.
"When he gave me that pass and I went over then I was looking straight for him - it was an awesome moment for me," Hughes said with a big smile.
Smith was impressed with the young back who has previously spent time at Gold Coast Titans and North Queensland Cowboys.

He revealed they also shared a special moment post-game. "He came up to me after the game, gave a me big hug and said "thanks mate, I appreciate being a part of this game and don't know I will get the opportunity again"," Smith said.
"That's the type of person he is and the type of person we want at the club. How good is that? A young fella coming up to an old boy like me and saying that.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"You take out Billy Slater, you leave some big shoes to fill but he came in and did a wonderful job, he has to be proud of his efforts."
Hughes joined the club this season following his second bout of back surgery and didn't get to start running straight lines until January.
But his form with feeder club Sunshine Coast Falcons was so strong he came into the Storm's side at full-back when Slater was called up for State of Origin duty and with Slater out this round he was called in again.
"I was so nervous to play with the types of players who were out there today," Hughes said. "They make your job so much easier and [Craig] Bellamy came up to me and told me to do my job and that's what you do in this great team.
"We talked during the week about not letting Cameron down, it was a big occasion, the guys who had played with him talked during the week about how he has never let them down and it was time to repay that favour."
Hughes is a realist and knows with Slater likely to return from a concussion for the Storm's clash with the Cowboys in Townsville on Friday night, he is likely to return to the Falcons.
So he was embracing his chance to play on Sunday and he should get more chances in the future after re-signing for two more years last week.
There could be a chance he could play at five-eighth this week as Cameron Munster is battling an ankle injury although Ryley Jacks is more likely to play if Munster misses.
​"If the opportunity comes up I will take it with two hands and do my best," Hughes said.
"I'm not looking that far ahead, Billy [Slater] will probably be back next game, I just have to go back to Sunny Coast and play my best footy. If the opportunity comes up again in the next seven weeks or so I will be ready."
The Storm play the Cowboys in Townsville on Friday night at 7.45pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Falcons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith's 350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slater</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Cianflone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storm's State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughes</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryley Jacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunny Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jahrome Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falcons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Titans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Cowboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
