<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400898114890112</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/residential/wa/singaporeans-add-perth-serviced-apartments-to-portfolio-20170731-gxm9ot</url>
  <title>Singaporeans add Perth serviced apartments to portfolio</title>
  <content>
Singaporean fund manager ZACD has snapped up 64 serviced apartments off-the-plan from Perth developer Finbar for $12.5 million.
The studio serviced apartments form the podium of Finbar's $108 million Aire West Perth development at 47-659 Murray Street, a 22-storey mixed-use tower that includes 178 one, two and three-bedroom apartments due for completion in mid-2018.
ZACD Group is currently in talks with potential serviced apartment operators and expects to shortlist one by the end of the year.
The deal is the third counter-cyclical hotel acquisition by Singapore-based investors in the deflated Perth market in recent months after listed real estate group Chip Eng Seng snapped up the  for about $15 million and a private Singapore-based investor paid $50 million to buy the 4.5-star Crowne Plaza Perth hotel.

According to hotel researchers STR, Perth was the worst performing capital city hotel market over the year to June with occupancy rates falling to 73 per cent from 78 per cent last year, and average daily room rates slumping to $172 a night compared with $188.

The Aire serviced apartments will have their own lobby and lift core as well as 65 car-bays and dedicated as well as shared amenities. Prime Resort Sales in association with Resort Brokers Australia negotiated the sale.
It's the second Australian acquisition by ZACD in a matter of weeks after the group acquired the suburban
The company founded by Yeo Choon Guan lists more than 30 industrial, commercial and residential developments completed since 2005 in Singapore, Malaysia and Indonesia on its website.
Finbar managing director Darren Pateman said 70 per cent of the apartments and all ground-floor commercial lots had been pre-sold with construction reaching level eight.

The company has one of the biggest apartment development pipelines in Perth, but has struggled recently amid the weaker market conditions, reporting a $3.2 million half-year loss in February following writedowns.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Resort Sales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Pateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singaporeans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ZACD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finbar's $108</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crowne Plaza Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeo Choon Guan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finbar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resort Brokers Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aire West Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ZACD Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chip Eng Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore-based</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
