<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400283934555845</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/bhp-billitons-fivemonth-high-leads-asx-gains-20170731-gxm8c3</url>
  <title>BHP Billiton's five-month high leads ASX gains</title>
  <content>
Resource stocks lit a fire under the ASX for most of Monday thanks to a surge in Chinese iron ore futures, driving a voracious appetite for BHP Billiton in particular, though investors sold off banks in the late afternoon following market chatter around RBA rates direction.
In addition to the broadbased buying in material and mining shares, a firming oil price flirted around the $US50 a barrel mark and a leap in the price of coal, propelled investors into energy and utility stocks. Healthcare and telecommunications were the only real drags on the bourse. 
The benchmark S&P/ASX Index rose 0.3 per cent to 5720.6 points, to end the month marginally lower - its worst July in six years.
"We're surprised the pick up in iron ore has been so strong because we're not really bullish on the outlook," said Romano Sala Tenna, portfolio manager at Katana Asset Manager. "But there's a cautious optimism ahead of this reporting season, boosted by a fairly benign confessions session."

BHP hit a five-month high, closing up 2.3 per cent at $25.85 while main rival Rio Tinto also finished the session up 2.3 per cent. Fortescue Metals was swept up in the positive iron ore sentiment and closed up 4.3 per cent. 

Australia's largest oil producer Woodside Petroleum closed 1.1 per cent higher, while refiner Caltex 1.2 per cent. 
The big four banks enjoyed positive investors attention for most of Monday's trade, however investors sold them off just before the market closed.
"There was chatter in the market around 3pm about the RBA remaining dovish and that might have spooked investors into selling the banks," said Mr Sala Tenna.
Commonwealth Bank finished the day off 0.04 per cent, ANZ closed down 0.2 per cent while Westpac was off 0.3 per cent and National Australia Bank closed down 0.07 per cent.

Gold prices managed to hold around their highest in seven weeks thanks to a slight pickup in safe-haven demand. A weak US dollar is also driving some of the support in bullion. 
As a result, Newcrest Mining was up 2.1 per cent, while Evolution Mining was 0.5 per cent higher and St Barbara was up 0.4 per cent. 
In other equities news, Sandfire Resources was off 2.3 per cent to $5.79, following Credit Suisse's reiteration of their "underperform" rating and $4.65 price target. According to a note to clients, the investment bank believes subdued copper prices in the medium-term will negatively impact the company's future earnings.
The prospect of a continued strong Australian dollar has given investors cause to sell off Treasury Wine Estates, which derives much of its earnings from overseas. The stock closed down 4.8 per cent to $12.18.

Stock Watch: Infigen Energy

Shares in wind farm operator Infigen Energy rebounded after sliding in the early hours of trade on Monday amid news that record low wind generation had resulted in a 36 per cent slump in quarterly revenue. The Sydney-based company, which owns and sells 557 megawatts of wind-generated electricity through the spot markets, said record low wind conditions across its NSW and South Australian farms meant that revenue for the three months to June 30 had dropped to $32 million, from the previous June quarter's $50 million. Production fell to 254 GWh, from 406 GWh in the same period last year, with wind output 40 per cent below the previous June quarter and 30 per cent below its previous June average, the company said. The stock finished the day up 1.9 per cent to 77¢ per cent.
Market Movers

Chinese PMI

China's official manufacturing purchasing managers index, slipped to 51.4 in July, compared to the 51.5 median forecast in a Bloomberg survey of economists and 51.7 in June, amid government efforts to curb financial risks. "Today's official PMI readings suggests that activity may have cooled this month," wrote Julian Evans-Pritchard, China economist at Capital Economics. "We anticipate further weakness ahead as the crackdown on financial risks weighs on credit expansion and economic growth."
House price growth

Adjusting house price growth for the recent inflation print shows that since 2008, only Sydney, Melbourne and Canberra have seen "real" growth in dwelling values, says CoreLogic's Cameron Kusher. Only Sydney, Melbourne and Canberra have actually recorded real growth in dwelling values, since the value declines ceased at the end of 2008. In all other cities, real dwelling values are currently lower than they were at the end of 2008 which is now almost nine years ago. "This data really highlights the uneven nature of growth across the capital city housing markets since the end of the financial crisis," wrote Mr Kushner. 
Private sector credit

Credit to the private sector grew 0.6 per cent in June, the fastest monthly pace in six months. The annual pace of growth picked up to 5.4 per cent, also the strongest in six months. The stronger pace of credit growth in June largely reflected a pickup in business credit growth, according to St George. It rose 0.9 per cent in June, following several months of subdued growth. The strong gain is now more in line with the high levels of confidence and conditions among businesses. The data might suggest that growth drivers in the Australian economy could be shifting, said Janu Chan, senior economist at St George.
Oil

WTI crude oil rose above $US50 a barrel for the first time since May after OPEC said the group and its partners will meet next week to discuss why some nations are falling behind on their pledge to cut production. Futures gained as much as 0.7 per cent after surging 8.6 per cent last week and crude oil was fetching $US1,268 an ounce on Monday afternoon. The Abu Dhabi meeting, co-chaired by Kuwait and Russia, is set to take place after Saudi Arabia said last week it would step up pressure on countries that aren't complying. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sala Tenna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodside Petroleum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Evans-Pritchard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katana Asset Manager</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury Wine Estates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WTI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuwait</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infigen Energy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Billiton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese PMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janu Chan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evolution Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcrest Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caltex 1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romano Sala Tenna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic's Cameron Kusher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandfire Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue Metals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Barbara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OPEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1,268</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Economics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
