<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400679071554180</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/cricket/big-bash/cricket-australia-release-fixture-for-bbl-amidst-pay-dispute-20170731-gxmej5.html</url>
  <title>Cricket Australia release fixture for BBL amidst pay dispute</title>
  <content>
The Sydney Sixers will host five Big Bash matches at the SCG including three double-headers with the women over the forthcoming season, although all eight franchises in Australia's Twenty20 competition remain without complete playing rosters due to cricket's ongoing pay war.
Cricket Australia released its revamped Big Bash draws yesterday, the men's version of which has expanded to 40 regular season games meaning each franchise will play two extra matches.

Up Next

Did McGuire intentionally stomp Mannah?

00:29

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Plays of the Week

Stars hold their nerve, six sixes in an over and fish and athletes both get aerial, these are the plays of the week.

Yet the make-up of each playing roster remains unknown with only male players who have signed long-term deals locked in to their respective franchises, .
Female stars have only been able to sign one-year deals in the opening two editions of the tournament meaning not a single player across Australia is on the books for WBBL03.

"We know the MOU is still being finalised, but we are confident this won't affect the upcoming BBL and WBBL season," CA executive general manager of events and leagues Anthony Everard said.
Everard was the head of the Big Bash last season but has since taken up a new role, with CA yet to appoint his replacement.

Each BBL franchise has received an extra home game in the new draw.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The Sixers, Melbourne Stars, Perth Scorchers and Brisbane Heat will play their fifth home game at their traditional venues, being the SCG, MCG, WACA and Gabba respectively.Photo: Getty Images
Hobart will take their fifth match to Launceston while the Sydney Thunder, Adelaide and Melbourne Renegades are still finalising the location of their extra fixture.
or at their usual home ground of Spotless Stadium.
They'll play the Hurricanes and Strikers twice, while the Sixers have two clashes against the Scorchers and Stars.
Standalone weekends in Sydney and Adelaide will kick off the WBBL again this season on December 9, while the Sydney Smash on December 19 launches the men's competition.
Three WBBL games will be played at Hurstville Oval by the Sixers as part of their regional expansion.
Sixers general manager Dominic Remond said his franchise was delighted with this season's draw.
"We love playing at the SCG, last year we had an over 30,000 average and our challenge is to keep that up next year," Remond said.
"We know historically from a lot of the research that we do that our fans perceive our biggest opponent as the Scorchers.
"Being able to play them twice and particularly being able to have a game in Sydney against the Scorchers is really good for our attendance.
"The last couple of years when we've played them at home we've had our biggest crowds outside our Sydney derby game.
"The Sydney-Melbourne rivalry means us against the Stars is a natural fit as well."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Sixers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBBL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WACA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sixers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Smash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Everard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Stars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Heat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Scorchers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Renegades</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hurstville Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Twenty20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBBL 03</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dominic Remond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
