<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400893819922780</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/greater-western-sydney-giants/gws-giants-coach-leon-cameron-says-brett-deledio-is-in-the-frame-for-afl-return-20170730-gxlzbf.html</url>
  <title>Brett Deledio 'a massive chance' for long-awaited AFL return</title>
  <content>
Greater Western Sydney Giants coach Leon Cameron has dubbed Brett Deledio "a massive chance" to make his long-awaited return to the AFL this weekend.
The Giants will play their final match at Manuka Oval for the season when they host the Melbourne Demons on Saturday afternoon.
Deledio's return would bring an end to an agonising hard-luck story that has seen him spend more than 13 months on the sidelines battling injury.
The 30-year-old was traded to the Giants this season having played the last of his 243 AFL games for Richmond in July last year.
But the calf injuries that have plagued the latter stages of his career haven't gone away, however the two-time All-Australian can see the light at the end of the tunnel.
Cameron praised the resilience of Deledio, who is in the frame to return for the top eight battle in Canberra after getting through two NEAFL games unscathed.

"He played some good game time and he's a massive chance to play this week," Cameron said.
"He's got to get through training, if he can get through then no doubt he'll put his hand up. That'll be fantastic for us if he can.
"He can give us a list in some areas that we need to get a lift in and it'll be good for confidence as well. Just to play again will be great for him because he's had a tough 15 months.
"He's got good levels of persistency and resilience so we look forward to seeing what he can do.
"It's a funny game AFL, you mightn't play much during the year but if you're up and running at the right end of the year then you could be a chance in some really big games."
Deledio is contracted to the Giants until the end of the 2019 season and will look to start his playing career for the western Sydney-based outfit on the right foot against the Demons.
The Giants are sitting third and this weekend will go a long way towards shaping the finals picture with Melbourne two wins behind them in seventh.
Deledio's injury struggle has been one of many headaches for the club this year, who have had a host of their biggest names spending stints on the sideline.
The likes of Steve Johnson, Rory Lobb, Phil Davis, Josh Kelly, Toby Greene, Zac Williams, Jacob Hopper, Stephen Coniglio, Ryan Griffen, Tim Taranto and Adam Kennedy have spent plenty of time in the medical rooms this year.
But competition for spots is slowly building with a number of Giants players overcoming their injury woes at the right time of the season.
Cameron says the Giants will need to be firing on all cylinders to stop a Demons side looking to bounce back from a shock four-point defeat to North Melbourne last week.
"They're absolutely one of the best three teams at the contest and around the source where they'll just hit hard, contest hard, tackle hard, scrap hard," Cameron said.
"There's a reason why they're in the eight, and that's because they playa brand of footy that everyone has sat back and admired.
"We've got to make sure bring our end of the bargain to match it."
Vision emerged of an on-field spat between Giants defenders Heath Shaw and Aidan Corr following their win over Fremantle but Cameron isn't flustered, saying it shows the fire is burning at the right time of the year.
"If you take a backward step or you're a bit timid in your actions, then you just get swallowed up," Cameron said.
"I'd prefer to deal with that than efforts that are unacceptable. I'd prefer to deal with that any day of the week."
AFL ROUND 20
Saturday: GWS Giants v Melbourne Demons at Manuka Oval, 1:45pm. Tickets available from .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heath Shaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Taranto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Griffen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL ROUND 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Hopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Lobb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aidan Corr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
