<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400910999792393</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/07/open-channel-whatblack-mirror-episode-should-get-a-sequel/</url>
  <title>What Black Mirror Episodes Should Get A Sequel? </title>
  <content>
Image: Channel 4

Black Mirror may be an anthology containing isolated episodes about our rising dependence on technology, but that doesn't mean the stories we've already seen are over. In fact, co-creator Charlie Booker is open to continuing some of Black Mirror's most iconic stories with sequels. The question is: Which episodes should they be, and how would their stories continue?

While chatting on , Booker said he and co-creator Annabel Jones have deliberated sequel episodes for some of the episodes. He didn't go into detail on what those would be, or whether any of the episodes in Netflix's upcoming fourth season will be sequels to previous ones (all signs indicate they won't be, since they're almost finished filming its sixth and final episode of the season).

"We've had ideas for sequels to stories as well, which is something we haven't entirely explored," he said. "I wouldn't be averse to it. There's a couple of ideas already in mind but we're sort of thinking about practically how we could do that and when the right time to do that would be."

I personally would love to see a continuation of the season one episode "The Entire History of You," looking at whether people's memories could be hacked and altered. If an entire society of people relied on this technology to keep their memories intact, how would having them changed impact them? Would it cause cognitive dissonance, or would people simply believe whatever their memory was...regardless of how it actually happened? Let us know if there are episodes you'd like to see sequels for, and how you'd like the stories to continue.

[]

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Booker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Mirror</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Mirror Episodes Should Get A Sequel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entire History of You</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annabel Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Booker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
