<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400932474629333</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4824477/talaileva-out-to-revoke-card/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Talaileva out to revoke card</title>
  <content>
IN DOUBT: Va Talaileva will see a concussion specialist. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

SOUTHERN Beaches captain Va Talaileva will see neurologist Dr Andrew Gardner at the Sports Concussion Clinic at John Hunter Hospital on Tuesday in a bid to have a blue card over-turned.

Talaileva was issued a concussion card after being hit heavy in a tackle late in Beaches' 33-31 loss to The Waratahs at Waratah Oval on Saturday.
Under guidelines introduced this season, players who receive a blue card are not permitted to train or play for 12 days and must be cleared before taking the field again.
Talaileva is adamant that he was not knocked out and has initiated a process to have the card revoked.

As required, the 34-year-old consulted a Newcastle sports doctor on Monday, which fell within the 48-hour time frame after receiving the knock, and was cleared of concussion-like symptoms.

The next step is for Talaileva's case to be assessed by an ARU- appointed doctor, of which Gardner is one.

If Dr Gardner concurs with the first doctor's assessment, Talaileva will be allowed to resume training. He will be observed at training after which Dr Gardner will determine if the blue card stands.

There have been two instances in juniors, where players are required to sit out 19 days, in which blue cards have been expunged.

Talaileva is the first player in premier one to query a concussion call.

If unsuccessful he will miss the clash with second-placed Wanderers at Alan Davis Field on Saturday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Gardner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratah Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Davis Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Andrew Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talaileva</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports Concussion Clinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hunter Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanderers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SOUTHERN Beaches</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Va Talaileva</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
