<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400631826913031</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/game-of-thrones/the-15-steamiest-game-of-thrones-sex-scenes/news-story/4b0c4aad358da30f625bf973b1ec17f5</url>
  <title>The 15 steamiest Game of Thrones sex scenes</title>
  <content>
Top 5 Game of Thrones Sex Scenes
1:08

Now in its seventh season, Game of Thrones has filled your television with swords, dragons and lots and lots of sex scenes. We've collected the five best.

July 31st 2017
2 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/Television/

Game of Thrones: Sex, sex and more sex.

Jade Budowski

Share

WHILE Game of Thrones is now in its seventh season, it only took one episode to know that they were never going to shy away from even the most shocking of sexual encounters.
Over the course of the fantasy epic, we've found out that pretty much anything goes in Westeros; incest, threesomes, orgies, bloodsucking, cave sex, you name it. There's truly nothing the show is afraid to touch, and we've consistently been left with a slew of steamy scenes that are impossible to forget (or maybe there are so many that they all blend into one massive skin-fest).

Many of our favourite, sex-having characters have met their tragic (or well-deserved) ends, but that doesn't mean we can't stop and enjoy their erotic endeavours in Wild, Wild Westeros. Whether Stark, Lannister, Martell, Sand, Snow, Targaryen, or even Bolton (ugh), pretty much every character on this series has experienced some kind of sexy time over the course of the past seven seasons.
In celebration of the recently-consummated relationship of fan-favourites Missandei and Grey Worm, we've compiled some of the steamiest scenes in the history of Game of Thrones. These encounters have occurred across climates, genders, age-groups, marriages, and more - the intercourse on this show truly knows no bounds. While we stop thinking about all the Thrones-related sex puns there are to make, take some time to look back at the steamiest sex had on this insane show.

Where it all began.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 1, Episode 1, Winter Is Coming
The Players: Tyrion & Ros
The Game: As a brothel superstar, Ros has many a partner during her Game of Thrones tenure, but our introduction to Tyrion (and their endearing, sexy chemistry) paints the perfect picture of what's to come.

Another episode 1 scene.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 1, Episode 1, Winter Is Coming
The Players: Jaime & Cersei Lannister

The Game: The first time we find out just how close the Lannister siblings are, they're getting it on in an empty tower. Unfortunately for young Bran Stark, accidentally bearing witness to this icky encounter evidently gets him pushed out of said tower and permanently paralysed, an action Jaime attributes to "love".

Daenerys & Khal Drogo get it on.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 1, Episode 2, The Kingsroad
The Players: Daenerys & Khal Drogo
The Game: Things get off to a rocky (rapey) start for this arranged couple, but Dany seeks the counsel of some particularly talented friends and winds up finding out that sex can be fun for her, too. In a move that surprises her new husband, she takes control and gets on top, and the two share something a lot more passionate than their first encounters. Talk about a Mother of Dragons, amiright?

'Do I have something on my face?'Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 1, Episode 5, The Wolf and the Lion
The Players: Theon & Ros
The Game: You might remember Theon better now as a sad, psychologically-damaged puppy, but in the early day of Thrones, he was a complete and total misogynist man whore. In one of many sexy times he spent with Ros, the two played rough and tested each others' boundaries - in more way than one.

... and that's how demon shadow babies are made.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 2, Episode 2, The Night Lands
The Players: Melisandre & Stannis
The Game: Stannis is so desperate for power he'll do just about anything, including succumbing to his lust for this fiery lady and creating a demon shadow baby on top of the table that holds all of their plans for conquering Westeros. We can't help but wonder how the Lord of Light felt about this one.

Loras & Renly have a pash.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 2, Episode 3, What Is Dead May Never Die
The Players: Loras & Renly
The Game: While they get into too big of a tiff to actually go through and have sex in this particular encounter, the forbidden duo's chemistry is totally electric. Here, Loras loses his temper with Renly and ditches him for the evening, but they clearly get off on this game of push and pull.

A rare non-weird Game of Thrones sex scene.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 2, Episode 8, The Prince of Winterfell
The Players: Robb & Talisa
The Game: It's pretty obvious from their first meeting that Robb and Talisa seriously want to get it on, so it comes as no surprise when they finally frantically strip down and have sex on the floor of Robb's tent. It's one of the rare sexual encounters on Thrones that features actual love and sweetness rather than rage-driven lust, making their future grisly fate even more difficult to deal with.

We had to crop this picture close, there was a LOT going on in the rest of the frame.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 3, Episode 3, Walk of Punishment
The Players: Podrick & Pals
The Game: Say what you want about Tyrion, but the man takes care of his friends. When poor young Podrick's lack of sexual experience becomes obvious, he sets him up with some of his favourite ladies in the brothel, leaving him with three very eager, experienced friends ready to help gain him some real-world knowledge.

Skinny dippin'.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 3, Episode 5, Kissed by Fire
The Players: Ygritte & Jon Snow
The Game: Jon Snow proved he knew a little more than nothing in this long-anticipated indulgence of these two characters' fieriest desires, and it does not disappoint. After being led into this sexy cave by spunky redhead Ygritte, this future King in the North also proves to be a King of the South, much to Ygritte's surprise. While cave sex can't be super hygienic, it's always nice to see some characters on this godforsaken show have brief moments of happiness.

Three's a crowd.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 3, Episode 7, The Bear and the Maiden Fair
The Players: Theon, Myranda, and Violet
The Game: Poor, poor Theon/Reek. After being tortured by Ramsay, he is surprised to find himself in the middle of some sort of relief - a sexy threesome. Little does he know, however, that this ill-fated encounter is part of the torture too, and is the last time he'll ever get to get it on.

Again, we had to crop this photo quite tight. Sorry, filth lovers.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 3, Episode 8, Second Sons
The Players: Melisandre, Gendry, and some leeches
The Game: Another man subjected to the wicked workings of another, Gendry finds himself in what he thinks is a very, very hot situation with our Red Priestess after she seduces him and ties him up in bed. Unsuspecting Gendry has no idea that his blood is needed for some very specific dark magic, so when she pulls out some leeches and sics them on him, he understandably freaks out. This is not the kink he bargained for.

It's like a Spencer Tunick photo up in hereSource:Supplied
The Episode: Season 4, Episode 3, Breaker of Chains
The Players: Oberyn, Ellaria & Company
The Game: It's no secret that the Dornish are pretty much down for anything, and they prove this early on during a visit to the infamous King's Landing brothel, where they get a gang together for their erotic exploits. While Oberyn might have only really had eyes for Ellaria no matter how many genitalia were flying around him, in the end, we know he ends up with no eyes at all.

Standing up? How EuropeanSource:Supplied
The Episode: Season 5, Episode 5, Kill the Boy
The Players: Ramsay & Myranda
The Game: Ramsay is a monster on many, many levels, including with the poor (and slightly evil) Myranda, who is unhealthily obsessed with him. Despite her jealousy of Sansa and sass with Ramsay, she totally gives into playing rough with him, indulging his grossest, most sadistic fantasies.

'Relatively normal intercourse'. Groundbreaking ...Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 5, Episode 7, The Gift
The Players: Daenerys & Daario
The Game: It's so nice when sex is not death-related, or forced, or creepy on this show. This sweet, relatively normal intercourse between the super hot, bearded Daario and our Khaleesi makes our hearts a little warm and fuzzy, mainly because she deserves a nice guy after everything she's been through. While their conversation turns to strategy (and sees her reveal that she is not down to get married), the build-up is incredibly passionate.

Lucky last on our list.Source:Supplied
The Episode: Season 7, Episode 2, Stormborn
The Players: Grey Worm & Missandei
The Game: Ugh, it's ABOUT TIME! These two adorable, loyal followers of Dany have been making eyes at each other for longer than we can remember, and finally getting to see them strip down and explore each other was so satisfying. While this brief moment of bliss will probably be quickly forgotten in all the violence to come, it's totally appropriate to treasure this passionate, sexy scene as long as we can.
This story originally appeared on and is republished here with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walk of Punishment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stannis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thrones-related</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myranda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breaker of Chains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Second Sons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bran Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winter Is Coming</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Scenes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jade Budowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daario</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellaria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theon/Reek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stormborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Targaryen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dornish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Tunick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dead May Never Die</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missandei</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ros</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Podrick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Priestess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord of Light</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey Worm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season 1</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season 2</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season 3</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season 5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talisa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gendry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robb</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King of the South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingsroad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EuropeanSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maiden Fair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mother of Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oberyn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khal Drogo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramsay</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ygritte</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince of Winterfell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loras</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Violet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Episode 7</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Episode 5</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Episode 2</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Episode 3</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Episode 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Episode 8</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Night Lands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wild Westeros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Landing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaleesi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melisandre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>hereSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renly</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
