<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400889524955325</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/national/three-plead-guilty-over-terror-plot-to-attack-afp-and-nsw-police-headquarters/news-story/1e823570da47e4283bd7addb4b9082d8</url>
  <title>Notes detail plan for guerilla terror war</title>
  <content>
THREE would-be terrorists have pleaded guilty to a plot involving an attack on the AFP headquarters in Sydney and carrying out guerilla warfare in the Blue Mountains almost three years ago.
Sulayman Khalid, 22, Jibryl Almaouie, 23 and a teenage male who cannot be identified, pleaded guilty on Monday to conspiring to commit a terrorist act.
Chilling handwritten notes and text messages between the plotters detailed a plot by six men to attack the AFP building in Sydney, launch a guerilla war in the Blue Mountains and attack Lithgow jail, according to documents tended in the NSW Supreme Court.
A handwritten note by Ibrahim Ghazzawy, who was sentenced to 8 years' jail earlier this year for his role in the 2014 conspiracy, reveal the group were intent on carrying out an attack.
"The plan is gorilla (sic) warfare (illegible) we are going to go to the woods and attack the dogs there, Blue Mountains and the surrounding forests," the note said.
Another said: "If we are gna do the Istishadi the AFP building is a good target, its in parra or the city," the note said.
Istishadi is an Arabic word for heroic death.
The police found six handwritten notes when they raided the Regents Park home of Khalid on December 18, 2014. Three of which were written by Ghazzawy and included additions by other members of the group including Khalid.
Another note written by Ghazzawy talks about plans to attack Lithgow jail.
"Near by theres lithgow jail, insha Allah if we make progress we will attack it," he wrote.
"On Sunday Abu bakr will tell him the Amir the 2 plans most preferably the Gorrilla warfare first then the istishhadi plan. Abu Azzam will lay (illegible) conditions. (illegible) As soon as we take out a dog, they will attack."
Police also uncovered a list which provided a key coded words used by the group to talk about planning the attack.
The group referred to firearms as "banana" or "motorbikes" while the date of the planned terrorist attack was referred to as the "wedding date" while a meeting of the group was described as a "party".
In a text message exchange between the teen and Khalid on December 3, 2014 the pair discuss sacrificing themselves for Allah.
"Tomatoes and BANANAS is our patience brother in al Islam make dua," the teen wrote.
Dua being the act of supplication.
To which Khalid replied: "Habibi I ask Allah to allow us to leave this world together together together me and you this is what I wish for this is what I want and this is what I ask Allah everyday for to leave to depart from this world with my little brother with my habeeb as I'm writing this to you I'm crying Ishaac I want you to stick by me stand with me together we will leave this life".
Jibryl Almaouie's brother, Mohamed, and Farhad Said were also involved in the plot and pleaded guilty earlier in July to knowingly possess documents connected with the preparation of a terrorist act or acts.
Members of the group were arrested following raids by Joint Counter Terrorism Team in 2014 as part of Operation Appleby investigation.
Khalid, 22, Jibryl Almaouie and his brother Mohamed along with Said and the teen are all in custody and will reappear before the Supreme Court for sentencing in October before Justice Bellew.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jibryl Almaouie, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gorrilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Mountains</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farhad Said</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ishaac I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arabic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ibrahim Ghazzawy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khalid, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Istishadi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allah</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regents Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jibryl Almaouie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khalid</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sulayman Khalid, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operation Appleby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lithgow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Bellew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Azzam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Counter-Terrorism Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Abu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ghazzawy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Habibi I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
