<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400855165216353</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/uber-next-ceo-male-2017-7</url>
  <title>Uber's next CEO will probably be a man despite its massive issues with sexism</title>
  <content>
Every female candidate is out of the running for the position of Uber's next CEO.

According to  and , there are now four people jockeying for the top position at the ride-hailing firm. They're all men, and only one of them isn't white.

HPE's chief executive Meg Whitman was on the list of candidates, but : "Uber's CEO will not be Meg Whitman."

Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg and General Motors' chairman and CEO Mary Barra were also reportedly under consideration, but not interested in the role, according to Recode. EasyJet's former CEO Carolyn McCall, a British leader, was also in the running but didn't work out. McCall is now chief executive of ITV.

One of the four men on the list is outgoing GE chief executive Jeff Immelt, though he's reportedly not the top choice. It isn't clear who else Uber is considering.

The optics of picking another male CEO to succeed Travis Kalanick don't look too good. Kalanick  after a long series of negative headlines, mostly related to Uber's sexist culture.

Those problems blew up in February when former employee , and continued through the year after an Uber executive was fired for

And Kalanick, while CEO, once talked about the fact he'd become more desirable to women since cofounding the company,

According to the New York Times, Uber will announce its new CEO in the next six weeks.

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ITV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Immelt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HPE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg Whitman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Mary Barra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Motors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalanick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Kalanick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Recode</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EasyJet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Carolyn McCall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
