<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400545927565653</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/special-reports/trailblazers/reslient-and-creative-leaders-required-for-success-20170730-gxlrkt</url>
  <title>Resilient and creative leaders required for success</title>
  <content>
by
Andrew Birmingham

This content is produced by The Australian Financial Review in commercial partnership with Salesforce.
When Bridget Loudon, co-founder of Expert360, set out to raise her first million dollars, she pitched her story to 72 people. On the the 73rd occasion, somebody said yes.
"In the next round, when we sought to raise four million, we pitched to four people and three said yes. I think the difference between making it and not making it as a leader is just that personal resilience."
According to Loudon, "If you're trying to create something out of nothing, you're going to fail a lot. You'll throw three or four things against the wall and one will stick. Other people don't know about the three things. But you absorb that. You absorb it on a personal level. You absorb it within your teams.

"As a leader, part of your job is absorbing the negativity and stress within a room. People need to walk out of a room with you feeling energised and empowered, and you definitely carry that," she said.

Curiosity, creativity, and resilience are three of the most important qualities of  leadership. However, it is important to recognise that leadership is not a single quality. It is the touchstone that takes a good team and makes it great.
That was the view that emerged from The Australian Financial Review Salesforce Trailblazers round table discussion of the impact of leaders on building fast growth and transformative businesses. The senior executives at the event were debating whether leaders were made or born. While that question failed to deliver a consensus, some common themes emerged.
According to Cambell Holt, chief customer officer at Mercer, "Intellectual curiosity and resilience are less able to be taught and more innate. Some of the best leaders I've had the privilege of working with are the most intellectually curious. I can't see how that's come from their professional experiences or even any other life experiences. That's a quality that just is imbued in certain people."
According to Andy Bateman, national lead partner, Innovation Strategy at Deloitte, "It's been my experience that some of the most transformational leaders are also innately creative.

"They are able to connect the dots other people couldn't see. Some people call that visionary, but it is actually about analysing a lot of information and saying, 'Actually if we put these three things together or these five things together, there's a different future for us.'"
Leaders also understand the need to draw their information from wider sources. They recognise that diversity is not just a moral imperative - it is an economic one.
Companies are missing out on a huge cohort of talent and leadership in terms of  and inclusion, says Eileen O'Mara, senior Vice President of Salesforce APAC. "I think this is the absolute right time for us to be much broader with our inclusiveness around LGBT, around gender, around race. Because whatever lens you brought into this meeting room is based on what you've seen before, and we need to see differently."
Leaders, of course, need more than a creative streak or a curious mind. They need to engage the talents of the people who work for them, says Jim McKerlie, Chairman of Lithium Consolidated Mining Exploration. "Someone might have that inquiring mind, but you need someone else there who's very good with people. It is leadership. If you want that sustainable change, and you want to have it so that it's de-risked, it cannot be one person."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Expert360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambell Holt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovation Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loudon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President of Salesforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridget Loudon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salesforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Bateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman of Lithium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim McKerlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eileen O'Mara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consolidated Mining Exploration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review Salesforce Trailblazers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
