<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400674776586817</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/woolworths-pushing-to-expand-pokies-in-victoria/8760898</url>
  <title>Woolworths in legal fight to expand pokies business in poorer Victorian communities</title>
  <content>
Supermarket giant Woolworths is pushing for an even greater share of Victoria's pokies market after receiving record revenue from the machines last financial year.

Key points:

Woolworths hit a record $669 million in pokies revenue in Victoria last financial year
The company is facing a legal challenge in VCAT from a Victorian council over expansion
A gambling researcher said pokies are entrenching inequality in disadvantaged communities

Woolworths' annual pokies revenue in Victoria grew to $669 million in the 2015-16 financial year, and now it wants to invest in more machines.
But the company is facing a legal battle against the City of Whittlesea over plans to introduce pokies to the heritage Commercial Hotel in South Morang.
Gambling reform campaigners like Stephen Mayne from the Alliance for Gambling Reform say the expansion is wrong and wants proper regulation.
"[Woolworths] are not happy with their current 81 venues across Victoria," Mr Mayne said.
"They're in [the Victorian Civil and Administrative Tribunal] courts trying to add to their portfolio to inject even more misery.
"The Whittlesea community and the council are fighting tooth and nail to say, 'enough Woolworths, take your misery elsewhere'."
The latest State Government figures show Victorians have lost a total of $67 billion in the past 25 years.
Each year, almost $12 billion is eaten up by an estimated 200,000 poker machines across the country.
"Australians are the world's biggest gamblers. We need massive reform to stop the deluge of harm right across the community," Mr Mayne said.
Government data shows Woolworths has collected over a quarter of its pokies revenue from Victorian gamblers.
Mr Mayne said no other state is so dominated by a single operator.
"It was a natural add-on to their dominant liquor position in Australia, and now they are the number one poker machine pusher with more than 12,000 machines across Australia," he said.
Pokies increasingly in low socio-economic areas

The latest pokies data also showed an increasing number of poker machines in lower socio-economic areas of Victoria.
Indeed Melbourne now has 128 postcodes where the mean property value is above $1 million, but hardly any of them host Woolworths pokies venues.

Deakin University gambling researcher Professor Samantha Thomas said Victorians want a significant reduction in poker machines in their community, as well as increased boundaries and regulations.
"That's the community standing up and saying they want a reduction in losses and harms associated with these machines," she said.
Professor Thomas argued poker machines are entrenching inequality in disadvantaged communities.
"It's not good enough to say we'll keep the number of machines the same over the next 20 years or so," she said.
"We have to look at significant harm-prevention strategies which reduce the number of machines and make them less acceptable in the community.
"Ultimately [we need to] not only reduce the financial harms but the social harms associated with these machines."
Government not doing enough: anti-gambling campaigners

Acting Minister for Gaming and Liquor Regulation, James Merlino, said the Victorian Government was doing what it could to minimise the harm caused by poker machines.
In a written statement he said the Government was taking strong action to reduce harm from gambling.
"The figures show that state-wide player loss on gaming machines has actually declined from where it was last year," the statement said.
"Earlier this month, we announced major reforms on gaming machines - including a freeze on the total number of pokies in Victoria for the next 25 years."
Mr Mayne said the Government was not doing enough.
"It's a vital time for gambling regulation in Victoria because the Government is about to introduce legislation, and they want to give new 20-year licences and perpetuate the misery which is being deluged on Victorians," he said.
The Alliance for Gambling Reform claimed money spent on pokies in NSW is currently pushing $6 billion a year and it expected this to increase significantly, particularly from the more vulnerable parts of western and southern Sydney.
Woolworths did not respond to the ABC's request for a comment.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liquor Regulation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Whittlesea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gambling Reform</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mayne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Mayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commercial Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Morang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Civil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Samantha Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Administrative Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Merlino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
