<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400717726260677</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/slain-timothy-pullen-family-call-for-parole-law-change-qld/8760880</url>
  <title>Family of slain man Timothy Pullen calls for changes to Queensland's parole laws</title>
  <content>
The parents of a slain Queensland man are calling for an urgent overhaul of the state's parole laws, as they prepare to see one of the men charged over their son's killing released from prison after spending little more than a year behind bars.
The Queensland Government is due to debate the , an amendment to parole laws that would stop offenders on murder or related charges walking free until they give viable information about the remains of the victim.
The parents of Timothy Pullen, who was killed in Mackay in north Queensland in 2012, said the proposed legislation would offer them hope that those convicted of their son's death may come forward with information about where his remains were.
The 34-year-old was reported missing five years ago and despite six men being charged over the killing, his body has never been found.
A  and his body dumped near Collinsville, west of Townsville, after a $30,000 bounty was put on his head over a drug debt.

His mother, Leanne Pullen, said she still had trouble sleeping, and spent every day hoping she would get a call telling her that her son's body had been found and he could have a proper burial.
"For a long time I was in denial and I just hoped every knock on the door that it would be Tim," she said.
"Then I started waking up every morning at 3:39am, I don't know why, and would have a sinking feeling that his body would be on the front lawn.
''That's not a way to live. It's like we're on a horrible roller coaster that you can't get off.
"We as a family have lost our freedom forever, we are left wondering, always wondering. The parole board have handed this perpetrator his freedom after he served less than 14 months in prison."
Ms Pullen said she felt let down by the justice system and hoped the Government would implement the laws soon.
Shadow Minister for Corrective Services Tim Mander said he hoped to see the Government's bill get bipartisan support.
"If you have been convicted of an unlawful killing and have not co-operated with authorities, you do not deserve to be released from prison early," he said.
Attorney-General Yvette D'Ath said it was important legislation.
"The suffering of victims' families is only extended when a killer withholds the location of a body," Ms D'Ath said.
"This legislation will mean killers are held accountable and grieving relatives get some measure of closure."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General Yvette D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leanne Pullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Pullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrective Services Tim Mander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collinsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Pullen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ath</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
