<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400812215542660</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/nsw-blues-coach-laurie-daley-breaks-silence-on-origin-series-defeat-20170731-gxmkyw.html</url>
  <title>NSW Blues coach Laurie Daley breaks silence on Origin series defeat</title>
  <content>
NSW Blues coach Laurie Daley has dissected the State of Origin series defeat, opening up on the culture of his team after a barrage of criticism in the aftermath of the heartbreaking loss.
Daley expressed his disappointment in Blues duo Josh Dugan and Blake Ferguson for deciding to consume alcohol on the Friday leading into game three, admitting he had no idea the pair had been drinking until after the series.

Up Next

Watene-Zelezniak forgives man who choked him

00:57

More Rugby League Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Did McGuire intentionally stomp Mannah?

Brisbane Bronco Josh McGuire dangerously stood on the ankle of Eels captain Tim Mannah, but was it intentional?

"Did they do anything legally wrong? No they didn't," Daley said on Fox Sports' NRL 360 on Monday night.
"Did we know they were going down to have a few beers? No we didn't. Yes we knew they were going down to Lennox Head to meet up with a mate. Obviously we've done something wrong to allow them to think they can go down there and have a few beers. We all admit it's not a great look. If we had have won we wouldn't have been discussing it but at the end of the day both of those guys would agree that it wasn't a good look and something we will address and need to address.

"I've got a great relationship with those two guys and I'm sure if they had have asked me if they could have a few beers, I would have said no. But that wasn't the case. I'm not holding anyone out as a scapegoat because I need to look at myself and what we've done to suggest to these players they can go out there and do that."
Daley also spoke about the selection of Andrew Fifita in the starting side for game three after reports the coached had backflipped on a decision to start David Klemmer because of a private chat with the Sharks prop.

"I told David he was starting then I had a conversation with Andrew - not about starting on the bench but another conversation that will remain private," Daley said on NRL 360.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"After that conversation I knew I needed Andrew to start. I couldn't afford to have Andrew on the interchange bench ... Andrew was disappointed that I didn't allow him to speak to the media and we discussed that. There were a couple of other issues we discussed but no way did I say to Andrew that you're starting on the bench. We didn't have that conversation. After having that conversation with Andrew I knew he needed to start and I went straight back to David and said he was going to go back to the bench."Photo: Chris Hyde
Fifita was also gagged from talking in the lead up to the series decider, a decision Daley defended.
"I wanted to protect Andrew because he was going through a tough period," Daley said.
"One, he was racially abused on social media and he was very disappointed with that. We also wanted to make sure that the questions to Andrew were about the game coming up. We didn't want Andrew in a situation where he was having to defend the camps, the venues of camps, the racial vilification, the fact his wife was about to give birth.
"Because what I wanted from Andrew was to make sure he was in the right head space to make sure he played his best football. After the performance in game one, he was always a big target for Queensland and they were coming after him. We wanted to make sure we gave him the best possible chance to perform."
 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lennox Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports' NRL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Daley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hyde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watene-Zelezniak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dugan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Blues</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Klemmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bronco Josh McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
