<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400245279849480</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/west-coast-eagles/afl-grand-final-lure-motivates-west-coasts-nic-naitanui-20170731-gxmgbn.html</url>
  <title>AFL grand final lure motivates West Coast's Nic Naitanui</title>
  <content>
West Coast ruckman Nic Naitanui has kept the door open for a fairytale return this AFL season, saying it would be hard to knock back the chance to play in a grand final.
Naitanui hasn't played since undergoing a knee reconstruction in August last year, but he's back in full training at the club.
With just four rounds left in the home-and-away season, Naitanui is running out of time to return.
A very best-case scenario would see Naitanui return in the final round of the season - against Adelaide in Perth.
If the eighth-placed Eagles are already out of finals calculations by then, it's almost certain Naitanui would be wrapped in cotton wool until next season.
But if West Coast can string some wins together and transform themselves into a legitimate premiership threat, then the chances of Naitanui returning would increase significantly.

Naitanui said there was no point making a decision on his availability just yet.
"I'm just going to keep training and see how we go," Naitanui said on Monday.
"The last thing I want to do is just focus on my little rehab stuff, and then we make it to a grand final and I'm not a chance or I've talked myself out of it because I haven't trained the way I want to do.
"Hopefully the team can keep progressing to give me more time, which is what I need."
Playing Naitanui this year would come with risks.
But if the Eagles somehow defied their recent form to make it through to a preliminary final, playing Naitanui might be a gamble worth taking.
West Coast have struggled in the ruck department all season.
Injuries to Naitanui and Scott Lycett (shoulder) has meant veteran Drew Petrie and former Cat Nathan Vardy have been forced to shoulder the ruck duties - with mixed results.
Naitanui, who said his leap isn't back to where it used to be just yet, said he would be open to playing a WAFL match before making an AFL return.
The 201cm ruckman recently completed an intensive two-week training camp in the US, where his reconstructed left knee was put to the test under the watchful eye of renowned sports reconditioning specialist Bill Knowles.
Naitanui says he has full confidence in his knee now, but concedes he still needs to do more work on his jumping, landing, slowing down, and changing directions.
- AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Naitanui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naitanui</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cat Nathan Vardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Lycett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Knowles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast's Nic Naitanui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
