<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400979719270541</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/cricket/australia-must-be-open-to-playing-test-cricket-against-emerging-teams-robert-craddock-writes/news-story/1b6f0be557076916334cfbae1d95b2ff</url>
  <title>Aussie Bangladesh tour well overdue</title>
  <content>
BANGLADESH here we come ... and about time too.
will enable Australia to tour Bangladesh this month and instantly address its reputation as the heavyweight nation that does not give a toss about emerging Test teams.
While the end of year Ashes tour has been treated like a sacred occasion the poor old Bangladesh tour has floated around like that occasional round of weekend golf which drifts on or off your radar depending how busy you are.
The whisper for months has been that some players have deep reservations about touring there and were privately hoping the pay dispute would settle the issue for them.
Now, surely, it's on and we will tip it will provide some of the most intriguing Test cricket of the year.
No one really likes to talk about it but the sad truth is that since Test cricket began 140 years ago Australia have been woeful at helping new Test nations find their footing.
And not just Bangladesh.
Officials from New Zealand and India have their own sorry tales about how Australia brushed them early in their Test development.
Since Bangladesh's admission to the Test arena way back in 2000 Australia have played them only four times in Tests, six times fewer than England, and its sole tour there was 12 years ago.
DEAL DONE:
Zimbabwe tells a similar story. When they were admitted as a Test nation a senior Australian official summed up our nation's dismissive nature with the line "we support their introduction into Test cricket in a non-playing sense.''
That's like saying "I can heartily recommend that butcher but I will never buy meat off him.''
Consequently Australia played Zimbabwe just three times in Tests, half as many as England played before the Africans temporarily lost their Test status.
New Zealand's story was even more stark.
Australia's lone Test (and it didn't even have Test status at the time) just after WWII was the only time Australia played New Zealand in 43 years between their first Test against England in 1929 and the Kiwis tour of Australia in 1973-74.
In that time England played New Zealand in 13 different series or one-off Tests.
When India were struggling to emerge as a Test nation Australia went 20 years between 1948 and 1968 without inviting them to tour Australia.
India now rule the cricketing world and take great delight in pushing around the nations who once pushed around them.
The moral of the story is be kind to the new boys - you never know when you are going to need them.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWII</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zimbabwe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
