<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400936769596752</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-union/brumbies/former-act-brumbies-president-geoff-larkham-slams-melbourne-rebels-merger-talk-20170731-gxm90t.html</url>
  <title>Geoff Larkham slams ARU after Melbourne Brumbies talk</title>
  <content>
The ACT Brumbies will be the only Australian Super Rugby club to announce a profit this season but it hasn't stopped Perth billionaire Andrew Forrest from dragging them back into merger talks.
The vocal Western Force backer has declared  to stop the Australian Rugby Union from axing the Force as the two parties began arbitration on Monday.Photo: Sitthixay Ditthavong
when the ARU promised to axe the Force or Melbourne Rebels within 72 hours.

That timeline was quickly scrapped and with no resolution after almost four months, Forrest is pushing for a Brumbies and Rebels merger to save the Force.
and have made the finals for the past five years in a row, while the Rebels won just won game this season.

Former Brumbies president Geoff Larkham has slammed the ARU board for allowing the saga to drag on and said he wouldn't be surprised if they backflipped on their promise to the Brumbies.
"The way they've performed I could see them doing that and that would be an absolute disaster if they did, they would need a complete sacking of the board if that happened," Larkham said.
"The debacle that has happened at ARU management level and board level is unprecedented and it's unbelievable an organisation such as this can keep carrying on the way it is.
"There's obviously pressures there that I'm not aware of and legal threats, but it's a situation where the hierarchy cannot make a decision and if they can't make decisions then they shouldn't be there.
"It astounds me the state of Australian rugby these days and I feel for the fans, players, staff and coaches."
Supporters of a Brumbies merger have pointed to Canberra's small population but Larkham said the numbers speak for themselves and it would make no sense to boot Australia's strongest club.
"This conversation should never be happening, we're the best performing club on and off the field and we should be the last team kicked out," Larkham said.
"In the history of the Brumbies we've only had to borrow money from ARU once and it was completely returned, whereas all the other franchises have borrowed or been gifted money and the majority has never been returned.
"The small population argument doesn't hold weight, we've always fought above our weight as a small state and if you look at the playing numbers we're 10-fold better than NSW and Queensland against their populations.
"I'm sure the Waratahs would love to see us go. They'd take over the ACT and I don't know what they'd expect to find in the way of supporters, but they'd love to rule the roost of over southern NSW and the ACT.
"The ACT schoolboys did remarkable well winning the national championships against all the odds this year, and did it quite convincingly, but only two kids made the Australian side which just typifies what happens here."
Larkham has tipped the Force to win their arbitration battle and that all five Australian teams will remain next season.
"I don't think a team will be cut and that we'll have 16-team competition next year. The ARU will have to go to SANZAAR and say 'sorry it can't happen' but we might all get kicked out then," Larkham said.
"Ultimately South Africa may go with the northern hemisphere and we may be left with competition between us, New Zealand and Asia which I wouldn't mind, but who know, it's a bloody mess."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rugby Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Larkham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Brumbies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Forrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Brumbies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Rebels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larkham</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sitthixay Ditthavong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanzaar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
