<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400468618152965</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-07-31/brownlow-not-a-factor-in-dangers-appeal-decision</url>
  <title>Brownlow 'not a factor' in Danger's appeal decision</title>
  <content>
How the MRP's judged 'dangerous tackles'
This is how some of the cases have been adjudicated in 2017

Patrick Dangerfield will weigh up what's best for the team when considering an appeal

PATRICK Dangerfield says his Brownlow Medal defence will not be a factor as the Cats weigh up whether to challenge the Geelong superstar's one-match suspension for a dangerous tackle on Monday night.

Dangerfield emerged from a team meeting on Monday afternoon to the news  for a tackle that left Carlton ruckman Matthew Kreuzer with concussion on Saturday.

If the Cats choose to challenge his ban they would risk Dangerfield missing a second match, with Friday night's clash against Sydney followed by a crunch game against top-four rival Richmond in round 21.

Dangerfield said a decision on challenging at the Tribunal would be made as a club. 

"We'll make a decision that is best for the team, not the individual, and best for the season," Dangerfield told reporters on Monday afternoon.

"It (the Brownlow Medal) is the last thing on my mind.

"What we're focused on is not only this week but the rest of the season and putting ourselves in a really strong position come the end of the year and come the start of the finals campaign.

"That's an important part of the decision that has to be made." 

. has responded to his ban from the MRP.

Geelong players Tom Hawkins (one match for striking), Sam Menegola (one match for rough conduct) and James Parsons (two matches for striking) have all been charged by the MRP this season.

In each case the Cats chose not to challenge at the Tribunal.

Coach Chris Scott declared after Hawkins was offered his ban in round 11 that the club would have challenged the striking charge at the Tribunal, but "we feel the odds are stacked against you". 

Seven players have been charged for dangerous tackles this season, with two offered $1000 fines and five banned for either one or two matches. 

Four players have been heavily scrutinised for dangerous tackles but cleared for reasons such as circumstances outside the control of the player or insufficient impact.   
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Menegola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Parsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
