<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401061323650555</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/cricketers-deny-agreement-on-protracted-pay-deal/8761396</url>
  <title>Cricket Australia, players' association deny end to pay dispute</title>
  <content>
Both Cricket Australia and the Australian Cricketers' Association have denied reports an agreement has been reached over their pay dispute.
It was reported on Monday evening a deal between the two parties was close to being finalised and could be announced as early as tomorrow.
"Negotiations are ongoing - no agreement has been reached," a spokesman for CA told the ABC.

External Link:

May Gearin: ABC understands significant progress made in cricket deal; parties working thru number of steps; Key elements yet to fall into place
Australia is due to play a two-Test series in Bangladesh in late August and there have been doubts about whether the tour will go ahead.
The  could also be scrapped.
Officials were forced to  because of the stand-off.
The bitter pay dispute has taken several twists and turns, with CA recently threatening to take the stoush to an independent umpire were it not resolved.
The impasse with the ACA came over the players' association's desire to dismantle a fixed-revenue-sharing system of player payments.
ACA hit back at those threats, saying the governing body was trying to end a successful 20-year partnership without making a case.
About 230 male and female cricketers have been out of contract since the most recent Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) expired on July 1, and have not been paid.
Several players have taken a vocal stand on social media, with Australia's vice captain David Warner pointing the blame at CA.
"This Baggy means the world to me. Myself and all the other cricketers female and male want to get out there and play," he said on Instagram.
The union said despite frustration at the way CA had handled negotiations, players had made important concessions in those talks.
Players have continued to train throughout the dispute, and the national men's team is due to come together for a training camp in Darwin next week.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memorandum of Understanding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gearin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
