<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400245279849477</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>IT News</source>
  <url>http://www.itnews.com.au/event/industry-breakfast---the-path-to-self-disruption---are-you-ready-469748</url>
  <title>Industry Breakfast - The path to Self-Disruption - Are you ready?</title>
  <content>
Phone:

0481232419

Pricing:

This seminar is FREE and a complimentary breakfast will be provided.

Interactive, an Australian IT services company, presents a business breakfast focused on the changing customer landscape and the benefits, challenges and value-add in migrating from legacy systems to the cloud.

Beat the disruptors at their own game. 

Is your business part of Australia's retail eco-system?  Are you ready for Amazon's arrival into the marketplace?

This breakfast will be an opportunity to hear insights directly from retail giant, Swisse, along with the likes of leading industry experts and solutions architects. 

Gain valuable insight into:

 

How the future of retail sales and profit is tech; What your CEO needs to know 

Practical examples of migration to the cloud - Do's and Don'ts.

Securing data - how to keep your data safe

Supercharging your customers' experience 

Cloud ROI: building an effective business case

This seminar is free and a complimentary breakfast will be provided. 
E: lclausen@interactive.com.au

Venue Information:

Aug 29, 2017, 8:00 AM  to  9:30 AM

25 Collins St, Melbourne
Melbourne: City & inner suburbs, Victoria, Australia

nextmedia takes no responsibility for the accuracy of the content contained in these listings.
Please contact the vendor with any enquiries.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian IT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Self-Disruption</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 29, 2017, 8:00 AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
