<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400975424303193</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/19/57/mahmoud-hrouk-murder-trial-aymen-terkmani</url>
  <title>Mahmoud Hrouk spoke with mum on phone before he was allegedly killed with a toaster</title>
  <content>
Sixteen-year-old Mahmoud Hrouk answered several calls from his worried family when he failed to return home on the night of May 16, 2015.
His father told him to "hurry up". His mother said, "where are you?"
Mahmoud replied: "It's ok mum I'm with a friend. I have my bike, I will come home."
She called again, telling him: "I'm coming to pick you up. Where are you? Don't worry about the bike."
He told her, "I'm at Aymen's house", before the phone cut out.
That was the final time they spoke.
His family spent the night searching for him and found his body the next morning at a vacant house nearby.

Related Articles

Today, two years on, his alleged killer Aymen Terkmani faced trial in the NSW Supreme Court.
Crown Prosecutor Adrian Robertson alleged Mr Terkmani "left the deceased lying in a pool of blood, naked from the waist down".
"He took the deceased's money, his two phones, his Nikes," Mr Robertson said.
He said a toaster was also found inside.
"One of the sides was bent inwards and was covered with blood," Mr Robertson said.
Mr Terkmani had told others he was renovating the vacant house, but the Crown alleged he also went there to play pool and smoke cannabis.
The court heard bloody shoe prints at the scene matched his size.
Police also alleged they found a black Adidas bumbag inside Mr Terkmani's home nearby.
Inside there was a $5 note, which had a small spot of blood that tested positive for the victim's DNA.
Mr Terkmani has pleaded not guilty.
"Not only has the accused denied to police that he was even present at the scene where the deceased was alleged to have been killed, but his father says he was home," his barrister Mark Austin told the court.
The trial is expected to run for four weeks.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Robertson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Terkmani</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aymen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Hrouk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adidas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aymen Terkmani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Adrian Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
