<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400464323185649</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/glenvale-woman-charged-over-rangeville-attempted-m/3207150/</url>
  <title>Glenvale woman charged over Rangeville attempted murder</title>
  <content>
BREAKING: A woman has been charged with attempted murder more than a week after a man was shot twice outside a Rangeville home.

Toowoomba detectives today charged a Glenvale woman, 26, with attempted murder after an alleged shooting incident outside a Curzon St home on July 19.

Police will allege just after 1am that day, a 20-year-old man was speaking with two men outside the home when he was shot in the knee and abdomen.

The Glenvale woman is the second to be charged in relation to the incident and will appear in Toowoomba Magistrates Court tomorrow.

It follows charges against a Scarborough man, 23, who was earlier this month charged with attempted murder, possessing a firearm and ammunition, driving offences and stealing.

He was remanded in custody to appear in the Toowoomba Magistrates Court on September 14.

Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Marilyn Freeman won Toastmasters International Speech district event
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rangeville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenvale</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters International Speech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curzon St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
