<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401018373976889</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/laurie-daley-speaks-on-blues-state-of-origin-issues/news-story/5acd5f3956948cea7bef27cd38dbebfc</url>
  <title>Daley in dark over Origin shocker</title>
  <content>
NEW South Wales coach Laurie Daley has broken his silence on the issues the Blues faced heading into the State of Origin decider.
The Blues culture has come under great scrutiny since their Origin capitulation and Daley admits New South Wales needs a "reality check", and "culture" is the first thing on his list to overhaul.
"The thing for me, and everyone has had their say on it, is culture," Daley told NRL 360.
"There are things there we could have done a lot better and with me being in charge I have to expect full responsibility for that.
"Any culture that you do have, you will have some things go wrong and you will always have opportunities to fix that as you go along the journey."
Plenty of things did go wrong for the Blues throughout the Origin campaign. The preparation for the final Origin match was blighted by infighting and ill-discipline.
Daley revealed that he only found out the extent of Josh Dugan and Blake Ferguson's eight hour drinking session the day after Origin III.
"I found out the Thursday after the game," Daley said.
"No one had any idea. No one had any idea of what happened.
"Did we know they were going down there to have a few beers? - No we didn't. We knew they were going down to Lennox Head to meet up with a mate.
"Obviously we've done something wrong for them to think they can go down there and have a few beers. We all admit it's not a great look. It's something we will and need to address."
Also, Daley spoke on the fiasco surrounding his plan to start David Klemmer in place of Andrew Fifita being overturned at the final hour, and both players going into the match thinking they were starting the Origin decider.
"I told David that he was starting," Daley said. "Then I had a conversation with Andrew not about starting on the bench, another conversation which will remain private. After that conversation I knew I needed Andrew to start.
"I couldn't afford to have him on the interchange bench. There were a couple of other issues that we discussed along the way. But no way did I say to Andrew 'you're starting on the bench'.
"After having the conversation I went back to David and told David that he was going to go back to the interchange bench."
While Daley admits Dugan and Ferguson did nothing illegal in heading down to Lennox Head for their drinking session, further punishment could arise.
The Blues coach did not say to what that may be, but he did say that several players will be dealt with when the squad comes together to reflect on the series at a later date.
"In terms of people being hung out to dry, that's not my go, publicly," Daley said.
"Internally, yes, that's what I think a strong culture would do.
"We address it as a group and address on what we consider to be the best by the group."
Daley admitted that his coaching staff underestimated the impact of the Blues blowing their opportunity to win game two and secure the series.
Queensland fought back to force a decider, where they blew New South Wales off the park.
The Blues coach says his staff failed to properly measure the impact the crushing defeat had on his side.
"Looking back now I think we were more scarred than I thought we were," Daley said.
"Something happened after that game and we lost a bit of confidence out of that.
"You could see they were really disappointed, but I thought that would help motivate them."
Daley will now undertake a review to find out what went wrong in the 2017 Origin campaign and admits his coaching position is no guarantee.
"It's something that haunts me," Daley said,
"I've got to find out why. The only way I can do that is get my points of view across and speak to the players and get an honest assessment. It's in the best interests of New South Wales rugby league that they have the best person.
"Obviously I've got a passion, I love doing the job, but it's the board that will come up that decision. I'm sure they'll make the right choice. I think New South Wales are on the verge of really good times.
"We've beaten Queensland before and we'll do it again under my watch."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daley</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lennox Head</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dugan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dugan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Klemmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin III</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
