<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400936769596684</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/canberra-uniteds-hayley-raso-says-matildas-can-be-best-in-world-after-japan-win-20170730-gxlzow.html</url>
  <title>Matildas star Hayley Raso says they can become best in world</title>
  <content>
The Matildas have followed their  with a comeback win against fierce rivals Japan in San Diego on Monday.
Three days after securing a maiden victory against world number one side USA, the Matildas were back to their devastating best Photo: Sean M. Haffey
The win was Australia's biggest over the "Nadeshiko" in 32 years as 23-year-old striker Samantha Kerr starred with a first half hat-trick.

Japan went ahead before Kerr scored her first thanks to a pinpoint cross from Canberra United defender Hayley Raso who showed electric pace down the right flank to set up the equaliser.
The Matildas never looked back and Raso said it was great to pull one back against Japan after 1-0 losses in the 2015 World Cup quarterfinal and 2014 Asian Cup decider.

"We've suffered a few tough losses to them, they are a class side, so there's a bit of a rivalry there and it's really exciting to get a win against them and show we can compete against the top countries in the world," Raso said.
"It was awesome to get the win against the USA, coming out and beating them for the first time in our history shows how well we're performing and to back it up against Japan is awesome.
"I think this is definitely one of the strongest Matildas sides I've ever been in and it comes down to a lot of us playing overseas and it just shows there is depth and quality and we can adapt to anyone."
The Matildas close out their Tournament of Nations campaign against Brazil on Friday and victory will see the sixth-ranked Australia crowned champions.
"We definitely we can beat anyone on our day and if we continue to beat the best in the world then one day we will be number one and results in these tournaments show we want be there," Raso said.
The match against the South American giants also provides a chance for the Matildas to avenge their Rio Olympics quarterfinal exit at the hands of Brazil in a penalty shoot-out.
"Everyone will be ready and raring to go for that one. I wasn't at the Olympics but I know it was tough on the girls to go out like that, so it will be extra motivation for some and I'm sure they'll go and show that," Raso said.
The 22-year-old said the challenge now is to replicate their form at the World Cup qualifiers next year and beyond.
"This is just setting a standard and hopefully we can continue to show we can perform and win big games in big tournaments, hopefully this is it just the start," Raso said.
Canberra United coach Heather Garriock has been in talks with Raso about returning to the capital for the next W-League season, but the defender said she hasn't made a final decision where she'll play.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heather Garriock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raso</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley Raso</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W-League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean M. Haffey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nadeshiko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
