<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400502977891949</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4824001/illawarra-radio-doctors-car-set-on-fire-during-house-call/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Illawarra radio doctor's car set on fire during house call</title>
  <content>
The car's rear catches alight before firefighters arrive. Pictures: supplied

Firebugs have set a doctor's car alight as he made a house call at Mangerton on Sunday night.

The doctor cancelled visits to another four patients as he dealt with fallout from the blaze, which has now taken one of Radio Doctor Illawarra's three cars off the road. 
The GP left the car - a brand new, unmarked Toyota Corolla hybrid - unattended while visiting a resident of Myuna Way at about 10pm. 

He and a driver chaperone returned five minutes later to find a rear wheel and bumper alight. 

Video obtained by the Mercury captures the frantic early efforts of neighbours to snuff out the blaze. One is heard proposing the use of a "water bucket, the water bucket!" before a concerned onlooker calls them off. 

"Our fear was that it may have exploded as fuel was leaking out of it," said one resident, adding car fires were common in the neighbourhood. 

"As a resident of Mangerton I'm over the fires being started on people's cars. No one can leave their car anywhere, it's sad."

Radio Doctor Illawarra general manager Frank Wallner said firefighters extinguished the blaze before it destroyed the car.

"Half of the rear bumper and the tyre have melted away. Fortunately it doesn't seem to have affected the fuel filler on that side," he said. 

"If it overheated and if they [the doctor and driver] hadn't come out when they did, who knows what could have happened.
"Really it's unsafe. Potentially that vehicle could have exploded. When you're in a residential area it's dangerous and stupid.

"Everyone was OK but it's obviously annoying and a little anxiety-inducing for the doctor and driver as they go about their business helping people who are unwell in the evenings." 

The car was driven to the service's North Wollongong headquarters under police escort and has since been taken to a smash repairers. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Wallner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Corolla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio Doctor Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Firebugs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mangerton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mangerton I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myuna Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
