<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400941064564137</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/07/31/alleged-bomb-plotters-may-have-tried-smuggle-device-plane-reports</url>
  <title>Alleged bomb plotters may have tried to smuggle device on plane before: reports</title>
  <content>
A father and son are claimed to be two of the four men arrested in various locations around Sydney on Saturday over an alleged plot to bring down an aircraft.

Source:

SBS World News, AAP

4 HOURS AGO  UPDATED 4 MINS AGO

The men in custody over an alleged NSW terror plot to bring down a plane may have already tried once before to smuggle a bomb on an international flight, according to media reports.

The ABC's 7.30 program claims that before the weekend raids in which four men were detained, the group was suspected of making a previous failed attempt, and the next plan was to get it on to a domestic flight.

There's also speculation the alleged plot may have involved an improvised bomb inside a meat grinder or poisonous gas, but authorities remain tight-lipped about what they've found as the investigation continues.

Detectives spent Monday scouring five properties in the Sydney suburbs of Surry Hills, Lakemba, Wiley Park and Punchbowl that were raided on the weekend.

The men - named in media as fathers and sons Khaled and Mahmoud Khayat and Khaled and Abdul Merhi - continue to be questioned at Sydney City Police Station after being arrested on Saturday.

The ABC's 730 program is also claiming some of the men have links to Islamic State fighters overseas.

Australian Federal Police are yet to confirm details of the suspects.

News Corp Australia reports the group planned to use either a bomb hidden inside a meat grinder or a device to disseminate poisonous gas on board a plane.

"I don't want to go into the detail but ... there was a significant threat that federal police, ASIO, NSW police and other agencies dealt with and are in the process of dealing with," Border Protection Minister Peter Dutton said on Monday.

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull described the conspiracy as "a very serious terrorist plot" but refused to elaborate.

He also refused to say whether the tip-off that triggered Saturday's raids came from overseas.

"Good intelligence, great police work, great investigation, great co-ordination has enabled us to disrupt that plot," Mr Turnbull told reporters in Perth.

Federal police seized part of a domestic meat grinder and a box containing a multi-mincer for making sausages from one of the men's homes, the Daily Telegraph reported.

The conspiracy may have involved smuggling the grinder in hand luggage onto a flight from Sydney to the Middle East.

After rifling through garbage bins at a property in Lakemba on Monday, police also found airline documentation known as a flight release slip relating to a Sydney to Jakarta flight.

Police are also reportedly concerned the men are so-called "cleanskins" with no previous association to a known group.

Australian National University criminologist Clarke Jones believes the poisonous gas theory is less likely than the grinder plot and suggested the latter was "amateurish" in nature.

"If it was to be hand luggage, that's a very crude plan and shows a lack of experience and the fact that they might not have travelled a great extent," he told AAP.

Meanwhile, travellers at Australian airports spent the day dealing with lengthy delays due to heightened security procedures.

Dr Jones said the beefed-up security was a typical response as the government seeks to deter would-be terrorists and demonstrate their capability.

But he also called for a heavier focus on prevention and community engagement.

"It's been full steam ahead in relation to security, legislation, police and intelligence ... at the expense of community resilience and building up protective mechanisms within vulnerable communities," he said.

A magistrate on Sunday granted police an additional period of detention meaning the four suspects can be held for up to a week without charge.

Security increased after terror plot allegations 

Airports across Australia have beefed up security procedures after the raids, with travellers being asked to pack light and arrive early for their flights.

Passenger, hand and checked luggage screening has been ramped up at all Australian airports, causing long delays.

Domestic passengers have been told to arrive two hours before flight departures, and international passengers three hours before, to allow for tougher checks including more intensive screening for explosives.

But permanent security upgrades could be imposed at Australian airports to protect travellers.

Australian Federal Police Commissioner Andrew Colvin also flagged possible long-term changes saying security measures were "always" under review.

Turnbull says Australian security agenies are unrelenting in efforts to keep public safe

Mr Turnbull said the measures would remain in place "for as long as the threat is assessed as requiring them".

But Mr Dutton suggested more permanent changes may lie ahead.

"It may be that we need to look at the security settings at our airports - in particular our domestic airports - for an ongoing, enduring period," Mr Dutton said.

What we know so far

What was the alleged plot?

The group allegedly planned to use an improvised device to bring down an aeroplane in as Islamist-inspired conspiracy, however police say they have limited information so far about the date, location or specific strategy involved.

What happened during the raids?

NSW and Federal Police swooped on five properties in the Sydney suburbs of Surry Hills, Lakemba, Wiley Park and Punchbowl on Saturday afternoon and found a "considerable" amount of material. But police won't say if they discovered an actual explosive device.

Who is in custody?

Four men were arrested and are assisting with police inquiries. No details have been released by police about their age, background or relationships to one another.

Could it have happened?

AFP Commissioner Andrew Colvin said they treated the plot as credible and there was an intention and "quite possibly a capability" to carry it out. However, he also said there was no reason to believe security at Australian airports has been jeopardised.

What's changing at airports?

Travellers have been told to arrive two hours earlier to make allowances for increased scrutiny. They may notice "intensified" security procedures, but some bolstered arrangements will happen behind the scenes. Travellers have also been asked to limit baggage to make things easier.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS World News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP Commissioner Andrew Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarke Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Protection Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 4 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dutton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's 7.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney City Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police Commissioner Andrew Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's 730</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jakarta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
