<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400932474629361</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/policy/climate/just-how-far-can-california-go-on-reducing-carbon-emissions-20170731-gxm3t9</url>
  <title>Just how far can California go on climate</title>
  <content>
by
Brad Plumer

Over the past decade, California has passed a sweeping set of climate laws to test a contentious theory: that it's possible to cut greenhouse gas emissions far beyond what any other state has done and still enjoy robust economic growth.
Now that theory faces its biggest test yet. Last August, the State Legislature set a goal of slashing emissions  a far deeper cut than President Barack Obama proposed for the entire United States and deeper than most other countries have contemplated.
So how will California pull this off?
Governor  signed a new law  in late July, which is expected to play a big role. But cutting greenhouse gases this deeply will involve more than . The state plans to rethink every corner of its economy, from urban planning to dairy farms.

No one knows yet if it can succeed. "You can think of California as a giant laboratory" for climate action, said , of the Haas School of Business at the University of California, Berkeley.

If California prevails, it could provide a model for other policymakers, even as President Donald Trump scales back the federal government's efforts on . The state may also develop new technologies that the rest of the world can use to cut emissions.
And if California falters, or if the experiment proves too costly? "Other states and countries will be watching that, too," Mr Borenstein said.
Uncharted territory

Until now, most states have followed a standard playbook for curbing emissions. Market forces have replaced older coal plants with cheaper and cleaner natural gas, while state mandates have added modest shares of wind and  to the grid. As a result, domestic carbon dioxide emissions  at relatively little cost.

But California has now plucked most of that low-hanging fruit. The state's emissions are nearly back to 1990 levels, it  and it  as the rest of the country combined. Per capita, California has , after New York and the District of Columbia, which means further cuts will come less easily than they would for a state like Texas.
"Each additional increment of carbon reduction is tougher than the previous one," said  He added, "California will have to reach deeper into the bag of technologies" to cut emissions from more stubborn polluters such as  refineries and cement plants.
In January, California's Air Resources Board, which has broad latitude to carry out the state's climate laws,  for cutting emissions 40 per cent below 1990 levels by 2030.
First, by law, California must get 50 per cent of its electricity from renewable sources by 2030, up from 25 per cent today. That's a herculean task in itself: The state  during afternoons and will soon have to juggle ever larger shares of intermittent renewable electricity, by deploying batteries, reworking its grid or taking .

Farmers push back

Second, the board envisioned the number of  and other zero-emissions vehicles on California's roads rising to 4.2 million by 2030 from 250,000 today. Freight trucks would have to become more efficient or electrified, while cities would need to adopt far-reaching strategies to promote mass transit, biking and walking.
But a major push on renewable power and transportation would get California just one-fourth of the way towards its goal. Other cuts would come from , no mean feat in a state that already has some of the strictest building codes in the country. The state would also need to lower the carbon content of its gasoline supply under the , possibly by increasing biofuel use.
One-third of the reductions in the proposal would come from curbing climate pollutants other than carbon dioxide, including hydrofluorocarbons from airconditioners and methane from landfills, wastewater facilities and manure piles at dairy farms. No state has ever regulated agriculture so aggressively, and dairy farmers , warning that capturing methane from millions of cows could prove untenable.

In its proposal, the board emphasised that some of these strategies may not pan out - for instance, the Trump administration could  to force automakers to build more zero-emissions vehicles. Other regulations might reduce emissions less than anticipated, especially if California's economy grows faster than expected.
So, as a complement to these efforts, Mr Brown insisted on expanding another major program: cap and trade.
Cap and trade starts to bite

In 2012, under a previous climate law signed by Governor Arnold Schwarzenegger, the Air Resources Board imposed a statewide ceiling on greenhouse gas emissions. It then distributed a fixed number of tradeable pollution permits to power plants, refineries, factories and other large emitters.

Under this , businesses need to either cut their emissions or buy permits. The idea is that by setting a price on carbon, cap and trade spurs businesses to figure out for themselves the most economical way to reduce pollution. The total number of permits is intended to dwindle each year, pushing the state's emissions downward.
Economists call the approach  than inflexible regulations.
So far, California's initial cap has had a relatively minor effect on emissions, as other policies, like the renewable electricity mandate, have done most of the heavy lifting and businesses have had relatively little trouble staying under pollution limits.
But as the cap keeps tightening, it's expected to have a sharper bite. The law Mr Brown signed extends the program through to 2030, and limits the ability of businesses to purchase cheap offsets to comply (by, for example, paying for tree-planting programs).
If it works, the Air Resources Board expects cap and trade to deliver at least one-quarter of the emissions cuts needed by 2030. And, by auctioning off permits, the state will raise billions of dollars for more climate programs. California  from past auctions to help finance  between Los Angeles and San Francisco, though under the new law lawmakers will have more say over spending and may redirect funds elsewhere.
In order to secure approval, the bill's backers made a number of compromises to critics worried that a strict cap might harm the state's competitiveness. Industries at risk of relocating  to cushion the blow. (Some environmental groups  for making too many concessions to polluters.)
Notably, the Air Resources Board must also now set a ceiling on permit prices - if they spike, regulators will flood the market with permits to prevent a political backlash. While no one is exactly sure how much California's climate policies will ultimately cost, this ceiling will set a limit on that price tag: if climate policy poses too severe a threat to economic growth, the state will prioritise growth.
Lessons for the wider world

Mr Brown has promoted California's policies as a way of convincing the world that the United States won't abandon the fight against climate change, even after President Trump announced a withdrawal from the Paris climate agreement. "I want to do everything we can to keep America on track, keep the world on track," Mr Brown  in May.
California is responsible for only 1 per cent of global emissions. But it could contribute even more to the world's efforts by advancing new tools to tackle climate change, such as .
If the state stumbles, that could provide valuable lessons, too. By 2030, California , Diablo Canyon, which provides 9 per cent of the state's electricity. The idea is to replace that lost power with renewables and efficiency. If that proves unworkable, it could offer a warning
California's push to make cap and trade effective could also have global ramifications, especially since Europe  with its emissions-trading program and China .
"If the cap-and-trade market melted down, that could be a real deterrent elsewhere," said Mr Borenstein, the University of California professor. "The rest of the world is going to be watching closely."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berkeley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>20</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Borenstein</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor Arnold Schwarzenegger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haas School of Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diablo Canyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of California</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brown</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Plumer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District of Columbia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California's Air Resources Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Legislature</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Resources Board</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
