<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400941064564072</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/soccer/les-murray-migrant-icon-idol--larger-than-life-without-the-ego-20170731-gxmazh.html</url>
  <title>Les Murray: Migrant, icon, idol ... larger than life, without the ego</title>
  <content>
The hardest approach I've had to make in my career so far was the one to my idol.
On a quiet afternoon, sitting at the front of the cafe at SBS' studios in Artarmon, was Les Murray. He was dressed impeccably in a pinstripe suit, like a chief executive, but had the manner of a rock star - leaning back with legs folded, he read with one hand and a cigarette in the other.

Up Next

Craig Foster remembers Les Murray

04:52

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

The best of Les Murray

Iconic SBS football presenter Les Murray AM has passed away following a battle with illness. Courtesy SBS

I was about 20, starry-eyed and a low-level production assistant on my second day on the job when I walked over and spluttered a nervous introduction to "Mr Murray".
"Please," he said, drawing from his cigarette. "It's Les."

The split second before his next words felt like an hour as I expected an instant dismissal. I was wrong. "So, Dominic, is it? Would you like a coffee?"
We had one, then another as he discussed football, journalism, SBS and his own values. For about half an hour, the most junior person in the building was treated as an equal by the company's most iconic face.

For all the egos in television, my experience with Les is that he didn't make people feel a gulf in stature. That was despite his larger-than-life aura, symbolised by his red Ford Mustang parked in car space No.1, his office being one of the largest in the newsroom and how some colleagues would joke Les worked on his own schedule. But, that's because they also knew he worked tirelessly, and always in pursuit of a cause.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Most importantly, he made people feel respected and valued. I shouldn't have been surprised - that much was evident by his punditry. He gave ethnic groups the ultimate dignity, whether it be his commitment to pronunciation or coverage.Photo: Fiona-Lee Quimby
At a time when 'wogs' were outcasts in school yards, Les, as he asked to be called, told the stories of their communities.
He aggressively pushed the National Soccer League in national media; so, too, the Socceroos and Matildas.
He cornered then SBS chief Brian Johns, near-physically pressuring him to buy the rights of the 1990 World Cup, the first of the eight Les covered: "There's a very good chance nobody in Australia will see the World Cup," he told him.
He brought global issues into Australian homes, famously broadcasting tapes of the successful Red Star Belgrade team of the late 1980s during a period of turmoil in Yugoslavia.
Before doing so, he spent days with the Serbian community to understand the history of the team and correct pronunciation of names. Whether it was Portuguese, Italian, Croatian or Greek teams, he conducted the same research and developed a particular fondness for South American football.
He spoke of how identity within football was integral to multiculturalism in Australia. The ability to tell their stories was fundamental to how he saw his role as a broadcaster. His panels were a stark contrast to modern Australian sports punditry, almost entirely made up of male former players.
Les understood the need for former stars, but the most articulate and analytical. The heavy Italian accent of Tony Palumbo was given a national profile, as was enigmatic rock singer Damien Lovelock.
In an industry where females are too often reduced to token roles, the likes of Mariana Rudan, Stephanie Brantz, Lucy Zelic and Liz Deep-Jones were given voices.
To many, football was a symbol of migration and inclusion in Australia and Les' defiance made him just as much an icon of multiculturalism.
As a refugee from Hungary, born Laszlo Urge, he was always a proud advocate for immigration. At a time when the Federal Government was preparing to open a detention centre on Manus Island, Les filmed a mission back to his homeland to find and thank the people smugglers that saved his family. 
The next time we had a coffee was in Double Bay for an interview prior to his retirement in 2014. He said he would work on his golf swing, spend time with his grandchildren and remain peripherally involved in football. Really, he couldn't leave.
On his arrival in Wollongong in 1957, the young Laszlo was ridiculed for being a wog and loving football. His last project was to establish an A-League franchise in that region.
Sadly, he won't be there to complete what would have been his final act of defiance.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manus Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laszlo Urge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz Deep-Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yugoslavia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Double Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Palumbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Soccer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Star Belgrade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford Mustang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dominic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy Zelic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laszlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona-Lee Quimby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariana Rudan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serbian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Lovelock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Croatian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Artarmon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portuguese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Brantz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
