<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400374128870797</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4822953/fly-by-knight-randell-on-grand-final-mission/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Fly-by Knight Randell on grand final mission</title>
  <content>
JUST as Tyler Randell's NRL career with the Newcastle Knights kicked off suddenly and unexpectedly, so too has it ended on an abrupt note.

MOVING ON: Tyler Randell with his wife Kelsey, daughter Lucia and son Koah before their departure for England. Picture: Jonathan Carroll
Randell was midway through a NSW Cup game against Newtown in 2014 when he was hooked from the field and informed that he was to be a late inclusion in Newcastle's top team for their clash with Parramatta, after first-choice hooker Travis Waddell succumbed to illness during the warm-up.

The Aberdeen Tigers junior helped the Knights to a 42-12 victory against the Eels, in the first of 44 top-grade games.

His hopes of adding to that tally ended last week when Knights officials agreed to an early release, allowing the 24-year-old to link with Wakefield Wildcats in time for the English Super League play-offs.
Randell said that after signing a two-year deal with Wakefield, he fully intended to play out the rest of the 2017 campaign with Newcastle.
But having appeared in only five NRL games this season, he did not take much persuading when Wildcats coach Chris Chester contacted him recently to gauge his interest in fast-tracking his transfer.
After discussing it with his wife Kelsey, they decided there was nothing to lose in relocating their young family as soon as possible.
Providing the appropriate paperwork arrives, Tyler, Kelsey and children Lucia and Koah could be on a plane this week, in time for a possible debut against Leeds Rhinos, in Wakefield's second game of the Super Eight play-off series on August 10.

The Wildcats finished fifth at the end of the regular season.

"I was thinking we'd be heading over next year, but then the Wakefield coach rang me a couple of weeks ago, asking did I want to come and help them out in the Super Eights," Randell told the Newcastle Herald.
"I thought I may as well. There's nothing really keeping me here.
"If I was a chance of playing NRL, I might have decided to stay on until the end of the year.
"But if I'm only going to be playing reserve grade, which I think would have been the case, I thought it was a better option to head over there and play six or seven games and maybe help Wakefield get to the grand final.
"They seem to be travelling pretty well."
Randell said organising a move to the other wide of the world in such haste was a logistical challenge.

"My wife and I, we're pretty settled here,'' he said. "It's not as if we just pack a bag and jump on the plane.

"There's a lot to get done and we haven't had a chance to sit down and think about anything yet.

"We're just flat out trying to get everything sorted.'' 
The Randells plans to return to live in Newcastle when their Old Dart adventure is over. How many years down the track that will be, he can only guess.

"I've signed for the rest of this season and then two more years after that,'' he said. "We'll just see how it goes. I've been in Newcastle for 10 years now, so it's pretty exciting to get to experience something new like this.''
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newtown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Knights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randell</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler Randell's NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Dart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelsey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wakefield Wildcats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wakefield</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight Randell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Super League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Waddell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler Randell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildcats</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aberdeen Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leeds Rhinos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Eight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
