<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400631826913032</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/the-future-of-work-17-jobs-and-five-different-careers-20170728-gxko39.html</url>
  <title>The future of work: 17 jobs and five different careers </title>
  <content>
With recent ABS figures showing a continuing deterioration of the teenager labour market, combined with multiple job changes happening later in life, the idea of a career may be evaporating.
A widely held view is that as pathways to work become more uncertain and less linear, young people need certain soft skills to navigate the choppy seas of the contemporary workforce.Photo: AP
Having analysed "over 20 billion hours of work completed by 12 million Australians", a  by the Foundation for Young Australians (FYA) argues that such portable skills and capabilities are vital to succeed in the increasingly automated and globalised workplace of what it calls the "New Work Order". What do young people make of this and what might the gig economy have in store for them?
Careers remain desirable but seem less attainable. A of 5029 Australians aged 18 to 29 found 67 per cent expressed concern about getting a career-related job. A majority (56 per cent) believed that job prospects in their field are not very strong. While most were happy to have multiple careers, nearly the same number want "a career, not just a job". The FYA report suggests "It's more likely that a 15-year-old today will experience a portfolio career, potentially having 17 different jobs over five careers in their lifetime".
The nature of young people's attitudes to work may also be changing. The idea of the "self as enterprise" has been noted by RMIT's  that "cultural, technological and economic transformations that have changed the nature and meanings of work and the sorts of behaviours and dispositions imagined as being necessary for ongoing participation in paid labour".
For example, in a book just published entitled , US anthropologist Ilana Gershon suggests that where labour has conventionally involved a transaction of the employee's time and effort for money, young people increasingly define themselves - and are defined by employers - as a business with a brand.

A  notes that in "peer-to-peer (P2P) economy", companies are shrinking staff, "with many other roles provided by the freelancer or portfolio worker community". Though freelancing "has not yet taken hold in Australia", it has become more common in other countries, and its growth here seems inevitable.  
While being entrepreneurial is not a bad thing, risk and responsibility is transferred to individual entrepreneurs. People working in sectors such as cleaning and hospitality (a big employer of youth) are increasingly asked by employers to provide business numbers; that is, to provide their services as a business.
In doing so, labour protections can be bypassed.  if Deliveroo delivery riders do not receive an order in an hour, they'll earn less than the delivery courier award rate ($18.31 per hour of work), with "no superannuation, no annual leave, no penalty rates and no insurance if they have an accident on their bike".
Leading a business is not for everybody. The survey above found only half of respondents want to be their own boss. If young people are not thinking about themselves as a business, then in the current climate and associated policy appetite for "agility", cultivating enterprise skills in young Australians such as digital literacy, critical thinking and presentation skills will be important.
But the question arises as to the nature of work they will undertake. A  offers the following definition a career: as a noun, it is defined as "an occupation undertaken for a significant period of a person's life and with opportunities for progress". But as a verb, it is to "move swiftly and in an uncontrolled way". Is this the New Work Order awaiting young people today?
Lucas Walsh's book Educating Generation Next: Young People, Teachers and Schooling in Transition is published by Palgrave Macmillan.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palgrave Macmillan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ilana Gershon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Work Order</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deliveroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucas Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P2P</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Educating Generation Next</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FYA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
