<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400979719270521</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/television/romper-stomper-revived-as-tv-series-on-stan/news-story/ee3bddd6dee7d2011e34d4ece299ee85</url>
  <title>Controversial Aussie classic revived as TV series</title>
  <content>
CLASSIC Australian film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel on Stan.
The streaming service announced today that it has started production on the six-part series starring Jacqueline McKenzie, Dan Wyllie, David Wenham and Lachy Hulme. McKenzie and Wyllie are reprising their original roles from the film.
The original 1992 film starred Russell Crowe in his breakout role as a neo-Nazi. The movie attracted controversy for its violent content.
The sequel will be produced by John Edwards, the Australian TV veteran behind Love My Way, Secret Life of Us and Offspring. Geoffrey Wright, who directed the 1992 film, conceived of the revival and will direct episodes alongside Daina Reid.
The resurgence of ultra-right groups in the current political climate in the wake of the Trump election and European political figures such as Marine Le Pen and Geert Wilders means Romper Stomper's exploration of neo-Nazi culture is chillingly timely.
Edwards said in a statement: "Romper Stomper is a fantastic chance to break the mould of Australian drama - a contemporary thriller with competing tribes and different points of view battling for power. The series brings together some of our greatest character actors and wonderful new talents as well."
Romper Stomper will add to Stan's growing list of original content, which also include No Activity, Wolf Creek and the upcoming comedy series The Other Guy.
Stan's chief content officer Nick Forward said: "With such an extraordinary creative team, Romper Stomper will be unmissable television, as provocative now as the film was in 1992, examining at a personal level the hatred, fear, vengeance and politics hidden in plain sight all around us."
Production on the series commenced this week.
Romper Stomper is the latest in a series of reboots, revivals and sequels of classic TV and films. Others have included David Lynch's Twin Peaks, Full House, The Gilmore Girls, Anne of Green Gables, Prison Break and Will & Grace.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachy Hulme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gables</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Wyllie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqueline McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolf Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Lynch's Twin Peaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne of Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Wenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Le Pen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Forward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Life of Us</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilmore Girls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoffrey Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyllie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Crowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prison Break</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daina Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Love My Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geert Wilders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
