<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401190172671753</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4822790/i-just-cant-believe-six-years-has-gone-by-wollongong-councillors-meet-for-a-final-time/?cs=12</url>
  <title>'I just can't believe six years has gone by' - Wollongong councillors' final meeting</title>
  <content>
Councillors had their final meeting on Monday, July 31.

After five years and ten months in office, Wollongong councillors held their final meeting on Monday.
It was their 110th meeting of council since they were elected in September 2011, when they took over from the administrators tasked to run the city after the council was sacked amid ICAC corruption allegations in 2008.
Despite an almost two years longer-than-usual term, Lord Mayor Gordon Bradbery - who will run for re-election on September 9 - said the time had "gone by so fast, I just can't believe six years has gone by".

"It's been one of the most interesting rides of my life," Cr Bradbery said.
"It's been one of the most interesting rides of my life," he said.

Although he was tasked with taking over a council which had been dogged with the sex-for-development scandal, Cr Bradbery said the biggest challenge had been turning around the council's finances, rather than its reputation.
"The council was going backwards by about $20 million a year, and we've been able to turn that around as add more to the capital works program bringing it up to over $90 million a year," he said.
"Admittedly we had to ask the city for more money with a special rate variation, but we applied that to what people wanted."
Reflecting on his time in office, Cr Bradbery also highlighted the "balanced" political makeup of the current crop of councillors.
With four Liberals, four Labor, two Greens and three independents (includinng Cr Bradbery) the council has, for much of the time, avoided dividing along harsh political lines.
"For me, it was an honour to work with the majority of councillors, who had one thing in mind and that wasn't political allegiance - it was trying to do the best for the city," he said. 

"I was given some of the most intelligent and capable people to work with."

Posing for posterity. Pictures: Adam McLean.
For three councillors - Jill Merrin, George Takacs and Bede Crasnich - the meeting was their last ever, as they will not be running for re-election.

Read more: 
Greens councillor and academic Cr Takacs marked the occasion by wearing a rarely-seen suit, while his colleague Jill Merrin said the group had been "the best council ever".
While sad to be leaving, she said she was proud to have witnessed a shift to more environmentally friendly policies. 
"After several years of talking about climate change, I think other councillors have been willing to accept the importance of climate change and the role of council in that area," Cr Merrin said.

For the youngest councillor, Cr Crasnich -  - there were two "missed opportunities" which stood out: not allowing the University of Wollongong to go ahead with redeveloping Gleniffer Brae, and not allowing the factory outlet to set up shop in Kembla Grange.
"But overall, we've accomplished a lot over the last six years and I think it's fair to say that the city is better off than it was in 2011," Cr Crasnich said.

The remaining 10 councillors have made public their plans to run for reelection.

Cr Bradbery, Liberal John Dorahy, Labor's David Brown and independent Greg Petty have said they will take a tilt at the position of Lord Mayor.

Read more: 
Read more: 

Liberal councillor John Dorahy (and mayoral hopeful) presented a Wigan Warriors jersey to the city - and whoever becomes Lord Mayor under the next council - after last week's announcement that the English Super League team will play at WIN stadium in February.
Nominations for the election close next Wednesday, August 9.
WHAT THEY SAID

The Mercury asked all councillors the following questions:

What do you think is the most significant thing achieved by this council?
Do you have one particular project that stands out for you personally?
Is there any decision that you would change/anything that you've been disappointed not to achieve in this time?
How do you think Wollongong is different compared to 2011 because of the council's actions?
Below are their responses, in the order received (they have been edited in some cases for style and clarity, but otherwise are in councillors' own words).
Ann Martin - Labor councillor, Ward 3

Q1: The most significant thing achieved by this council is reinstating a sense of confidence and, I think, enthusiasm for what the future of Wollongong could be. We followed a very difficult time for the city, and our actions, including sorting out the finances, carrying out major new work across the city and neighbourhoods, and the civility that, on the whole, this council has operated within will be part of our legacy.
Q2: The one particular project that stands out for me is the work we have done on the night time economy, the cultural plan, and the live music taskforce. These, combined, which are all initiatives I championed, have lifted the entrepreneurial output, introduced a feeling of creativity and, of course, generated new jobs through more music and sporting festivals and events, increased visitation to the city, more live music, more cultural activity, and is a glimpse of what a great city Wollongong is and can be. It also meant we retained Glennifer Brae, Phoenix  Theatre, Project Contemporary Arts Space, invested in activities like the Spiegeltent, Wonderwalls, the new public art in the city, and we are now investigating opportunities for the Lower Town Hall, and of course Elton John.
Q3: I am disappointed that we still have more work to do to support our neighbourhoods, more work in finding a site for a new library and community and facilities in Warrawong, Primbee, that we haven't finalised Glennifer Brae, and that we haven't sorted out the city centre and zoned important land for new housing in west Dapto.
Q4: Wollongong is a more vibrant, confident, and upbeat city. We have the funds to invest in new projects while upgrading and maintaining our existing facilities, the city looks and feels good, we still have a working steelworks but we have more to do.
Leigh Colacino - Liberal councillor, Ward 1

Q1: I think this council has given the community a revitalised sense of worth in our and to our business community. There is a real feeling that if it can be done it can be done in Wollongong.
Q 2: For me it is definitely Cruise Ships. Having cruise ships come to our city gave a real vitality back to the residents of Wollongong. Those ships could have gone anywhere but, they came here, to our city. The residents of Wollongong know how great this place is and those visits, by cruise ships, proved what we have always know ... great city, great beaches, great cafes and restaurants and great people.
Q 3: I don't like to dwell on what we could have done. All Councillors did what they thought was the right thing to do at the time. The next three years for the new council will be the time to do the the things some might consider could have been the better choice. But, never look back, always set your sights on what can be achieved and what is coming.
Q 4: A line was drawn in the sand on the day the old stack at Port Kembla came down. From that moment the past was finally nothing more than a memory. Once the dust had settled, the future was there for everyone to see. That was the point when Wollongong said yes, we are part of the future of this State. We can compete and we can win.
Greg Petty - Independent councillor, Ward 1

Q1. Stopping Coal Seam Gas
Q2: Mall revitalisation and Flinders Street dalliance into property development because of the cost overrun
Q3: West Dapto cost is be slugged onto current ratepayers and not being borne by the future generations that it will benefit.
Q4: Worse because effective community engagement has been killed off by the removal of acknowledging Neighbourhood Forums.

John Dorahy - Liberal councillor, Ward 2

Q1: For me, it was the excellent integration of the 13 Councillors using mostly a bi-partisan approach to achieve many firsts and deliver what the community wanted, i.e. good corporate governance with no hint of malpractice or favours for mates; increased tourism, see Cruise Ships, Major Events; Free WiFi in the City; Council Meetings available Online; and the [completion] of the Mall
Q2: Definitely, the most two productive projects have been in governance improvements and increased tourism through major event recognition
Q3: The most disappointing decision made was the lack of foresight and opportunity to invest in the Glennifer Brae establishment through the proposed UOW, a poor decision for an outstanding opportunity for the community.
The second most disappointing decision was the decision to put in place parking fees, especially when you compare business reaction at both Shellharbour and Miranda.
Q4: Through what was a longer term of local government and now with 'experienced' councillors, Wollongong has an opportunity to advance more strongly beyond the small steps made during the past 6-years. It is going to take a different brand of leadership, one that is able to work with the governments of the day to achieve greater outcomes.

Jill Merrin - Greens councillor, Ward 1

Q1: Recognition of our important role as Local Government advocate in the State and Federal arenas, on issues that affect Wollongong, as well as more broadly

Q2: Agreement to join the Global Covenant of Mayors for Climate and Energy - this entails assessing Wollongong's greenhouse gas emissions, setting targets for reductions, and reporting in a public forum using a globally accepted format
Q3: Greater respect for public spaces, with high-quality landscape design, public art, and stronger environmental protection. Poor examples include the decision to allow a commercial building in the middle of Stuart Park, and the failure to turn McCabe Park into an attractive, central city park for passive recreational use

Q4: 

Stronger commitment to Ecologically Sustainable Development (ESD), and environmental protection
More and better footpaths and cycleways
Greater recognition of the need for gender equity and diversity on staff
More investment in buildings and businesses - creativity and 'buzz'
We are no longer under threat from coal seam gas mining!
David Brown - Labor councillor, Ward 2

Q1: Council over this term has worked hard to make the organisation financially sustainable and was declared 'fit for the future', unlike several other local Councils, in the bungled State Government mergers process.
Q2: What has stood out in his term is the increasing and record level of community trust in council, which is a testament to those councillors who have avoided personal conflict and worked hard to make evidence-based decisions.
Q3: A major disappointment in this term was the Local Government reform process, which started as a genuine partnership between councils and the state government but soured into a rancorous debate over just amalgamations.  Lost on the way was more than a year of council's time and any chance to have a serious debate over things like council financing and the share of responsibilities between the two levels of government.
Q4: Over this term of council we have been able to allocate many millions of dollars into infrastructure renewal and replacement - the city is beginning to show the benefits from the program over the past six years.
Bede Crasnich - Liberal councillor, Ward 3

Q1: Most significant thing we did was prioritise ward 3 in terms of funding. We got Fowlers road and a skate park for example.. Two things the administrators wouldn't have done.
Q2: The skate park, there's significantly less antisocial behaviour around the Berkeley shops now
Q3: Not outsourcing more council operations to local businesses, we financially shot ourselves in the foot with that one.
Q4: There's a lot more accountability and community input with all policies.
Michelle Blicavs - Liberal councillor, Ward 2

Q1: The economic growth we've seen across the city, with the completion the Mall, GPT, Dwyers site, Oxford Tavern and so many more empty sites that are now filled with people living and working in our city.
Q2: Precinct planning and implementation plans. I recall the 2010 CBD Action Plan had no budget and there are still elements not implemented. I'm excited to have seen both the Unanderra and Figtree plans activated with new pathways and community sites activated.
Q3: I would have liked to see a solution for the Wollongong South Precinct and solving the flooding issues for residents in that area. This is an area that has been neglected for too long and one of the reasons I want to run again - a job unfinished.

Q4: Wollongong is now a place that is talked about beyond the escarpment with positivity and excitement. Businesses now what establish themselves here. People want to live here. Communities are now proud of living in such a great city like Wollongong.
Janice Kershaw - Labor councillor, Ward 1

Q1: That we are now in a sustainable financial position. Enabling council to do the required work across the city and to plan for major projects for the future.
Q2: There are 2, the finalisation and adoption of the Corrimal Town Centre Plan and the completion of Towradgi Park, which included picnic shelters, a playground, toilets and a formalised parking area.
Q3: I'm disappointed that we have not yet been able to provide a second access route to and from Thirroul.
Q4: Wollongong Council has worked to restore the confidence of the community in council. We have brought stability to the city, which has encouraged investment and enabled Wollongong to move ahead in an orderly and progressive way.
Chris Connor - Labor councillor, Ward 3

Q1. Returning community confidence in our local government and increased capital investment in our city by both council and the private sector.
Q2. The commencement of work for the construction of the Fowlers Road Bridge. This project has been promised for decades and is now being delivered. It will give the West Dapto community flood free access, economic benefits and better connection to the Dapto CBD and the M1.
Q3. I am disappointed that the Lake Illawarra Authority was disbanded by the State Government and council has not not been given the money from the State to manage the Lake to the standard the community requires.

Q4. Stronger local economy, increased cultural activities and a new level of confidence in the future of our city.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cruise Ships</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Figtree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Crasnich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berkeley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Kembla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Dorahy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ecologically Sustainable Development</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wonderwalls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gleniffer Brae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Project Contemporary Arts Space</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Covenant of Mayors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miranda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Takacs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wigan Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Colacino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Merrin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD Action Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Bradbery</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ann Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bede Crasnich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q4</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q1</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q2</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q3</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Blicavs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford Tavern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrawong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal John Dorahy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's David Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major Events</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council Meetings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fowlers Road Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coal Seam Gas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janice Kershaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neighbourhood Forums</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Super League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Dapto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fowler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Towradgi Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Gordon Bradbery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glennifer Brae</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCabe Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong South Precinct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Takacs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Petty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spiegeltent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primbee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal Town Centre Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unanderra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Merrin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ward 1</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ward 3</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ward 2</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillors</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Free WiFi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elton John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kembla Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
