<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400889524955269</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/esperance-police-thief-passed-out-after-too-much-champage/8761210</url>
  <title>Esperance alleged burglar passed out after downing expensive champagne, police say</title>
  <content>
A man who allegedly passed out drunk in a bed in the house he was attempting to burgle after finding and drinking a bottle of expensive champagne has been charged with stealing, police say.
The 36-year-old man allegedly kicked in the front door of the house in Esperance, 700km south-east of Perth on Friday.

Esperance police officer-in-charge Richard Moore said a woman returned home to find the thief sound asleep on her bed, after downing most of a bottle of champagne.

"He has consumed some champagne, I'm not sure how expensive it was but in the photo, it looks expensive," Senior Sergeant Moore said.
"It must have been quite potent because he has fallen asleep in the resident's bed, which is not a good thing, and the owner has returned home and located this male person in her bed."

The woman quickly left the property and phoned police.

"She actually used her initiative which is really good, she crept out of the house and managed to phone police who attended and arrested the offender," Senior Sergeant Moore said.
He said the man was highly intoxicated when taken into custody, and police had taken him to Esperance Hospital as a precaution.
Senior Sergeant Moore said the 36-year-old recorded a blood alcohol reading eight times the legal driving limit when tested by police.
"This is a bit weird, to fall asleep in the bed and be laying there when police came in," he said.
"It would have been a shock for him and an easy pinch for the coppers."

Senior Sergeant Moore said police were investigating the man for links to other recent burglaries.

The 36-year-old was charged with burglary and stealing and will appear in Esperance Magistrate Court on August 8.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senior Sergeant Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
