<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401155812932604</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/netball/nsw-swifts-coach-rob-wright-has-quit-the-club-20170731-gxm48j.html</url>
  <title>NSW Swifts coach Rob Wright has quit the club</title>
  <content>
Netball NSW has been left reeling by Rob Wright's shock decision to quit as head coach of the Swifts, just a month after finalising the club's roster for 2018.
The trailblazer, who became the first male coach in the trans-Tasman league, has cited personal reasons for the decision and will travel overseas after he leaves the Swifts at the end of the month before

Up Next

Craig Foster remembers Les Murray

04:52

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Plays of the Week

Stars hold their nerve, six sixes in an over and fish and athletes both get aerial, these are the plays of the week.

Carolyn Campbell will begin a search for Wright's replacement, with the Netball NSW CEO keen to bed down a new coach sooner rather than later.
Swifts assistant Megan Anderson is one name being considered, although she doesn't have the high-performance qualifications necessary to be a head coach in Super Netball.

"That doesn't mean we can't get dispensation and work through all that, there's lots to happen and lots of conversations to be had and it's certainly our intention to get her up to that qualification," Campbell said.
"There's a small pool of people that are qualified, we need to move quickly as well, we're just trying to work through that and what the options are.

"I'll be looking for someone that has had some sort of SSN experience that we can bring into the fold - it's too hard to come from nothing. We're looking at all opportunities and all options at this stage."

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

All 10 Swifts players were informed of Wright's decision by Campbell in recent days, many of who are overseas including Sam Wallace who learned of the news from her home in Trinidad.Photo: Brendan Esposito
and spent last month at the Super Club competition in New Zealand with Giants coach Julie Fitzgerald, the pair helping NSWIS to a third-placed finish.
Campbell said there would always be a place for Wright at Netball NSW should he ever decide to return to the organisation.
"I'd have him back in the fold in a heartbeat in any way I possibly could. It's not a termination or a sacking or anything like that, it's purely his decision," Campbell said.
"He's not tired of netball or anything like that, he just doesn't want to be head coach."
Wright coached the Swifts for four years, and led the club to back-to-back grand finals in 2015 and 2016
He coached 61 matches in the ANZ Championship and Super Netball, with a 55 per cent win rate.
"This has not been an easy decision to make but I feel now is the right time for me to take some time out and I will continue to focus on individual athlete coaching and development," Wright said.
"Both the club and Netball NSW have been very understanding in this matter and I remain steadfast in the belief that this current crop of players we have at the Swifts are destined for great things.
"The club's 2020 vision remains very much intact and having seen such wonderful potential on display this season I feel confident I am leaving the club in a very strong and settled position."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netball NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trinidad.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSWIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netball NSW CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Wright</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolyn Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SSN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Swifts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swift</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Netball</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Esposito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
