<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401172992802201</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:05</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/07/music-video-celebrates-that-comic-con-still-is-about-the-comics/</url>
  <title>Music Video Celebrates That Comic-Con Still Is About The Comics</title>
  <content>
The biggest comic book show of them all, San Diego Comic-Con, has come and gone this year. Amidst all the hype and trailers, it can feel like it's more about big films and shows than actual comic books. Luckily, one music video from the event is here to remind us that, yes, Comic-Con does still have comics.

has released a music video called "Get Your Comics (On the Floor)." The song, recently shared by , shows us that, if you knew where to look, you can indeed replace that very first Spider-Man comic you owned as a child that mum unceremoniously tossed out. Hyper RPG's vid is a fun watch for several reasons. First and foremost, look, longboxes! Again, a sight for sore eyes belonging to longtime comics fans. Plus, it's insanely catchy, almost frustratingly so.

But, the music video includes something else that is often easily missed at San Diego Comic-Con, as well as other comic cons - and that would be the comic creators themselves. Alas, many do not make all that much money, and appearing at conventions to sell pages of their work or original sketches help them to continue paying the bills. But it's getting more expensive for creators and sellers to do so. This sad reality really hit home after news hit that longtime SDCC staple Mile High Comics, .

Comic-Con might be a spectacle of entertainment, but it's not only movie trailer debuts or cast reunions of your favourite shows, it's also about the awesome comics that inspired those movies and shows in the first place. You can check out the music video below, possibly while starting your savings for San Diego Comic-Con 2018.

[]

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comic Con</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spider-Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mile High Comics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SDCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyper RPG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego Comic-Con 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego Comic Con</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Video Celebrates That Comic-Con Still Is About</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CONS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
