<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401194467639068</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/20/57/nt-could-face-boat-licencing-and-alcohol-restrictions-on-the-water</url>
  <title>NT could face boat licencing and alcohol restrictions on the water</title>
  <content>
The Northern Territory is the only jurisdiction in Australia without any boat licencing and alcohol restrictions on the water - but that could be set to change in the future, with the issue being investigated as part of the Government's alcohol review. 
Review panel chairperson, Trevor Riley, has written to fishing groups asking for input, after a submission called for the introduction of boat licences to restrict operators to have a blood alcohol limit less than 0.05. 
One in four Territorians own a boat, and any discussion about bringing in restrictions has always landed previous governments in hot water.
So today, it's no surprise Attorney-General Natasha Fyles was quick to hose down any talk of immediate action.
"Government policy is not to introduce boat licences and not to put in place the measures," Ms Fyles said.
But she was careful not to rule it out in the future.
"It's not something that's on the government's agenda but we do have this review in place," she said.

Related Articles

"It's having a board look at alcohol policy legislation and I can't foresee what will be in the future.. This is a conversation we need to have."
President of the Darwin Game and Fishing Club, Steve Roberts, said the club believes any changes are "inevitable", but restrictions must cater for our unique lifestyle.
"We've got to be understanding that yes people do enjoy a drink at the end of the day," Mr Roberts said.
"If we're camped out overnight and the skipper does want to have a few drinks, it's pretty tough if legislation stops that."
Ms Fyles has promised to publish the review in full.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General Natasha Fyles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fishing Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fyles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Riley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territorians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
