<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400803625607985</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/alice-springs-council-calls-for-return-of-youth-outreach-service/8761072</url>
  <title>Alice Springs Council calls for return of youth outreach service following month of vandalism</title>
  <content>
After a month of increased vandalism in Alice Springs during the school holidays, the Alice Springs Council is urgently moving a motion calling on the Northern Territory Government to re-introduce the Youth Street Outreach Service, known as YSOS.
and a councillor called for a youth curfew, which failed to attract support from authorities.
On Tuesday night the council will vote on the motion.
Under YSOS, which ran from 5:00pm until 3:00am, senior child protection workers could take children who were at risk into care.
However, the program was defunded by the former Country Liberals government.
NT Police say they have arrested 270 young people since January.
"Youth crime is always concerning around this time of year and the school holidays, we do see a slight rise in criminal offences," Superintendent Bradley Currie said.
Alice Springs Mayor Damien Ryan wants to see youth officers back on the street.
"I think we're seeing the problem right now, from this year's middle of the year school holidays, the concerns the community has had, and the vandalism that's been created," he said.
"YSOS clearly did work in our community, let's bring it back."
John Adams used to head the youth service, and he said the program worked.
"If a child protection worker who's authorised under the act sees an eight-year-old who's unsafe, not only do they have the power, but they have the responsibility to do something," he said.
July the 'perfect storm' of youth crime

Unseasonably hot weather and a football carnival staged too close to the Alice Springs Show combined to facilitate a crime spike, Mr Adams said.
"You've got to realise 80 to 90 per cent of these kids are just [hanging out], the trick with this is working out which 10 per cent aren't," he said.
Alice Springs residents are frustrated with the lack of diversionary activities for young people.
"I know we all blame the parents, but also we need to take control of the community, there needs to be more for young people to do," resident Alison Furber said.
"The community should all work together, black and white."
But Territory Families Minister Dale Wakefield said a program similar to YSOS was already in place.
"Our youth outreach workers are already on the ground, they started on the ground in May, they will be picking up many of the roles that were previously covered by YSOS workers," she said.
"We've taken the best bits of the program, growing it, and absolutely ramping up the ability for those workers to work effectively with kids after hours."
Mr Adams challenged her assertion, saying he was "not aware of senior child protection workers that are out in Alice Springs at night".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territory Families Minister Dale Wakefield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alison Furber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YSOS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs Mayor Damien Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Bradley Currie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Adams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth Street Outreach Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
