<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401194467639124</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/theresa-may-insists-freedom-of-movement-will-not-continue-as-it-is-now-after-brexit-2017-7</url>
  <title>Theresa May insists freedom of movement will not continue 'as it is now' after Brexit</title>
  <content>
The prime minister insists that free movement of people will end in 2019.

Theresa May's spokesman slaps down suggestions from Hammond that current rules could continue after Brexit.

Chancellor had insisted that "literally nobody"wants a dramatic drop in immigration.

Comments sparked Cabinet row with Liam Fox who Hammond's allies accused of "living in fantasy land".

LONDON - The free movement of people from the EU into Britain will not continue during any Brexit transition period, Downing Street has insisted.

The prime minister's intervention, comes amidst a growing Cabinet row over the future of Britain's immigration system.

The row was sparked after Philip Hammond said on Friday that there should be no "cliff edge" for immigration when Britain leaves the EU in Spring 2019.

His comments left the door open for current immigration rules to remain in place during any transitional period after Brexit, which minister expect to last up to three years.

"At the present time, we have a high level of dependence on foreign workers in the UK," he told the Today programme.

"Nobody wants us to go over a cliff edge in March 2019 where suddenly our health services are unable to cope, social care is unable to deliver."

However, the comments triggered a row with Hammond's Cabinet colleagues.

The International Trade Secretary, Liam Fox told the Sunday Times that such an outcome would "not keep faith" with the referendum result.

He added: "If there have been discussions on that I have not been party to them. I have not been involved in any discussions on that."

The foreign secretary was also forced to

Free movement will not continue as it is now

A spokesperson for the prime minister insisted on Monday that free movement will end in Spring 2019.

The spokesperson told a briefing attended by Business Insider that while they would not otherwise speculate on what future immigration rules will look like it was "wrong" to suggest "that free movement will continue as it is now."

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Trade Secretary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hammond's Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hammond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Fox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring 2019</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downing Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theresa May</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Hammond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
