<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401147222997905</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/big-besen-buy-bolsters-gpt-portfolio-value-20170731-gxm3wy</url>
  <title>Big Besen buy bolsters GPT portfolio value</title>
  <content>
The premium paid by GPT's unlisted retail property fund for the remaining stake in Highpoint shopping centre will boost the value of the investment GPT already holds in the Melbourne mall.
The unlisted GPT Wholesale Shopping Centre Fund to buy up the 25 per cent in Highpoint shopping centre it doesn't already hold in a $680 million deal with its co-owners, the Besen family.
The sale price of $680 million represents a 10 per cent premium to the June 2017 book value of the mall.
The unlisted shopping centre fund held a 58.33 per cent stake in Highpoint before the Besen acquisition while GPT itself holds a 16.67 per cent stake.

However, GPT also has a 25.3 per cent investment in its own malls fund, giving it about a 40 per cent exposure in total to Highpoint.

With the uplift in value through the premium paid for the final stake of Highpoint, GPT's net tangible assets will gain by around $125 million, or 7¢ per share, on Macquarie Research estimates.
The acquisition will be earnings neutral for the unlisted malls fund because the yield on the deal of around 4 per cent matches the cost of funding.
Macquarie had already upgraded GPT to an outperform.
Deutsche Bank analysts initiated coverage of GPT, although before the Besen deal was announced.

They rate the stock a hold, noting that capitalisation rates are at all-time lows and will begin expanding soon.
GPT has historically underperformed in rising bond yield markets, the Deutsche Bank analysts wrote in a note to clients, noting however, that GPT could expect earnings upside in its office and logistics portfolio due to strong market fundamentals.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Besen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highpoint</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT Wholesale Shopping Centre Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
