<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400584582272025</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/celebrity-selfies/coco-austin-flaunts-gravitydefying-40dd-boobs-at-the-pool/news-story/d15b6f073bc63d6d7758d9eba971b0e1</url>
  <title>Coco Austin flaunts gravity-defying 40DD boobs at the pool</title>
  <content>
Coco Austin Posts Unrecognizable First Magazine Cover Throwback Photo
1:10

Woah, you're definitely going to have to do a double take when you see Coco Austin's first ever magazine cover. The tv host shared the ultimate throwback photo that's completely unrecognizable.

January 20th 2016
2 years ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Coco Austin gets up close and personal with fans on the Instagram video.

Share

COCO Austin has given fans an up close and personal glimpse at her 40DD boobs.
In an Instagram video, the 38-year-old model strapped herself into the The Perfect Sculpt's "Push-Up" bikini and gave fans a thorough demonstration of the garment's gravity-defying efforts.
"Watch this. Don't blink. Wooo! Tie these suckers up. Uh-huh! Tie these suckers up, uh-huh!" she said in the video as she wrestled with the bikini top's strings and straps.

Before ... Coco looking a little more free before tying the bikini straps.Source:Instagram

The mum-of-one wrestles with the straps and strings on the garment.Source:Instagram
Once firmly tied and hoisted, Austin - the wife of rapper Ice T - proudly showed off her well-supported assets.
"And they're ready for action because I could seriously take an aerobics class and they wouldn't move. Pow!" the mum-of-one informed.

Ready to roll.Source:Instagram

The bikini top in full swing.Source:Instagram

A post shared by Coco (@coco) on

Once the swimwear was fully secured, the blonde turned around and waded into the pool as she showed off the Brazilian back of the bikini top.
After  Chanel Nicole, Austin lost six kilograms of the baby weight she gained while pregnant and credited the "acro-yoga" trend for the results.
In the past, the model has spoken about her complex relationship with her body, telling The Real it wasn't until she met her rapper husband 16 years ago that she began to embrace her curves. She also revealed the self esteem boost she got from getting breast implants at the age of 18.
"I was always flaunting my boobs. I loved my boobs. I bought them at 18. I loved them. But I was still taking away from the hip area. I was covering up and it wasn't until I got with my husband, Ice," she said.

"He's the one. I give him credit for me being me to this day because he's the one who's like, 'You have something to work with. Work it, it's unique'."

A post shared by Coco (@coco) on

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coco</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uh-huh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanel Nicole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>POW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ice T</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perfect Sculpt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coco Austin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coco Austin Posts Unrecognizable First Magazine Cover Throwback Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
