<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401276072019425</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4823906/toronto-homing-in-on-minor-premiership/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Toronto homing in on minor premiership</title>
  <content>
TORONTO moved a step closer to the minor premiership with an 8-3 win over Belmont at Waterboard Oval on Sunday. 
The result takes the competition leaders tally to nine wins and two losses for the season. 

Phoenix Charlestown are next best on eight and two, followed by Belmont with seven wins and three losses. 
All three are guaranteed finals action but results in the last four rounds will determine their finishing position. 
Teams one and two will clash at Stevenson Park in the first week of the finals with the winner progressing to the grand final at Waterboard Oval. 
The loser will take on the third placed team in the preliminary final at Miller Field. 
All three teams have destiny in their own hands and can move up or down the table off their own bats. 
It was the Seagulls' bats which let them down in Sunday's loss as they managed only five hits. Jason McAdam kept the Seagulls at bay for seven innings with five strikeouts and two walks. 
Thomas Holland then closed out the win with three strikeouts, two walks and no hits in the final two digs. 
All nine Toronto starters contributed as the Tigers tallied 17 hits. Pat Maat was unstoppable with four singles, a double and two RBIs. 
Dillon McMaster batted in four runs from two doubles. 
A solo home run to Tom O'Gorman was the high point for the Seagulls. 
At Windsor Park, Phoenix celebrated their old boys day with a  19-12 victory against Boomerangs. 
Phoenix are back at home on Sunday to tackle White Sox, while Boomers host Toronto at Stevenson Park. 
The game will be the focal point of the Mayfield club's Past, Present and Future Day with a good turnout anticipated for the celebrations. 
On Saturday, Boomers came out firing and led 7-1 midway through the third inning. 

Phoenix plated six to square it all up before the visitors added another five in the top of the fourth. 
The home side tied it all up again in the bottom of the fifth and never looked back. 
In a game dominated by offence, Phoenix finished with 20 hits to Boomers' 15. 
Phoenix clean-up hitter Cameron Henderson had a game he will never forget smashing four home runs. 
Brendan Lower also hit the ball out of the park with a three-run bomb. 
Lower started as catcher before relieving John Warren on the mound after Warren  had given up seven runs. 
Lower struck out nine and allowed one walk and 10 hits in almost seven innings work. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dillon McMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterboard Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seagulls</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Maat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Sox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom O'Gorman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stevenson Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miller Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmont</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason McAdam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Lower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boomers' 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
