<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401190172671749</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/17/24/murray-darling-basin-rory-mclaren</url>
  <title>Political foes join forces over handling of Murray Darling Basin water theft claims</title>
  <content>
Next to nothing usually unites the South Australian branches of Labor, The Greens, The Australian Conservatives and Nick Xenophon Team.
But today political lines blurred to pile pressure on the Federal Government over its handling of water theft claims from the Murray Darling Basin.
Joined by downstream farmers and irrigators, South Australian Senators stood side-by-side with the State Government to ramp up the push for a judicial inquiry into the allegations.
"This could not be of any more significance for the nation," South Australian Premier Jay Weatherill said.
"And of course it's of vital interest to South Australia."
The allegations, first aired by ABC's Four Corners program, centre on billions of litres of taxpayer-purchased water being diverted from the river system rather than being kept for environmental reasons as intended in the Murray Darling Basin Plan. Cotton growers are claimed to be the beneficiaries.
"What we are seeing unfolding here is potentially one of the biggest public policy scandals we've seen in many years," Senator Nick Xenophon said.

Related Articles

Senators Cory Bernardi and Sarah Hanson-Young sit at opposite ends of the political spectrum. But both hit out at the Federal Government's decision to have the Murray Darling Basin Authority, the body which oversees the basin plan, investigate the claims.
"Something that has the teeth to take this on properly. We can't simply leave it for New South Wales or Murray Darling Basin Authority to investigate themselves," Senator Hanson-Young said.
"It is too big an issue for it to be investigated by those with their own interests at heart," Senator Bernardi said.
Penny Wong, Labor Senate leader and former Federal Water Minister, used the joint press conference to attack current minister Barnaby Joyce.
"This man cannot be trusted on the River Murray," she said.
Amid the politicians was farmer Rob McBride. His Tolarno station takes in a stretch of the Darling River in western New South Wales, about 600 km from Adelaide.
"It's no stunt. We are warning you. Your Murray Darling basin system is about to collapse," he said.
"Our family have proudly been farming for 162 years in this nation. We're not fly-by-nighters, we're pretty proud of our history.
"We are looking for the next generation. We're looking at sustainability. Now, if I cut your water supply for eight and a half months, how would you cope?"
Absent from the show of unity was the state Liberal Party. A spokesperson confirmed there was no invite to take part alongside the other parties.
In wake of the theft claims last week, the state opposition had agreed to a bipartisan approach to the issue.
"The allegations of bureaucratic collusion in the theft of water from the MDB raised on Four Corners are of sufficient weight to require an independent inquiry to establish the facts of the matter," Shadow Minister for the Environment David Speirs said.
"The delivery of the Murray Darling Basin agreement in full and on time is non-negotiable for the South Australian Liberal Party.
"We were very clear in the public domain last week we would work alongside Minister Hunter and Jay Weatherill. That we would put politics aside and make sure we got the best outcome for the River Murray in South Australia."
The Murray Darling Basin Plan came into effect in November 2012.
It was designed to sustainably manage the use of water from the top of the system in Queensland, right down to the Murray mouth at Goolwa.
In light of the Four Corners allegations, Senator Xenophon said his office had been approached about further claims relating to water misuse.
"There are people calling us from New South Wales saying that significant amounts of money were spent on supposed water saving measures, only to be undermined, only for the opposite to happen after tens of millions of dollars were spent," he said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MDB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Conservatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Hanson Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tolarno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment David Speirs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Plan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goolwa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson-Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Cory Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Water Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Premier Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Corners</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob McBride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
