<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401237417312992</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/national/adrian-attwater-on-trial-for-manslaughter-if-lynette-daley/news-story/6c61198371481ffbd2c95528740a3905</url>
  <title>Rape accused: 'Boys will be boys'</title>
  <content>
A MAN on trial over the 2011 manslaughter of a drunk woman on a remote northern NSW beach "repeatedly and vigorously" sexually assaulted her, a jury has heard.
Accused man Adrian Attwater later told police "girls will be girls, boys will be boys", an interview played at the NSW Supreme Court in Coffs Harbour on Monday revealed.
Attwater has pleaded not guilty to the manslaughter and sexual assault of mother-of-seven Lynette Daley, 33, who died at Ten Mile Beach in January 2011.
The "on-again-off-again" couple were on an Australia Day camping trip with Attwater's friend, Paul Maris, 47, who pleaded not guilty to sexual assault and hindering the discovery of evidence.
In his opening address, crown prosector Philip Strickland SC said "all three of them drank a lot of alcohol on that day".
At dusk, they stopped halfway up the beach in Maris' troop carrier where Attwatter and Daley got on a mattress in the back.
Attwater "repeatedly and vigorously" sexually assaulted Ms Daley for a couple of minutes, Mr Strickland said.
Maris joined in with a sex act at Attwater's invitation, the barrister told the court.
Attwater only stopped the assault when he noticed blood on his hand and Maris later burnt her bra and the bloodstained mattress "because it stank," the Crown said.
Confronting photos shown in court showed injuries to Ms Daley that caused significant blood loss.
The assault "substantially or significantly contributed to her death," Mr Strickland said.
Her autopsy also revealed a small amount of methylamphetamine and a blood alcohol concentration of 0.303 - meaning she was "grossly intoxicated".
The prosecutor said Attwater told police "she was blind, she was off her f***ing face last night".
Attwater claimed Ms Daley had a fit or seizure in the ocean when she went for a swim while naked and he performed CPR after dragging her back to shore. When questioned about how the trio came to have group sex, Attwater said: "These things happen ... girls will be girls, boys will be boys." Both men told police they thought it was consensual.
Mr Strickland said Maris told police: "Well she didn't object when I jumped in the back, she'd moved over to give me oral." The trial is expected to run for six weeks.

Four Corners takes a look at the case of the horrific death of Lynette Daley, who died on Ten Mile Beach in NSW after an alleged night of violent sex with Adrian Attwater and Paul Maris. Courtesy: Four Corners/ABC

Callous Disregard: Lynette Daley left to die
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Maris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mari</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Maris, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attwater</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Daley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Mile Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Strickland SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attwatter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynette Daley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Attwater</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Corners/ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Strickland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
