<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400597467174132</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/new-ferry-service-for-was-rottnest-island/news-story/8aa2f005e7ceabf6c712d63012ab60d8</url>
  <title>New ferry service for WA's Rottnest Island</title>
  <content>
A third ferry service to Perth's popular Rottnest Island is expected to provide a tourism boost and could bring down the price of travelling to the attraction, the state government says.
From November, Captain Cook Cruises will join the existing operators servicing the island and the state government is hoping to boost the number of people travelling to Rottnest from 645,000 last year.
An adult return fare currently offered by Rottnest Express and Rottnest Fast Ferries costs more than $50 plus an admission fee to the island. Captain Cook Cruises is yet to release its prices.
Premier Mark McGowan said making the ferries more affordable would attract more visitors.
"If you're not on a good income, getting to Rottnest is expensive," he told reporters on Monday.
"The more operators you have, the more competitive the market.
"Certainly when it comes to these sorts of operations, it provides the opportunity for additional or downward pressure on prices, and hopefully it attracts more tourists as a consequence."
Mr McGowan said 20 new jobs would be created to operate the ferry service and there would be more employment on the island as businesses grew from increased visitation.
SeaLink general manager Andrew Lane said subsidiary Captain Cook Cruises would invest in infrastructure and other things on the island, as it has done elsewhere including Kangaroo Island and the Tiwi Islands.
"We look at investing heavily in the destinations to which we run," Mr Lane said.
He expects a decrease on the price of a ticket and insists a third operation is sustainable.
But Tourism Minister Paul Papalia conceded the other operators might not be happy with the competition.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rottnest Express</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rottnest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook Cruises</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SeaLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA's Rottnest Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rottnest Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rottnest Fast Ferries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism Minister Paul Papalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiwi Islands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Cook Cruises</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
