<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400292524490652</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/breaking-news/qlds-top-cop-reappointed-for-three-years/news-story/03f7e68fdcdea331a612507c27f5fdc9</url>
  <title>Qld's top cop reappointed for three years</title>
  <content>
Queensland's top cop Ian Stewart has been reappointed as police commissioner for three more years.
Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk made the announcement on Monday following Mr Stewart's security briefing to cabinet on the Gold Coast.
Ms Palaszczuk said stability and continuity in the preparation and planning for next year's Commonwealth Games were important factors behind his reappointment.
"I wanted to ensure we had continuity in the leadership of the Queensland Police Service to and through the Gold Coast Commonwealth Games to be held in April next year," she said in a statement.
"I acknowledge that ensuring this continuity of leadership means the government has, in this instance, used a closed merit process."
Ms Palaszczuk also praised Mr Stewart for his leadership in handling the response efforts to Cyclone Debbie.
Mr Stewart says he is "extremely honoured and humbled" by the confidence shown in him to continue leading the Queensland Police Service's almost 15,000 members.
"I am very proud to serve as police commissioner and will continue to work hard, along with each and every other officer and staff member of the QPS, to ensure the safety and security of all Queenslanders," he said in a statement.
Mr Stewart, a career police officer with more 40 years experience, has been Queensland's top cop since November 2012.
His time in the position hasn't been without controversy, with the Queensland Police Union in May attacking the service's senior management.
Acting union president Shayne Maxwell said morale throughout the force was low and labelled an organisational restructure of the QPS as a failure.
Senior Sergeant Maxwell denied at the time his attack was an attempt to stop Mr Stewart being reappointed, simply a call to ensure he supported "frontline police".
Snr Sgt Maxwell's complaints came shortly after an article in the March/April copy of the QPU journal by another senior sergeant, Phil Notaro, claiming "the QPS has been mismanaged and is falling down around us".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March/April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snr Sgt Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stewart</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Service</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyclone Debbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Notaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QPU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QPS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shayne Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
