<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401104273324351</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/royals/family-and-friends-vent-fury-at-channel-4-decision-to-air-secret-diana-tapes/news-story/88fb872da5a48204978b398fcd86ca9f</url>
  <title>Family and friends vent fury at Channel 4 decision to air secret Diana tapes</title>
  <content>
Andrew Morton describes the backlash after his book on Diana was released
0:40

Speaking on The Project, journalist and author Andrew Morton describes the backlash after he publish his book on the life of Princess Diana. Courtesy: Network Ten

July 28th 2017
3 days ago

The young princess enchanted the public but was desperately unhappy inside her marriage, secret tapes of her candidly speaking reveal. Picture: Kypros/Getty Images.

Share

FRIENDS of the late Princess Diana have blasted the decision to air private tapes of her speaking about her sex life and marriage as "exploitative" and "grubby blood money".
The UK's Channel Four will air "dynamite" unseen footage of the Princess talking with her speech coach, Peter Settelen, about her marriage and public life.
Friend Rosa Monckton lashed out at Channel 4 bosses after they refused a plea from Diana'a brother, .
"It's completely inappropriate. How intrusive is this? It doesn't matter that it was 20-odd years ago," she told . "Think of the hurt they are causing to her family, to her sons."
Former Queen spokesman Dickie Arbiter called selling private tapes "grubby blood money and tawdry."
"The tapes were private. It doesn't matter if the princess is alive or dead, private should mean private," he said. "It's obvious Mr Settelen is making them public for whatever gains he is going to make out of it.

Secret tapes showing Princess Diana speaking to her voice coach will be aired in the UK this week despite calls to keep them under wraps. Picture: News Group Newspapers Arthur EdwardsSource:News Corp Australia

The late Princess can be heard talking about her sex life and the terrible state of her marriage candidly. Picture: Tim Graham/Getty Images.Source:Getty Images
Royal author Ingrid Seward  she thought Diana's legacy was being "exploited."
"I think it's remarkable any TV station would stoop that low. It really is lowest common denominator TV."
The  in a documentary to mark the twentieth anniversary of her death. Channel 4 executives have defended their decision, saying the content is a matter of the public record.

Deputy Chief Creative Officer Ralph Lee said the tapes are an important contribution to the "historical record".
"For British viewers to be able to see a candid, relaxed, informal Diana talking about her life and revealing her personal perspective on events that are now familiar to us is remarkable," he said.
"Given that the only filmed interview that we've ever seen with her is the Martin Bashir Panorama interview this is a really unique historical archive."
"I think a lot of viewers will feel for the first time that they are really seeing a natural, relaxed and personal Diana.

Earl tried to stop publication of Diana video
1:55

Princess Diana's brother has reportedly pleaded with Channel 4 not to broadcast video tapes of his sister.

July 31st 2017
14 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

Diana later described her wedding day as the "worst" day of her life. Picture: Tim Graham/Getty Images.Source:Getty Images
The tapes were recorded by Mr Settelen in 1992 when he was working as Diana's speech coach to help her prepare for speaking in public.
They show the late Princess rehearsing her speaking voice and revealing stunning admissions about her marriage and public life which paved the way for her famous Panorama interview with Martin Bashir in 1995.
She can be seen describing her wedding day as "the worst day of her life" and the constant battle to live up to her "fairy princess" public image.
She also suggests one of her bodyguards was "bumped off" in a road accident and describes her "" relationship with Charles. On their sex life, she revealed: "there was never a requirement for it from him."
"Once every three weeks about and I kept thinking it followed a pattern."
"He used to see his lady once every three weeks before we got married."
She also claims  and how they hadn't had sex for seven years after Prince Harry was born.

Prince William and Prince Harry have recently opened up about the effect their mother's death had on them. Picture: Anwar Hussein/Getty Images.Source:Getty Images

Floral tributes outside Kensington Palace for Princess Diana's funeral. Picture: Ralf-Finn Hestoft/CORBIS/Corbis via Getty Images.Source:Getty Images
Describing her marriage in crisis, she said: "If I could write my own script I would have my husband go away with his woman and never come back."
The footage was found in 2001 during a police raid at the home of Paul Burrell, the former royal butler. The content was regarded as so sensitive it was not aired in court, however some of it was sold to US network NBC and broadcast in the US as a two-part documentary.
Former UK MP Teddy Taylor called for the tapes not to be aired while Prince William and Prince Harry were still alive. However it's believed the Prince's recent opening up about mental health led to a change in thinking at the broadcaster.
"Because the princes are talking about it, it was considered more OK to release it," a source told The Telegraph.
"Also, there comes a point when something becomes historically interesting so it was decided to let the material speak for itself."

Prince Charles and Princess Diana dancing during a ball on their tour of Australia on October 31, 1985 in Melbourne. Picture: Anwar Hussein/Getty Images.,Source:Getty Images
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kypros/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ralf-Finn Hestoft/CORBIS/Corbis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Network Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anwar Hussein/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosa Monckton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK's Channel Four</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Settelen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Group Newspapers Arthur EdwardsSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Graham/Getty Images.Source</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anwar Hussein/Getty Images.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickie Arbiter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panorama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Settelen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Burrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Bashir Panorama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Chief Creative Officer Ralph Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Bashir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingrid Seward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK MP Teddy Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Morton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
