<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400369833903428</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/17/41/snake-9-news-darwin-office</url>
  <title>9NEWS cameraman finds snake hiding on his desk</title>
  <content>
There aren't many things that can bring a newsroom to a standstill, especially here in the Northern Territory - but this afternoon, something did.
Our senior 9NEWS cameraman had just made his afternoon cup of coffee and was about to settle in to his edit suite to begin cutting tonight's stories, when something on his desk moved.
He was on the phone at the time, let out a few choice words and then calmly came out to ask if any of us knew there was a snake on his desk?
It triggered a small panic and a few terrified screams, mainly from me.
We were about to call a snake catcher, but this is the Territory - they breed them tough up here.
Instead, we called on our Program Manager, Alexia, and Sales Executive, Myk, who were more than happy to help.
They improvised, using a coat hanger and shopping bag to capture the surprise visitor, who initially wasn't too happy about being woken from his warm sleeping spot.

Related Articles

Once he was safely stowed away, we took him outside and he was released into the bushes - hopefully far enough away from the 9NEWS Darwin newsroom!
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sales Executive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Program Manager</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
