<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401104273324377</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/07/31/20/35/facebook-tipoff-could-help-solve-coldcase-murder-of-adelaide-mother</url>
  <title>Facebook tip-off could help solve cold-case murder of Adelaide mother</title>
  <content>
A Facebook tip-off has given police new leads in the cold case murder of Adelaide mother Gail King, who vanished 20 years ago.
9NEWS has learned Ms King's sister-in-law, Cathy King, received a message on the social media platform, which contained potentially credible information about her disappearance.
"I was contacted via a personal message and this person wanted to be interviewed by the police so I asked them to ring Crime Stoppers," Mrs King said.
"It's a really big hope that this information they've given us is credible and that they can actually do something with it."
Detective Inspector Greg Hutchins from the Major Crime Investigation Branch has confirmed police acted on the tip-off.
"We have spoken to a new person in relation to this investigation," Insp. Hutchins said.
"Our contact with that person is still ongoing (and) the information certainly warrants further investigation."

Related Articles

Ms King has not been seen since leaving her holiday home at Minlaton on Yorke Peninsula at about 7pm on Sunday, July 7, 1997.
Her partner, Marvyn Upton, told police she'd headed back to Adelaide for work commitments. But when he arrived at their Brahma Lodge home the following day, she wasn't there.
"He eventually reported her as a missing person," Mr Hutchins said.
"It quickly escalated to serious concerns that something sinister had happened to her and ultimately it was declared a major crime."
Mr Upton has previously revealed that police have informed him they are treating him as a suspect, but he has always proclaimed his innocence.
It's unclear if the new information received via Facebook has identified a new person of interest.
However, Insp. Hutchins said the tip-off has "pushed them in a slightly different direction."
"This (new information) is still under investigation so it's very difficult to say where it will lead until we've explored all avenues," he said.
"It may prove to be extremely beneficial or it may prove to be not correct."
Gail King's brother, Peter King, said the tip-off partially supports his existing theories.
"(It is) sort of different to what we thought, but along the same sort of lines," he said.
"I've heard it's ... pretty credible, so hopefully something will come of it."
Mr King said his mother and father passed away in recent years without knowing what happened to their daughter.
"Obviously mum and dad didn't get the outcome so I'd like to get an outcome, just to get a bit of closure," he said.
9NEWS requested an interview with Mr Upton, but he declined to comment.
Police are offering a $200,000 reward for information that helps solve the murder of Gail King.
Anyone who can help is urged to contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail King</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvyn Upton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brahma Lodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorke Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathy King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Upton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hutchins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minlaton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 7, 1997</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hutchins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Greg Hutchins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms King</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major Crime Investigation Branch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
