<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400889524955404</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/north-northeast/woman-searching-for-new-home-for-alpacas-after-tea-tree-gully-council-says-they-cant-stay/news-story/5dc8deb21b70d86bd810248a54056bbc</url>
  <title>'I can't find a home for my beloved alpacas'</title>
  <content>
A DISTRAUGHT Highbury alpaca owner has begged Tea Tree Gully Council for more time to find a home for her beloved animals after the council declared they had to be removed.
A tearful Jodi Hume said she'd received "verbal approval" from the council seven years ago to house Leonardo and Theodore, who were then around six months old.
However, following an anonymous complaint to the council last year, she's been told the alpacas now have to go.
The council will not confirm when the alpacas will be removed, but has given Mrs Hume several extensions since November last year.
Her "boys" had been tethered in the front yard of her Atlanta Court home, she says, then moved out back to keep the peace after complaints.
But she's now worried the alpacas will be destroyed.
"They're very domesticated, they have personalties, they're just like dogs," she said.
"They like to sleep on blankets in winter, play under the sprinkler in summer time, they love kisses.
"They've even been up to the local childcare centre for show and tell.
"They're well known in the neighbourhood, have been for years, they're famous.
"I can make them sit on command. I'm their mum. Nobody understands."
With the family also looking to move house this year, Jodie says she can't find a new home for the alpacas.
"I've had all kinds of complications moving them," she said. "I've rung alpaca farms, they're not interested because they're not pedigree.
"The only other option I had was a horse agistment, which was too expensive.
"We just want some more time. It wasn't an issue (having them) for so many years."
Mayor Kevin Knight said the alpacas didn't belong in Highbury.
"They can't stay in a suburban backyard - you have to draw the line somewhere," he said. "I feel for her.
"We have no intention of destroying them, we just want them removed."
The council's manager of city development, Nathan Grainger, said "non-domestic animals" were not permitted in residential zones "due to the negative impact on neighbouring property owners".
"Compliance orders are generally issued following unsuccessful long-term negotiations with property owners and do not involve animals being needlessly destroyed," he said.
A RSPCA spokeswoman said animal management compliance issues were a matter for councils.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Grainger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tea Tree Gully Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlanta Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DISTRAUGHT Highbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodi Hume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Kevin Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
