<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401327611628137</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/teams/storm/melbourne-storm-star-josh-addocarr-credits-hardest-ever-preseason-for-breakout-year/news-story/4cbf5829832c93200b172f3bf22c9327</url>
  <title>Addo-Carr issues Storm warning</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE Storm boom recruit Josh Addo-Carr wants to repay Craig Bellamy and finish the year off strongly.
Addo-Carr, 22, endured the hardest preseason of his life under Bellamy, but said the brutal test of physical and mental strength laid the foundation for his breakout season.
Addo-Carr on Sunday moved to equal third in the race for the NRL top tryscorer behind Alex Johnson (16) and Storm's Suliasi Vunivalu (15), scoring his 14th try during a 34-point demolition of Manly at AAMI Park.
He threatened with searching runs throughout the game and finally broke through in the 80th minute.
"It was good to get a try at the end there, but it was good to get away with the win more importantly," Addo-Carr said.
He has played 19 games this season, averaging 140m a game from 12 carries.
He only enjoyed mixed success at West Tigers last year, scoring six tries in nine games.
"I wasn't consistent last year," Addo-Carr said.
"I played some good games, some pretty ordinary games. I've come here, done a pre-season and am doing things well.
"Craig spoke to me about being consistent during pre-season, that's all I was really looking for - consistency in my game and being fit and doing my job for the boys and the team.
"It's the hardest pre-season I've done. You get a lot of confidence out of the pre-season you do down here. That shows in my performance."
Addo-Carr yesterday said Storm had shifted quickly from toasting Cameron Smith's 350th game to Friday night's blockbuster against North Queensland.
"We want to finish the end of the year strong, we've got five more rounds to go and we want to win that minor premiership."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addo-Carr</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith's 350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Addo-Carr, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storm's Suliasi Vunivalu (15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Johnson (16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Addo-Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
