<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400597467174184</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/tas-drug-legalisation-backed-by-exjudge/news-story/672d1b44510d161b57b46c0ebc1a4681</url>
  <title>Tas drug legalisation backed by ex-judge</title>
  <content>
Ethan JamesAustralian Associated Press

Share

A report calling on the Tasmanian government to decriminalise illegal drugs and invest more money in treatment services has the backing of a former chief magistrate.
Community Legal Centres Tasmania on Monday released a study advocating a health-based approach to tackle the state's "failing" war on drugs.
Australian Crime Commission data shows nation-wide drug seizures almost doubled in the decade to 2014-15 while drug convictions had risen by 70 per cent.
The report found 1,000 Tasmanians were charged with drug-related offences on average per year.
University of Tasmania economist Dr Paul Blacklow estimates the cost of illegal drug use to government would be cut by $28 million a year through decriminalisation.
The move has been supported by ex-judge Michael Hill, who says low-range offenders facing minor charges, particularly relating to cannabis, have better prospects of rehabilitation if they're not sent to court.
"Decriminalisation in those areas would keep them out of the criminal justice system and relieve them of scars of (the) court system," Mr Hill said.
"If you're diverting people from the criminal justice system and diverting them from offending, you're protecting the community."
Mr Hill estimated around two in three cases he saw during his career were drug-related, soaking up the court's time and resources.

Former president of the Australian Drug Reform Foundation Dr Alex Wodak agrees, saying Tasmania should follow overseas models such as Portugal which decriminalised drugs in 2001.
"We don't want to see ice or cocaine for that matter sold in one kilogram packs at the supermarket checkout counter," Dr Wodak said.
A gradual approach to decriminalisation was ideal.
"I do think we need to start considering the possibility of having not-so-dangerous drugs in small quantities available," he said.
"The best thing you can do for somebody with a severe drug problem is to get them back in the workforce.
"We make very feeble attempts to do that - our drug treatment system is too small and underfunded."
The Liberal government has indicated it won't alter current drug laws.
"I take the position that illicit drugs are a scourge that should be eradicated, not normalised," Police Minister Rene Hidding said in a statement.
But Mr Hill says it would be foolish to dismiss the report entirely.
"These changes are based on principle, they're evidence-based and not on a whim or a soft-on-crime situation," he said.
"I would have thought it would be worthwhile for the government to give some consideration to it."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Wodak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Drug Reform Foundation Dr Alex Wodak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Crime Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Minister Rene Hidding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ethan JamesAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legal Centres Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Paul Blacklow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
