<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401288956921652</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/ukeu-free-movement-to-end-in-march-2019/news-story/1f0ae464d336c6f688c263446aa8255a</url>
  <title>UK-EU free movement to end in March 2019</title>
  <content>
Free movement of people between Britain and the European Union will end in March 2019 when Britain leaves the bloc, Prime Minister Theresa May's spokesman says.
Tory Brexit tensions have heightened after Chancellor Philip Hammond and Home Secretary Amber Rudd backed transitional arrangements after the UK leaves the bloc, which suggested EU migration could could continue with a registration scheme.
However, International Trade Secretary and leading Brexiteer Liam Fox said unregulated free movement of labour after Brexit would "not keep faith" with the EU referendum result and that the Cabinet had not agreed a stance on immigration.
May's official spokesman insisted the government's position remained as set out by the prime minister in her Lancaster House speech on Brexit.
"The prime minister's position on an implementation period is very clear and well-known," he said.
"Free movement will end in March 2019. We have published proposals on citizens' rights. Last week, the Home Secretary said there will be a registration system for migrants arriving post-March 2019.
"Other elements of the post-Brexit immigration system will be brought forward in due course. It would be wrong to speculate on what these might look like or to suggest that free movement will continue as it is now."
Number 10's intervention came as Cabinet ministers Jeremy Hunt and Sir Michael Fallon sought to play down reports of splits within May's top team.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Secretary Amber Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Trade Secretary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2019</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexiteer Liam Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Secretary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Theresa May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tory Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lancaster House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK-EU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chancellor Philip Hammond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Michael Fallon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
