<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401323316660748</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/local-sport/now-the-pub-can-be-the-pinnacle-for-those-who-find-the-full-mountain-run-a-bit-too-steep/news-story/05005a94349538adad3d124c6c15bf66</url>
  <title>Now the pub can be the pinnacle</title>
  <content>
FOR those who find the iconic Point to Pinnacle too much of a challenge, there is now an alternative with the option of a tasty reward at the finish line.
The gruelling 21km Point to Pinnacle slog up kunanyi/Mt Wellington is branded the world's toughest half marathon.
But in this year's event, on November 19, there is the new race - the Point to Pub. The Point to Pub is a shorter track of 10km from Wrest Point to the Fern Tree Tavern.
Race director Tim Smith hopes the new event can be a stepping stone for people to compete in the major event.
"The idea behind the Point to Pub is to allow more people to take part on the day," he said. "We wanted to create an option with a more fun and inclusive environment."
The participants of the Point to Pub will be able to enjoy live music, food and drinks from tavern and Mr Smith hopes a view of the main race will inspire some people.
"From the pub, people will be able to see the Point to Pinnacle participants about to head up the mountain," he said.
"Hopefully some people think the walk or run to the pub wasn't too hard and take the next step the following year."
Entries open at 7am on Tuesday for both events, with the Point to Pinnacle open to 3000 participants and the Point to the Pub open to 500.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wrest Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fern Tree Tavern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
