<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401323316660760</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/television/farmer-wants-a-bloke-karl-stefanovic-helps-country-boy-come-out-on-this-time-next-year/news-story/b88c8e40c68260a290ccaf661fcbe13b</url>
  <title>Meet the farmer who wants a bloke</title>
  <content>
COMING out to your family is a big deal for a country boy.
Worried that he might back out, farmer Brad Purdy committed to telling not just his family, but all of Australia on Karl Stefanovic's new show, This Time Next Year.
"I felt like I was wasting my life," said Purdy from Baradine, NSW.
"I was sitting at home feeling sorry for myself, and this ad kept coming up. I was like, it feels like it's almost talking to me."
The ad was for Stefanovic's new Channel 9 show, where guests make a pledge and have a year to follow through with their promise.
Purdy, now 36, says telling his family was by far the hardest part.
"There was quite a few times there I felt like running. But it was good to have deadlines to meet. And we got there.
"My friends and family, they're the people who have been lied to. It's nice to wake up and think 'what am I going to do today?' instead of going over the last 20,000 lies you've told."
With his big news well-received by his loved ones and the local community, Purdy did have a short relationship with another young farmer in the area, but he is still looking for a long-term relationship.
"Work is getting quieter now, I have some time off in winter, so I want to get back into the dating scene hopefully.
"Hopefully someone might see this show and contact me. I'm certainly open to that idea."
Another, completely unexpected benefit from This Time Next Year stemmed from tragedy.
During filming, a close friend of Purdy's had a car accident and was facing paraplegia.
On set, Purdy met Rhiannon Tracey, 27, who is confined to a wheelchair after suffering a neck injury. Her pledge to Stefanovic is that she will walk down the aisle when she marries her partner.

Purdy said meeting Rhiannon was "definitely the best thing I ever got out of the show."
"It was so inspiring to see her story. As a result of that she got in contact with my friend, and she's setting up a lot of his plans to move forward. Some amazing things come out of the show.
"I feel like my story is pretty left field, compared to the others."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Stefanovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baradine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhiannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Next Year</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Purdy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Purdy</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhiannon Tracey, 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefanovic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
