<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401319021693389</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/why-is-new-south-wales-alp-pushing-for-palestine-recognition/8758540</url>
  <title>Palestine-Israel: Why does New South Wales ALP care about this dispute?</title>
  <content>
The New South Wales ALP has passed a resolution urging the next federal Labor government to unilaterally recognise the state of Palestine.
It sailed through fairly uneventfully on Sunday - but furious backroom negotiations roiled the state party in the lead-up to vote.
The turmoil in the Middle East is a long way away from Australia. So why has so much time and energy gone into an argument about Labor's stance on a conflict thousands of kilometres away?
What is 'unilateral recognition' of Palestine? What does that mean?

Peace talks between Israelis and Palestinians have been stalled for years. A two-state solution - with two separate countries, Israel and Palestine, co-existing peacefully - remains a distant prospect.

Over the last 30 years, most countries have decided to unilaterally recognise Palestine - in other words, to recognise Palestine as a state, even though there has been no agreement.
Some of the countries which have gone down this path blame Israel for the breakdown in talks, and argue that unilateral recognition will help exert pressure on the Israeli Government to get back to the negotiating table.
Other countries which recognise Palestine are just hostile to Israel's very existence.
But most Western countries haven't gone down this path - and neither has Australia. Some in Labor want that to change.
Why do people care?

Pro-Palestine MPs and activists in the ALP say an increasing number of people in the party want to see Australia shift its stance on Israel and Palestine.
They blame Israel for the current impasse, arguing that Benjamin Netanyahu's Government has fatally undermined the peace process by allowing Israeli settlements to spread in occupied territories.
The former foreign minister Bob Carr led the push for unilateral recognition at the NSW conference - declaring that the party should not be "left stranded in history" by refusing to join other countries who have taken the step.
Labor MPs who back Israel scoff at those arguments. They maintain that it's difficult for any nation to recognise a country which is essentially split between two governing factions - with Hamas ruling in the Gaza Strip and Fatah ruling in the West Bank.
Labor frontbencher Mark Dreyfus took aim at the champions of unilateral recognition earlier today, saying it "flies in the face of international law".
Pro Labor MPs also argue that in the end an agreement can only be hammered out by the Israelis and the Palestinians. Other countries who try to exert external pressure on Israel, they say, are more likely to hamper than help.
Israeli diplomats make a similar point. A spokeswoman from the Israeli embassy in Canberra said that unilateral recognition is "a danger, rather than a promotion of the two-state solution".
"Such a recognition would only push the Palestinians further away from the negotiating table - which is the only place where peace can be achieved," she said.

What else is going on?

Israel is always a totemic issue in the ALP. The contest over this policy is increasingly fraught because it's part of a broader factional arm wrestle.
The Left of the party has always been pro-Palestine, and it's exerting more sway over the party membership.
And while the party's Right faction in Victoria is holding firm for Israel, the NSW Right has split.
Over the last five years, the rank and file of the ALP shifted away from Israel and towards Palestine.
The Queensland Labor Party and the ACT Labor Party also passed motions over the weekend endorsing unilateral recognition.
So - was there a winner?

When it comes to the Israel-Palestine conflict, small changes in language can matter a lot. So let's take a close look at what the motion says.
The NSW motion urges the next Labor government to recognise Palestine. But it also notes that Labor "supports the recognition and right of Israel and Palestine to exist within secure and recognised borders".
This language was inserted at the last minute in order to avoid a messy brawl on the floor of the conference.
Both sides have claimed the final motion as a victory.
Pro-Palestine MPs argue that for the first time the ALP's most powerful branch has unambiguously endorsed recognition of Palestine. They say this is a historic step, and will exert enormous sway on the next federal Labor government when it weighs up its foreign policy.
Pro-Israel Labor MPs don't agree. They argue the motion doesn't bind the federal party to anything.
And they say the last-minute changes also dilute its impact, by making it clear that a future Labor government must also recognise that Israel's security is vital.
The next big internal battle on this will be in July next year - when the Federal ALP Conference meets in Adelaide.
Do any of these motions actually force a Labor government to do anything?

No, it doesn't. In fact they might just ignore it entirely.
Some in the ALP maintain that a Labor government's foreign policy would be primarily shaped by two people - Opposition Leader Bill Shorten and shadow foreign minister Penny Wong.
Mr Dreyfus made a similar point earlier today: "Foreign policy for a Labor government federally, is a federal matter. It will be set federally by decisions made by the Federal shadow cabinet, by the federal Caucus."
And both Mr Shorten and Senator Wong have made it clear they're not rushing to embrace unilateral recognition.

Mr Shorten side-stepped questions on the NSW Labor conference motion earlier today, simply stressing that .
So, the ALP's federal party leadership might hold firm and resist the push towards recognition.
Pro-Palestine MPs say that will put them on a crash course with the party's membership.
The debate inside Labor over Israel and Palestine has always been fraught.
It's not losing any intensity.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Netanyahu's Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal ALP Conference</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro-Palestine MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Labor Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Right</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dreyfus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaza Strip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fatah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro-Israel Labor MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palestinians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palestine-Israel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel-Palestine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Dreyfus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palestine</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales ALP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro Labor MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Labor Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
