<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400240984882137</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/city/check-out-our-pick-of-the-citys-best-dogfriendly-cafes/news-story/a74294afcb1d618870c72aad46bc0065</url>
  <title>The city's best dog-friendly cafes</title>
  <content>
WANT to go cafe-hopping with your best friend? Check out these dog-friendly cafes (where humans are welcome, too)
Flying Fig Deli
Owner Paul Serafin loves dogs but doesn't have time to look after one of his own. With so many gorgeous mutts making an appearance here each day, he still manages to get his fix. Paul's considering putting a "puppaccino" on the menu, but for now has a water bowl at the front. Look out for an August menu of Reuben sandwich variations (that's just for the humans, though).
161 Jeffcott St, North Adelaide
Dogwatch:@theflyingfigdelica
Fawn Coffee
One thing that gets us through the start of the working week is Murphy Monday. The Toy Poodle (below) is the six-month-old pup of Fawn owner Amber, who posts pics of this little fella to social media every Monday. She'll eventually bring him to the cafe to sit out the front, but at the moment he's a little too young for that. Dogs are welcome to sit outside, and there are poles perfect for attaching leads. There's always a water bowl, and a side door for quick takeaway orders.
269 Gilles St, city. Dogwatch: @fawncoffee
Archie & Co
Named after Adam Hadley-Darrie and partner Paul Engelhardt's Pug x Jack Russell (the little cutie on the right), this coffee shop/salon automatically gets cred as a dog-friendly spot. Archie features on social media fairly often, so dog owners (rightly) assume they're welcome here. Adam and Paul can't help but take photos of the pups that come their way, so expect to see squishy-faced pugs among the usual flat lays and latte art shots. At the cafe, there's outdoor seating as well as a retail section of leather and velvet collars from Melbourne business Nice Digs. Because the guys live behind the shop, it means they can head out daily to take Archie for a walk or keep him out the front - Paul says Archie is outside every day. If you've wandered by lately you may have noticed Archie has been playing with a new mate - a rescued greyhound called Agyness.
Paul and Adam named her after supermodel Agyness Deyn. Wonder if we can expect the 'Co' to change? Kids don't like when you play favourites, guys.
48/81 Carrington St, city
Dogwatch: @archieco - cafe
Cafe Komodo
Simply put, the workers here really love dogs. They get giddy over any type of pup and always have water bowls nearby for their new furry friends. On weekends, you can expect to see up to 10 dogs hanging out in the cafe's leafy courtyard.
There's one regular who has a dog that's more like a bear - the cafe's unofficial mascot. Oscar the schnoodle, pictured (known on Instagram as @oscarinadelaide) is another fave.
118 Prospect Rd, Prospect
Dogwatch: @cafekomodo
Five Little Figs
When the coffee orders are piling up faster than usual, Five Little Figs owner Michelle Campbell knows there's a dog outside because the barista is out the front going goo-goo. The entire staff is like this. Pups are welcome to treats and doggychinos (water) and regular customers are known not by name, but their dogs ('hey it's Benji's dad, there's Tintin's mum.') Michelle runs a monthly Post and Boast/Brag and Tag comp on social media where she chooses her favourite dog and the owner gets a coffee or meal for free.
52 Devitt Ave, Payneham South
Dogwatch: @fivelittlefigs
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Serafin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fawn Coffee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilles St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice Digs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dogwatch</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fig Deli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Hadley-Darrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devitt Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tintin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeffcott St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toy Poodle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PUP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Engelhardt's Pug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrington St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archie</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murphy Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Payneham South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prospect Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cafe Komodo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agyness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agyness Deyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Figs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boast/Brag</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
