<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400674776586785</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/kidnapping-trial-hears-ransom-demanded-by-alleged-captors/8761140</url>
  <title>Victorian man allegedly kidnapped by six Tasmanians in 2015 told to pay $75k, court hears</title>
  <content>
A Victorian man was beaten, held at gunpoint and had $75,000 demanded from him during a three-day ordeal, a jury in Launceston has heard.
Six Tasmanians are on trial accused of kidnapping Anthony Merkhael two years ago.
Caine Robert Richardson, Sean Gregory Richardson, Matthew Luke Williams, Malcolm Joshua Mayne, Christopher John Humphries and Carly Ann Dekkers have pleaded not guilty in the Supreme Court in Launceston to kidnapping.
Several of the defendants are also charged with aggravated armed robbery, aggravated assault, assault and perverting the course of justice - charges they have denied.
In his opening statement on Monday, Crown Prosecutor Luke Brett said Melbourne man Mr Mekhael was abducted at gunpoint by Caine and Sean Richardson while he was visiting a friend in Launceston in February, 2015.
He said they pointed a pistol at him and said, "don't run or you'll be shot", before forcing him into a car owned by Dekkers.
They were allegedly joined by Humphreys and Mayne.

Mr Brett said Mr Mekhael was punched and kicked and had $20,000 stolen from his backpack, before the kidnappers demanded another $75,000 from him, "or else".
Mr Brett told the jury that when Mr Mekhael later tried to escape, Caine Richardson fired two shots in his direction, then fired the gun into the ground next to his head and strangled him.
He said Mr Mekhael was put into the boot of a car and was taken to various locations, including properties in Port Sorell and Swan Bay, a caravan park and a house where Williams was present.
It is alleged Mr Mekhael was locked in a cupboard under some stairs.
He was released when police officers raided a Rocherlea house on the third day of the alleged kidnapping.
Prosecutors allege Dekkers later cleaned her car to eliminate evidence of the kidnapping.
Mr Brett said although the six had each acted differently, they were all responsible for the kidnapping.
"They all worked together to commit the crime."
Lawyer questions victim's honesty

Caine Richardson's lawyer, Evan Hughes, cast doubt on the honesty and reliability of the complainant, Mr Mekhael, who he said was the pillar on which the prosecution's case was built.
"A lot of the prosecution's case rests of the honesty of the complainant," he said.
"There is a lot about Anthony Mekhael that will lead you by the end of this trial to disbelief."
Lawyers for the other defendants told the jury they would dispute most of the facts of the case.
They said although they conceded their clients were at the Rocherlea house, no kidnapping had taken place.
Dekker's lawyer said her client had merely lent her car to her boyfriend and had no knowledge of the kidnapping.
"If you lend your car to your boyfriend and it comes back messy, you clean it," he told the court.
The trial continues.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carly Ann Dekkers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher John Humphries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caine Robert Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocherlea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dekkers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Luke Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Joshua Mayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Gregory Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Sorell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Merkhael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mekhael</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caine Richardson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Mekhael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Humphreys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evan Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Luke Brett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
