<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401280366986832</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/breaking-news/possible-breakthrough-in-king-cold-case/news-story/b0ec3185b001836b6146a889e3c48c92</url>
  <title>Possible breakthrough in King cold case</title>
  <content>
The suspected murder of Adelaide mother-of-two Gail King 20 years ago could be on the verge of a breakthrough, police say.
Ms King was reported missing in July 1997 after her partner, who is a suspect, said she left the Yorke Peninsula property the duo were renovating for work in Adelaide.
When the man returned to the couple's Brahma Lodge home with the children the next day, Ms King's car was in the driveway but she could not be found.
Police on Monday said they were recently in contact with someone who provided "a different taint" to the investigation, part of a wider review of cold cases.
"While I can't comment too much on what we have, I can confirm that we have information that is credible and needs to be explored," Detective Inspector Greg Hutchins said.
"It is another avenue we need to look at.
"We are keeping an open mind in relation to this matter - there are a number of unexplained aspects of this case which we will keep working on."
A $200,000 reward is on offer for anyone who provides information leading to the arrest and conviction of the person responsible for Ms King's death or the recovery of her remains.
"I would urge anyone with information that might be relevant to pick up the phone and talk to us about what they know - her children and her family deserve that much," Insp Hutchins said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brahma Lodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insp Hutchins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorke Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail King 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Greg Hutchins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms King</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1997</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
