<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401327611628101</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/television/bookies-favourite-adam-parkin-eliminated-from-australian-survivor/news-story/c60f591b91ec7ce756fe8c6980b2b2b7</url>
  <title>'Hurricane' wipes out Survivor contestant</title>
  <content>
POKER player Adam Parkin was one of the favourites leading into Australian Survivor, but that wasn't enough to save him in the second episode of the show, after an episode of big game plays.
The Queenslander, 40, was outmanoeuvred by a desperate AK Knight, from South Australia, 29.
Parkin said the initial feeling was one of disappointment, to be voted out so early after having a huge game plan, that he couldn't roll out.
"I guess disappointment is the biggest feeling," he told News Corp.
"It's a long hard process to get there, even to get on the island.
"When you have watched the show for so long, and you get there, you have got all of these ideas.
"I was ready to play a massive game, I had so many moves I wanted to do.
"I came prepared, but unfortunately it just didn't happen."
Parkin said everyone wanted to get Knight out of the game, but that all changed when he found the hidden immunity idol.

Frantic scrambling by Knight - including giving the idol to Perth photographer Jarrad Seng at tribal council - ending up saving him.
Parkin received five votes, compared to four for Melbourne's Anneliese Wilson, two for Melbourne's Kate Temby, and one for Knight.
Parkin said things all changed for Knight when he found the Idol, and he accused him of playing too hard.
Knight is fast becoming the most talked about contestants on this year's series of Australian Survivor.
"AK is like a hurricane," Parkin said.
"He was playing way too hard from the moment we went on the barge.
"Unfortunately with a hurricane, it takes victims with them.
"Unfortunately I was one of those victims, caught up in the hurricane that was AK."
'He was 100 per cent going until he found that Idol."
Parkin said he believed his Samatau tribe made a mistake in getting rid of him, as he was a real asset in the physical challenges.
"For me they are losing their second strongest person in the tribe," he said.
"That has never been a successful strategy in Survivor history."
In the end Parkin couldn't win the support of the other alpha male in the tribe, Perth adventure guide Lockie Gilbert.
THE THIRD EPISODE OF AUSTRALIAN SURVIVOR AIRS ON TUESDAY NIGHT ON CHANNEL 10 AT 7.30PM.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkin</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THIRD EPISODE OF AUSTRALIAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslander, 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SURVIVOR AIRS ON TUESDAY NIGHT ON CHANNEL 10 AT 7.30PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockie Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Anneliese Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrad Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Kate Temby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AK Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samatau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Parkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
