<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401104273324361</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4824509/nnswf-ready-for-joint-response-to-plan/?cs=305</url>
  <title>NNSWF ready for joint response to plan</title>
  <content>
Northern NSW Football chief David Eland remains confident premier clubs will express their individual concerns about the prospect of taking on the skills acquisition phase (SAP) program despite a campaign to secure a uniform response.
Clubs have until close of business on Tuesday to submit a comprehensive online questionnaire and provide other feedback to the plan in which NPL and WPL clubs take over under-9s to under-12s elite development from the Emerging Jets and zone SAP programs. The change comes after the Jets' decision to take control of the Emerging Jets program from under-12s and above. 

The NNSWF board is expected to consider the new SAP proposal on August 16. Clubs were given a month to complete their submission following a series of standing committee meetings and individual consultations.
Behind the scenes, clubs have been asked to sign a memorandum of understanding on amendments to the plan, which will be presented to NNSWF on Tuesday. Hamilton chairman and Association of Australian Football Clubs director Christo Patsan confirmed he had been speaking to NPL and Northern League One clubs about a submission.
"We've been talking together, which is part of that consultative process which Northern have set up," Patsan said. "There's a majority of clubs who have signed it, but it basically says 'yes'. All clubs are in favour of youth development and improving it.

"With that in mind, people are saying, 'yes, we're prepared to go into this, even though it's a continuing stretch on our resources, but we're keen to look at this further, and here's some thoughts on how it might operate'."
Patsan did not detail the amendments, saying he wanted to respect the process, but "the clubs' submission is not rejecting it".
Eland said clubs had told NNSWF management about Patsan's moves to form a joint submission but it was "not really a concern because this is something we've had to deal with for quite some time".
"It just feels like every time there's a review or change, there's an attempt to get all clubs on the same page and present back a consistent response to Northern NSW Football," Eland said.
"I remain confident clubs will put their position forward through the submission that we've provided. That's what the consultation process is all about.
"It's about clubs being informed and given an opportunity to put their club's views forward so the board can consider that. That's the only danger of a consistent MOU, because clubs lose their ability to put their views forward."
He said principle concerns of clubs had been the projected costs of the program, implementation of consistent fees on players and a standard pay-rate of $15 an hour for coaches.

He said Football Federation Australia wanted the SAP base broadened and "premier clubs are at heart of that". He said the governing bodies were ready to invest heavily in supporting clubs take on the programs.
He said while the NNSWF board would take the views of the members, it made decisions in the best interests of the game.

"I've got every confidence, regardless of what is going on behind the scenes, that clubs have had every opportunity to put their views forward about the proposed changes and those views will come through," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NNSWF</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patsan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Association of Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emerging Jets</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Clubs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAPS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern NSW Football</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern League One</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Eland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christo Patsan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
