<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401319021693405</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/chanticleer/nab-ends-the-sales-driven-bonuses-for-bank-managers-20170731-gxmk4r</url>
  <title>Pay reform is happening at the big four banks</title>
  <content>
The move by National Australia Bank to scrap sales based bonuses is a welcome development that should prompt the other major banks to move faster on reform of incentives.
The bank will on Tuesday announce that more than 700 retail branch managers, assistant branch managers and team leaders in consumer call centres will from to the bank's group short term inventive plan from October 1.
NAB's chief customer officer, consumer and wealth, Andrew Hagger, says NAB wanted to fix its pay before the deadlines agreed under the reforms put forward by Stephen Sedgwick in April.
Sedgwick said the sales based bonuses paid by the big four banks needed to be scaled back as part of an industry wide effort to restore trust in the banking system.

He recommended that any incentive or variable reward payment be constructed with a range of inputs that better reflect the responsibilities and consumer expectations flowing from the role while improving consumer outcomes.

"This change to our staff incentive program sends a very clear message: that the customer must be at the heart of everything we do, and that great leadership is both valued and rewarded," Hagger says in an official statement.
NAB's short term incentives have a range of measures which are referred to as a balance scorecard.
The latest NAB annual report has a detailed explanation of the STI measures. These include cash earnings, return on equity, customer advocacy, risk management and NAB's values.
These values are: passion for customers, will to win, be bold, respect for people and do the right thing.

There is also a "conduct gate" which is defined as the level of conduct that is expected of all employees.
NAB has made a number of other changes to its employee remuneration structure including: moving away from performance-based, fixed pay increases for customer service and support staff. They now receive a standard pay rise of three per cent a year.
NAB says it was the first bank to commit to implementing the Sedgwick reforms and Hagger says the bank aims to implement them well ahead of the 2020 deadline.
Other banks have talked about implementing the Sedgwick reforms next year.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hagger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sedgwick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Sedgwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hagger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
