<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400717726260641</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/dayne-beams-says-brisbanes-future-most-exciting-since-he-arrived-at-the-club/news-story/f1e476dc6494d62e6dcc3af6f29227b3</url>
  <title>Beams never more excited about Lions</title>
  <content>
SKIPPER Dayne Beams says he is the most excited about Brisbane's future he has been since arriving at the club and is confident the Lions can finish the season on a high and avoid the wooden spoon.
Beams produced a superb captain's performance in the Lions' 17.11 (113) to 6.9 (45) loss to West Coast at Subiaco Oval on Sunday.
He said despite the size of the loss, he thought it would not rob the Lions of the momentum they had built since the bye.
STANDING UP:
THE BAROMETER:
BOTTOM PLACED:
The Collingwood premiership player said it was common for sides with no hopes of making the finals to drop away at the end of seasons but he did not think it would happen to the Lions.
"I haven't felt as excited as I am now about our club in the three years I have been here and the older guys that have been here their whole career say the same thing,'' he said.
"Often the last four weeks when you are in our position it can become monotonous and you are hanging out for the end of the season, but we have got a lot to play for, we hope we can finish with six or seven wins and show our fans and ourselves we are on the right track, it can serve as a boost ahead of the pre-season."
Beams said he had been rejuvenated by the quick turnaround the club had experienced under new coach Chris Fagan. He said there was a critical shortage in the middle-tier of experience - players in the 24 to 26 years-of-age - bracket and a strong finish was important to help lure players North during the end of year trade period.
He thought any players contemplating a move would be impressed with the first to third year players at the Lions.
"Hopefully we are pretty active in the trade period, for anyone we might be looking to get to the club it is important to demonstrate the spirit in the group and the belief that we are going places,'' he said.
"You look at our list and if we can keep everyone together, the sky is the limit for our group, you can't buy time and it takes time, but they have all shown something.
"When you are my age you look for little signs in kids that they can be good footballers and you see it in all of them. As they play more they will only get better.
"We have got some good experience and we have great young kids, we just lack that middle tier, that a lot of clubs have and that is because a lot of those guys that would be there left out club years ago.''
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subiaco Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lions' 17.11 (113</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Fagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Beams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
