<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401705568757769</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/world/asia/the-curious-friendship-between-queen-victoria-and-her-indian-servant-abdul-karim-20170723-gxh718</url>
  <title>Her Royal Highness and the Indian servant. Nothing impropper</title>
  <content>
by
Radhika Sanghani

It was on a family trip to  that Shrabani Basu discovered a secret that had lain untold since Queen Victoria's death. The Indian journalist had taken her two teenage daughters with her to the former Queen's palatial holiday home to witness the restored Durbar Room; an original banquet hall. As Basu wandered through the house's Indian wing, she couldn't help notice several portraits and a bust of an Indian servant called Abdul Karim.
"He didn't look like a servant," explains Basu, 54, from her north London home. "He was painted to look like a nobleman. He was holding a book, looking sideways. Something about that expression struck me, and when I moved along, I saw another portrait of him looking rather gentle. It was very unusual."
At the time, in 2003, everything she knew about Queen Victoria's Indian servants came from a book she had written on curry several years earlier - namely that the Queen had loved curry (chicken curry and daal being a particular favourite), and had servants from India who cooked it for her every lunchtime. "It was in the back of my mind all along, so when I saw the portraits of Abdul, including a tableau of ladies serving him, I was intrigued," says Basu. "I knew I had to look into this."
In a project that spanned five years and three countries, Basu slowly uncovered the story of Victoria and Abdul - a 24-year-old former Indian Muslim clerk who had been granted as a "Golden Jubilee gift" to the Queen, and ended up becoming her closest confidante until she died.

Patrick Eden / Alamy Stock Photo

The astonishing story of the curious friendship between the Queen and her Indian servant, to whom she a bestowed a title of "Munshi", will be told this autumn  and Bollywood star Ali Fazal. Based on Basu's book Victoria & Abdul, republished this week, it brings to life the relationship that caused such controversy that upon Queen Victoria's death, her family tried to erase the story of Abdul entirely.

The many letters that the pair wrote to each other were burned, and the mention of him in the Queen's own journals were edited out by her daughter, Beatrice. References to Abdul by other historians were brief, and had him painted as a "rogue" who had used the Queen to climb the social ladder.
The true nature of the pair's friendship of 13 years was consigned to the recesses of history until Basu went off to Windsor Castle and asked to look at Queen Victoria's Hindustani journals - a collection of "exercise books" where Abdul would teach her what we now know as Urdu. "No one had seen them up to that point," explains Basu. "The blotting paper fell out of these journals which hadn't been opened for 100 years - presumably because all Queen Victoria's biographers had been western and couldn't follow Urdu."
Basu, however, had been brought up in Delhi and could make sense of the journals. She read through
13 volumes of the Queen writing about Hindustani lessons in Balmoral, visiting Abdul when he was ill, and visits to take tea with his wife - who she had granted permission to come from India to join him - and see their cat's new kittens. Her passion for India was obvious, from her desperate wish to eat a mango to her view of the Karims as her equals. It showed a completely different side to the Queen's life than had been previously recorded.

Pictorial Press Ltd / Alamy Stock Photo

After the Queen's death, Abdul returned to Agra, and it was here where Basu found a ruined mausoleum which would have once been studded with gems and rubies. His inscriptions still lay engraved on the tombstone.
"It was a big moment," says Basu. "I felt, now I've found his grave, this man's story had to be told. It became a passion. Within a few months, it had taken over my life. I mean, it was the Queen and a young Muslim man - what's not to be curious about? The more and more I got into it, it became more and more gripping."
Abdul had never had children with his wife, but eventually Basu discovered his nephew's descendants, who introduced her to relatives in Karachi. There, locked up in a trunk in their attic, were Abdul's untouched personal journals. They detailed his story of coming to England aged 24, to take up what he thought was a prestigious position in the Queen's household, but was actually just a glorified "exotic servant" role.
"He was a clerk who had never done menial work," smiles Basu. "There was a bit of arrogance as he wrote about that and, after a couple of months in England, he writes about how he wants to go back to his wife in India. He tells the Queen, but she asks him to stay, saying she enjoys his company and wants to learn Hindustani from him."

That discovery was crucial, as it proved that the existing narrative about Abdul as a rogue who used the Queen just wasn't true. "It put their whole relationship into a different perspective," says Basu. "He was devoted and has nothing but praise for her, about how good she is, how she's kind and has always stood up for him."
Over the next few years, Basu pieced together the true story of 68-year-old Queen Victoria, Empress of India, and Abdul, the young Munshi who stayed with her until her death in 1901. She found letters from the Queen where she signs off as "your closest friend", "your true friend" and "your loving mother".
"Sometimes she's a mother figure to him; sometimes he's her closest friend," explains Basu. "At the same time, the physical aspect is important. Two Indian servants came - one she describes as very short, very dark and she describes Abdul as handsome. It's important she goes for the tall handsome one."
She stresses their relationship would not have been sexual, though, "there might have been some hand?holding or a few intimate moments," but was a true friendship: "He spoke to her as a human being and not as the Queen. Everyone else kept their distance from her, even her own children, and this young Indian came with an innocence about him. He told her about India, his family and was there to listen when she complained about her own family."

Some of the letters between the pair are written with a frankness we would never expect. She writes to Abdul about his wife's difficulty in conceiving, advising: "She should be careful at the particular time every month not to tire herself," and tells Abdul: "There is nothing I would not do to help you both, as you are my dear Indian children and you can say (any) thing to me."
When he is criticised and subjected to racial abuse - from her son and heir, to the rest of the household and the staff - she stands up for him. He is part of the "black brigade" from India, accused of theft, being a spy, and of lying, but Queen Victoria refuses to believe the lies, and, in memos to her children, reprimands them for their lack of respect.
"He was an ordinary commoner from Agra who was close to the Queen," points out Basu. "They were snobs and Queen Victoria told them as much. She told them this is not acceptable. She was definitely ahead of her time.
"There was a young Muslim at the heart of the royal court during the most crucial years of Victoria's reign, of the longest-reigning monarch in an empire at its height," Basu explains. "This young man caused so much confusion. It's delightful and funny, but it's also sad and, more than anything, it's a reflection of the times they lived in."

The Daily Telegraph
Victoria and Abdul by Shrabani Basu is published by the History Press.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Karim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Victoria's Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shrabani Basu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Victoria</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Press Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hindustani</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Jubilee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Durbar Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munshi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor Castle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radhika Sanghani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urdu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alamy Stock Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balmoral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beatrice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basu</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Highness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>History Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karachi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Eden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Fazal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basu, 54</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Muslims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Empress of India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Victoria's Hindustani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
