<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401361971367164</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-men-plead-guilty-to-rape-aggravated-robbery-over-sex-worker-attacks-20170731-gxm3le.html</url>
  <title>Canberra men plead guilty to rape, aggravated robbery over sex worker attacks</title>
  <content>
Two brothers have pleaded guilty to rape and aggravated robbery charges that stemmed from two violent attacks against sex workers in the ACT. 
Mohammed Alabbasi, 22, and Ahmed Al Abbasi, 31, were set to fight allegations they raped women in separate incidents in apartments in Reid and Braddon in 2016. 
But the men will avoid trial after switching their pleas in the ACT Supreme Court on Friday.
Documents previously tendered in court said one female sex worker was raped after a man booked an appointment and several men showed up in Reid on March 13.
In the second attack, another woman was raped after she accepted a booking for a half-hour service in a Braddon hotel on May 10. 
Ahmed Al Abbasi, also previously named as Khaled Al Abbasi in court documents, pleaded guilty to two counts of third degree rape, two charges of rape in company, attempted rape in company, rape and aggravated robbery.
Mohammed Alabbasi pleaded guilty to two counts of third degree rape, two charges of rape in company and aggravated robbery.
The pair will return to court for sentencing later this year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Al Abbasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Al Abbasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohammed Alabbasi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohammed Alabbasi, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Al Abbasi, 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braddon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
