<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401533770062267</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/isis-fighters-wife-reveals-twisted-lives-of-schoolgirls-becoming-jihadi-brides-after-fleeing-to-syria/news-story/4dcf2b0c87a8425daff286d6524efaa7</url>
  <title>ISIS fighter's wife reveals twisted lives of schoolgirls becoming jihadi brides after fleeing to Syria</title>
  <content>
White Widow Sally Jones wants to return to Britain
1:03

Sally Jones left Britain to join the Islamic State with her now-dead jihadist husband and young son. But now, she wants to return home...

July 4th 2017
a month ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

Islam Mitat, a 23-year-old fashion-mad physics student, has revealed the twisted lifestyle of ISIS wives in Syria. Picture: The Sun.

Charlie ParkerThe Sun

Share

THE runaway bride of an ISIS fighter who escaped a beseiged terror stronghold has exposed the secret lifestyle of British schoolgirls fleeing to Syria.
Three years ago Islam Mitat's British husband forced her to move to Syria and live with Brit jihadi teenagers while he trained with the terror group.
Mitat, 23, who has met "Mrs Terror" Sally Jones, told The Sunday Times what life is like for the schoolgirls who fled the UK to wed extremists.
The fashion-mad physics student described Syria as "Little Britain" because so many young people from the UK have settled there.
She was made to live with notorious Manchester terror twins Salma Halane and Zahra, as well as three other schoolgirls from Bethnal Green, east London, who fled to Syria in 2015.

Teens Amira Abse, Kadiza Sultana and Shamima Begum pictured leaving the UK for Syria in 2015.Source:The Sun
According to Mitat the teenagers were happy to be in Syria and were delighted to read about themselves in British newspapers online.
She said: "They looked happy about it. I was so shocked."
Her next-door neighbours were London-born Muslim convert Grace Dare and her Swedish husband Abu Bakr.
Mitat said their young son, who was featured in an ISIS propaganda video pressing a button that detonated a car bomb killing four, often played in her living room.

Former punk singer-turned-extremist Sally Jones also came round for tea, and the three Bethnal Green teens were also close neighbours.
Kadiza Sultana, one of the trio, was killed in an air strike last year. She was just 17.
ISIS 'security forces' then swooped on the remaining two girls, Amira Abase and Shamima Begum, both 16, and took them away. Mitat never saw them again.

Mitat was forced to join the 'caliphate' by her British husband Ahmad Khalil.Source:Supplied
Mitat also discovered that the jihadi brides were bitterly jealous of their husband's sex slaves. She said they were 'a bit of fun' for the ISIS fighters but caused marital tension.
"One day I saw a Yazidi woman and her son being beaten by her owner in Salma and Zahra's house," she explained. "I went to her when he left and said, 'why is your husband beating you?' She said, 'he's not my husband, I'm a slave.' I didn't even know what it meant."
Mitat's terror nightmare began after husband Ahmed Khalil told his then 20-year-old wife that he had a surprise that he would reveal during their holiday in Turkey.
To her horror, after they arrived, he said they were moving to Syria to join the 'caliphate', and when Mitat objected Khalil said bluntly: "You are my wife and you have to obey me."
Kahlil ignored her pleas to leave and only visited her occasionally during short trips back from military training.
But just two months after the couple arrived in Syria - and after Mitat had become pregnant - her husband was killed fighting for ISIS.
She was later forced to remarry but managed to escape after hatching a plan with neighbours to smuggle her and her children away.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>London-born Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Jones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yazidi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie ParkerThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zahra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Khalil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam Mitat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitat, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam Mitat's British</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amira Abse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grace Dare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Bakr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amira Abase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khalil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swedish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Widow Sally Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shamima Begum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salma Halane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kahlil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitat</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kadiza Sultana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmad Khalil.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bethnal Green</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRS TERROR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
