<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401018373976898</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/changing-rainfall-leaves-some-areas-experiencing-the-wettest-july-on-record-a-month-after-their-driest-june/news-story/fc2d651a8db1b79fbba1278a9540c1b3</url>
  <title>From the driest month to the wettest</title>
  <content>
SOUTH Australia has gone from the driest month on record for some areas to the wettest for others as the state catches up on its annual rainfall in a tumultuous 31 days.
In parts of Kangaroo Island, the Yorke Peninsula and areas to Adelaide's north, June was the driest on record while large swathes of the state measured well below average rainfall.
Flash forward to July, and some of those same areas have recorded the highest rainfall on average.
A small area in the Barossa Valley went from having the driest June on record to its wettest July.
Also basking in the high rainfall was areas of the lower Yorke Peninsula, which also had its highest monthly rainfall on record.
Adelaide experienced more than 13mm rainfall in July over the average of 77.4mm.
The rain has bought Adelaide back in line with the average for the year so far, only 15mm off the 319.5mm average.
The rain is far from over with the beginning of August heralding more cold days and evenings with rainfall expected later this week.
A cloudy, dry day is forecast for Tuesday with a top of 16, but rain is predicted for the rest of the week.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorke Peninsula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barossa Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
