<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400198035208416</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/cyclists-targeted-by-bike-path-oil-slick-vandal-20170731-gxm9nw.html</url>
  <title>Cyclists targeted by bike path oil slick vandal</title>
  <content>
A malicious vandal is targeting cyclists in Melbourne's inner city, leaving oil slicks across bike paths in a potentially deadly act.
A number of cyclists have lost control of their bikes in North Melbourne in the past three weeks.

Police believe oil has been deliberately poured across the width of the tracks.
In the latest incident, a cyclist required medical attention after losing control on the oil on Sunday night. She is believed to have required dental work as a result.
On Monday police called for the woman to come forward to help with their investigation.

Constable Lauren McCormack said the oil was believed to be diesel oil, which was dark in colour and difficult to see on the paths.
Most incidents had occurred at night or dusk, when the oil was hard to see.
"Once they get to it, they're hitting it and just sliding off their bikes," she said. "They're just losing control."

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Oil slicks have been reported on the Dynon Road path, particularly on the bend between Dynon and Arden roads.
The Capital City Trail has also been affected.
Bicycle Network chief executive Craig Richards said a few riders had reported oil on bike paths and the group had spoken to Victoria Police.
But he urged cyclists not to "overreact publicly" and give offenders the satisfaction they seek.
"These incidents seem like a hard-to-fathom cry for attention," he said.
The cyclist injured on Sunday night is urged to contact Constable McCormack at Melbourne North police station on 8379 0800.
Anyone with information can call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constable Lauren McCormack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dynon Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital City Trail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constable McCormack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dynon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
