<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400601762141508</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/mining-forum-disappoints-aboriginal-elder/news-story/f1403d20800022f0d949e5f207acdaf5</url>
  <title>Mining forum disappoints Aboriginal elder</title>
  <content>
Australian Associated Press

Share

Organisers of WA's annual Diggers and Dealers mining conference who dumped the traditional Welcome To Country ceremony have been accused of being "condescending and patronising" towards an Aboriginal elder.
Trevor Donaldson was informally approached in May to open next week's conference in Kalgoorlie, but organisers later claimed the schedule was too tight for a 15 to 30 minute ceremony.
But Mr Donaldson said his ceremony would likely only last about five minutes and he was disappointed the Welcome To Country had been scrapped.
"I'd be pushing 10 minutes to the maximum," he told AAP on Monday.
"I am bitterly disappointed."
Mr Donaldson said he would be happy for any traditional custodian of the land to perform the ceremony and it was not a personal issue, but a matter of reconciliation and mending bridges.
Conference organiser John Langford insisted last week there was no disrespect meant towards the Aboriginal community and the Welcome To Country would return next year.
One Nation upper house member Robin Scott has urged the conference organisers to reconsider their decision for this year and described it as a gratuitous snub.
It is a sensitive time in Kalgoorlie after a 56-year-old man who ran down and killed 14-year-old Aboriginal boy Elijah Doughty was acquitted of manslaughter in the WA Supreme Court and was instead jailed for three years for dangerous driving causing death.

The teenager's death in August last year sparked a violent riot, exposing racial tensions in the Goldfields town, but a peaceful march was held this month when the verdict was handed down.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Donaldson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Langford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Welcome To Country</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Donaldson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldfields</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elijah Doughty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
