<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400889524955320</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/nrl-canberra-raiders-welcome-back-josh-papalii-and-jordan-rapana-for-cronulla-sharks-clash-20170730-gxlz94.html</url>
  <title>Raiders welcome back Josh Papalii and Jordan Rapana for must-win clash</title>
  <content>
Joe Tapine can see it in Josh Papalii's eyes - the Canberra Raiders star is intent on making a statement against one of the NRL's most intimidating forward packs.
The Raiders are set to be bolstered by the return of Papalii and mercurial winger Jordan Rapana for their must-win clash against the Cronulla Sharks at Shark Park on Saturday.Photo: Sitthixay Ditthavong
Both are returning from suspensions for shoulder charges, a ban that had Papalii stewing for two weeks ahead of a date with the reigning premiers.
Raiders forward Tapine says a look into Papalii's eyes gave him all he needed to know the Raiders enforcer is itching to get back out and test himself against the title contenders.

The Raiders need to run the table if they are to have any chance at playing finals football and the forwards have a huge task ahead of them this week.
The Sharks sit third in the competition for metres gained and it's Paul Gallen and Andrew Fifita leading the charge.

The menacing duo are the poster boys for a "knock them down, drag them out" style of play and lead the club in total carries, sitting first and third respectively for metres gained.
Tapine says Canberra can't afford to get caught up in a Sharks game plan that sees them "get dirty", and Papalii's influence will help the Green Machine along the way.
Tapine could return to a bench role after playing 80 impressive minutes for the Green Machine in a convincing win over South Sydney that kept their season alive.
"I'm happy with doing that. I was just filling in for Paps [Papalii] and he's an outstanding player so I'm happy to just go wherever I can to help," Tapine said.
"You can see in his eyes when he was giving me tips last week on how to play back-row, you can tell he can't wait to come back and the boys can wait for him to be back either.
"It's just a little boost, a little confidence boost when the boys come back. You know they've got skills. The boys are more confident when they're on the field as well."
Clay Priest made a long-awaited return to first grade with Raiders coach Ricky Stuart needing to find cover for the suspensions handed out to Papalii and Sia Soliola, who won't return until round 26.
Priest says Papalii will be a huge inclusion for the Raiders but he doesn't feel like they lost too much in his absence against the Rabbitohs, laughing Tapine did enough to keep the State of Origin star out of the side.
"He's a big part of the team, he does a lot of work on and off the field, so having him back will be a big plus," Priest said.
"I reckon Paps might not get his spot back, [Tapine] was unreal. Everything he did, I heard him out there, there was a lot of talking from him. I thought he was one of the best."
Priest is desperate to hold his spot in the NRL side as the Raiders embark on an unlikely run to the finals, which will be helped this week by more than a returning Papalii.
Flashy winger Rapana will force Michael Oldfield out of the starting squad when Stuart names his team on Tuesday.
Priest says Rapana's desire to roll up the sleeves and do the hard yards will be another huge boost for the Canberra pack.
"He brings so much to the team," Priest said. 
"His enthusiasm in around the ruck is remarkable, so to have him back there will be a big plus."
NRL ROUND 22
Saturday: Canberra Raiders v Cronulla Sharks at Shark Park, 7.30pm. Live on Fox League.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tapine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rapana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sia Soliola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shark Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Rapana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Papalii</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Oldfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL ROUND 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Raiders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Gallen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papalii</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla Sharks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tapine</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREEN MACHINE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clay Priest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sitthixay Ditthavong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
