<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400627531945714</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>08:58</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/new-federal-task-force-targets-the-black-economy/news-story/4b7d4fa2791e42b72dde7a7bed22df1b</url>
  <title>The rise of the 'black economy'</title>
  <content>
POPULAR on-demand services such as Uber and Airbnb are behind a dramatic rise in the "black economy" because mum-and-dad entrepreneurs are ignorant about or ignore their tax obligations, the chairman of a new Federal task force warns.
Black Economy Taskforce chairman Michael Andrew said many people making money from these "sharing economy" ventures were wrongly treating it like a hobby, in a lot of cases naively.
"It's not. It's actually business income and you're taxable on it and all of it has got to be reported to the Australian Taxation Office," he said.
"All of these people have suddenly come into the economy as contractors for the first time, not really recognising what their tax responsibilities are. But equally there's probably a lack of governance and regulatory framework around these new and emerging industries."
The task force will recommend ways for the Federal Government to crack down on the black economy, in which people and businesses use cash to operate outside the tax and regulatory system.
Institute of Public Accountants general manager of technical policy Tony Greco said while some were naive about their obligations, "a lot of people just choose to ignore the obvious". But the tax office had wide-ranging powers to access information from sharing economy operators.
An Airbnb Australia spokesman said Airbnb was an "economic lifeline for everyday West Australians", with the average host earning just over $5000 a year.
"Airbnb has taken proactive steps to help our hosts - seniors, mums and dads, young families - meet their tax obligations. We make it easier for hosts to declare their income by giving them a summary of earnings every year before tax time," he said.
An Uber spokeswoman said when drivers signed up to use the app, they were reminded of the tax office's expectations regarding getting an ABN, paying GST and complying with other tax obligations.
Mr Andrew said a host of problems had been raised with the task force, which is set to hand down its final report in October, including the exploitation and under-payment of workers.
He said there was a big problem in WA with "sham contracting", in which employers masquerade as contractors to avoid paying normal employee entitlements. Worker exploitation was a problem in the labour-hire and agriculture industries in WA, he said.
Mr Andrew said the task force also knew of money laundering in the WA car sector, with vehicles bought in the Eastern States sold for roughly the same price in WA.
"They're quite happy even if they have to drop 5 to 10 per cent off the price if they can turn black money into white money," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Institute of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Economy Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrew</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnb Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Greco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Taxation Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
