<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401366266334493</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/obamas-former-photographer-pete-souza-is-trumps-classiest-troll/news-story/33fd99886eb16b45b103a748f116fa2a</url>
  <title>Obama staffer is cleverest Trump troll</title>
  <content>
THE world doesn't seem quite sure what to do about Donald Trump's Twitter account.
ABC political editor Chris Uhlmann attacked it in a brutal but articulate fashion, accusing the US President of "(barking) out bile in 140 characters".
Saturday Night Live writer Josh Patten has taken a much lighter approach, mocking Mr Trump's tweets by replying to them as if the two were close friends.
However, former Obama photographer Pete Souza may have come up with the classiest way to troll him yet.
He started posting pictures on his Instagram account in February, taking subtle digs at the US President almost immediately after his inauguration.
His burns have become far more bold - and blistering - since then.
GOLF
They may be polar opposites when it comes to politics, but President Trump and Barack Obama share a love for a quiet 18-holes.
But while Mr Obama usually limited rounds of golf to his holidays, Mr Trump has been copping a fair bit of flak for spending a lot of time on the greens.
He's spent weeks on end in Florida, claiming he's been having meetings.
Working hard or hardly working, Mr President?

A post shared by Pete Souza (@petesouza) on

THE FIRST LADY
Mr Trump has had a few awkward moments with his First Lady, Melania.
Who could forget the time she snatched her hand away when he tried to hold it on the red carpet on arrival in Israel?
Or the time she moved her hand away to brush away her hair on the other side of her face when they disembarked from Air Force One in Rome?
It couldn't be further from the warm image portrayed by her predecessor.

Donald Trump arrives in Rome for a high-profile meeting with Pope Francis in what is his first official trip to Europe since becoming US President. His wife Melania doesn't seem too happy to hold his hand however.

Melania Trump pulls her hand away from Donald Trump's

A post shared by Pete Souza (@petesouza) on

COVFEFE
That was the tweet that took everyone by surprise, and disappeared almost as fast as it was bashed out late one night at the White House.
His tweet, shared at 12:06am on May 31, read: "Despite the constant negative press covfefe" and had experts around the world scratching their heads.
But while he was befuddling the masses on Twitter, this is how Mr Souza says Mr Obama typically spent his late nights in the Oval Office.

A post shared by Pete Souza (@petesouza) on

THE GRANDFATHER CLOCK
When former FBI Director James Comey gave evidence about his interactions with Donald Trump, he spent a lot of time describing where he was in the Oval Office.
It's a confusing room with a lot of doors, but there's a big grandfather clock on one side of the room, and Comey made sure to mention it. A lot.
So while Trump was trying to claim meetings never happened, and that issues were never discussed, Mr Souza focused on the details.
WIRE-TAPPING
The President's repeated, and unfounded, claims that Mr Obama's administration tapped the phones at Trump Tower in New York City made headlines in March.
Among the wild allegations was a suggestion Mr Obama was able to spy on Mr Trump using electrical devices such as his microwave.
Pete Souza didn't create this image himself, but he was more than happy to share it with his 1.5 million followers for a bit of a laugh.

Terrible! Just found out that Obama had my "wires tapped" in Trump Tower just before the victory. Nothing found. This is McCarthyism!
WOMEN
Mr Trump had a go at MSNBC hosts Mika Brzezinski and Joe Scarborough for painting him in an unflattering light, focusing his attack on Brzezinski in particular.
He claimed she had been "bleeding badly from a face-lift" during a visit to his Florida mansion, Mar-A-Lago, in a series of misogynistic swipes.
Members of his own party slammed the tweets - Republican Senator Lindsey Graham writing: "Please just stop. This isn't normal and it's beneath the dignity of your office".
You stay classy, Pete Souza.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday Night Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Scarborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mar-a-Lago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete Souza</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GRANDFATHER CLOCK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Uhlmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope Francis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Tower</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIRE-TAPPING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSNBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Lady</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melania Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Patten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COVFEFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Senator Lindsey Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCarthyism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump's Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brzezinski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mika Brzezinski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI Director James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Force One</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Souza</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Obama</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
