<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401765698301225</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:23</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/leadership/investors-target-overloaded-directors-20170728-gxkj0v</url>
  <title>Investors target overloaded directors</title>
  <content>
Investors and proxy advisory firms will take aim at overloaded directors this annual shareholder meeting season, and plan to vote against directors sitting on more boards than they can handle.
this year and while gender and  are rising in prominence, investors expect that "overboarded" directors could become one of the hottest issues of this AGM season, as professional non-executive directors swell in numbers.
Last year, the major proxy firms that advise many super funds and shareholders which way to vote, declared open season on "overloaded" directors such as Woolworths and Origin chairman Gordon Cairns,  and Aurizon and McMillan Shakespeare chairman Tim Poole, after investor pressure forced Suncorp and NBN chairman .
The Australian Shareholders Association warned it will target directors who take on more than five listed boards and US proxy firms ISS and Glass Lewis have adjusted their policies, warning of an "explosion" in the amount of time it takes to sit on a top listed board .

Ten years ago, all boards had audit committees but now many have a separate remuneration committee, a risk committee and a sustainability committee. Most airline boards have a specific safety committee.

Analysis undertaken by recruitment firm Korn Ferry calculates that a listed company board will take a commitment of at least 31 days, including board meetings, sub-committees, strategy days and site visits.
Rule of five

"When we are searching for NEDs we do look at the number of listed and non-listed boards they serve on but also the complexity of those boards and the complexity of their roles. If the company is expanding or going through a period of major change the time commitment might also increase. Chairing a board also takes more time," executive chairman of Korn Ferry Australasia Katie Lahey says.
"NEDs are devoting more time to their board roles than they would have done previously and are limited to the number of boards they can sit on due to the demands of the role," Ms Lahey says. "Time pressures occur when one of the boards involves work that is transactional or an issue occurs. If this happens with two boards concurrently it can be very time-consuming to manage. We always advise directors to build spare capacity into their portfolios so they can comfortably respond to an event with their boards."

The ASA rule of five listed boards is generally considered to equate to four listed, plus two not-for-profits boards. However, being appointed chairman of the board is considered to be the equivalent of two NED roles. Major proxy firms ISS and Glass Lewis have also adjusted their policies.
"Citing an explosion in the time commitment needed for board service, both ISS and Glass Lewis have lowered from six to five the maximum number of directorships a director may have before being considered overboarded."
NEDs on the rise

The focus on "overboarded'' directors comes as research by the  showed that professional NEDs are on the rise.

Multiple board seats were held by 182 directors across the top 200 listed companies with most, 126, holding two board seats. Fifty directors held three board seats - a more than 60 per cent increase over two years.
Four held four board seats and three of them were women - Maxine Brenner, Rebecca McGrath, Margaret Seale and Gene Tilbrook - while two directors, Trevor Gerber and Linda Nicholls, each held five board seats.
Nicholls is chair of Japara Healthcare, as well as a director of Medibank Private, Fairfax Media, Sigma Pharmaceuticals and recently retired from Pacific Brands (since relinquished, following its acquisition). She is also a director of the Olivia Newton-John Cancer Research Institute and Inghams chicken.
Gerber was chair of Sydney Airports Group, and a director at CIMIC Group, Regis Healthcare, Tassal Group and Federation Centres.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation Centres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glass Lewis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurizon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regis Healthcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Shareholders Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korn Ferry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medibank Private</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia Newton-John Cancer Research Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CIMIC Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Nicholls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airports Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Poole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japara Healthcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Brands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maxine Brenner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gene Tilbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korn Ferry Australasia Katie Lahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Seale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassal Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEDs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McMillan Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Gerber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sigma Pharmaceuticals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
