<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401190172671723</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/perth-dad-home-after-bungled-bali-operation/news-story/4f13aa8c16718524612fd6ca6de62ef6</url>
  <title>Perth dad home after Bali surgery nightmare</title>
  <content>
A FATHER who went into cardiac arrest while undergoing routine hernia surgery in Bali is now being treated in Perth.
Steven Didmon is in Fiona Stanley Hospital after his family raised enough money to get the 39-year-old on a mercy flight on Sunday.
"He's awake, he's not communicating at the moment though," Mr Didmon's sister Fiona Vojnovic said.
"He's signalling, he can understand us but he's very sleepy, very sedated.
"We're relieved just knowing he's here (in Perth) and he's in the best care possible."
Mr Didmon suffered what doctors have described as an extremely rare medical complication, and is now facing close to $100,000 in medical bills.
The 39-year-old was given an epidural at the Bali hospital moments before he went into cardiac arrest.
According to Australian medical figures, six in every one million epidurals end in complications.
Mr Didmon's family say he had no choice but to undergo the operation in Bali, given the procedure would have cost him $20,000 with a six-month delay, due to his ineligibility for Medicare.
"We're still being hounded by the Indonesian hospital for payments to continue, we're still trying to piece it together," Ms Vojnovic said.

Doctors are unsure if Mr Didmon has sustained any permanent damage.
So far, the family's GofundMe page has raised more than $32,000 in eight days.
*gofundme link*
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Vojnovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Didmon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Didmon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Stanley Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Vojnovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
