<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401447870714520</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/funding-cuts-mean-nursing-home-residents-receiving-minimal-care-20170731-gxmkrq.html</url>
  <title>Funding cuts mean nursing home residents receiving minimal care</title>
  <content>
Already stretched staff in nursing homes across south-east Queensland are preparing for further cuts, as one of the state's not-for-profit providers restructures due to a reduction in funding.
Residents say the phrase "sorry, we're just so short-staffed" is commonly heard in Southern Cross Care Queensland nursing homes, as staff run around trying to respond to every resident buzzer call for assistance.
However, SCCQ CEO Peter Bell said the concerns of staff and residents were being heard and addressed during consultation sessions and acknowledged that it was a stressful time for everyone in the organisation.
In early June, staff at the organisation's 11 centres were told by management that .
The Queensland Nurses and Midwives Union said almost 2000 nursing hours were going to be cut across four of the facilities, with more information regarding the other seven centres yet to be released by SCCQ.
Staff and residents were concerned by these cuts, with resident care already being impacted.

A resident at one of SCCQ's facilities in south-east Queensland, who wished to remain anonymous, said she had been woken in the night by cockroaches.
"Three nights in a row I woke with cockroaches crawling across my face, they reckon they fly in off the balcony," she said.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The maintenance man came and sprayed after the first time, but they have now organised for professional pest control."
The resident, who had been in the aged care facility since May, said she had been left "disappointed" as her the aged care facility was "supposed to be one of the better ones".
"When they do the walk-through they tell you the care is top-notch, but I have been left waiting sometimes 25 or 30 minutes after calling for assistance and sometimes staff don't come at all," the resident said.
"Staff don't have time to give that personal patient-nurse care, they only have time to come in, rush through and get out."
"Other residents feel the same, every day we hear 'sorry, we're just so short-staffed'.
"The staff who are here do work hard, but there just doesn't seem to be enough hands."
Meanwhile, a manager at another south-east Queensland facility, who also wished to remain anonymous, raised concerns about the inability of staff to dispense medication 24/7 as a result of the roster realignment.
Only registered and enrolled nurses are able to distribute medication, and the manager accused the SCCQ directors of "wanting to do away" with them.
"Morphine can't be given to people who are dying with no registered nurses on shifts and families need to be advised."
She also said that management were trying to demote registered and enrolled nurses to personal carers to cut costs, and that the implementation dates had been scheduled after independent audits, to ensure the changes would not put the accreditation of the facilities at risk.
In response, Mr Bell said Southern Cross Care Queensland had investigated the pest control regime and ensured that centres were regularly treated for cockroaches.
Staff had been made aware of the sightings and appropriate processes had been implemented to minimise the risk of this happening again.
He added that a new buzzer system had also been implemented for residents to use when needing assistance, due to reported problems with the previous system.
"Ghost calls were being received and some calls were not going out to all phones," he said.
"Technicians came to investigate the problems, and are now monitoring on a weekly basis, with new programs also in place to educate staff about how to use the new system effectively."
Mr Bell went on to say that the organisation was hearing the concerns of staff and residents regarding current nursing numbers.
"We have also reviewed current staffing levels after the consultation process, and additional hours are being put back in as a result," he said.
"We plan to have registered and enrolled nurses working on every shift, but depending on staffing levels we might have to have some nurses on-call rather than being at the facilities themselves."
He also added that the changes were being implemented after the independent audits to minimise staffing stress.
"We know that the accreditation process can be stressful, so we didn't want to throw too much at staff at one time, so we had a break between accreditation and the realignment as part of our methodology for managing change.
"We are also providing a senior leadership team to support staff and management with the implementation of these changes. A fresh set of eyes might be able to see if something can be done more efficiently and they are also there to hear concerns which are raised."
.
 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Nurses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midwives Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Cross Care Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCCQ CEO Peter Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCCQ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
