<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401370561301844</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/environment/utter-stupidity-greens-attack-cokes-role-in-nsw-container-scheme-20170731-gxmh5u.html</url>
  <title>'Utter stupidity': Greens attack Coke's role in NSW container scheme </title>
  <content>
The decision by the Berejiklian government to award a major role in the state's container deposit scheme to Coca-Cola Amatil and other companies opposed to it was an act of stupidity, the NSW Greens say.
The program aimed at paying for waste containers will be co-ordinated by the Exchange for Change consortium, which includes big beverage suppliers CCA, Carlton & United Breweries, Asahi, Coopers and Lion Nathan, the government said over the weekend.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Greenpeace targets Coke over recycling scheme

A Greenpeace video mimicking a Coke ad calls for support for a proposed NSW container deposit scheme, which is being opposed by Coca-Cola Amatil.

TOMRA-Cleanaway will be the network operator of about 800 reverse vending machines to be rolled out across NSW, the first of their kind in Australia. People depositing eligible containers between 150 millilitres and 3 litres will be able to collect 10¢ each, a potential boon for community groups and others.
But Mehreen Faruqi questioned the choice of the winning tender, noting the beverage industry had lobbied hard against the program proposed by former premier Mike Baird.

"It is utterly stupid to put the fox in charge of the hen house," Dr Faruqi said. "Big beverage companies like Coca-Cola have no interest in reducing litter or increasing recycling rates and will only work to sabotage and undermine the scheme. 
"The whole integrity of the container deposit scheme sits with the independence of the scheme co-ordinator. The Greens and other environment groups have consistently called for an independent third party to run the scheme."

A spokesman for CCA dismissed the criticism as "unfair", adding it was "completely behind" the NSW CDS.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"We have an incentive to keep the scheme as cost-effective as possible," the spokesman said, adding that the company had decades of experience in recycling and deposit programs in places such as South Australia.Photo: Viki Lascaris
CCA used recycled bottles for more than half the material used in new bottles, and recycled about 62 per cent of the aluminium it used in its cans, he said.
Environment Minister Gabrielle Upton said the scheme would be a "convenient and rewarding scheme for everybody".Photo: Joe Armao
"This is the biggest initiative to tackle litter in the state's history and it will make a massive difference to the amount of rubbish on our streets, parks and waterways right across NSW," Ms Upton said in a media statement.
The Exchange for Change consortium "will have defined and limited responsibilities and will not set the scheme price or service level", a spokesman for Ms Upton said, adding the NSW Environment Protection Authority would be responsible for regulating the scheme's operation, not the co-ordinator.
"Exchange for Change will be held to strict performance requirements including ensuring payments are made on time and flow through the scheme correctly, there is high community awareness of the scheme and the containers are verified to ensure the integrity of the scheme," he said.
Last year, activist group , stating the company had sought to undermine such deposit schemes in Australia and elsewhere.
"It was Coke that took the Northern Territory government to court over their introduction of a container deposit scheme and, in documents from global Coca-Cola, they make it clear opposing container deposit schemes is something every country should push for," Greenpeace campaigner Nathaniel Pelle said at the time.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Breweries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cokes</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asahi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Upton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenpeace</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coca Cola Amatil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Armao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Gabrielle Upton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lion Nathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Faruqi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coopers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Greens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Environment Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coca-Cola</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW CDS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Viki Lascaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOMRA-Cleanaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mehreen Faruqi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathaniel Pelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
