<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400283934555857</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/game-of-thrones-creators-confederate-project-is-controversial/8760386</url>
  <title>Confederate: The next project from the Game of Thrones creators is proving controversial</title>
  <content>
At this point, all we really know about the TV show Confederate is the name, the basic premise, and the fact that the writers of Game Of Thrones are involved.
But some people are worried that the show will exploit the historical wounds of African-Americans, and they want HBO to put a stop to it before it goes any further.
What do we know about Confederate?

On July 19, HBO announced that once Game Of Thrones had wrapped up, production would begin on an original new series called Confederate.
The show would tell the story of the lead-up to the Third American Civil War, in an alternative timeline in which the southern states of America have seceded and slavery remains legal.
This is how HBO described the show:
"The story follows a broad swath of characters on both sides of the Mason-Dixon Demilitarized Zone - freedom fighters, slave hunters, politicians, abolitionists, journalists, the executives of a slave-holding conglomerate and the families of people in their thrall."
The show is the creation of Game Of Thrones showrunners David Benioff and DB Weiss, with Nichelle Spellman (The Good Wife) and Malcolm Spellman (Empire) also on board as executive producers and writers.
The final season of Game Of Thrones might not air until 2019, which means we're probably a long way from watching Confederate.
Why were people protesting today?

At 11:00am this morning, you may have started seeing a bunch of tweets or Facebook posts using the #NoConfederate.
Activist and former lawyer April Reign, who was also behind the  hashtag, timed the campaign to coincide with this week's episode of Game of Thrones going to air in America:

External Link:

@ReignOfApril tweet: We believe the time to speak up is now, before the show has been written or cast. Before @hbo invests too much money into #Confederate.
She said the best chance of success was to send a message to HBO before the show progresses any further. The campaign quickly went viral:

External Link:

@bonnesauvage tweet: "decent ppl: slavery, a stain upon humanity, should never be depicted for cheap entertainment  hbo: yes but what if"
What have people got against a show that hasn't been made yet?

For starters, it's because two white men have been given the greenlight to tell a story about slavery:

External Link:

Roxane Gay tweet: "It is exhausting to think of how many people at @HBO said yes to letting two white men envision modern day slavery. And offensive."
But many are concerned by writers Benioff and Weiss in particular as a result of Game of Thrones.
The show has often been criticised for its lack of diversity, and many see it as perpetuating racist stereotypes as well as the "white saviour" narrative.

External Link:

@roqabyebaby tweet: "That Khaleesi thing where she tames the savage Dothraki and frees the slaves was just a warm up, eh, Benihoff & Weiss?"

External Link:

@TheNerdsofColor tweet: "One (of many) reasons why Benioff & Weiss shouldn't be allowed to do a show about slavery"
How have the writers defended Confederate?

Nichelle and Malcolm Spellman are African American, and Malcolm says they were brought on to the project because Benioff and Weiss "knew they needed black voices".
"For me and Nichelle, it's deeply personal because we are the offspring of this history. We deal with it directly and have for our entire lives," he told Vulture.
"As people of colour and minorities in general are starting to get a voice, I think there's a duty to force this discussion."
Nichelle said when they sat down to the discuss the idea, they joked that it was "going to be a black Game of Thrones spin-off".
For his part, Weiss told Vulture that slavery was "our original sin as a nation".
"It's an ugly and a painful history, but we all think this is a reason to talk about it, not a reason to run from it. And this feels like a potentially valuable way to talk about it," he said.
Has HBO said anything yet?

Yes, the network said it's confident the show will be written with "care and sensitivity".
"The project is currently in its infancy so we hope that people will reserve judgment until there is something to see."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weiss</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TheNerdsofColor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April Reign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Empire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NoConfederate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nichelle Spellman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African-American</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mason-Dixon Demilitarized Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Third American Civil War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benioff</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxane Gay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benihoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Spellman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Confederate</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dothraki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Good Wife</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DB Weiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vulture</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nichelle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Benioff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaleesi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ReignOfApril</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
