<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400206625143095</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/mums-fear-after-rare-2kg-tumour-removed/3207125/</url>
  <title>Mum's fear after rare 2kg tumour removed</title>
  <content>
SIMONE Boulton may have survived a one-in-a-million cancer that had surgeons removing a 2kg tumour, but she and her family still face life in limbo.
The Buderim mum of two was first diagnosed in February with Adrenocortical carcinoma, a cancer that affects only one in a million people.
Mrs Boulton had her kidney, part of her liver, her adrenal gland and gallbladder removed earlier this year, but her trials are far from over, with six chemotherapy tablets a day, regular blood tests, CT scans every six months and more doctor and surgeon check-ups to catch the cancer if it returns.
"I think the worst thing is the unknown," Mrs Boulton said.
"They don't know if it's going to come back, they don't know where it's going to come back.
"It could come back in the bones, or the lungs, or whatever, they're not sure."
Mrs Boulton worked as much as she could at the Maroochydore Newsagency during the treatment process, but medical costs have eaten away the Buderim family's savings.
"We're lucky we had money saved," she said.
The family has put off their home renovations for fear the cancer will return, bringing with it expensive medical bills.
Mrs Boulton said she only realised something was wrong when she became dizzy and ill over a weekend, and mentioned it to her doctor the next week during an appointment for her daughter.
An ultrasound came back clear, but a further CT scan revealed a black mass on her side.
Doctors first believed the mass was an abscess, but an MRI scan finally revealed the truth.
"This beautiful surgeon at the private hospital sat me down," Mrs Boulton said.
"She just looked at me and she held my hand, and she just said, 'I have got some bad news.'"

Mrs Boulton had a massive tumour growing in her adrenal gland, a major artery and encroaching into her liver and kidneys, the doctor told her.
"She said, 'We need to get it out, quick-smart,'" Mrs Boulton said.
After working the following week, Mrs Boulton went straight into major surgery.
The surgery left her with a "train track" scar and an ongoing radiotherapy and chemotherapy schedule.
Radiation alone cost $1500 every week for five weeks.
Mrs Boulton said she was determined to see the treatment though, for her daughters.
"It's very daunting for a two-year-old and a five-year-old to see their mum like that," she said.
Mrs Boulton's sister Claire Glasson will face her own fear in a skydive this Saturday at Mount Coolum to help raise awareness and funds for the Boulton family.
Ms Glasson has set up a GoFundMe page for donations.
Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
Marilyn Freeman won Toastmasters International Speech district event
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boulton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrenocortical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Boulton</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Glasson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Glasson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIMONE Boulton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Newsagency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters International Speech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
