<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401443575747172</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/police-and-council-crack-down-on-feral-cat-feeders-20170731-gxmi4v.html</url>
  <title>Police and council crack down on feral cat feeders</title>
  <content>
Residents allegedly attempting to interfere with suspected feral cats have been warned by Queensland Police and Brisbane City Council to stop, or face criminal charges.  
More than 400 residents have become members of a Facebook group, , as they believe cats are trapped underneath a recently-enclosed building at Coopers Plains.
It is understood residents visit the area on Boundary Road and leave food and water for the animals they believe to not be feral.
Since 2011, the council has received 29 separate complaints from business owners and residents about feral cats in Coopers Plains.Photo: Supplied
In the past year, 49 cats were captured in Coopers Plains as part of the council's feral animal trapping program.
Residents appear to be working against the council animal trapping program and have taken matters into their own hands.
Animal activist Lyn Laskus, a member of the Facebook group, said residents were concerned about the welfare of the cats.

"They call them crazy cat people, that's the tag they get for them," she said.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"But all they are is concerned for the welfare of cats.
"What they [residents] want to do is get the remaining cats behind the shopping centre to get them rehomed and not destroyed.
"Council are not sending cats off to be rehomed, they are actually trapping them and destroying them."
As a result of residents trying to rescue cats, a 49-year-old Acacia Ridge man is facing two counts of wilful damage after he allegedly attended an address on Boundary Road between 10.45pm on July 20 and midnight of July 21 and damaged a concrete block wall.
It is understood the man believed cats had been trapped underneath the building and he had been trying to free them.
Acacia Ridge Police Sergeant Kylie Doyle told Fairfax Media the man also allegedly smashed a window to a different building to look for cats late July 23 and early July 24.
Sergeant Doyle said police had also seen the man feeding cats in the area on July 17, which was reported to the council.
The man was located at midnight on July 26, while feeding the cats, and arrested by police on the two wilful damage charges.
The man is due to appear in Holland Park Magistrates court on August 31.
"The actual feeding the cats isn't a police matter," Sergeant Doyle said.
"It's wasted a lot of our time because we're assisting the council and then he's actions have now led to criminal activity as wilful damage is a crime.
"What he thinks is doing a good thing in feeding feral cats, it's actually now lead to a crime."
Sergeant Doyle said it was an offence under the council's local laws to feed a feral animal.
"We don't want to encourage it, we don't want anyone else to take up where he's left off," he said.
"The council is removing the cats humanely in the interest of public safety...we don't want anyone to start feeding the cats it's just going to keep escalating the problem."
Both the council and police are able to commence proceedings in court, and the man was already facing council-ordered proceedings in the Holland Park Magistrates Court.
Police said the man last appeared in court on March 17 where he was given conditions by the council to not go to the area or feed the cats.
A council spokesman confirmed the man was facing two charges under the Land Protection (Pest and Stock Route Management) Act, 2002, for allegedly feeding a declared pest animal without reasonable excuse.
"Feral cats spread disease and threaten native wildlife, including endangered species," the spokesman said.
"Feral cats are declared as pests under the state government's Biosecurity Act and are required to be euthanised once captured.
"In the past year, one cat captured at this site was identified as a domestic cat and was rehomed.
"Council is aware that some residents have been interfering with trapping programs, including interfering with traps and providing food to pest animals. 
"Feeding declared pest animals is an offence under the Biosecurity Act 2014 and anyone caught can be charged."
RSPCA Queensland spokesman Michael Beatty said one cat was taken from the Coopers Plains area to its Wacol facility on Saturday after residents alleged it was caught in a trap.
It was unclear if it was a trap set by council or by a resident.
Ms Laskus said the residents trying to help the cats had an undeserving reputation.
"It has all got out of hand because there are people on council who are definite cat haters...the council has a big thing where they trap the cats and kill them," she said.
"There has to be an ethical solution."
Ms Laskus suggested the introduction of a neuter and release policy for Brisbane.
A discussion paper by the RSPCA, Identifying Best Practice Cat Management in Australia, has suggested several recommendations for how to improve the management of both domestic and feral cats in Australia. 
Residents can make a submission on the recommendations within the paper until August 3.
Anyone concerned about feral cats can contact the council on (073403 8888.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland Park Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Doyle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Practice Cat Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coopers Plains.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acacia Ridge Police Sergeant Kylie Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland Park Magistrates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boundary Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biosecurity Act 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stock Route Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Laskus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wacol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Beatty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Land Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biosecurity Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acacia Ridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyn Laskus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coopers Plains</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
