<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400679071554145</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/through-his-passion-for-football-les-murrary-helped-australia-fall-in-love-with-the-world-game/news-story/164f8ccd91d0b15f2f0f2a4470401fc0</url>
  <title>Murray helped us fall in love with football</title>
  <content>
LES Murray used to call it the "mission" that defined his entire life: from schoolyard arguments to World Cup finals, he wanted Australia to fall in love with football.
Some people come to embody the soul of the sport they portray, and Murray was one of them. Just as Ray Warren is the essence of rugby league, it was no coincidence that Murray was always known as Mr Football.
VALE LES MURRAY:
TRIBUTE TO LES MURRAY:
But the sport lost one of its greatest ambassadors on Monday when Lowy died following a battle with illness. He was 71.
For 35 years on SBS, sporting a long line of natty ties and glasses, he gave Australians who loved football a place to congregate each week and watch the best of the action from around the world. At the start it was a time, as Socceroos coach Ange Postecoglou has recalled, when loving football in Australia wasn't always easy.
The extent to which Murray succeeded can be gauged by the generations of fans born since who, in his own words, have little concept of how hostile an environment it was back then.
Unlike his soulmate on screen, Johnny Warren, Murray lived to see Australia qualify for not just one World Cup but three, and establish a mainstream and popular domestic football league.
"I'm happy with where things are," he said on the day of his last World Cup broadcast just three years ago.
The announcement of his death on Monday is partly so shocking precisely because he was on air that day from a studio overlooking Copacabana Beach, and it seems like such a short time ago.
Earlier this year he sat with a group of us in the football media to announce he would be the face of a consortium seeking to add a third Sydney team to the A-League.
The way he talked that day, and the plans he outlined, just added to the assumption that Les would be around for ever.
From the outset, Murray used to say, he simply couldn't understand why anyone wouldn't love football. He tried to convince his Wollongong classmates as an 11-year-old immigrant from Hungary, and never really stopped over the decades that followed.
SBS gave him a platform to do that, by broadcasting beautiful football from all over the globe.
He called it the "world game" for good reason, seeking to open the nation's eyes to what he liked to call the only true global language. His partnership with Johnny Warren was a powerful one, a man whom Murray said could translate football into a language that Australians understood.
Perhaps it was inevitable that Murray would begin to find himself moving in the upper circles of the game he championed so vocally. He was close to the president of FIFA for 30 years, Sepp Blatter, and served on the ethics committee that was meant to keep the scandal-plagued FIFA honest - though Murray himself at times seemed almost bewildered by the breadth of allegations of corruption mounting up against executives.
But it's as a weekly visitor to lounge rooms up and down the country that he will be remembered.
In 2006, as the Socceroos prepared for their first game at a World Cup in 32 years, he described the players emerging "to feel the sun" of a German afternoon.
Today it's Murray's memory that feels the sun.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sepp Blatter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Copacabana Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VALE LES MURRAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ange Postecoglou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
