<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400163675469428</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/breaking-cq-coal-miner-wicet-part-owner-liquidated/3207093/</url>
  <title>BREAKING: CQ coal miner, WICET part owner liquidated</title>
  <content>
CALEDON Coal, the owner of Cook Colliery mine and a part-owner of Wiggins Island Coal Export terminal was placed into liquidation today.

Administrators PPB Advisory confirmed this afternoon that all five companies in the Caledon Coal Group (Caledon Coal Pty Ltd), CC Pty Ltd, Guangdong Rising (Australia) Pty Ltd, Blackwater Coal Pty Ltd and Bowen Basin Pastoral Company) were placed into liquidation.

RELATED |

Liquidation possible for struggling CQ coal miner

The Cook Colliery mine owner and Wiggins Island Coal Export Terminal part-owner was placed into administration earlier this year with a debt of about $4billion.

Two of the main reasons for the administration were the significant water damage to the mine's longwall on March 7 and ongoing payments for its share in owning WICET.

A request for a 45-day extension earlier this month for the next meeting was rejected by creditors.

The last meeting was due on July 17 but instead it was adjourned until this morning.

Administrators PPB Advisory recommended placing the company in liquidation.

Caledon Coal owes its employees $22million and WICET more than $24million, according to the report.

There are concerns WICET and its miner owners are unable to repay nearly $4 billion to 19 lenders under the original contract.

The company's failure forced 180 workers into redundancy from the Cook Colliery mine.

A creditor's report said Caledon workers - believed to be senior management - would receive their full entitlements and Cook Colliery workers would receive 52c in the dollar.

Councillor says Sippy Downs needs more developments like it
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
Marilyn Freeman won Toastmasters International Speech district event
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
*WARNING this story contains spoilers*
An upcoming concert will raise funds for Cittamani Hospice
Latest woman eliminated from The Bachelor says she "hates" Matty J.
There's little chance The Block will be returning to Sydney
The singer's most recent tweet proves why he has so many fans.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARCH 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WICET</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caledon Coal Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook Colliery</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITTAMANI Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CALEDON Coal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caledon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guangdong Rising</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CC Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackwater Coal Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marilyn Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caledon Coal Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiggins Island Coal Export Terminal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPB Advisory</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toastmasters International Speech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiggins Island Coal Export</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen Basin Pastoral Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
