<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401370561301813</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>11:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/ten-inmates-captured-after-12-escaped-from-alabama-prison/news-story/a7336bf70a3b3a1ec7113a976433de1a</url>
  <title>Alabama jailbirds' daring prison break</title>
  <content>
THERE is a mass manhunt underway for prisoners who escaped from an Alabama jail.
A dozen jailbirds escaped on Sunday night and 10 of them have now been captured.
According to , Walker County Jail officials said 12 prisoners made a brazen escape from the prison about 9.30pm local time but it has not been revealed how they managed to flee the prison.
Two are still on the run including Christopher Michael Smith, a 19-year-old jailed for attempted murder, first-degree burglary, unlawful breaking and entering and second-degree theft.
Brady Andrew Kilpatrick, 24, jailed for the possession of a controlled substance, drug paraphernalia and marijuana is also on the run.
Police were also searching for Larry Inman Jr, 29, jailed for two counts of receiving stolen property, and Ethan Pearl, 24, jailed for resisting arrest, obstructing government operations, the possession of drug paraphernalia and promoting prison contraband. They were the last to be captured.
The other eight escapees were captured by police about two hours after their jail break.
Police wrote on Facebook a $500 reward is being offered for information that leads to an arrest of the escapees.
The Jasper Police Department wrote on Facebook that additional officers were looking for the rest of the escapees.
"We ask that downtown residents stay indoors and turn on all outdoor lighting," the post said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ethan Pearl, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Inman Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker County Jail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jasper Police Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Michael Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brady Andrew Kilpatrick, 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alabama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
