<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651400984014237870</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/gladys-berejiklian-faces-another-byelection-test-after-katrina-hodgkinson-quits-20170731-gxmhg4.html</url>
  <title>Berejiklian faces another byelection test after Hodgkinson quits</title>
  <content>
Premier Gladys Berejiklian faces yet another byelection within weeks, after Nationals MP Katrina Hodgkinson announced her retirement from Parliament.
Ms Hodgkinson informed the Nationals party room of her decision on Monday, putting it down to a "length-of-service" decision.Photo: Katherine Griffiths
Ms Hodgkinson has been in the Parliament for 18 years, including as the minister for small business and the first female minister for primary industries.
Last year she was an outspoken opponent of the government's aborted bid to ban greyhound racing.
Ms Hodgkinson's seat of Cootamundra is held on a margin of 20.4 per cent, but the Nationals will be nervous about a challenge from the Shooters, Fishers and Farmers Party, which took the seat of Orange from the party in a byelection last year.
"It's been a really challenging couple of years," Ms Hodgkinson told Fairfax Media.

"Every government faces its share of issue. It's wonderful to be in government but I feel the time is right to undertake some succession planning within the seat of Cootamundra and I would hope that as many members as possible who think they can do the job the community expects of them put their names forward to be preselected."
Ms Hodgkinson said any suggestion her decision was a vote of no confidence in Nationals leader John Barilaro or Ms Berejiklian was "blatantly untrue".

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I've had several discussions with both Gladys and John about this," she said. "They have both been very kind, because this is not an easy decision. Gladys and John have both been very generous."
Mr Barilaro said Ms Hodgkinson had worked tirelessly for her electorate.
"I thank her sincerely for the work she has done in her electorates of both Burrinjuck and Cootamundra, and wish her all the very best for the future," he said.
Ms Hodgkinson predicted "a Melbourne Cup field" would line up for preselection, noting the electorate covers 35,000 square kilometres. 
Shooters, Fishers and Farmers MP Robert Borsak said the party would be announcing a candidate shortly.
"We look forward to a byelection in the seat of Cootamundra," he said.
"We know it will be hotly contested and we're certainly going to put every effort into it as we did in the seat of Orange and hope to be successful."
The decision follows two byelections in the seats of North Sydney and Manly earlier this year, which saw significant swings against the government.
Ms Hodgkinson will leave parliament at the end of August.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hodgkinson</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burrinjuck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cootamundra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmers MP Robert Borsak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Barilaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmers Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Barilaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodgkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals MP Katrina Hodgkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
