<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401529475094941</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/nsw-government-offers-140m-deal-for-new-powerhouse-museum-site-in-parramatta-20170731-gxm8bd</url>
  <title>NSW government offers $140m deal for new Powerhouse Museum site in Parramatta  </title>
  <content>
Sydney's Parramatta Council has offered the former David Jones car park site in Parramatta to the NSW government for the construction of the new Powerhouse Museum in return for a package deal worth $140 million.
The government's $140 million will pay for the site, provide a $40 million fund to promote arts and culture in the community over the next 20 years and pay for a $100 million redevelopment of the Riverside Theatre directly opposite, across the Parramatta River. The government will also take a 50 per cent interest in the Riverside Theatre redevelopment, as a equal joint-venture partner with the council.
The government will separately fund the construction of the new Powerhouse Museum but the cost of the project has not been finalised.
The car park sits adjacent to the old David Jones building now owned by Meriton and home to its Altitude high-rise 57-level residential project at 330 Church Street.

Meriton once owned a 50-year lease over the 520-space car park, purchased in late 2010, but has since relinquished the lease in 2015 as part of its Altitude project voluntary planning agreement with council.

Site 'locked in'

Premier Gladys Berejiklian said the $140 million agreement has secured the best deal for the new museum.
"The relocated Powerhouse Museum in Parramatta will be the anchor for arts and culture for the region, and now the site for the museum is locked in," Ms Berejiklian said.
The NSW government announced in 2014 it would move the Powerhouse Museum or the Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences to Parramatta but had run into delays amid objections from the public including high-profile elites such as actress Cate Blanchett and former NSW premier Bob Carr.

With the move now certain, the government will consult with the community on the development of the new museum and undertake a business case to determine the future of its current Ultimo site, long eyed by residential developers for its prime position.
, and is already in private discussions with the government to buy the site for a campus expansion.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Church Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverside Theatres</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Parramatta Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Carr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meriton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultimo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Powerhouse Museum</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Museum of Applied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cate Blanchett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
