<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401147222997941</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>10:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/residential/vic/stockland-beefs-up-townhome-pipeline-in-melbourne-20170731-gxm84k</url>
  <title>Stockland beefs up townhome pipeline in Melbourne</title>
  <content>
Stockland has taken its investment in future Melbourne townhome sites to $110 million this year after acquiring a 6.3-hectare industrial land parcel in Altona North with plans for 276 townhomes.
The land parcel, comprising two neighbouring sites at  278-288 Blackshaws Road and 8-38 Kyle Road in Altona North in the city's south west, was snapped up for $48 million. In March, Stockland paid $62 million for a 11.5-hectare site in Braybrook with capacity for 422 townhomes. 
"This acquisition in Altona North supports our strategy to grow our portfolio of new townhomes close to the Melbourne CBD. This is another great site in a rapidly gentrifying middle-ring suburb of Melbourne that we'll transform into a highly liveable community," said Andrew Whitson, CEO of residential communities at Stockland.
"The Melbourne property market continues to outperform, driven by strong fundamentals, including high-net migration and strong employment."

Stockland, the country's biggest residential developer with an $18.2 billion pipeline of mainly outer-suburban land sub-divisions, has been beefing up its medium-density townhome (or townhouse) and apartment offering in recent times as it looks to offer a greater range of more affordable housing options.

Townhomes in its Braybrook development will be priced in the low-to-mid-$500,000s for an entry-level three-bedroom home.
The latest Melbourne acquisition - 10 kilometres from the Melbourne CBD - takes Stockland's future townhome pipeline to more than 2800 nationally. Five per cent of its townhomes will be offered as affordable housing.
The sites on Blackshaws Road and Kyle Road form part of the broader 67-hectare Precinct 15 urban renewal zone currently going through the rezoning process. It will include a 3800-square metre central park, a community centre, local town centre and a commercial precinct. 
The Blackshaws Road site was sold by logistics group Secon, while the Kyle Road site was offloaded by local Melbourne investors.

Subject to rezoning and development approval, Stockland plans to commence construction in early 2020. Ben Cantwell, Stockland's medium density manager, said Altona North would provide a range of options to suit first-home buyers, upgraders, downsizers and investors.
"We're very focused on providing a diverse range of homes in convenient locations and to contribute to the creation of much-needed affordable housing and key infrastructure for our future communities," Mr Cantwell said.
Over the last 12 months, Stockland has commenced construction on more than 600 townhomes in Brisbane, Sydney, Melbourne and Perth. 
Earlier in July it bought a  marking its first medium-density acquisition in Queensland.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braybrook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackshaws Road</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Precinct 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Road</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cantwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Cantwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Altona North</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Whitson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
