<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401757108366461</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/rear-window/elliott-not-cutting-through-to-retail-investors-20170728-gxkv0h</url>
  <title>Elliott Associates not cutting through to BHP's retail investors</title>
  <content>
BHP Billiton's New York-based corporate raiders, Elliott Associates, have been toiling away since April on their grand plan to fix the Big Australian, with a Crosby Textor-inspired website, social media and now billboards in our capital cities.
Given the media attention they've attracted (not least from this column) and the cling-on investment advisers they've enlisted, you'd reckon the broader public, for whom BHP is a household name, might have noticed the diversified miner is in play.
After all, Paul Singer and his merry band recently stunned corporate Australia by slapping big - and no doubt expensive - billboards in key locations in several of Australia's capital cities. Our favourite is the one on the corner of Flinders and Swanston street in Melbourne, which we understand several BHP execs have to pass on their way to the miner's Australian HQ.
But if the billboards aren't just aimed at rattling BHP execs and are actually intended to reach BHP's 600,000 Australian retail shareholders, which seems a reasonable assumption to us given their geographical spread, they don't appear to be cutting through.

According to an analysis by SimilarWeb of the  website - which the THINK SMART billboards reference - Elliott's big proposal for the Big Australian has received what can only be described as small audience figures. The site has attracted around 2000 visitors between April and July, despite a "petition" urging shareholders to sign up to stay informed about the campaign and despite advertising via Google Adchoices your columnists cannot seem to escape after typing 'BHP Elliott' into Google a few times to many. On audience, the site ranks a stunning 6,351,175th in the world on Monday, and 289,161th in Australia. We suggest they ditch the petitions and consider some cat videos!

The social media foray seems to be about as successful as the website. On Facebook, Elliott is advertising its Facebook page (23 fans, 26 followers last we checked) for the campaign. The ad has attracted a range of comments with the undisputed highlight coming from Facebook user "Brad Koala", according to his profile a BHP engineer, who responds succinctly to Elliott by urging the American raiders to simply "Fuck off !!!".
Still here's two pieces of indisputable good news for Singer. If much of the miner's conservative retail shareholders aren't interested, Elliott doesn't really need them. They're only a third of the register. And secondly, as we've previously pointed out, the high-profile campaign does seem to have been good for Elliott's funds under management - the firm's added  from investors keen on a slice of the activism since this whole thing started.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SimilarWeb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Adchoices</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian HQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliott Associates</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP's 600,000 Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliott</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crosby Textor-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Billiton's New York-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swanston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THINK SMART</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Singer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Koala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
