<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401971856735801</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/stephen-curry-kyrie-irving-lebron-james-workout-video-2017-7</url>
  <title>Stephen Curry and Kyrie Irving appeared to mock LeBron James' workout videos while dancing at a wedding</title>
  <content>
As a potential trade looms on the horizon, Kyrie Irving may not be improving his allegedly fractured relationship with LeBron James.

When Irving requested a trade from the Cleveland Cavaliers, he reportedly said he didn't want to play alongside James anymore.

While the particulars of James and Irving's relationship are unknown, it may have taken a hit when Irving appeared to enjoy a laugh at James' expense, courtesy of Stephen Curry.

Over the weekend, Curry and Irving attended the wedding for Dallas Mavericks forward Harrison Barnes. Video of the reception made its way to Instagram in which Curry appears to be mocking one of James' workout videos as Irving laughed alongside of him.

Here's Curry's "dance":

It features the same song as one of James' most recent Instagram videos:

It's unclear if any of this is meant as a shot at James or just good fun. After all, despite the rivalry between the Warriors and Cavs, most of the players seem to be on good terms.  shortly after the Finals, that even with some harsh insults, seemed to be in good fun. 

After news of Irving's trade demands were leaked, James took to Twitter to push back against the idea that he was mad at Irving.

However, given the state of the Cavs, perhaps there's a bit more to this roasting of James. He surely can't be happy about Irving having fun with Curry, whose Warriors just beat the Cavs. Additionally, there's already reportedly  among NBA stars, including James.

Again, perhaps it's all in good fun, but given the timing, it will be interesting to see if and how James responds.

Steph making fun of LeBron's workout video with Kyrie egging him on ???????????? (via ryanonlyryan/IG)
- Sports Illustrated (@SInow)

people! ????Boooo!! Get another source. ????????‍♂️.   ????????????
- LeBron James (@KingJames)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irving</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrison Barnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curry</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland Cavaliers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SInow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Mavericks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LeBron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebron James</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KingJames</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Curry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrie Irving</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cavs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
