<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401967561768369</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/jen-costello-josh-black-and-marcel-yammouni-to-perform-at-the-melbourne-guitar-show/news-story/b6552ea9c01586d9c6733ff9c15b6a97</url>
  <title>Trio strikes a chord for loudest show in town</title>
  <content>
MUSICIAN Jen Costello has come a long way - from playing the trombone at Donvale High School to supporting touring American punk singer Courtney Love in 2014.
After switching from brass to guitar at 16, Costello found a passion for grunge and punk rock.
Along with her band The Mercy Kills, she will be bringing her sound to the Melbourne Guitar Show this weekend.
Costello said being a support act for Love, once the wife of grunge icon Kurt Cobain, was her career highlight.
"I was a tomboy teenager in the '90s and was very into grunge, so getting the Courtney Love tour support gig in 2014 blew my mind," she said.
"I'm very influenced by alternative '80s and '90s bands such as the Cure, Nine Inch Nails and Sonic Youth, to name a few."
Costello said she started working with TMK singer and guitarist Mark E in 2004 and they have collaborated ever since, with The Mercy Kills line-up unchanged for eight years.
MARCEL TO RIP IT UP AT GUITAR FESTIVAL
GUITARIST Marcel Yammouni has worked tirelessly behind the scenes supporting famous artists such as Vanessa Amorosi, Pete Murray and Em Rusciano.
But now you can see the Diamond Creek muso take centre stage with drummer Andy Sylvio.
The duo, dubbed the Yammouni & Sylvio Project, have a warped sense of humour and passion for playing music that makes them a powerful unit.
"It's the guitar Olympics, that's how I'm looking at it," Yammouni said. "People will be standing around watching, thinking, I can do this better than that guy, so I need to be at the top of my game."
The pair's "progressive rock" sounds promise to take the audience on a musical journey into the depths of tranquillity one minute, then to a blaze of fiery, face-melting glory the next. Yammouni will be floating around the Caulfield Racecourse on the weekend, not only performing, but also doing a workshop for aspiring musicians.
The duo will perform at the Whammy Bar at the racecourse on Saturday, August 5, at 2.45pm.
STILL KILLING IT ON STAGE AFTER EIGHT YEARS
WHEN it comes to the alternative rock scene in Melbourne, The Mercy Kills are stalwarts.
Formed in 2009 when drummer Josh Black ran into vocalist and guitarist Mark E at a bucks night, Black said they had seen many other bands come and go.
Black said the bucks night was fortuitous timing, as Mark needed a drummer and he needed a band. The Mercy Kills, who have supported big acts such as Courtney Love, are looking forward to playing at the Melbourne Guitar Show this weekend.
Black, who has lived in Heidelberg since 2003, said while he played drums for The Mercy Kills, he also played guitar and loved the instrument.
He said the show would be an exciting event for guitar enthusiasts, with the opportunity to see live music and visit exhibits.
Black is also heavily involved with songwriting for The Mercy Kills. The 45-year-old said he had been playing music for 33 years and had no plans to stop.
He said working around a job in a factory on a packing line was sometimes tough and tiring, but the band always made time to rehearse each week and catch up to plan gigs for the future.
The Mercy Kills have already had a busy 2017.
They recently released an EP, End this Way, and have another one for later this year. They also released an LP on a French label this year, Paradise Motel, and will travel to France to play - the first time The Mercy Kills have played in that country.
"It is pretty awesome, we are building a bit of fan base over there," he said.
LOUDEST SHOW IN TOWN
The Melbourne Guitar Show features many talented artists from around the world, as well as Australian rock legend Diesel, who will take part in a clinic and a Q & A session.
Now in its third year, the Melbourne Guitar Show brings the latest in electric guitars, acoustic guitars, pedals, amps, accessories and technology all under one roof at Caulfield Racecourse on August 5 and 6.
There will be live performances and information seminars, and something for every guitar lover to enjoy.
The Mercy Kills will play on Sunday, August 6, at 1.30pm.
Details and tickets, click .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercy Kills</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtney Love</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARCEL TO RIP IT UP AT GUITAR FESTIVAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield Racecourse</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanessa Amorosi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcel Yammouni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paradise Motel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TMK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Cobain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonic Youth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costello</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Em Rusciano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Inch Nails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHOW IN TOWN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Sylvio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvio Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yammouni</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jen Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Guitar Show</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whammy Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donvale High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark E</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KILLING IT ON STAGE AFTER EIGHT YEARS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
