<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402006216475041</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/nab-dumps-sales-incentives-for-branch-managers-20170731-gxmhn1</url>
  <title>NAB dumps sales incentives for branch managers</title>
  <content>
Product sales will form a smaller part of the remuneration equation for NAB's frontline staff when a new incentive plan is rolled out from October 1, well ahead of the deadlines for reform recommended by the Sedgwick review.
The changes will see more than 700 National Australia Bank staff, including branch managers, assistant branch managers and call centre managers, move from their existing incentive programs, which rely on product sales, hard on the heels of a similar move at ANZ earlier this year.
The change will see NAB staff transition from a sales-based incentive system to a short-term incentive program almost identical to the one used to evaluate the performance of senior managers and executives.
NAB chief customer officer Andrew Hagger said the adjustment to incentive plans would better reflect the role of staff at the bank and place it at the forefront of remuneration reform going into the new financial year.

"Their reward now will not be as focused on product sales but rather on this balanced scorecard which includes outcomes, customer outcomes, risk outcomes and financial outcomes," Mr Haggar said.

The balanced scorecard is one of 21 recommendations from a review conducted by former Australian Public Service commissioner Stephen Sedgwick into banking remuneration systems for the Australian Bankers Association.
ANZ introduced a balanced scorecard for its retail banking branch and contact centre businesses in April in which financial performance relative to target accounted for 30 per cent and the remaining 70 per cent of the incentive was determined by customer outcomes, team work and measures of compliance.
The Sedgwick review was convened in a response to the perception that remunerating frontline banking staff for product sales was leading to poor customer outcomes.
. NAB has already implemented a recommendation to remove volume-based sales incentives for the broker channel.

Mr Haggar, who is approaching his first year in the chief customer officer role after a period as group executive for wealth, said he had no reservations about the change and pointed to the British experience where removing sales-based incentives for branch managers was a positive experience.
"What you found was that they embraced the change, they were being remunerated as business leaders and they embraced the fact that this [sales driven] perception was removed," he said.
Mr Hagger said in many cases the right outcome for both customers and the bank was achieved without a single product being sold but rather a deepening of the relationship that led to organic business growth. Mr Hagger said that over the next 12 months the bank would continue to review performance plans, incentives and team meeting structures.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sedgwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Sedgwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Haggar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hagger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hagger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bankers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Public Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
