<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402010511442425</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/the-naked-ceo-is-now-invisible-20170731-gxm9ag</url>
  <title>The naked CEO Alex Malley is now invisible</title>
  <content>
CPA Australia's monthly magazine, INTHEBLACK (their capitalisation, not ours), has a long history of examining "issues facing many organisations and the way they have responded to the challenges they face". It says so, right in its editorial.
So we were hopeful the magazine's August edition would examine the issue of an  run by a publicity-loving CEO and an accommodative board (though most of it has now resigned), so enthused with their plan to make accounting sexy they failed to consider how a conflict of interest caused by their strategy would lead to the  to offer their members professional indemnity insurance.
But for all its big talk, INTHEBLACK's only mention of the multiple scandals enveloping that organisation since it last went to press was the editorial by chairman Jim Dickson, who told CPA members of an "independent review with broad terms of reference" that would help "reshape the organisation".
"Working with member input, the independent panel has the qualifications and experience to support CPA Australia to become a stronger and more transparent organisation ... I commit to keeping members informed through this process".

It's a commitment members may find hard to square with the very limited information about the review, or anything else involving CPA's revival, one can find in the magazine. Dickson's editorial makes no mention that the review is already down its lead investigator, Sir Angus Houston, , nor of the public outcry over the original make-up of the review panel that led to the addition of several governance experts, nor of 16 past presidents of CPA Australia now seeking an emergency meeting of members.

And the entire magazine - even the letters page! - makes no mention of Alex Malley, rendered invisible from a magazine so obviously moulded to his strategy. Most of its content remains in Malley-mode: it offers readers a feature on women on Antarctic missions, a strategy piece on "transforming the air force", and a piece on - we like this one - whether taking a sabbatical will harm your career.
And then there's the spectacularly timed lead feature of the edition, with embattled Wallabies skipper Stephen Moore (not that you'd know it from the glowing write-up on his leadership skills). He stepped down from the Wallabies captaincy last Thursday after a disappointing few months for his team, too late we presume for INTHEBLACK's deadline as the piece makes no mention of it. Outstanding!

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antarctic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malley-mode</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INTHEBLACK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Angus Houston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Alex Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
