<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401963266801040</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/stuart-bailey-former-homicide-cop-doubles-as-a-runner-for-st-kilda-in-the-afl/news-story/b0966db32af8b676dc9bbb306821564f</url>
  <title>From thin blue line to boundary lines</title>
  <content>
ALMOST 19 years ago, Stuart Bailey was assigned to his first major homicide case - the police murders that shook Melburnians.
Sergeant Gary Silk and Senior Constable Rodney Miller were brutally gunned down in Moorabbin in 1998 by career criminals.
Since then, in a police career spanning nearly 30 years, the Port Phillip Acting Inspector and former homicide cop has seen the darkest and cruellest underside of society.
But the stress of the job melts away when he jogs onto the field as a runner for St Kilda each weekend.
In nine years as a runner for three different AFL clubs, he hasn't missed a match.
"It's a total mental break from work but it can be stressful in its own right," he said.
"But I actually thrive on that adrenaline, I love it, and the closer the game, the more I enjoy it.
"It's crucial that you get things right so you really focus and they're probably the games I get the most out of - mind you, I love it when we win by 10 goals."
August 16 marks 19 years since the . They were shot at close range while staking out a Chinese restaurant as part of an undercover investigation into a series of armed robberies.

Bandali Debs and Jason Roberts were later convicted of the double homicide.
Silk and Miller's deaths were the catalyst for the successful Blue Ribbon Foundation, which supports community projects in memory of police killed in the line of duty.
The Silk-Miller Cup, an annual friendly football match between Port Phillip and Stonnington police, will be held on Wednesday, August 16.
Regretfully, Bailey said he wouldn't be playing as he couldn't risk injury, but would be a runner.
Entry is via gold coin donation to the Blue Ribbon Foundation.
"It is played in memory of (the fallen cops) but it's also a reminder to members this can be a really dangerous job and it's really important to look after and support one another," Bailey said.
An annual AFL match between St Kilda and Hawthorn - the teams Silk and Miller supported - also commemorates their sacrifice.
Bailey said players rallied around him during the round six match this season when .
"We celebrate the day as a club and the players are really supportive of me because they know I've had involvement with the case," he said.
"It's kind of funny how things realign; I had strong involvement with that case and now I am involved again from a footy perspective."
It is not the first time his policing and footy worlds have collided amid tragedy.
Bailey also had to identify the body of Port Adelaide player John McCarthy after he fell from the roof of the Flamingo Hotel in Las Vegas in 2012.

"I was a runner for the Bulldogs at the time and they asked me to chaperone a group of players on their end-of-season trip," he said.
"When the death message came in from the cops in Las Vegas, the AFL asked me to step in and support the Port Adelaide players as well."
As Victoria Police's man on the ground during the tragic trip, Bailey rallied to get Bulldogs and Power players home quickly, and stayed behind to help the Las Vegas police and coroner.
When he returned to Australia, he took statements from players and supplied them to the coroner and Las Vegas police.
Despite working on some of Melbourne's most high-profile cases - including the murders of ,  and  - Bailey said identifying 22-year-old McCarthy's body had been tougher than attending most crime scenes.

"It's always much harder seeing the body of someone you know than being at a crime scene," he said.
While that moment will stick with him forever, chaperoning players overseas was easy, Bailey said.
"My wife thinks it's the best junket in the world but I tell her it's more stressful than anything," he said.
"You've got to stay up all night to be with them, make sure they all make it home and you can have a drink with them, but you can't get drunk, but you can't be a stick in the mud either.
"They're there to enjoy themselves and you want them to but you've got to minimise any risks."
Bailey said he owes his football career to his "good mate", St Kilda Football Club senior coach Alan Richardson.
The pair met while playing together at East Burwood, and when Richardson stepped up to coach the Coburg Tigers, he brought Bailey on as the club's fitness adviser.
He spent five years with Coburg and struck up a friendship with Matthew Knights.
He moved to the Northern Bullants; then his "moons aligned" and Knights made him a runner at Essendon.
Bailey spent two great years under Knights, an "interesting" year under James Hird, then two years at the Bulldogs before Richo offered him a gig with the Saints.
"It had always been my ambition to try and get back together with him; we've got a good relationship," he said.
"We get along really well and he knows I support him wholeheartedly and I've always got his back."
Except once many years ago during a VFL match, when Richo sent him out to deliver a message to a player on the opposition team.
"It was basically a sledge - a couple of players chased me off the ground, they wanted to kill me," he said.
"I told (Richo) I was never doing that again, and he hasn't asked me to since. It was a big learning curve for both of us."
In the AFL, Bailey said he's been on the end of a few expletive-laden sprays from players.
"It's sort of par for the course as a runner and I understand that; (players) are highly strung and I was exactly the same as a player, I used to crack it at times," he said.
"It's like water off a duck's back to me, I never worry about that and just get on and get the job done.
"As long as they don't treat me like that after the game, off the field, I have no issue."
Keeping fit is a major part of being a runner, with Bailey running about 15km each match.
"I train most mornings; I'll (cycle) 20km into work or I'll stop off at the Tan and run," he said.
"When I can, I train with the players - it's important to go to training, especially in the pre-season with the new players coming in, to make that connection and build those relationships so they have respect and confidence in you and vice versa."
Bailey also does Bikram yoga and weights training and has a "fairly strict" recovery regimen post-match.
"I'm really careful about doing the right things to recover and that's probably why I haven't missed an AFL game in nine years," he said.
"I do ice baths and I get a massage after every game.
"The players all laugh at me but I always say 'I'm double your age, I need it more than you guys do'."
Bailey said his colleagues and family - wife Annitia and daughters Nikita, 20, and Mia, 17 - had always supported his hectic schedule.
"For interstate games, if I can get in and get out the same day I will, to make sure I don't cut down on time with either work or my family," he said.
"And my youngest daughter loves her footy so I take her to most games."
But he makes the mad Richmond supporter hide her scarf before she enters the Saints' rooms.
Bailey said he planned to stay with the Saints "as long as they'll have me".
"You don't choose the club, the club chooses you and I've been very fortunate, that's why I'm indebted to Richo," he said.
"He gave me the opportunity to perform that role in the VFL and has supported me the whole way through.
"And the people I've met at St Kilda - you couldn't meet a nicer or more professional bunch."
Bailey is also a strong supporter of women's football and believes it's a great vehicle for Victoria Police to promote itself to potential female recruits.
"We're having a lot more women push into the leadership ranks at Victoria Police and (women's footy) is a great foundation to bring home the message that we really value women in the force," he said.
Officers will be at the Peanut Farm Reserve on August 6 for the game between St Kilda Sharks and Eastern Devils as part of a Victoria Police recruitment drive.
Bailey, who will celebrate his 30th anniversary with Victoria Police in September, said some cases would always stay with him.
"Any involving the murder of a child sticks with me and I've had a lot of those," he said.
The kind-faced cop is also keen to see justice for .
"I was heavily invested in that case and put a lot of time into it so to see that brought to an end would be great for the whole St Kilda community," he said.
"Tracy was a pretty amazing woman and she'd had such a hard life; she was really liked in the community and they really supported her."

We explain the procedures involved in a criminal trial in Victoria

WHAT HAPPENS IN A CRIMINAL TRIAL?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda Sharks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bailey</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Burwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senior Constable Rodney Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Bailey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Phillip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Phillip Acting Inspector</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coburg Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peanut Farm Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bandali Debs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mia, 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikita, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silk-Miller Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bikram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Ribbon Foundation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Gary Silk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flamingo Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annitia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moorabbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Knights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonnington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HAPPENS IN A CRIMINAL TRIAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Bullants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Devils</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melburnians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
