<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401443575747168</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/karl-stefanovics-this-time-next-year-is-oprah-in-the-tardis-20170731-gxmkz9.html</url>
  <title>Karl Stefanovic's This Time Next Year is Oprah in the TARDIS</title>
  <content>
Welcome back to prime time, Oprah Stefanovic.
And welcome back those fans starved of night-time Oprah Stefanovic shenanigans ever since a venture into a Q&A-style catastrophe called The Verdict went belly-up after a short but messy hurl across the nation's living rooms in 2015. 

Up Next

Life after Pitt: Jolie reveals

01:26

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Karl Stefanovic's bad year

Getting skewered by tabloids and crashing in the ratings, Today's Karl Stefanovic is having a bad year.

As for the rest of us, one can only say: welcome back - but we should have been pre-warned. That at least applies to the more cynical among us, who should have been given some sort of heads-up about Nine's new Oprah Stefanovic vehicle, This Time Next Year, which premiered on Monday night. 
What is one to say about this weird blancmange of insistent inspiration, incessant flashing lights and emotional incontinence other than that the jaundiced should have been advised to either stay away or to check their yellowing eyes at the door.

What is This Time Next Year? 
To quote the official Nine spiel: "In every inspirational episode people from across the country will pledge to change their lives by 'this time next year' - whether it is to overcome a setback, find love, reunite with a relative or even achieve a world record. Hosted by Karl Stefanovic, many of the stories take unexpected turns over the course of the year, with the result of each story revealed in an instant."

To quote the alternative view: This Time Next Year is like finding yourself trapped in a cross between The Twilight Zone and Australian Story while being beaten about the head by Oprah Stefanovic with a book of inspirational quotations.
Let it be said, this reality format's selling point - based on a British program - is not entirely stupid.   Photo: Supplied
A collection of potentially extraordinary ordinary folk is trotted on to Stefanovic's sprawling set, which features lounge chairs lodged against a backdrop of flashing lights and sound effects that suggest what it might be like to visit your therapist if your therapist lived inside a pinball machine. 
After hearing each story, Karl/Oprah strides across the set as lights flash and things ping and pop - a journey that on our screens takes mere seconds but in the filming process took an entire year. Then comes the big reveal. Would the forlorn couch-dweller of the preceding segment have completed their journey to thinness, gayness, stuntwomanhood or literally walking again in the year between Karl's thoughtful wander from one side of the set to the other?Photo: Supplied
Surprise! With one exception, yes they would. 
There was the couple who wanted to get married, but only to get married thin.  The nation heard Jennifer and Darren tell us variously that "I don't wanna be that fat bride" and "I'm sick of being big fella. No more fat fumble sex". A year later, "fat fumble sex" was but a distant nightmare. 
Inspiring!
There was the couple who wanted to have a baby after a long struggle with infertility, who returned to the other side of the set a year later bearing not one but two offspring, leaving one to wonder how much Nine would have paid for sextuplets.
There was the gay farmer from a small town, who volunteered: "I'm 34 years old... I'm one step off being the 40]-year-old virgin." 
He returned having mysteriously failed in his mission to find someone willing to spend the first year of a relationship consumed by the dread of explaining things to Oprah Stefanovic before a national television audience. Evidently even Grindr doesn't include that as a profile option. Helpfully, his coming out to his family was performed in front of a battalion of Nine cameras. 
We also met a cute-as-a-button five-year-old, whose ambition was to read 1000 books in a year and whose alleged exceeding of that mark to reach 1002 books - including, they wanted us to believe, a couple of Shakespeares - was frankly unbelievable (you do the sums).
In short, it was all enough to make you want to get yourself off the couch and ... find the remote mainly, though there were some moments that were genuinely moving. To quote a review of the British version of this show in the Radio Times: "You might shed a tear, but you'll be annoyed about it."
To that end, the producers saved the best for last in the person of Emma Henderson, whose dream of walking again after an accident delivered a real punch to close the show. It was, on its own terms, great television but not quite enough to make you wish you hadn't sat through much of what came before. 
In that sense, This Time Next Year is reality television in its purest form - perhaps best evidenced by breast cancer survivor Mel, whose ambition was to be a stuntwoman. She returned a year later and was literally set on fire as she arrived on the time-travel set. 
As she and Oprah Stefanovic prove beyond doubt, there is pretty much nothing people won't do to appear on prime time TV.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tardis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grindr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oprah Stefanovic</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Stefanovic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jolie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Story</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oprah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Stefanovic's This Time Next Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Next Year</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefanovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twilight Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl/Oprah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
