<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401920317127072</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/western-sydney-wanderers-hit-the-ffa-cup-trail-against-phoenix-as-new-signings-aim-to-make-mark/news-story/50220fcb11bc684bb937a0f43e67a1ec</url>
  <title>Popa's posh new squad on Cup trail</title>
  <content>
IT'S the first sighting of Tony Popovic's most expensive squad, but the Wanderers boss is adamant that there's no change of ambition at Western Sydney.
Western Sydney host Wellington in the FFA Cup at Campbelltown Stadium on Tuesday night, boasting a squad featuring two Spanish marquees, several high-profile A-League recruits and the return of Mark Bridge.
Though some of the new faces won't feature in the Round of 32 clash, awaiting final paperwork on their deals, it's the first opportunity for Popovic to show his new playing group will challenge Sydney FC in the coming season for the title.
Spanish striker Oriel Riera is likely to lead the line, with former Phoenix playmaker Roly Bonevacia coming in at No.10 to play against his former club.
Bridge and Spanish winger Alvaro Cejudo are still waiting for international clearance while Josh Sotirio will be suspended.
But Popovic said having secured a new-look squad did not alter the demands placed upon him and his players to succeed.
"That's an easy one for you guys - you bring in these new faces and there's more expectation," he said. "But the expectation internally is always the same. I wouldn't say the club has backed us any more (financially) this season particularly - our club always backs us. They backed us last year as well but you don't always get the players you go for, it's not always possible to get them.
VALE LES MURRAY:
TRIBUTE TO LES MURRAY:
TOM SMITHIES:
"There's been no change for me from the chairman and owners in their support, not in their financial support or any other. It's about trying to bring in the right players when you do spend, and we believe we've been able to do that.
"We've also been able to bring them in early - that's always the plan but it doesn't always work out. Often you get these players in late August or early September. That will help the settling in period, and by the time the season starts all those new players will be good to go.
"I'm sure you guys will have your views on how we're playing - we're working on certain things we want in our game but it's still very early. We're happy with the progress, and day by day, week by week, we'll see those improvements."
The scheduling of the Round of 32 ties presents an annual challenge for the A-League teams, more than two months out from the start of the season proper, and Wellington are also getting to grips with a new coach in Darije Kalezic.
"We're all the same, the A-League sides - we're building, trying to put a team together the way you want to play," Popovic said. "Some will be more advanced than others, but when you go out there on the field it's a cup game you're desperate to win. Hopefully we'll be that bit better than Wellington and we get through to the next round.
"Regardless of the changes, at this stage it's hard to judge anyone and where they'll be at. I'm sure every team in August compared with October, you'll see a big difference. They've got a new coaching staff, who will implement their new style, their expectations and their standards. I'm sure there'll be some changes in what they do."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roly Bonevacia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbelltown Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alvaro Cejudo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOM SMITHIES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oriel Riera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darije Kalezic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Popovic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Sotirio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VALE LES MURRAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanderers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Popa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Popovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
