<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401963266801005</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/these-are-the-suburbs-where-prices-are-tipped-to-grow/news-story/cb585cc3d3a20def399f693ca6553b47</url>
  <title>These are the suburbs where prices are tipped to grow - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
AS southern property markets start to cool, the market is heating up in dozens of Brisbane suburbs.
A new report has revealed the 33 suburbs within greater Brisbane where transaction numbers are steadily rising.
Property analyst Terry Ryder of Hotspotting said increased sales numbers were a good indication of future price growth.
"Changes in sales volumes are far more relevant and useful: medians record the recent past for prices, while sales volumes predict the future,'' he said.
Mr Ryder said the number of sales changed first and then prices usually reacted.
His latest Price Predictor Index found the suburbs where things were set to improve price wise and has also highlighted Brisbane's danger suburbs - those to avoid.
Suburbs with a high number of units - Fortitude Valley, Kangaroo Point, Kelvin Grove, South Brisbane and West End plus Clayfield and Chermside were all labelled danger markets by Mr Ryder.
"Sales levels have dropped away markedly at a time when new supply is rising,'' he said.
"Values, inevitably, will fall in these locations - and there is evidence of price decline in the latest figures on prices from the Real Estate Institute of Queensland and other sources.''
In terms of suburbs performing well, Mr Ryder said the Moreton Bay region had more than any in greater Brisbane.
There were 10 suburbs where sales levels were rising steadily - Morayfield, Burpengary, Bellmere, Arana Hills, Mango Hill, Sandstone Point, Scarborough, Woorim, Murrumba Downs and Warner.
Although it had weakened a little, Mr Ryder said it still remained solid, as it had for the past three years.
The report found sales levels were lifting in the outer ring suburbs of Brisbane, where the buy in price was more affordable.
Suburbs in Logan City also performed well with transactions rising steadily in eight suburbs - Edens Landing, Hillcrest, Jimboomba, Logan Cental, Loganlea, Regents Park, Waterford West and Springwood.

Kath Lollo at the house she is selling at Chapel Hill. Picture: Annette Dew

Redlands City had four suburbs, Thorneside, Cleveland, Ormiston and Redland Bay where transactions were steadily rising and Ipswich had Springfield and Springfield Lakes.
Within Brisbane suburbs with steadily rising sales numbers were Holland Park, Sunnybank, Sunnybank Hills, Fitzgibbon, Keperra, McDowall, Paddington, Red Hill and Chapel Hill.
Michelle McLeod Ray White Indooroopilly - McLeod Partners said in the last three months many properties listed in Chapel Hill had sold within the first weekend.
"Many with multiple offers situations, and attendances at open homes are up markedly with 30 plus families visiting the new properties that get listed, particularly between the $600,000 and $1 million bracket.''
Ms McLeod said Chapel Hill was for many an unknown or undiscovered part of Brisbane as people didn't really need to drive through it.
"I think that it is just showing value for money,'' she said.
Ms McLeod said there were good public transport routes and there were a lot more cafes and restaurants on the boundaries of Chapel Hill so people didn't have to leave the suburb to get the basic family needs.
Kath Lollo is helping her daughter Emma sell the home the family bought atChapel Hill which has its first open inspection today.
"We bought it about six years ago,'' Ms Lollo said.
Emma was studying at UQ at the time, but was now making a sea change so the house was on the market.
"It has three bedrooms, the bedroom has a floor to itself, it is just a retreat, I would call it.''
Ms Lollo said the market appeared to have picked up in the area of late.
"I'd say probably the last year or so, they are not on sale for very long by the looks of it.''
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelvin Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellmere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle McLeod Ray White Indooroopilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redlands City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry Ryder of Hotspotting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Price Predictor Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunnybank Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chermside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springfield Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keperra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woorim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McLeod</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzgibbon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redland Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>atChapel Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chapel Hill</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murrumba Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mango Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ryder</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regents Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterford West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortitude Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillcrest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimboomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arana Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate Institute of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDowall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunnybank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edens Landing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLeod Partners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan Cental</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ormiston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lollo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burpengary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annette Dew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath Lollo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thorneside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loganlea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandstone Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
