<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401920317127009</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-07-31/ronaldo-in-court-to-face-judge-questioning-in-tax-fraud-probe/8761698</url>
  <title>Cristiano Ronaldo faces Spanish judge questioning over tax fraud investigation</title>
  <content>
Cristiano Ronaldo has appeared before a Spanish judge as part of an investigation to determine whether the Portugal forward committed tax fraud worth almost 15 million euros ($20.7 million).

Key points:

32-year-old gave evidence in a closed court
In June prosecutor accused Ronaldo of four counts of tax fraud from 2011-14
Real Madrid star has denied allegations

The Real Madrid player spent more than 90 minutes answering the questions of investigating judge Monica Gomez at a courthouse on the outskirts of Madrid that was closed to the public because it is part of an ongoing investigation.
The 32-year-old Ronaldo used an alternative entrance to avoid a large swarm of journalists gathered near the main door to the court.
Court officials had said that either Ronaldo or his lawyer would speak to the media after he saw the judge, but neither stepped up to the temporary podium in front of the courthouse.
Instead, spokesman Inaki Torres emerged from the building to announce that Ronaldo "was on his way home".
Judge Gomez took .
In June, a state prosecutor accused Ronaldo of four counts of tax fraud from 2011-14.
The prosecutor accused the Portugal forward of having used shell companies outside Spain to hide income made from image rights. The accusation does not involve his salary from Real Madrid.
Ronaldo has denied any wrongdoing.
The prosecutor alleged that Ronaldo used what was deemed a shell company in the Virgin Islands to "create a screen in order to hide his total income from Spain's Tax Office".
The prosecutor accused Ronaldo of declaring 11.5 million euros ($16 million) earned from 2011-14 in a tax return filed in 2014, when the prosecutor said Ronaldo's real income during that period was almost 43 million euros ($60 million).
It added that Ronaldo falsely claimed the income as coming from real estate, which "greatly" reduced his tax rate.
The prosecutor also said that Ronaldo did not declare income of 28.4 million euros ($40 million) made from the cession of image rights from 2015-20 to another company located in Spain.
Ronald claims come amid Mourinho accusations

Ronaldo's agency, Gestifute, said he was up to date on his taxes and that he had maintained the same financial planning in Spain that he had while playing for Manchester United before joining Madrid in 2009.
A four-time Ballon d'Or winner, Ronaldo is one of Europe's best soccer players. He has led Madrid to back-to-back Champions League titles and helped Portugal to win last year's European Championship.
Last month, Spain's state prosecutor also accused former .
Mourinho, now coach of Manchester United, has yet to be summoned for questioning and through his agent has denied any wrongdoing.
The probes into Ronaldo's and Mourinho's financial arrangements are the most recent high-profile tax cases involving soccer's top names in Spain.
AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Madrid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain's Tax Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cristiano Ronaldo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Islands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mourinho</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monica Gomez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gestifute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Gomez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronaldo</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inaki Torres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MADRID</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
