<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402006216475100</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/by-jupiter-former-bhp-boss-brian-gilbertson-might-be-preparing-for-a-return-to-the-asx-20170730-gxlvyv.html</url>
  <title>By Jupiter: Former BHP boss Brian Gilbertson might be preparing for a return to the ASX</title>
  <content>
Could BHP's short-lived but memorable chief executive, Brian Gilbertson, be making his long-awaited return to the ASX? 
More than three years have passed since the Gilbertson-chaired Jupiter Mines delisted from the ASX, with a shareholder list that included Gina Rinehart's Hancock Prospecting. 
And it looks like the time spent in hibernation has been good for Jupiter.  
With the price of manganese ore staging a recovery last year, Jupiter's Tshipi venture is starting to churn out cash - including dividends - to the point where Jupiter has appointed Merrill Lynch to "investigate strategic options to realise shareholder value from the Tshipi manganese mine", according to its annual report. Photo: Wayne Taylor
This includes a potential re-listing on the ASX of Jupiter, which reported a net profit of more than $200 million for the February 28 financial year, compared to a $172 million loss last year. 
The company has already conducted a $73 million share buyback funded by a distribution from Tshipi, and Jupiter says an independent valuation of its Tshipi stake came up a figure of $890 million.  

It has not helped soothe Gilbertson's investors at Pallinghurst, which holds the largest single stake in Jupiter. 
Pallinghurst's shares have underperformed woefully and investors have accused their chairman, Gilbertson, and his executives of enriching themselves at shareholder expense. 
Yes, we know. What were they expecting? This is the guy who ruffled feathers at BHP by reportedly demanding to have his initials, BPG, painted on the company jet. 
And in a previous role in South Africa, staff would greet the arrival of his helicopter with the declaration: "the ego has landed".
But not even Gilbertson's ego can eclipse the most colourful tale associated with Jupiter - an infamous escapade aboard a Abu Dhabi-bound jet.
Nearly a decade has passed since Jupiter Mines directors David Evans and Jeremy Snaith were arrested after alleged inappropriate antics on a flight to Abu Dhabi while on business for what was then a mining explorer.
The pair - dubbed "bananas in pyjamas" after the fiasco - claimed they were innocent of charges of sexual harassment, intoxication and offensive behaviour.
On the spot 

The independent directors at Spotless launched their latest missive in reply to the news that unwelcome suitor, Grant Fenn's Downer EDI, now owns more than 80 per cent of its shares. 
Is it time to pull the Spotless Group's ASX-listing, as Downer insists? 
Not so, say the Spotless independents who pointed out on Monday that there are more than 2000 investors in the group.  
According to the ASX guide, the exchange operator uses its discretion to delist when investor numbers get below the 150 mark. 
"Under these circumstances, ASX guidance is that any application to delist by Spotless would need to be approved by remaining Spotless shareholders," said the statement from the indi directors. 
Hopefully the independents did not jinx themselves given their announcement went out just hours before the current offer was due to expire, at 7pm on Monday. 
But if it makes the holdouts feel any better, there was no indication from the Spotless trio - CEO Martin Sheppard, chair Garry Hounsell, and former Australian of the Year Simon McKeon  - that they plan to sell their 3 million shares to the Downer barbarians who now control the Spotless boardroom. 
It means the first meeting of the new board in a few weeks, to approve the Spotless financial results, should be interesting. 
Force majeure 

May the Force be with you (Saint) Andrew "Twiggy" Forrest. Western Force, that is, after our favourite billionaire in the world cleared up just how he would support the embattled rugby club. 
In a deal that only Forrest could have thought of, he is offering interest-free loans to fans who buy shares in the Force as part of the club's "Own the Force" campaign.
Any money paid back on the loans will go to West Australian Rugby, not Twiggy.
And to anyone who thinks this doesn't sound promising at all, think of what we were writing about Fortescue in the early days. 
Now all we need is rival Perth billionaires, Kerry Stokes or Gina Rinehart to start buying into the campaign. 
Follow CBD on . Got a tip? 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jupiter</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX of Jupiter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pallinghurst</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon McKeon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerry Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Snaith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gina Rinehart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Group's ASX-listing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twiggy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gina Rinehart's Hancock Prospecting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Fenn's Downer EDI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Gilbertson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilbertson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tshipi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jupiter Mines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jupiter's Tshipi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Martin Sheppard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilbertson-chaired Jupiter Mines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrill Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Hounsell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Former BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forrest</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
