<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401971856735749</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/25m-boost-to-snakes-prowess/news-story/c446f83a582725d2e228bbd1b1aa6129</url>
  <title>$2.5m boost to Snakes</title>
  <content>
BIGGER, better, stronger and healthier Cairns Taipans players is the aim for the NBL club after further increasing their involvement with CQUniversity.

A $2.5 million Professional Sports Centre of Excellence will be embedded within the Taipans training base at their Cairns Basketball Stadium complex on Aumuller Street from February next year.

As part of CQUniversity's $54.7 million plan to expand its presence in the Far North, the Taipans will host the only educational qualifications of its kind in Australia with students and researchers working with professional athletes, coaches and sports administrators in sports science, management and marketing.

Snakes coach Aaron Fearne, who last week inked the signing of new import point guard Scoochie Smith, was all smiles at the announcement yesterday.

"Ultimately it is about trying to make a bigger, better, stronger, healthier athlete," Fearne said.

The new facility, which is expected to house around 20 students, will include purpose-built biomechanics, performance analysis and skill acquisition laboratories as well as athlete recovery facilities.

The construction of the facility, as well as a fifth court at Cairns Basketball, has CQU Vice-Chancellor Scott Bowman expecting to have the first students on hand early in 2018.

"I think it is a first for Australia, doing it in complete partnership with the Taipans and offering the degree at Taipans headquarters," Bowman said. "The players and coaches will be able to use the state of the art facilities."

Fearne said he was "comfortable" with the decision to hand the playing group's strength and condition program to longstanding team physio Tom Maher and not rehire a specific replacement for previous strength and conditioning coach Scott Callaghan.

"He is running our strength and conditions right now, the guys have done a month of that already," Fearne said.

"He has done a really good job and he will have to continue to do that during the preseason and during the season."

Taipans boss Mark Beecroft believes the move will help the club stay ahead of the competition.

"We want to stay ahead of the curve and ahead of the game, and being innovative is what we have had to do in terms of recruiting our players and talent," Beecroft said.

"Adding this with another layer, that investment and relationship with CQUniversity will only help us from a Taipans perspective in terms of performance."

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Fearne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQUniversity</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQU Vice-Chancellor Scott Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Basketball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Basketball Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beecroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taipans</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Taipans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Maher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aumuller Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scoochie Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQUniversity's $54.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professional Sports Centre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Beecroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
