<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401971856735816</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/editorial-its-a-hot-august-fight/news-story/601cc8c5024b486ba2576cc1787cb739</url>
  <title>It's a hot August fight</title>
  <content>
THE consistent line coming out of the State Government and Premier Will Hodgman is that there is no intention of going to an early election.
Every piece of public dialogue has pointed to a March 2018 election, with the Government going full term.
But still the rumours persist.
The latest is a November poll, with an election campaign coming in the afterglow of the AFL Grand Final and on the eve on the festive season - a time of high spirits and strong consumer spending.
There also is concern about going to the polls when the new year is back in full swing. Come March, reality is returned. The Christmas credit-card bill is often still to be paid, school costs kick in and household budgets are under pressure. It is not traditionally a happy time for incumbents.
Still, the Government says this remains its preferred option.
And we must take it at its word.
But situations can change and the Mercury is of the firm opinion that the Government will go to the polls when it feels it has the strongest chance of retaining majority rule.
As we pointed out in detail on Saturday, there are deep-seated concerns among the business community about the potential economic and consumer confidence damage if this state again faces a hung Parliament.
The Government has echoed these concerns.

It has been stung by polls showing the rising popularity of Opposition Leader Rebecca White but also encouraged by indications it is the only party which has a realistic chance of gaining a majority and is still regarded by most voters as the preferred manager of the economy.
That is why the next few months of Parliament are so significant.
Firstly, the Government will need to ask itself whether it expects the polls to get any better and whether it is a smart move to go early, while the ALP is still finding its feet and establishing its team, and thereby seize the momentum.
Secondly, it faces the challenge of getting some key pieces of "big ticket" legislation through the Upper House. None is more significant than the proposed takeover of TasWater. Politics is a high-stakes game and the stakes come no higher than this piece of law.
The Government says it wants to fix a troubled water system, will make water prices cheaper and still return bountiful dividends to the councils. Its approach has been aggressive and uncompromising.
TasWater appears bemused by the whole shebang, saying there is no crisis and warns of debt blowouts.
Whichever side of the fence you sit, blockage in the Upper House would represent a major setback for the State Government and its policy agenda, given how much energy it has thrown behind this issue.
If it can't get the numbers to force through this Bill, it will blame Labor. It will then say its mandate to govern for all Tasmanians is being blocked by a recalcitrant Upper House. It is then not outside the realms of possibility that this would prove an election trigger. Elections have been called for much, much less. Watch this space.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasWater</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Grand Finals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Will Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Rebecca White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
