<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401757108366513</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/technology/samsungs-galaxy-tab-s3-brings-back-the-coloured-pencils-20170728-gxki0x</url>
  <title>Samsung's Galaxy Tab S3 brings back the coloured pencils</title>
  <content>
People must think I'm an idiot.
People who don't know me, I mean. Anyone who knows me already know about the idiocy, obviously. But now everyone who can see me sitting here in this cafe drawing on the screen of my Samsung Tablet with a lead pencil, they too must pick me for a dunce.
What sort of ninny would draw on their tablet with a pencil, they must be thinking?
The sort of ninny who has the new , a wood-composite pencil that has essentially had the lead removed and replaced with a digital stylus that works with Samsung's new Galaxy Tab S3, that's who!

The Tab S3, Samsung's top-of-the-range Android tablet that competes with Apple's iPad Pro, actually comes with a regular-looking stylus, that transforms the tablet into a first-rate note-taking device somewhat akin to a Galaxy Note (only with a 9.7-inch screen), or into a very decent, if imperfect, device for sketching, drawing and Photoshopping. More on how it compares to an iPad Pro in a moment.

​But for just $59 extra you can buy the Staedtler stylus, too, and have a very different experience using the Tab S3: an experience that will remind you of a simpler time, before things went all digital and soulless. Anyone watching you draw on your tablet with what looks like a coloured pencil will probably think you're a little simple, too, but who cares what people think?
It's actually a very good stylus, too, long and skinny and light which makes it a great pointing device if you're using your Tab S3 as a laptop replacement, with the keyboard attached but without a mouse. The new keyboard for the Tab S3 doesn't have a trackpad like the Tab S2's keyboard did, you see, and its keys, though bigger and much easier to type on, aren't quite as well thought out as the keys on the previous model (there are no home or escape keys on the new keyboard, which is annoying), so you will find yourself either reaching up to the screen a lot with your fingers, or picking up the pencil and using it to point, like a mouse.
Yes, the Tab S3, just like the iPad Pro, is one of those tablets that's intended to be used instead of a laptop, when you need to travel and don't want to carry something bigger.
In that respect it's something of a mixed bag.

On the one hand, its screen is smaller than the screen on the new iPad Pro (9.7 inches versus 10.5 inches), and when you're trying to use a tablet for work, every inch counts. It's also not quite as fast as an iPad Pro: oddly enough, considering it's a very premium device, the Tab S3 has a processor from last year, and when you've got a lot going on it can feel ever so slightly sluggish.
But on the other hand, it runs Android, which means you can access the file system and attach a mouse,  that we have no hesitation recommending the Tab S3 ahead of the iPad Pro if you are looking for a tablet that, at a pinch, can be used for working on.
I've written this entire review on the Tab S3 with little difficulty, for instance - something that was impossible on the iPad Pro, just because Apple won't let you attach a mouse.
The battery life on the Tab S3 is pretty good in productivity mode, too. We've been getting around 10 hours of solid work done on a single charge, making heavy use of the tablet's Wi-Fi, Bluetooth and 4G connectivity the whole time.

But of course you wouldn't fork out $949 for the Tab S3 (or $1099 for the version with 4G), plus $189 for the keyboard, just to use it as a laptop. For that money you could just buy a laptop. 
With its High Dynamic Range (HDR), high-resolution OLED screen, the Tab S3 is the sort of device you'd take on a plane to watch Netflix and Stan videos, and it will be especially good at that if and when the video services take advantage of the Tab S3's HDR capabilities. At the time of writing, neither Stan nor Netflix recognise the Tab S3 as a 4K-capable device, much less an HDR device, but if and when they do this tablet should be the best portable video player on the market.
The other big reason you'd get the Tab S3 is for its stylus (or pencil) support, which allows the tablet to be used for drawing and photo editing, just like an iPad Pro with an Apple Pencil.
Well, it's not just like it, but it's almost as good. The stylus is every bit as sensitive to work with as an Apple Pencil, but probably due to that slightly older processor I mentioned earlier, it's not quite as fluid an experience as you'll get on an iPad.

When you're making large, fast brush strokes with Adobe Draw, for instance, the visible stroke on a new iPad Pro's display might lag five millimetres behind the tip of the Pencil, but on the Tab S3 it can lag three centimetres behind. It's not a big problem, but it does make the stylus (or the Staedtler pencil, which behaves identically) feel slightly sluggish.
Much worse is what seems to be a bug in Adobe's recognition of the pressure sensitivity of the Tab S3's stylus/Staedtler pencil, which can make it hard to draw fine dots on the screen. What's a tiny dot in Adobe's drawing apps on the iPad can come out as a giant blob on the Tab S3. Let's hope Adobe fixes that.
The pen and pencil support also gives the Tab S3  seriously good note-taking capabilities, using the Samsung Notes app that, as with the Galaxy Note phone, forms the centrepiece of the handwriting functions of the tablet.
It's a great app for taking handwritten notes of meetings and lectures, and as with the Note you can even use it to jot down a note on the black lock screen.

Frustratingly, though, Samsung still refuses to add a voice recorder to Samsung Notes, that's synchronised with your handwriting so you can quickly get to a section of a recording just by pointing the stylus or pencil at the note you took at that instant. There is a third party app, S-Pen Voice, that does that, but it's not terribly good on a Galaxy Note and it's worse still on the Tab S3.
I've begged Samsung many times to add that function to Samsung but do they listen to me? No!
They must think I'm an idiot. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple iPad Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pen Voice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OLED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tab S3</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>19</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tab S2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HDR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy Note</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staedtler</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung Notes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple Pencil</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad Pro (9.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adobe Draw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K-capable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad Pro</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Dynamic Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung Tablet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluetooth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung's Galaxy Tab S3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samsung</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galaxy Tab S3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adobe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
