<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401971856735740</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/sport/olympics/brits-are-now-better-at-swimming-than-australia/news-story/64f60fb04fdd0282ce057ee48b78c2ef</url>
  <title>Brits now better swimmers</title>
  <content>
Brits are now better at swimming than Australia

Nicole Jeffery, Budapest

The Australian

Bronze medalist team Australia celebrate on the podium of the women's 4x100m medley relay final during the swimming competition at the 2017 FINA World Championships in Budapest, on July 30, 2017. / AFP PHOTO / FRANCOIS XAVIER MARIT

The Brits are now better at swimming than Australia. Yes, you read that right.

The medal tally of the world swimming championships just concluded in Budapest makes disturbing reading for an Australian. Occasionally we have to accept that England will win the Ashes and the English rugby team will triumph but our superiority in swimming was a constant, until now.

A nation that has less than a dozen Olympic pools and is the world's leading creator of head-up breaststrokers has been more successful at this year's major championship than one bathed in sunshine most of the year round and, well, swimming in facilities.

The final medal tally shows that Britain achieved their equal best ever performance at the world titles to finish second behind the United States with four gold, one silver and two bronze medals. Australia are in seventh place with one gold (Emily Seebohm in the 200m backstroke), five silver and four bronze.

The women won eight of those 10 medals, largely through the efforts of Emma McKeon, who became the first Australian woman to win six medals at a single world championships (four silver and two bronze). Olympic 400m freestyle champion Mack Horton was the only male medallist, picking up silver in the 400m and bronze in the 1500m.

Australia's gold medal count may have slumped at this event, but on total medals Australia are still equal second with Russia and China. All trail far in the wake of the sport's only superpower, the USA (38).

However the gold standard is gold medals and by that score Australia have not sunk so low since the 1980s.

The good news is that it is only eight months until the national team can seek redress at the Commonwealth Games on the Gold Coast.

Some overblown assessments have predicted embarrassment for Australia at a home Commonwealth Games.

However a comparison of the respective positions of the top competitors in the Commonwealth nations across all the Games events in Budapest suggests that it will be a close competition on the Gold Coast.

Australians are ranked No 1 in the Commonwealth in 15 events, three ahead of England (11) with Canada third (7), ahead of Scotland (2), South Africa (1) and Wales (1).

That's while giving England the benefit of the doubt that they can beat Australia in two of the men's relays without Scotland's Duncan Scott.

The Australian team is expected to be substantially stronger with the return of a group of senior swimmers who have skipped the Budapest meet to prepare specifically for the Gold Coast (Olympic gold medallists Kyle Chalmers and Cate Campbell, Olympic silver medallist Madeline Groves and dual world champion James Magnussen).

National head coach Jacco Verhaeren has deliberately made these world championships a lower priority for the leading swimmers than they have been in past years.

He wants the Australian team to build through the quadrennium to a peak in Tokyo in 2020, rather than trying to peak for the major championships every year.

He argues that peaking annually can leave Australia's best swimmers exhausted by the time they get to the Olympics. That is one explanation for why seven gold medals at the world championships in 2015 became three gold medals at last year's Rio Olympics.

Another striking characteristic of the Rio team was a poor conversion rate of swimmers improving from the national trials to the Games (33 per cent). Improving that rate has been a particular mission for Verhaeren and the Budapest team has raised its strike rate to 57 per cent.

"(This result) reflects where we are at and where some of our medal contenders are in terms of their preparation,'' he said.

"I'm absolutely very pleased with the rookies (who made up more than a third of the team) and the performances they set and the steps they made into finals, into records, into personal best times.

"I wouldn't want to use the words happy or satisfied because that would mean we were at the end of the journey when it's the beginning.

"We definitely felt Kyle and Cate not being here. It makes a massive difference in some relays."

"All in all I'm very proud of this team. I heard some noise about the team not being united, but I haven't seen anything of that."

Verhaeren said he was willing to wear any criticism of the Budapest medal tally because he believed in the longer-term strategy the team was taking.

"I think we need to take responsibility for the choices we make and the choices we made this year included extended travel ... because we definitely saw in Rio that we needed to race more internationally and the guys that have done that, it was an incredible experience for them.

"Emily Seebohm and Emma McKeon really like this way of preparing and they swam themselves into the meet so for some that works great. For others it's more of a gamble.

"Of course we need to improve, in many events. This world championship has truly set standards in many events but I'm very hopeful for the young ones we have seen here on their first occasion. Almost without exception they improved on what they did at trials. They could handle the meet, they could handle the travel and I think that is good and we are truly looking forward to next year.''

The youngest two swimmers on the team, 16-year-olds Kaylee McKeown (200m backstroke, world junior record) and Ariarne Titmus (400m freestyle) finished fourth in their best events, and fellow teenagers Jack Cartwright (100m freestyle) and Matt Wilson (200m breaststroke) set personal bests to reach the finals.

Verhaeren said the swimming team "want to do the nation proud'' at the Commonwealth Games.

It is also worth remembering that no man who won an individual event at the 2013 world titles, won again in Rio three years later.

In the women's program, there were only three women who maintained their ascendancy through the Olympiad - Katie Ledecky (400m and 800m freestyle), Sarah Sjostrom (100m butterfly) and Katinka Hosszu (200m and 400m individual medley).

So the distribution of gold medals in Budapest is not a reliable forecaster of what might happen in Tokyo in three years.

Follow us

More Stories

Ray Gatt

For over 40 years Les Murray was the face of soccer - a passionate advocate of a sport once derided as 'wog ball'.

Courtney Walsh

Nick Riewoldt truly wishes he could play footy forever but his body was telling him otherwise.

Patrick Smith

It was a day in sport that saw our very foundations rocked by defeat, victory, retirement and, sadly, death.

Nicole Jeffery, Budapest

The Brits are now better at swimming than Australia based on the final medal tally at the world titles.

Greg Denham

Dustin Martin just has to stay out of trouble over the final month of the season to win this year's Brownlow Medal.

Will Swanton

No club is more cloaked in uncertainty than the Swans ahead of Friday night's blockbuster against Geelong.

Brent Read

State of Origin enfant terrible Josh McGuire has made himself some fresh enemies at Parramatta.

Greg Denham

Greater Western Sydney could regain ruckman Shane Mumford for Saturday's crucial clash with Melbourne in Canberra.

Courtney Walsh

Nic Naitanui will step out in the WAFL for the first time this decade in a bid to build match fitness.

Nicole Jeffery

James Magnussen can expect a call from coach Jacco Verhaeren to reprimand him for criticising Australia's relay strategy.

Features

The Australian,The Wall Street Journal, 

You are currently using private or incognito browsing mode so you'll need to log in every time you visit The Australian

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FINA World Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaylee McKeown (200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Games (33</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland (2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Denham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympiad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swanton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtney Walsh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FRANCOIS XAVIER MARIT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic 400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England (11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Cartwright (100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacco Verhaeren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Naitanui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma McKeon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP PHOTO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SOUTH AFRICA (1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katinka Hosszu (200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wales (1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mack Horton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland's Duncan Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Gatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Wilson (200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Ledecky (400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA (38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeline Groves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verhaeren</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cate Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Sjostrom (100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Jeffery</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Chalmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Magnussen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Seebohm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ariarne Titmus (400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
