<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402006216475085</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/ausgrid-hires-banks-to-refinance-bridge-loan-in-the-us-20170730-gxlyjb</url>
  <title>Ausgrid hires banks to refinance bridge loan in the US</title>
  <content>
Ausgrid's new shareholders and management team are wasting no time in addressing the company's capital structure. 
Street Talk understands that Ausgrid is preparing to tap the United States privately issued debt market as early as this week, with the help of lenders and advisers Bank of America Merrill Lynch and Commonwealth Bank of Australia. 
The US debt deal is expected to be worth more than $US500 million, and represents the first part of Ausgrid's push to refinance a $2 billion bridge loan which matures in December 2018. 
The bridge loan was arranged as part of a wider $12 billion debt package last December, when the NSW electricity distributor's new investors

Sources said Ausgrid and its advisers have already met debt investors in the US ahead of the deal, with more than a dozen meetings said to have taken place in the past fortnight.

Ausgrid's new raising is expected to mirror a $US727 million from fellow NSW power network infrastructure company TransGrid, which tapped the United States Private Placement market for a combination of 10-year, 12-year and 15-year debt less than two weeks ago. 
TransGrid's shareholders also arranged cross currency swaps to convert the US dollar debt into Australian dollars, and expects to receive the funds in October. 
If successful, Ausgrid's raising would be the first US denominated debt in its capital structure which also includes a $1 billion loan due in June 2020, a $6 billion loan due in 2021 and a $1.5 billion loan in 2023, according to Bloomberg data.
 Ausgrid is rated Baa1 by Moody's. 

Elsewhere, investment services and superannuation advice company Netwealth kicked off a non-deal roadshow on Monday as it ramps up plans for an ASX-listing. 

Netwealth is expected to pitch the high growth it has seen in its investment platform, with $14.3 billion in funds under advice and more than 2000 advisers on board. It's expected to seek an ASX-listing later this year. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netwealth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US727</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baa1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States Private Placement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TransGrid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2020</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ausgrid</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrill Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
