<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401997626540249</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/jake-king-afl-star-to-appear-at-macleod-womens-luncheon-club-defends-decision/news-story/94be5c60ddc26e4d40b54a89dbc510cf</url>
  <title>Local footy club in Jake King storm</title>
  <content>
MACLEOD Football Club has defended its move to secure former Richmond footballer Jake King for a one-off star appearance this weekend, just weeks after he was arrested for threats to kill.
King, 33, will be the special guest speaker at a women's luncheon on Saturday at Macleod.
King, who is not being paid an appearance fee, will also pull on the boots against Whittlesea in their Northern Football League Division 1 clash at De Winton Park and will help auction Richmond memorabilia after the game to fundraise for the club.
RELATED:
If convicted, King could face jail time.
When asked if it was a bad look for the club, Macleod football manager Christian Brandt - King's uncle - said he did not have an issue with the former Tiger forward's appearance.
Brandt said King, who may play at the Roos again this year but more likely next season, would be available to field questions from women in the audience about his AFL career.
"It hasn't been an issue for the club, we know his character, he is down there often watching our games so it is not a problem," Brandt said.
"We know Jake personally, he is a family member and we know his character.
"He's never been in trouble before, despite what people may think.
"He has always been a very loyal family member and that is what it is about."
King, who has other family connections at Macleod, and childhood friend Ty Vickery were arrested on July 5 over an extortion investigation.
It was reported at the time police were probing whether Vickery hired King to stand over a third party he was in dispute with over a six-figure sum related to a restaurant he ran.
King was later charged with six offences, including extortion, making threats to kill and inflict serious injury.
Hawthorn forward Vickery was released without charge, pending further investigation.
King will train at Macleod on Tuesday and Thursday night in preparation for the game, which will be his first since his AFL career came to a close in 2014.
His career at the elite level, which produced 107 games and 79 goals, was cut short after a toe injury.
Brandt said fundraising from the day would go towards the improving club facilities.
King, who was a premiership player at North Heidelberg in 2005, lodged a clearance to Macleod on June 27 ahead of the June 30 deadline, but the transfer was still listed as 'pending' as of Monday morning.
"I've wanted to play with my brother and extended family since retiring and am looking forward to pulling on the Macleod jumper," King said.
"It's also an opportunity for me to assist the club in fundraising."
King is scheduled to next appear at Melbourne Magistrates' Court on November 15.
The Northern Football League was contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Football League Division 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Heidelberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Football League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King, 33</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Winton Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Brandt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MACLEOD Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brandt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MacLeod</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ty Vickery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JAKE King</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vickery</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
