<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401967561768432</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/premiers-powerhouse-plan-shortchanges-sydney-20170731-gxm8c0.html</url>
  <title>Premier's Powerhouse plan short-changes Sydney</title>
  <content>
The case for a new cultural facility in Parramatta is overwhelming. The population of western Sydney is 1.9 million, more than 7 per cent of Australia's population and 38 per cent of Greater Sydney's. Its population is projected to reach 3 million by 2036 and to absorb two-thirds of the population growth in the Greater Sydney region, making it one of the largest growing urban populations in Australia.
Yet according to a study two years ago western Sydney received only 1 per cent of cultural funding from the Commonwealth government, compared with 36 per cent to eastern Sydney. It shares in only 5.5 per cent of state government funding, compared with 87 per cent going to eastern Sydney.

Up Next

Man on trial for murder, sexual assault of 'friend'

02:06

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Will you visit the Powerhouse in Parramatta?

For some visitors to Sydney's Powerhouse Museum, its relocation to Parramatta will make the trip easier; others say they will cancel their memberships.

It would be great to have a Parramatta venue for the Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences to complement its current base at the Powerhouse Museum in Ultimo. After all, the museum already has two facilities in eastern Sydney - the Powerhouse and Sydney Observatory - and one in western Sydney, the Museum Discovery Centre in Castle Hill. One more venue in Parramatta would even up the score: two in the east and two in the west.
A purpose-built Parramatta museum would enable the Museum to display more of its huge collection. More important, it will enable it to play a quite different cultural role from the Ultimo Powerhouse, thoroughly in keeping with Parramatta's aspiration as a centre for technology and innovation. But the sting in the tail of the Premier's announcement on Monday is her statement that "the NSW government will retain an arts and cultural presence at the current Ultimo site following the relocation of the Powerhouse Museum to Parramatta". This suggests the downgrading of the Powerhouse facility at Ultimo, with no assurance as to how the site will be used. This short-changes Sydney.

Sydney needs MAAS Parramatta and MAAS Ultimo, not one or the other. The Ultimo Powerhouse should stay.
Imagine the Ultimo museum displaying the science and technology treasures of the past, and the Parramatta museum exploring the science and technology of today and tomorrow: the perfect combination of past, present and future.

The adaptive reuse of the Powerhouse building in 1988 won the Australian Institute of Architects NSW chapter's highest honour, the Sulman Medal, and it's on the institute's own Register of Significant Buildings. We therefore need to ensure the integrity of the building is maintained in any future use. This will be difficult to achieve if residential as well as cultural use is envisaged, as suggested by the Premier.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

There's another compelling argument why the Powerhouse should retain a vibrant cultural presence in Ultimo - it's currently the destination at one end of the Goods Line, linking Central Station with the Harris Street cultural ribbon that includes the ABC, Frank Gehry's Dr Chau Chak Wing UTS building and the Powerhouse. The conversion of the railway from a 19th century goods line to a 21st century leisure precinct tells you all you need to know about the transformation of Sydney's economy in that time. Its access to the Powerhouse gives the museum the best entrance it's ever had.Photo: Fiona Morris
What should be non-negotiable in this discussion is that the Ultimo Powerhouse site remains in public hands and retained for cultural uses. The Ultimo Powerhouse Museum has served the public well for nearly 30 years; there's no reason why it cannot continue to play an essential part in Sydney's cultural life for decades to come. Particularly if its role is complemented by a Parramatta museum providing a window into Sydney's science and technology future.
Andrew Nimmo is the NSW chapter president, Australian Institute of Architects.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAAS Ultimo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Powerhouse Museum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sulman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Museum Discovery Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Nimmo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harris Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute of Architects</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier's Powerhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Gehry's Dr Chau Chak Wing UTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goods Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Observatory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Register of Significant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultimo Powerhouse Museum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAAS Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultimo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castle Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Powerhouse Museum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Museum of Applied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultimo Powerhouse</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
