<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401963266801032</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/talking-point-gas-contract-uncertainty-a-problem-for-the-state-economy/news-story/0774442482f82ac0af036105384fe5b6</url>
  <title>Gas uncertainty a problem for economy</title>
  <content>
WHEN initially constructed, the take-or-pay pipeline capacity agreement (gas transportation agreement) with the Tamar Valley Power Station was the cornerstone of the investment in the Tasmanian Gas Pipeline (TGP) and now represents more than 50 per cent of the pipeline's annual revenue.
The agreement was facilitated by the State Government of the day and was integral to the market design arrangements that underpinned Basslink and Tasmania's entry to the National Electricity Market.
The pipeline, as the sole means of supply to the Tamar Valley Power Station, remains a critical component of Tasmania's energy security as recently recognised by the Tasmanian Energy Security Taskforce.
The power station and the agreement with TGP are now with Hydro Tasmania. The agreement is set to expire in December 2017 with no certainty on future arrangements and leaving TGP with a potential 50 per cent reduction in revenue.
TGP has worked diligently to restructure its business to reduce its reliance on this agreement ahead of its expiry and has, among other things, made an investment of approximately $18 million to connect the pipeline directly to the Victorian wholesale gas market.
This move enables TGP to provide gas storage services and diversify TGP's revenue away from a sole reliance on Tasmanian industry.
In addition, TGP has significantly reduced the cost base of the pipeline through the renegotiation of major service provider contracts and the implementation of a number of efficiency improvements.
Nevertheless, despite these steps and TGP's willingness to accept a significant reduction in revenue from the arrangements with Hydro Tasmania, the future of our business and a critical infrastructure asset that was facilitated by the state, is challenging if a new gas transport agreement (GTA) with Hydro Tasmania cannot be reached.
The Tasmanian Gas Pipeline has consistently maintained the future of the Tamar Valley Power Station and associated risks to gas transmission prices is a shared responsibility between TGP, Hydro Tasmania, Government and customers. In particular, as a critical security measure, Hydro Tasmania should contract on a firm basis what is required to enable the power station to operate, as well as supply its other customers.
Unfortunately, with the transport agreements of two major industrial users due to expire in August and with no meaningful progress from Hydro Tasmania on an agreement for TVPS, TGP had no option but to offer prices on gas transmission that were significantly higher than their current arrangements that would only come into effect on January 1, 2017 if no agreement is reached on a replacement TVPS contract before then.
Like any business, TGP's prices are set to recover the costs of doing business and without a commitment from Hydro Tasmania, more of those costs have to be recovered from the remaining users.
TGP offered that these prices would be reduced if Hydro Tasmania subsequently entered into an agreement.
TGP is conscious of the uncertainty this has caused for some industries and that is why it has been seeking to negotiate an agreement with Hydro Tasmania for over three years.
It is not just the viability of the pipeline and Tasmania's energy security at stake.
In 2014, TGP commissioned an Economic Impact Assessment of Natural Gas Supply in the Tasmanian Economy, which assessed the likely impact of increasing gas commodity and gas transmission pricing on 11 of Tasmania's major industrial gas users.
The study found at least 3550 full-time equivalent jobs could be lost and a similar number would leave the state if the delivered price of gas becomes uncompetitive.
As a response, TGP has taken a pragmatic approach to negotiations with Hydro Tasmania since 2013 in line with our shared responsibility of mitigating the impact of revenue lost when the current agreement expires.
TGP recognises the impact of the potential price increases on its other customers and has therefore accepted it will need to absorb a significant reduction of revenue even if Hydro Tasmania enters into an agreement.
TGP's last offer to Hydro Tasmania for TVPS would have reduced its revenue from those contracts for gas transportation by some 45 per cent on a like for like basis.
TGP saw this as a very generous and fair offer and certainly in the best interests of jobs and the Tasmanian economy.
This offer has been rejected.
Had this offer been accepted, it would have ensured that TGP would have longer-term certainty over its future and in turn, we would have been able to provide similar certainty to our other customers with a marginal increase on their existing arrangements.
TGP considers a new agreement with Hydro Tasmania is imperative for the future of Tasmania's economy, energy security and the ability for Hydro Tasmania to optimise its position in the National Electricity Market. TGP will continue to negotiate with Hydro Tasmania.
In terms of continuity of supply from late August when the gas transportation contracts start rolling off for some of the major Bell Bay Industrial precinct employers, Hydro Tasmania has finally exercised their option to extend these contracts - something Hydro could have done months ago and avoided a lot of the angst that has been felt by Tasmania's big employers.
This now provides additional time for TGP and Hydro to hopefully negotiate an outcome that takes in the best interest of all stakeholders.
Lindsay Ward is the CEO of Tasmanian Gas Pipeline.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gas Supply</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Gas Pipeline</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Economy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gas Pipeline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TGP</name>
    <count>22</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Electricity Market</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamar Valley Power Station</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Economic Impact Assessment of Natural</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hydro Tasmania</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hydro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TVPS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindsay Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Energy Security Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell Bay Industrial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basslink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GTA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
