<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401916022159705</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/retail/online-pioneer-catch-group-to-open-bricks-and-mortar-stores-20170731-gxm438</url>
  <title>Online pioneer Catch Group to open bricks and mortar stores </title>
  <content>
In its third strategic shift in six months, online retail pioneer Catch Group plans to open as many as 12 bricks and mortar stores in an attempt to recruit more customers ahead of the arrival of e-commerce behemoth Amazon.
Catch Group chief executive Nati Harpaz says the pure-play online retailer, which owns Catch.com.au and the Scoopon, Mumgo and Grocery Run e-commerce sites, is searching for 2000 square metre stores in high retail traffic areas where it can sell a curated range of the 30,000 products it sells online.
The "bricks and clicks" strategy comes less than two months after Catch Group transformed its  - thrusting the Melbourne-based e-tailer into direct competition with Amazon Marketplace and eBay - and five months after it outlaid $2 million to buy the Pumpkin Patch brand.
Mr Harpaz dismissed suggestions the change in tack was an admission that pure-play online-only retailers will struggle to survive as Amazon sets up shop in Australia and as established bricks and mortar retailers including Myer, David Jones, BIG W, JB Hi-Fi, Kmart and Target improve their online offers.

Supplied

"It's about the fact that you have to be open minded around models and the fact that the physical space is viable for customer acquisition and transactions and click and collect," Mr Harpaz told The Australian Financial Review on Monday.

"I've moved away from thinking about pure online retail - it's one retail - you have to be where the customers are."
'We feel ready now'

Mr Harpaz also denied the new strategy was a reaction to the imminent arrival of Amazon,  and is expected by some retail analysts to start shipping orders before Christmas.
"In the first week I started the team took me to a physical store a year ago, before we even knew about Amazon," he said. "The strategy has been in the minds of the Catch Group for a while now.

"We had a lot of things to fix in-house from a merchandise and marketing point of view and a people point of view before we jumped into it - we feel now we're ready."
Mr Harpaz, the chairman and principal of digital publisher Octomedia, took the reins last August, when Catch Group founders Gabby and Hezi Leibovich bought out investors including James Packer, Andrew Bassat and Tiger Ventures
The 40-year-old Israeli-born entrepreneur is
Mr Harpaz said that while online spending is growing faster than spending in bricks and mortar stores it still represents only 7.5 per cent of total retail spending and the cost of acquiring new customers is rising.

"The physical space is actually one of the best ways to acquire new customers - it's a lot cheaper to acquire customers through the physical space and then migrate them online," he said.
"Trying to acquire them through digital channels is becoming more expensive. Google and Facebook are the guys winning the most - you spend a lot of money to acquire the customers and you're pretty much in their hands."
Permanent retail stores will also help Catch Group build credibility and relationships with consumers and enable them to shop online and collect in store or return online purchases more easily.
The Catch bricks and mortar stores will reflect the group's online offer, stocking about 3000 to 4000 products including fashion, footwear, groceries, health and beauty, appliances, electronics, toys and homewares and featuring time-limited deals and shopping events not available online.

Boosting sales

Mr Harpaz hopes to open the first flagship store in Melbourne in October, subject to finding a suitable site, and says there is scope to open three or four stores in each of Victoria and NSW, two in Queensland and one each in Western Australia and South Australia over time.
The Catch stores will be a cross between Kmart, BIG W, Aldi and US-based off-price retailer TK Maxx, selling big-name brands at discounted prices.
The investment will be funded from internal Catch Group resources and Mr Harpaz believes the stores will eventually break even or contribute to profits in their own right while boosting sales across the entire group.

If Catch's "endless aisle" strategy succeeds, it threatens to increase pressure in the crowded department store sector, where Myer, BIG W and Target are struggling to grow sales and earnings in the face of competition from global physical and online retailers.
"The concern will be more from the likes of Myer and specialty retailers who may carry similar stock - they're the ones who will see it as more of a threat," Mr Harpaz said.
"The reality is whether it's physical or online it has the same impact. We are bringing the best we can find at the best price we can find. Currently it's available online and it's going to be available instore as well. If it's not us, someone else is going to do it."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BIG W</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israeli-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eBay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiger Ventures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kmart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catch Group</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Harpaz</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Octomedia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nati Harpaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pumpkin Patch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Hi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Bassat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumgo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hezi Leibovich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TK Maxx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scoopon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grocery Run</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
