<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402010511442469</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/tony-robbins-even-billionaires-can-be-miserable-2017-7</url>
  <title>Tony Robbins explains why even billionaires can be miserable  --  and how to prevent it</title>
  <content>
If you ask Tony Robbins, money won't make you happy.

Even if you have billions.

In a , Robbins explained why you can seem to have everything in the world and still be miserable.

"We have a two-million-year-old brain," he told the crowd at the Inc. 5000 conference in October 2016. "And that two-million-year-old brain is not designed to make you happy. It's designed to make you survive. So no matter how much money you get, how much success, there's this part of your brain still that will see, that's always looking for what's wrong."

What's wrong, he continued, is easy to find.

"What's wrong is always available," he said. "So is what's right."

Robbins explained that finding the latter is more difficult. He has personally trained his brain to find it by using what he's called the 90-second rule - enabling him to "blow through" negative emotions like frustration and anger in a matter of seconds.

And it started, he said, with a decision. "I made the most important decision of my life. You can choose to do this if you want today," he said. "I'm suggesting to you that this decision, if you made it, could be the most important one of all."

That decision, Robbins explained, was to remain in what he called "a beautiful state."

"This beautiful state's not limited - it could be happy, it could be playful, it could be bold, it can be creative," he said. "But those make you feel alive, and you do the right thing for other people, and for yourself, and your family, and your clients when you're in a beautiful state."

He does himself by choosing to be fascinated by things that would otherwise be frustrating. "What are the chances somebody's messing up?" he asked. "One hundred per cent. So now I'm not surprised. I'm fascinated."

Robbins said:

"The most valuable decision of all is to make a decision that will free you. The decision that I'm going to be in a beautiful state every day no matter what, even if it craps on my parade, even if everybody does something wrong, even if they destroy the economy, I'm still gonna be that.

"Because I would love to make you happy for the rest of your life, but I can't do that. Only you can."

NOW WATCH: Ideas videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbins</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Robbins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
