<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401963266801036</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/national/public-service/outside-experts-could-reduce-intrusion-of-politics-in-public-service-work-20170726-gxixot.html</url>
  <title>Outside experts could reduce intrusion of politics in public service work</title>
  <content>
In the long list of great future prime ministers Australia never had, Greg Combet looms large in recent memory. 
Smart, hard working and more steak than sizzle, the former climate change minister and union boss was talked up as part of a next generation of Labor leaders during the party's troubled period in government. But, mired in the Rudd-Gillard dysfunction and unhealthy from years of the fictional notion of frontbench work-life balance, he left politics to work as a consultant and company director. Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
Speaking recently to Katharine Murphy for her thoughtful Meanjin essay on the structural failures of contemporary politics, the 59-year-old suggested one improvement Australia could take from the United States. 
Like former WA premier Geoff Gallop and other political thinkers, Combet proposed people of appropriate experience, knowledge and expertise be considered for cabinet or executive positions from outside parliament. Possible under the constitution now, he said it could help widen the cross-section of decision makers. 
With proper structures and accountability, the idea would see experts - not politicians - leading policy development and delivery and ensure leaders come to the job with relevant experience and knowledge, instead of years on the backbench and climbing party ladders.  

As if the idea wasn't bold already, making it six months after Donald Trump's election might lessen the chances of it being taken seriously. Mr Trump's Energy Secretary, former Texas governor Rick Perry, admitted he initially said yes to the job thinking it involved advocating for oil and gas industries. In fact, it oversees America's nuclear weapons arsenal. The US Senate confirmed him in March. 
Mr Trump has been praised for some cabinet choices while Barack Obama, Bill Clinton and presidents from both sides have made at least a few shocking picks each. Who could forget George W Bush naming Arabian Horse Association boss Michael Brown to lead the disaster recovery authority FEMA? 

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Asking leading experts in medicine, agriculture or infrastructure to join government could see more evidence-based decision-making and best practice guiding policy implementation. Think an economist treasurer, ADF veteran defence minister or an education minister who has been in the classroom more recently than year 12 graduation. 
Any change would need new systems and processes - not least some discussion about how ministers from outside parliament would work with or replace departmental secretaries - but debate about improving the quality of politics in Australia could see the public service have more impact and less politics in their work. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katharine Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FEMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George W. Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudd-Gillard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Trump's Energy Secretary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meanjin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arabian Horse Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Combet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Combet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Gallop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
