<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401843007714141</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/heres-why-compensation-claims-may-hinder-banks-innovation-2017-7</url>
  <title>Here's why compensation claims may hinder banks' innovation</title>
  <content>
This story was delivered to BI Intelligence "" subscribers. To learn more and subscribe, please .

The UK's big banks began selling payment protection insurance () - a product designed to cover customers' loan payments if they fell ill or became unemployed - in the 1990s.

In the early 2000s, it emerged that banks had mis-sold the product in a number of ways, for example, by failing to explain that the cost would be added to customers' loan payments.

The banks ended up setting aside over £40 billion ($US52 billion) in the years after to cover compensation costs to customers who claimed they'd been mis-sold the product. And last week, Barclays and Lloyds both another £700 million ($US916 million) to cover PPI payouts (and other smaller misdemeanours in Lloyds' case), bringing Lloyds' total set aside for PPI to £18.1 billion ($US24 billion), and Barclays' to £9.3 billion ($US12 billion). Lloyds has now increased its PPI provisions 17 times, and acknowledged it may have to do so again.

These continuous provisions could negatively affect big banks' current innovation strategies. Even though incumbents have by now poured significant funds into modernisation, we may see such investments slow as PPI costs keep stacking up. That's because, while incumbents are preoccupied with remedying their historical misdemeanours, compensating customers, and mitigating their reputational damage, they will likely prioritise these measures over their existing innovation efforts. In particular, banks may be distracted from particularly difficult projects like core system  and  of corporate culture.

Moreover, this scandal may affect the way incumbents approach innovation more broadly. The UK's Financial Conduct Authority () has set August 2019 as the deadline for making PPI compensation claims, and will launch a  to encourage more customers to come forward - as such, banks will likely have to make even more payouts in future. The danger is that, if these institutions keep being penalised for a historical misdemeanour - which, significantly, involved the selling of a new product - they might be permanently put off experimentation and trying new strategies, for fear something will go wrong and cause more damage to their business. It's therefore imperative for incumbents to realise that, while mistakes due to negligence should be avoided, failure is acceptable when there is a goal in sight and steps have been taken to ensure compliance.

Sarah Kocianski, senior research analyst for , Business Insider's premium research service, has compiled  that:

Explains the structure and current state of the insurance market.

Highlights areas where insurtechs can help legacy players modernise.

Describes where insurtechs are competing with incumbents and how their models compare.

Provides case studies of insurtechs.

Outlines the legacy response.

And much more.

To get the full report, subscribe to an All-Access pass to BI Intelligence and gain immediate access to this report and more than 250 other expertly researched reports. As an added bonus, you'll also gain access to all future reports and daily newsletters to ensure you stay ahead of the curve and benefit personally and professionally. >>

You can also purchase and download the full report from our .

Learn more:

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyds</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Kocianski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK's Financial Conduct Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPI</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barclays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Access</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US916</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BI Intelligence</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$52</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
