<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401967561768357</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/technology/ahmed-fahour-joins-bcg-digital-ventures-to-stay-in-identity-game-20170728-gxku29</url>
  <title>Ahmed Fahour joins BCG Digital Ventures to stay in identity game </title>
  <content>
Ahmed Fahour, who has joined BCG Digital Ventures as non-executive chairman for Asia, said the future of e-commerce will rely on trusted digital identity and his new role advising the global venture capitalist, part of Boston Consulting Group, will place him at the forefront of blockchain being rolled into some of the world's largest companies.
After , Mr Fahour has re-emerged at BCG, where he worked for 13 years before embarking on a banking career; the new role would take up a couple of days a month, he said, as he "works on the organisation, not in it".
BCG Digital Ventures worked with , which has recently launched. The technology allows people to verify identity in just a few minutes via a smartphone using biometric data, and will be robust enough to satisfy passport or mortgage applications. It could become a new growth business for the national utility; it is understood BCGDV will earn a success fee if the platform scales up but does not own equity in it.
Mr Fahour will now have the opportunity to advise BCGDV as it deepens its understanding of digital identity, after investing heavily in DVloution, a platform that will allow companies to access next generation blockchain protocols - known as Dfinity - which will provide scalable, secure, enterprise-grade solutions on open blockchain. It is hoped these will ultimately slice computing costs while enhancing IT security.

Josh Robenstone

"Identity and digital identity is one of the most important opportunities in the next 10 years," Mr Fahour said on Monday. "How people shop, how people pay and how people transact - these are the three big changes corporations are seeing. And every single one of those three trends is underpinned by identity. You can't do anything until you know who you are dealing with.

"The single biggest issue slowing corporations and governments down from taking advantage of the digital economy, in all three of those aspects, is cybersecurity. It is one of the top three issues in every boardroom in every corporation in this country; but on the flipside, one of the single largest opportunities to do something about it is blockchain. BCG Digital Ventures has identified this as a significant area that will have a significant amount of resources applied to it."
'Desperate need for talent'

Australia Post also worked with Boston Consulting Group to produce a white paper on digital identity, A frictionless future for identity management, published in December. It found a digital identity platform could unlock up to $11 billion in economic value for the Australian economy. The idea is digital identity verification is re-used in physical and digital interactions and universally recognised and trusted by others to prove who customers are.
BCG Digital Ventures has a blockchain unit being run from its headquarters in Manhattan Beach, Los Angeles. The global head of BCG Digital Ventures, Jeff Schumacher, said blockchain will end up being more disruptive than the discovery of electricity.

"One of the benefits of Ahmed working on our business is he was one of the early adopters [of digital identity] and can see the power of corporates moving on this idea."
BCG Digital Ventures' Sydney team has doubled over last year to 80 staff. It wants to double its Australian staff again this year, including in Melbourne. "I am in desperate need for talent," Mr Schumacher said.
The firm is working with about 150 of BCG's 2300 global clients to create new digital businesses and has 24 of these live in markets; sometimes it invests equity alongside clients. As well as Australia Post, is has worked in Australia with Qantas and Allianz.
Paul Hunyor, BCGDV's regional lead of Asia, said Australia is in a unique spot to start exporting its technology capability into the region. "As we continue to learn what is happening from this fast-growth region, we can continue to be a bridge between the entrepreneurial community here in Australia and amazing things at scale, and blockchain is at the forefront of that," he said.

Mr Fahour said along with China there are growing opportunities in India and Indonesia. He said unlike traditional management consultants, BCG DV blends providing advice, implementing that advice, and investing.
"What is unique is DV is prepared to put its own capital at risk with its clients from a balance sheet point of view, to share in that experience and that opportunity on the upside. That combination of being able to be a preeminent advisory firm, an incubation organisation, an acceleration organisation and an investment partner is a unique business proposition."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCGDV</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fahour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston Consulting Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCG's 2300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCG Digital Ventures' Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allianz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Robenstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVloution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCG DV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Hunyor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Schumacher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Fahour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCG Digital Ventures</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Schumacher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dfinity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
