<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402031986279504</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:25</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/business/technology/sonys-vplvz1000es-projector-puts-you-in-picture-for-a-price/news-story/928605e8b1b25faef116cb225d064de6</url>
  <title>Projector puts you in picture</title>
  <content>
Fancy paying $30,999 for a home projector? You can buy a recent year SUV for that, or place a deposit on a country shack. But you may be tempted to buy a 4K resolution Sony short-throw projector anyway, if you have enough cash under the mattress.
That's because it solves the logistic problems of where to put a projector in your room. And you get 4K high dynamic range (HDR) cinema at the same time.
You place it underneath the screen on a table and everything looks tidy.
You don't need to throw the image from 4m or 5m away. So if your apartment has small rooms, you can still house a high-resolution home theatre system.
If the dimensions of the room don't suit, you're not limited to wheeling a projector in and out whenever you use it.
The VPL-VZ1000ES overcomes all of this. And you can get up in the middle of a movie without casting a shadow, or seeing a constant silhouette of your ceiling fan whirring around.
Sony says the projector can produce a perfectly aligned 254cm (100 inch), 16:9 image when it's just 16cm away from the screen.
The projector itself is largish, 92.5cm x 49.4cm x 21.9cm, but it will fit on a decent-sized table. At 35kg, it is heavy. We needed two people to handle the box that it came in. Sony says the previous model was housed in a big metal chassis and was 40 per cent larger and heavier.
The Z-Phosphor laser light and an SXRD (silicon X-tal reflective display) produce a 4K image. The light then passes through a lens and an assembly of mirrors. The result is a sharp image and the short-throw capability.
Sony says the short-throw capability itself is not so costly. Its WXGA short-throw projector with 720p resolution costs about $2500 and targets more the education market such as schools and kindergartens. These institutions presumably aren't so fussy about resolution.
However, the SXRD 4K panels are Sony-only technology and expensive. Crystals in the panel are only four microns apart and Sony says this is very specialised technology to create. Only Sony and JVC do it, apparently.
Then there's the high cost of 4K projection. Sony's 4K home projector range without the short-throw capability is expensive anyway, from $11,000- $90,000.
The light is rated at 2500 lumens, so you project to a screen in front of an apartment window.
So is it expensive to maintain? You do get a five-year warranty or 12,000-hour use warranty, whichever comes first, on your $30K investment.
But you need to clean the filter and change the light about every 20,000 hours. Sony equates that to about 20 years use. I hope they are right.
Presumably at 20 years you'll be cashed up to buy another projector, or newer projection technology will be in use at that time.
Being a laser, the light switches on and off quickly rather than slowly warming up like a conventional projector light.
But what happens if the light source conks out after, say, seven years when you're out of warranty? Sony says it has been making laser projectors since 2013 and in that time, lasers in its projectors have not died in Australia.
The solid metal housing makes the VPL-VZ1000ES heavier than it otherwise needs to be, but Sony says that's preferable than housing it in plastic and having you accidentally step on it and squash your $30,000 asset. It could be lighter and smaller if potential floor usage was ruled out.
Price: $30,999
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WXGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HDR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JVC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SXRD 4K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VPL-VZ1000ES</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony-only</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony's 4K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SXRD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Z-Phosphor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-tal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
