<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401666914051121</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/pm-leaves-door-open-for-mps-to-cross-floor-on-samesex-marriage/news-story/8423fe2aa91e5cd3747020b4d2e26005</url>
  <title>'Treasonous' push for gay marriage vote</title>
  <content>
PRIME Minister Malcolm Turnbull left the door open for MPs to cross the floor on a same-sex marriage vote, as moves in the Coalition to hold a parliamentary vote gain momentum.
It is shaping up for another fiery Coalition party room showdown when Parliament resumes next week.
Queensland LNP senator Barry O'Sullivan said it "borders on treasonous" for Coalition MPs to push for a parliamentary vote on the issue. He warned that if it succeeded it would bring into question the Prime Minister's ability to control the Government.
But first-term Member for Brisbane Trevor Evans, who is openly gay and is calling for the Coalition to hold a parliamentary vote, said only Labor was being helped by the stalemate, which distracted the Government from its agenda.
Mr Turnbull, who supports same-sex marriage but is standing by his party's position to hold a plebiscite, indicated he could not stop Coalition backbench MPs from crossing the floor.
"In our party, backbenchers have always had the right to cross the floor," he said.
Senator O'Sullivan said the LNP at its state conference confirmed its support for a plebiscite on the issue and it was disappointing to see at least one Queensland LNP MP calling for a parliamentary vote.
"This borders on being treasonous," he said.
"If this were to succeed (and MPs cross the floor) it will have an impact on the reputation of the Prime Minister to have a cohesive, operating Parliament.
"Let the people have a say through a postal plebiscite, we can be done in a period of months and it can be an end whether it's yea or nay."
Mr Evans has not ruled out crossing the floor and said while he had previously supported and voted for the plebiscite, the matter was hurting the Government while it remained unresolved.
"This stalemate is distracting from the Government's very real achievements in areas like small business, the economy, passing the Budget and creating jobs," he said.
"Marriage equality should have been achieved by way of a plebiscite in February; that's six months ago.
"In the interests of resolving it once and for all, I'm calling for the Government and the Parliament to deal with this quickly and in a businesslike fashion," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland LNP MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
