<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401877367453260</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/anu-sexual-assault-survivor-codie-bell-says-the-university-didnt-care-20170731-gxm9kz.html</url>
  <title>'They're not interested': ANU sexual assault survivor shares story</title>
  <content>
Codie Bell armed herself with carefully highlighted policy documents when she decided to report her alleged rape to the Australian National University.
The now 23-year-old wanted to be able to clearly articulate how having her alleged rapist return to their former residential hall after she reported her sexual assault was in contravention of the university's misconduct and discipline rules.Photo: Jamila Toderas
Ms Bell dressed well and prepared herself for what she said felt like a job interview. Afterwards, she felt like she aced it. There was enough emotion that her story was believable, but she was clear enough on her demands something might change, she said.
On her way out, the high-level administration officer dealing with her complaint wished her a good day and told her she was lucky to be able to go outside and enjoy the sunshine.
Meetings afterwards didn't go anywhere, and several months after she first complained, Ms Bell received an email saying there was nothing the ANU could do.
"They're not interested, they're not listening, they don't care about me or my story or anything," she said.

Ahead of the Human Rights Commission's report into sexual assaults in university communities, released Tuesday, the ANU Students' Association and Postgraduate and Research Students' Association has called on the university to apologise to sexual assault survivors like Ms Bell.
An ANU spokesman said the university could not comment on individual cases.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"However, we are grateful to those students and survivors who have had the courage to speak out about their experiences," he said.
"Through the bravery of those who have come forward, universities including ANU can better understand the extent of the problem and to improve the way we prevent sexual assault and harassment, and provide the right support to survivors."
ANUSA and PARSA have demanded the ANU go further. The student bodies want the university to implement an accessible, centralised policy based on a culture of belief in survivors and accountability for perpetrators, create an independent office for reports and investigations of sexual assault and harassment, fully fund a specialised counselling service, and agree to a partnership agreement with the two groups.
ANUSA president James Connolly, , said universities needed to take a zero-tolerance approach to sexual violence.
"Universities have all the policies and resources at their disposal to tackle this issue - but they have chosen to drag their feet and not take the issue seriously," he said.
"The release of this survey should be a national wake-up call, and universities must take immediate and meaningful action to respond."
More than 30,000 students have been involved in the Human Rights Commission survey and the results are expected to be damning.
Universities Australia, the peak industry body, will announce on Tuesday that it will develop an evidence-based respectful relationships education program tailored for students and coordinate specialist training for staff.
ACT universities have called in independent consultants, provided training to staff and, in one case, installed extra CCTV ahead of the report's release.
The ANU spokesman acknowledged the results of the survey would likely be traumatic for many people.
"The results of the Universities Australia - Human Rights Commission survey will show we need to do much more to support survivors, and to make sure they are supported and feel confident in reporting incidents to the university," he said.
If you or someone you know is impacted by sexual assault or family violence, call the Canberra Rape Crisis Centre on 02 6247 2525. Nationally, call 1800RESPECT on 1800 737 732. In an emergency contact 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PARSA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Research Students' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Codie Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU Students' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANUSA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Rape Crisis Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
