<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401967561768365</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/real-estate/tasmania/hobart/salamanca-a-harbourside-lifestyle-in-a-luxury-apartment/news-story/43402a0715a7eb65b6b88d471057656d</url>
  <title>Salamanca: A harbour-side lifestyle in a luxury apartment - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
51 Salamanca Square, Battery Point. Charlotte Peterswald. Picture: SUPPLIED

IF there was a lifestyle rating scale, a luxurious apartment in Salamanca Square would score a 10 out of 10.
This three-bedroom apartment overlooks Salamanca's shops, restaurants and cafes.
From the balcony there are views over Hobart city's skyline.
In a colonial harbourside precinct, this modern apartment is set across a generous floor plan showcasing high-quality materials, construction and finish throughout.

Luxurious living space

Entry is via a contemporary tiled hall that leads to an open-plan living and dining area with sliding-door access to a massive, north-facing courtyard.
The adjoining galley-style gourmet kitchen has an extra-large pantry, breakfast bar and room for a family meals area.
There are three double bedrooms, each with extensive built-in wardrobes.

Outstanding views

The master bedroom is luxurious with its spa ensuite and access to a second courtyard.
The master also leads to a convenient home office space, which in turn has walk-through access to the kitchen.
This package includes two undercover car parks.
Battery Point is Tasmania's most expensive suburb for houses, with a $943,000 median for the 12 months to April, and $580,000 for units over the same period.
CoreLogic figures show the unit median is up by 15.7 per cent in the 12 months to April.
House medians, despite being as expensive as Tasmania gets, have also improved by almost 6 per cent.
Almost 60 dwellings have been sold over the same 12-month period.
Charlotte Peterswald has this property listed at $1.65m plus.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salamanca Square</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salamanca</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battery Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlotte Peterswald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
