<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402010511442456</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/banking-and-finance/nab-revamps-pay-incentives-for-more-than-700-retail-staff-post-sedgwick-banking-review-20170731-gxmcxu.html</url>
  <title>NAB revamps pay incentives for more than 700 retail staff</title>
  <content>
National Australia Bank will overhaul bonuses paid to its retail staff later this year, well ahead of the 2020 start date set under the industry's banking pay review.
More than 700 NAB retail branch managers, assistant branch managers and sales team leaders in consumer call centres will move off their existing incentive plan in October.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

NAB delivers $6.48 billion profit

National Australia Bank delivers a full year-profit of $6.48 billion and kept its dividend steady despite predictions it would cut its payout to shareholders.

The plan was among big-four-by former Australian public service commissioner Stephen Sedgwick.
Mr Sedgwick's review came after a string of scandals in the banking sector which have raised concerns about conflicted remuneration. One of his main recommendations for reform was that staff shouldn't receive bonuses for simply hitting sales targets. Photo: Bloomberg
Instead, eligibility for personal incentive payments would be based on other measures and maximum available payments would be scaled back significantly for some roles.
The reforms would also have any sales-based bonus to be "product neutral", meaning it would not encourage the sale of one product over another.

In line with this recommendation, NAB on Tuesday will announce that it is switching to a new "Group Short Term Incentive (STI) Plan", which will take effect from October 1, well before the 2020 deadline set by the Sedgwick review.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The other big banks have also committed to making similar changes to staff incentives in response to the review.Photo: Eddie Jim
NAB chief customer officer of consumer banking and wealth, Andrew Hagger, said the change will mean greater emphasis placed on customer outcomes, actions and behaviours, not just product sales, for staff incentives.
"Our branch managers are the respected and trusted face of our business in the community and their priority is to deliver the best outcomes for customers," Mr Hagger said.Photo: Louie Douvis
"This change to our staff incentive program sends a very clear message: that the customer must be at the heart of everything we do, and that great leadership is both valued and rewarded."
He said incentives would now take into account a range of factors, including risk management, conduct, and adherence to NAB values.
Over the coming 12 months we will continue to review our practices - including things that influence our culture, such as performance plans, incentives, visual management, and team meeting structures.
NAB's Andrew Hagger

"Over the coming 12 months we will continue to review our practices - including things that influence our culture, such as performance plans, incentives, visual management, and team meeting structures - to ensure we are consistently delivering great customer outcomes," he said.
Financial Services Union national secretary Julia Angrisano said NAB had taken "encouraging first steps" in implementing a significant recommendation of the Sedgwick review, which ensures that bonuses are not directly linked to the achievement of sales targets.
"If we get this right it goes a long way towards fixing the cultural problems at NAB and across our industry," she said.
The FSU was this week consulting with workers impacted by changes.
"NAB workers want to be part of the solution of rebuilding trust and confidence as we work together to improve the standing of the industry," Ms Angrisano said.
NAB said it had already made a number of other changes to its employee remuneration structure, including last year moving away from performance-based, fixed-pay increases for customer service and support staff.
Staff receive a standard pay rise of 3 per cent per year, under the 2016 NAB Enterprise Agreement.
The bank said it had also introduced higher standards for conduct and compliance.
The banking remuneration reforms have not stopped calls for a royal commission into the sector by Labor and the Greens.
Follow Nassim Khadem on  and .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB Enterprise Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Angrisano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sedgwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Sedgwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hagger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB's Andrew Hagger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hagger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Jim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Angrisano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nassim Khadem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sedgwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FSU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Short Term Incentive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
