<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401971856735762</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/munster-loss-could-hurt-storm-johnson/news-story/05718b4215d9e00b4e46f6d5571a7484</url>
  <title>Munster loss could hurt Storm: Johnson</title>
  <content>
Melbourne 'big three' enjoy most of the plaudits but Dallas Johnson believes the potential loss of Cameron Munster would be a huge leg-up for North Queensland as his two former teams ready for battle in Townsville.
Munster has been in spectacular form all season and was rewarded with a Queensland debut, outstanding at five-eighth in the Maroons' series-deciding win in game three.
But the 22-year-old is in doubt for Friday's blockbuster after twinging his ankle in Sunday's 40-6 belting of Manly.
The five-day turnaround doesn't help Munster's cause, who provides the x-factor that complements the class of Cameron Smith, Billy Slater and Cooper Cronk in the ladder leader's spine.
"He most definitely is their x-factor," Johnson said.
"Everyone thought when he was playing at fullback he was awesome and it may be remiss to play him at five-eighth, but he's taken that really well.
"He's building confidence off Origin as well, to play that well on debut shows he's going to be around a fair while."
If Munster plays, it would set up an intriguing battle with Michael Morgan after he was given the nod to play five-eighth over the Cowboys playmaker in Origin III, with Morgan playing centre.
But Storm coach Craig Bellamy said he is in extreme doubt after the win over the Sea Eagles.
"I'm not quite sure how bad it is but I'm thinking for him to get treated a couple of times on there then it must be pretty bad," Bellamy said.
"He is tough. If it was nearly anyone else they would have gone off but he is a tough kid.
"I would imagine there is a bit of damage there, I'm no medical person, but for him to finish the game - most people in this game wouldn't.
"I couldn't see him playing next week but he is a tough kid. There's obviously an issue there."
Smith said he has noticed similarities in the current Storm crop to the 2007 grand final-winning team, a premiership eventually stripped due to salary cap breaches.
"It's quite a similar team, (in 2007) we had some older senior players guiding the team around but the others were kids with a lot of enthusiasm, that's what we've got here at the moment," Smith said.
"The one thing that side was they were tough, they were ruthless in how they played their football.
"I can see that in this team, there's no doubt, (but) we've got away to go before we can play like that '07 team did.
"(Against Manly) it was a great victory and we scored a fair few points, but I don't think we played our best football for the 80 minutes."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munster</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin III</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
