<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401769993268617</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:24</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/personal-finance/superannuation-and-smsfs/super-funds-use-apps-to-focus-on-unpaid-super-20170731-gxm6il</url>
  <title>Super funds use apps to focus on unpaid super</title>
  <content>
One of Australia's largest superannuation funds, AustralianSuper, has put its 270,000 contributing employers on notice, telling them that it will use push notifications via its mobile app to inform members every time their compulsory super payments are paid.
The new version of the AustralianSuper app - which has so far been downloaded by 100,000 people - sends alerts to members when their superannuation payment arrives in their account as a default setting.
"Our employers are aware of it. Alerts will pop up on a mobile device saying that your super has been paid," said AustralianSuper group executive of member experience and advice Shawn Blackmore.
"Obviously if you don't receive an alert it's a cue to contact payroll to see where your money is. People can use the app to track their super, rather than relying on the Tax Office to discover any issues."

While the push notifications can be turned off Mr Blackmore said most members haven't done that, with the messaging "making members aware of what they are entitled to".

Employees missing out on their superannuation guarantee entitlements has become a chronic issue for the government and the ATO. In July, Financial Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer moved to close a legislative loophole that allows employers to avoid paying the full SG to staff.
, a figure that includes $1 billion lost to employees who use salary sacrifice arrangements to try to boost their retirement savings.
Celebrity chefs Adriano Zumbo and George Colombaris also hit the headlines this year over their own underpayment issues with theMasterChef
Newer niche fund Grow Super is also giving its 3500 members information about their SG entitlements, but unlike AustralianSuper it uses push notifications to notify members if a monthly or quarterly payment is late or missing, rather than when the SG is paid.

"We envisage this feature will greatly reduce the incidence of underpayment of SG contributions for Grow Super members," said Matthew Keeley, co-founder of Grow Super.
Visibility and oversight

"In one case, we had a member in Brisbane who discovered her employer hadn't been paying her super for more than 18 months when she opened her account and attempted to consolidate her existing super to Grow. Her employer initially denied not paying her super until she showed him the $0 balance on the Grow app."
Mr Keeley said that technology wasn't "necessarily" the solution to ensuring that employers pay SG, but "it does help build trust between the consumer, the employer and the super system".

"Employers are currently required to include contributions on payslips, however contributions are generally paid quarterly and employers are not required to provide any evidence that the contributions have in fact been paid. This makes it difficult for employees to track payments," he said.
"Getting a summary of payments once a year from your super fund is useless in monitoring SG payments. By then it's too late. Giving people visibility and oversight of their super in real time helps build trust and learn good financial behaviours."
Mr Blackmore said that around 1 per cent of its employers have been found not to be meeting their SG requirements, with ATO data showing that as many as 11 per cent of employers miss payments.
"We have an arrears process where we monitor contributions being made and after a period of time if they are late or payment has not occurred we will contact the employer," he said.

"In some instances this can go down a legal path where the employer goes into a payment plan. Some employers have cashflow difficulties ... but still try and get their entitlements through."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adriano Zumbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Keeley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SG</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Keeley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Colombaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grow Super</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tax Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Blackmore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AustralianSuper</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shawn Blackmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>theMasterChef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
