<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401993331572821</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/monash-councillor-says-the-date-of-australia-day-should-be-changed-as-it-is-symbolic-of-invasion-day/news-story/98a1e0deac24deb4812702d7447a2e85</url>
  <title>Fresh push to move Australia Day</title>
  <content>
A MONASH councillor has spoken out against Australia Day saying the date should be changed as it is symbolic of "invasion day".
Councillor Josh Fergeus, who started a controversial discussion among fellow councillors, said the date of Australia Day should be up for discussion within local government.
Cr Fergeus told the Monash Leader the date of Australia Day should be changed.
HAVE YOUR SAY: What do you think of Cr Fergeus' argument? Tell us below.
"This is not something that I plan on moving as a motion or be likely to get support on in council, but I would like to start a conversation about Australia Day celebrations and how they should be more inclusive as possible," Cr Fergeus said.
"I support the date to be changed because it's still seen as invasion or survival day."

A group of culturally diverse Australians are asked how they celebrate Australia Day

HOW DO YOU CELEBRATE AUSTRALIA DAY?
He said celebrating Australia Day on January 26 was a poor decision by the government.
"It's always been an issue where I feel there's been a bit of disparity and there needs to be an open discussion about this."
Cr Fergeus said the National General Assembly of Local Government passed a resolution to consider efforts to lobby the government to change the date of Australia Day.
"January 26 can bring up a lot of hurt feelings for indigenous Australians and we need to think more about their feelings."
But Cr Robert Davies said there was "absolutely no reason" for the date of Australia Day to be changed.
"January 26 is a great day to celebrate because it symbolises the creation of modern Australia by the British," Cr Davies said.
He said it was a Federal Government issue and not one for local councillors.
Cr Theo Zographos said he did not have an issue with having an open discussion about the date.
Monash Reconciliation Group president Felicity Smith said the date needed to be changed.
"Australia Day is not a day of celebrations, it's a day of mourning," Ms Smith said.
"I'm speaking on behalf of the group when I say reconciliation means changing the date."
Monash Mayor Rebecca Paterson said the council recognised that Australia Day was a difficult day for indigenous communities.
"It is a matter for the Federal Government to decide on how and when Australia Day is recognised," Cr Paterson said.
"While Australia Day is still recognised on January 26 the council will continue to acknowledge the day on that date."
Last month, Immigration Minister Peter Dutton threatened to revoke Darebin Council's power to hold citizenship ceremonies after the council pushed to change the date of Australia Day ceremonies.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Mayor Rebecca Paterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National General Assembly of Local</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Fergeus</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 26</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Paterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Reconciliation Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felicity Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillor Josh Fergeus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Theo Zographos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CELEBRATE AUSTRALIA DAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darebin Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MONASH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Robert Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
