<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401963266801002</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/cowboys-keen-to-break-storm-drought/news-story/2559526fcb66065d6ddced4cf6d50abf</url>
  <title>Cowboys keen to break Storm drought</title>
  <content>
The Cowboys will use the reality check they copped from the Roosters' second half ambush to bring the ruthlessness required to prevent a fifth straight loss to Melbourne on Friday night.
North Queensland hasn't beaten the premiership favourites since the 2015 preliminary final, where they went on to win their inaugural title.
The Cowboys had beaten four bottom eight teams in the lead-up to the Roosters clash in Sydney on Saturday night, and led 16-6 at the break.
But they couldn't match the hosts' intensity once they lifted after halftime and Cowboys fullback Lachlan Coote said they learned plenty on the hard edge required to compete with the best teams.
The Storm enhanced their title credentials with a brutal 40-6 demolition of Manly on Sunday and are expected to welcome back Billy Slater from concussion.
However five-eighth Cameron Munster is in strong doubt to make the trip to Townsville after hurting his ankle against the Sea Eagles.
"100 per cent (we learned a lot), they're in the top four and that's where we need to get to," Coote said.
"They showed that in how they were relentless in what they were doing and completing their sets.
"They just didn't let us back in the game. They were relentless in what they were doing in the second half, we were under the pump for about ten minutes.
"To defend your line for that long against a quality team was a good effort, but they got their roll on and we didn't know how to handle it."
Cowboys centre Justin O'Neill intimated the wins over Warriors, Raiders, Panthers and Rabbitohs had papered over the deficiencies in their game.
The Storm are highly unlikely to be as generous and Cowboys coach Paul Green has called for his team to lift their preparation.
"The last few weeks there's been errors there when we've won the game, but we probably haven't played to a level or standard that we'd be happy with," O"Neill said.
"Areas like completing (sets), we knew if we came up against a side like the Roosters they won't go away.
"They're ruthless in attack and defence and can grind a team down, we need to be better there.
"Melbourne are going to be a lot like the Roosters, they're going to be ruthless and not give us much.
"We're going to have to take our opportunities when we can and be better in the little areas."
The clash will feature both teams's Origin stars after they were absent for Melbourne's 23-22 golden point win at AAMI Park in round 15.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin O'Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Coote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
