<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401984741637924</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/tullamarine-sixstorey-hotel-to-go-ahead-with-conditions/news-story/5b32d4fedc395442210de193abfbde7c</url>
  <title>Tullamarine hotel to go ahead with big changes</title>
  <content>
HUME Council has reaffirmed its support for a six-storey hotel in Tullamarine but has slapped almost 50 conditions on the development.
The council has given the go-ahead for the residential hotel with a business centre, gym, cafe and basement carpark at 1-3 Freight Rd.
Councillors had deferred their decision on the development after knocking back a council officer's recommendation to refuse the permit at a council meeting on June 26.
They voted last week to confirm their support for the hotel while enforcing 41 requirements including that a construction management plan had measures to control noise, dust and water run-off and prevented pollutants from entering the drainage system or road network.
The site, which is occupied by a vacant three-storey warehouse, will have 66 apartments and 24 car spaces. Despite a shortfall of 50 carparking spaces the applicant stated most of its clients would come there from the airport and arrive via shuttle bus.
Two objections were received regarding parking and traffic issues and inconsistency with the industrial neighbourhood character.
Cr Geoff Porter said Freight Rd was once a vibrant area but the same couldn't be said today.
He said it had become a blight on the area with vacant and vandalised warehouses. The development was a "great opportunity" to invest in the area, he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freight Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tullamarine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Geoff Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
