<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401980446670532</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/wally-sharpe-of-cranbourne-to-hit-road-for-32nd-great-victorian-bike-ride/news-story/af36560ff2d853de323bd532ab1e8ded</url>
  <title>Wally, 72, to get blood pumping on 500km ride</title>
  <content>
WALLY Sharpe has always looked for something to get his blood pumping.
The 72-year-old Cranbourne resident is about to embark on his 32nd 500km Great Victorian Bike ride.
Before he took up cycling at the age of 40, he jumped out of planes for 20 years, completing more than 600 jumps before it became "boring".
He said some people treated the ride like a race, but he was looking forward to the scenery, saying he loved taking in the Great Ocean Road last year.
"Skydiving was very innovative in those days, pretty gung ho sort of stuff ... it's all tandem these days," he said.
"It just got to the point where I had done it all, I did night jumps and nude jumps, all sorts of jumps, and it got a little boring because it's governed by the weather.
"Sightseeing is very much part of (the Great Victorian Bike Ride).
"Each time you go somewhere different and it's an eye-opener."
Mr Sharpe, a former maintenance engineer who now walks dogs, also enjoys swimming.
He said regular exercise could even keep dementia away.
He said his partner of 30 years, Inga, was interested in theatre not outdoor adventures but was supportive of everything he did.
"She just goes with the flow, she's my backup."
The ride will go from Wilsons Prom to Ninety Mile Beach with riders camping at some of Victoria's prettiest places.
The RACV Great Victorian Bike Ride will run from November 25 to December 3.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Victorian Bike Ride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninety Mile Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Ocean Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACV Great Victorian Bike Ride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally, 72</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilsons Prom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WALLY Sharpe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Victorian Bike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sharpe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
