<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402268209486025</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>15:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/game-of-thrones-character-showrunners-feel-won-their-death-2017-7</url>
  <title>'Game of Thrones' showrunners revealed the only character they felt won their own death scene</title>
  <content>
Warning: Major spoilers for those who have not season "Game of Thrones" season 7 episode 3.
In the surprising final scene on "Game of Thrones" Sunday night, Highgarden's ruler Olenna Tyrell is poisoned by Jaime Lannister.

After Highgarden is overthrown by the Lannister army, Jaime finds Olenna in her chambers, and after speaking with her briefly, pours a vile of poison into her glass of wine. Olenna calmly accepts her fate, and finishes her poisoned glass of wine.

But she go the last laugh.

Olenna, in her final moments on the show, reveals to Jaime that she was the one who had poisoned Joffrey, and asks that he relay the message to Cersei.

"I'd hate to die like your son. Clawing at my neck, foam and bile spilling from my mouth, eyes blood red, skin purple," Olenna says. "Must have been horrible for you, as a Kingsguard, as a father. It was horrible enough for me. A shocking scene. Not at all what I intended. You see, I'd never seen the poison work before. Tell Cersei. I want her to know it was me."

In an , "Game of Thrones" showrunners David Benioff and D.B. Weiss discuss Olenna's final scene:

"What I love about the way she plays the scene is that even though you leave the scene knowing she's soon going to be dead shortly after you cut to black you still feel like she won. She's probably the only character to win her own death scene," said Weiss.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna Tyrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highgarden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joffrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Benioff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D.B. Weiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingsguard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
