<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402096410790400</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/opinion/its-a-problem-we-need-to-fix/news-story/c4ace8bb3cdeda08fcde970ad93f143d</url>
  <title>It's a problem we need to fix</title>
  <content>
THE kind of anti-social behaviour Nightcliff residents and business owners have put up with year-in-year-out is typical of scenes across Darwin and Palmerston on any day of the week.
The shocking images captured by our photographers reveal the extent of seedy activity few would realise was so prevalent in our community.
Nightcliff MLA Natasha Fyles and Chief Minister Michael Gunner have pinned their hopes on the Banned Drinker Register to stop the rot - not only in Nightcliff but across the city.
With the reintroduction of the alcohol management policy less than a month away, only time will tell.
To her credit, Ms Fyles is not backing away from the problem or criticism that not enough resources were being thrown at it to fix it.
Nightcliff police station, while operational, remains closed to the public.
Planning to replace the ageing station is in its early stages.
Community members the NT News spoke to said a stronger police presence would not deter the loiterers who hung around the village.
They say lighting around John Stokes Square and more stringent rules on public housing tenants, in conjunction with alcohol restrictions, are needed.
Alcohol is the driving factor behind the issues in Nightcliff and restricting supply Darwin-wide would surely have a positive effect.
The residents and business owners of Nightcliff Village certainly hope so.
The village could become a thriving community hub for the beachside suburb, a place people want to embrace if the problem is fixed. Hopefully, permanent CCTV is a step towards a brighter future for the area.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nightcliff MLA Natasha Fyles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nightcliff Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nightcliff</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmerston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Minister Michael Gunner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fyles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Stokes Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banned Drinkers Register</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin-wide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
