<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401533770062272</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/sydney-primed-to-take-advantage-of-patrick-dangerfieldless-geelong-on-friday-night/news-story/027544b462e9eba63237c6cb3cd63e56</url>
  <title>Swans sense golden Cattery chance</title>
  <content>
PATRICK Dangerfield's Brownlow-busting ban has rejuvenated the top four hopes of the Sydney Swans, who are now sensing a golden opportunity to infiltrate the Cattery and cement their finals' berth.
Sydney's history-making charge hit a speed bump last week against Hawthorn, but the club received a major double-boost with Geelong superstar Dangerfield facing a suspension ahead of Friday night's blockbuster and on the flip side, Swans' captain Josh Kennedy likely to lead his team into battle.
Clear Brownlow favourite Dangerfield has been offered a one-week ban from the AFL match review panel, setting up the likely scenario that Richmond's Dustin Martin will now be gifted the game's top gong - with any suspension ruling a player ineligible.
FOR:
AGAINST:
However, Sydney are the other big winners as they look to get out of a dogfight for the bottom positions in the eight and cement a playoff platform from which they can launch a premiership bid.
Dangerfield is an AFL juggernaut and if he is rubbed out of Friday night's scintillating clash for the sling tackle that left Carlton ruck Matthew Kreuzer concussed, Geelong will be cut down to size even on their home turf.
"If he plays, you've got to be really good around the ball. He and (Joel Selwood) are two are key players for them there's no doubt about that and every team relies upon your key players and we're no different," said Swans coach John Longmire.

"But they (the Cats) have got a really even team and they're obviously playing on their home deck so they'll have their tails up."
Geelong is yet to decide whether they will challenge the suspension at the tribunal tonight and risk blowing Dangerfield's ban out to two weeks and potentially jeopardising their top-two placing on the ladder.
It's understood the Cats were last night weighing up legal advice on a possible appeal, but Dangerfield said himself it will be a "team first" decision, with no thought given to the precious Brownlow that's about to slip through his fingers.
"It's not ideal but at the end of the day we'll make a decision that's best for the team not the individual," said Dangerfield.
"What's best for the rest of our season.
"(The Brownlow) is the last thing on my mind."
Sydney on the other hand are celebrating the potentially season-defining news that fearless leader Kennedy does not have a serious hamstring injury.
He will face tests on Wednesday, but there is confidence the gun midfielder will play on Friday night and further assert Sydney's favouritism against a Dangerfield-less Geelong.

AFL: A 'little known cause' for the AFL Tribunal could encourage Geelong to challenge the MRP's ban offered to Patrick Dangerfield, reports Mick Warner.

MRP's 'little known clause'
"He'll certainly be running on Wednesday and we'll see how he is there and then," said Longmire.
"(The hamstring) is a little bit inflamed but it's certainly a lot better than what our medical staff thought. That was a good sign."
Kurt Tippett will only come into the frame to play if ruckman Sam Naismith fails to recover from a side injury.
However, even then Sydney could elect to play just the one ruck in Callum Sinclair and ask for Tippett to add to his one run in the NEAFL before he is thrown back into the big time.
Longmire is bullish about injured pair Sam Reid and Gary Rohan returning, but was more reserved in making predictions on Tippett's long-awaited return.
"We'll have to wait and see how Naismith pulls up and we'll make the decision based upon what we think is the best team for this week," said the coach, who is wary of the fact the NEAFL team had the bye on the weekend.
"A bit depends on Sam Reid as well and his availability - he comes back into the team too. It's not about Kurt it's about Sam and what the whole team looks like with Naismith and those guys and our general talls when we find out most of the information on Wednesday."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Tippett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Naismith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cattery</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield-less Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Sinclair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naismith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond's Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tippett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PATRICK Dangerfield's Brownlow-busting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Reid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Longmire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
