<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402019101377296</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/disruption-at-top-of-cochlear-will-not-shift-strategy-20170731-gxmc2t.html</url>
  <title>Disruption at top of Cochlear will not shift strategy</title>
  <content>
The "disappointing" and premature departure of Cochlear's chief executive will not sway the company from its strategy, insists chairman Rick Holliday-Smith
The company announced that chief operating officer Dig Howitt will become the third chief executive in as many years after encumbent Chris Smith signalled he would retire in January of next year.Photo: Ben Rushton
Mr Smith had himself only taken the job over from long-term boss Chris Roberts in late 2015, and Mr Holliday-Smith said the intention had been for Mr Smith to move to Sydney from America and run the business.
However by mid-2016 it had become clear that would not work for his family so it was agreed he would attempt to do the job based from Denver and commuting.Photo: Supplied
Mr Smith had now decided that arrangement did not suit him for family reasons, prompting the shift to Mr Howitt, Mr Holliday-Smith said.
But the leadership disruption would not affect  the direction of the hearing technology company, he said.

"It is the same strategy, we are not changing the strategy, this is about setting out what we need to execute."

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Mr Holliday-Smith pointed out that Mr Howitt had been involved in formulating the company's strategy over recent years.
Mr Holliday-Smith said the board had accelerated its work on succession planning when Mr Smith opted for the commuting role.
"Whatever time frame we [had] expected ... it was shorter than normal," he said, adding that the company had considered external appointments.
Mr Smith will collect a $1.45 million payment in lieu of notice, as well as remaining eligible for short and long-term performance bonuses.
Mr Holliday-Smith defended those payments despite Mr Smith altering his position on his willingness to move to Australia.
"He hasn't left the company short, he has managed the situation at substantial sacrifice to his family. He is quite a family man and the family issue was quite difficult for him," he said.
"I would point out Chris has been with us for 12 years, built the US business which at the moment is a powerhouse, he came out here and did a really good job. He has made a very substantial contribution to the company."
Mr Holliday-Smith also defended the board's position to appoint Mr Smith insisting it was made clear and was "understood" that the job was based in Sydney.
Cochlear's share price has fallen in recent weeks.
Investors were unimpressed by the news, dropping the share price by 1.6 per cent to $142.85.
Asked about the fall, Mr Holliday-Smith noted the price had been falling for a few weeks as broader sentiment and a higher dollar crimped expectations.
But the company also stuck to its full year guidance of a $210 million to $225 million net profit ahead of its results being released on August 17.
"Let's get through our results in two weeks' time ... then we will have a much better idea of what people think of us," he said.
Mr Howitt has worked at Cochlear since 2000 and worked as chief operating officer since July last year.
Mr Smith said he was honoured to have led a company "that has positively impacted the lives of so many patients, and to work with an amazing team of people within our company and industry".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rushton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dig Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Holliday-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Howitt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Holliday-Smith</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
