<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402220964844656</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>15:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4822035/states-airbnb-options-in-focus/?cs=4200</url>
  <title>State's Airbnb options in focus</title>
  <content>
A public options paper published by the NSW government addressing short-term holiday letting, proposes a crackdown on accommodation services in NSW, such as the popular Airbnb website.
Airbnb is a global marketplace to list or find accommodation, from single rooms to castles. NSW Airbnb has about 42,000 listings, providing plenty of options for tourists and regulatory headaches for the government. 
Australian law treats Airbnb differently based on the state that the property is in. In NSW short-term holiday letting is regulated by local councils.  The laws that regulate home sharing in NSW are outdated and cause confusion as they were developed before platforms such as Airbnb existed.
While NSW Airbnb has been expanding rapidly online, it is the community concerns and grey areas in the laws and regulations that have caught the government's attention.
The government lists some of the main concerns surrounding short-term holiday letting as being strata issues in apartment buildings, noise, party houses, waste and parking concerns. It suggests that options to regulate the short-term holiday rental industry include:

Licencing and levies;
A Code of Conduct; and
Placing limits on things such as how long guests can stay, the days per year the property can be leased and the number of bedrooms offered.
These are among many proposals in the government's options paper. The government has not said which changes will be implemented, but confirms it is committed to regulating the industry. 
It is interesting to look at the regulatory approach to Airbnb in other states. Tasmania, Queensland and Victoria are not looking to implement the same stringent regulatory framework. Tasmania has been the most welcoming, opting for an 'open-door' policy giving home owners the right to lease their properties short term as long as they are meeting the safety standards.  
There are concerns that the options the government are considering do not factor in the impact on tourism or the amount of money that Airbnb injects into the economy each year. 

The difficult question to answer is how does the government find a balance to provide for the people renting out their properties short-term as well as protecting the neighbours' and communities' rights? 
Dean Frith  is a partner and solicitor at Baker Love Lawyers  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baker Love Lawyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Airbnb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State's Airbnb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Frith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Code of Conduct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
