<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402105000725168</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/former-property-md-pip-comport-sees-jll-new-activity-work-space-up-close-at-launch-last-week/news-story/269b88b715bfe17b88e704493bf0a93e</url>
  <title>Pip pops in to see a seismic change</title>
  <content>
IT says much for this city that when Jones Lang Wootton chose to open its fourth global branch 55 years ago, it looked no further than Adelaide.
London came first, next up Sydney and Melbourne, and then, intriguingly, South Australia's capital, with Singapore and Tokyo nowhere to be seen.
Pip Comport, the 95-year-old managing director who saw the property giant through the 1960s and much of the '70s in SA, was back for a new office launch last Thursday. He will not have recognised much.
JLL, as it now is, has offices across 80 countries and 70,000 employees. Much has changed in the property industry in that time but the past few years have been wedded to warp factor 10.
Hence its activity-based working model, WorkSmart, a new way of thinking that has led to a new office, albeit several floors lower in the same Grenfell St, CBD building, the standout 'Black Stump'.
"The challenge is around converting office growth on a desk to person space. We always have that flexibility but 13 people to 10 desks is the aim," said current managing director Jamie Guerra.
"There are no set desks, you choose your desk for the day (there is a three-hour use it or lose it JLL dictum beyond SA).
"It's all around IT, having a Wi-Fi experience, moving to electronic filing, using iPads and touchscreens."
Staff have taken a fungible and positive approach to the new work outlook, he said
"We had a half-day sandpit session, touch, pull, play. The stand-up desks, for example, are very good for interactive work but no good to focus on something longer."
The genesis of the move came last year amid thoughts of a move to a near paperless office and through necessity, JLL doubling its staff to nearly 100 people over the past seven years.
Previously 790sq m, the new pad pans out at 1077sq m and will feature interactive wall maps of the CBD and industrial Adelaide to show clients exactly how the markets are moving in real time.
Signage rights have been snapped up too, a four-metre banner at the top of the building an in-your-face reminder of how to get your name out there for commuters coming in from North Adelaide.
"This move reflects our ongoing commitment and confidence in the Adelaide market," Mr Guerra said.
"This year, we acquired two Adelaide businesses, Australian Valuation Solutions and Maloney Field Services, who have a national geographic reach, and this has bolstered our specialist advisory platforms and employee numbers.
"The timing of our new building signage coincided with a new fitout and tenancy for our colleagues in Adelaide - a valued investment in modern and efficient office space for our team.
"As part of our fitout we have selected carpets, paints and workstations with low volatile compounds and have incorporated 168 plants to contribute to the air quality."
WorkSmart incorporates enhanced mobility and flexibility through multiple activity settings and work locations. This includes non-assigned desks, discussion hubs and 'hush' rooms for quiet working.
"This new way of working has transformed our office environment by significantly increasing the creative and collaborative experience for our teams and has resulted in a much more dynamic work environment," CEO of JLL Australia, Stephen Conry, said.
"The feedback from our teams around Australia has been positive. We have never been bigger in Adelaide and we want to accommodate our team in the best possible environs."
"Real estate is an incredibly important transformational industry for our future and a great growth story for Adelaide," said Adelaide Lord Mayor Martin Haese, who attended the launch at the building where his father had an office in the 1970s.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones Lang Wootton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JLL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Lord Mayor Martin Haese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Guerra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maloney Field Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WorkSmart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of JLL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Valuation Solutions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Guerra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grenfell St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Conry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pip Comport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Stump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
