<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401920317127020</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/adani-loan-too-much-of-a-risk-for-taxpayers-according-to-independent-study-20170731-gxmarj.html</url>
  <title>Taxpayers could do their dough on Adani according to independent study</title>
  <content>
A $1 billion concessional loan to the controversial Adani Carmichael mine project in Queensland's Galilee Basin could expose taxpayers to a high risk of losing their money, according to an independent business analysis.
The economic assessment of the troubled project's outlook found the collapsing coal price, the uncertain global picture for thermal coal, and the $21.7 billion project's heavy reliance on external financing contributed to a high risk for taxpayers.

Up Next

Whitlam's son in fight for 'Palace letters'

01:14

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Turnbull labels coal opponents 'delusional'

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has mounted a defence of coal-powered electricity, saying those who think the resource doesn't have a future are 'delusional'.

Among the problems was Adani's hope of using the Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility to fund a key part of the project - a rail link to Abbot Point - while relying extensively for security on the availability of other, as yet unsecured, debt and equity financing.
The assessment was done by the business consulting firm, ACIL Allen, and commissioned by the Australian Conservation Foundation.Photo: Glenn Hunt
The study was fully independent of both the ACF and Adani, and forms the basis of a submission from the environmental group to a Senate Economics References Committee currently examining the "Governance and Operation of the Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility".
Noting that a number of unknown commercial factors made definitive third-party assessment problematic, ACIL Allen found there were multiple reasons why a public loan from the Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility appeared risky.

"The task of securing debt and equity finance for a $21.7 billion project comprising thermal coal mines and supporting infrastructure, including a new 388 kilometre standard gauge rail link and a new coal export terminal, would be very demanding at any time. It would be particularly difficult in the context of the current widespread perception of a negative thermal coal market outlook," its final report states.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Both the failure to obtain sufficient financial support from commercial sources, and provision of concessional terms mean provision of a loan or other financial mechanism to Adani for the rail project must be regarded as a high risk financing arrangement for the financier. Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility's risk management framework has stated that the Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility has a high financing risk tolerance, but they will be imposing the high risk on Australian taxpayers."Photo: AAP
ACIL Allen also highlighted a contradiction between the Infrastructure Facility's rationale, which is to provide finance to economy enhancing infrastructure projects that are unable to secure private capital funding, while also relying on the project principals' assurances that adequate private investment will become available for the mine to go ahead.
"It is not clear how the Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility could meet the direction from government that there be an expectation of full repayment of the loan with interest, while providing support only if commercial financiers do not provide sufficient finance for the project to proceed. It seems that the expectation could not be high if sufficient private sector finance is not forthcoming."
The ACF's economist Matt Rose said lending $1 billion to Adani "would be throwing good money after bad, all in the name of cooking the planet".
"A properly designed and accountable Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility could be investing in clean energy, higher education, telecommunications and loads of other critical infrastructure, rather than this white elephant," he said.
Adani has made significant progress towards realising the hotly contested coal mine, which would be Australia's largest open-cut and the biggest coal export project in the world. This includes obtaining the necessary environmental approvals, negotiating a deferred royalty arrangement with the Queensland government and securing the enthusiastic political support of the federal government.
However, that support had been led by the recently resigned northern Australia and resources minister, Matt Canavan.
ACIL Allen said amid the uncertainties, "one thing is clear" about the project. "The substantial decline of thermal coal prices since 2011 has stripped in excess of $A40 per tonne from profit (after adjusting much larger US$ price declines for depreciation of the $A). This has raised doubts about the likelihood of any significant surplus of revenue over full costs (including a reasonable risk-adjusted rate of return on investment) in medium- and long-term timeframes."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbot Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Rose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operation of the Northern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's Galilee Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani Carmichael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2.2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitlam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Economics References Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACIL Allen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infrastructure Facility</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Conservation Foundation.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Infrastructure Facility</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
