<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401615374442541</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-07-31/where-is-my-name-afghan-women-protest-to-claim-their-identities/1690174</url>
  <title>Where is my name? Afghan women protest to claim their identities</title>
  <content>
A group of Afghan women have launched a social media campaign to protest the country's custom of erasing women's names.
In Afghanistan's patriarchal society, a woman's name should not be revealed, even on her grave.
"Mr X's" mother, daughter or sister, the headstone might read, rather than the name of the deceased.
Publicly using the names of women is regarded as inappropriate and even an insult in the Islamic nation.
And according to Afghan law, a mother's name should not be recorded on a birth certificate.
The campaign, which uses a hashtag that translates to #WhereIsMyName, aims to change this custom by challenging women to reclaim their names and calls on others to address them by their given names.

External Link:

@MaihanWali:When my loving father, brothers and nephews are not ashamed of addressing us by our names so neither should you! #Whereismyname
"Our society is full of injustice for women, basically everything is taboo for women," activist Bahar Sohaili, a prominent member of the campaign, said.
"With this campaign we aim to change many things for women and social media has opened a new window to Afghanistan's young generation."
Campaigner Batool Mohammadi said: "I went to a private bank office to fill up the form, when the manager asked my mother's name, I paused for few seconds, because I had actually forgotten my mother's name.
"Nobody in all these years asked or called her by her name."
Popular Afghan singer Farhad Darya has supported the campaign, posting a picture of himself with his wife and using her name in the caption.
Thousands of Afghans, including authors, journalists and musicians have backed the movement on Facebook and Twitter, aided by widening access to the internet in the country.
Tradition defended as 'way of respecting women'

Niamatullah Ibrahimi, a researcher of social and political movements in Afghanistan at Australian National University, said the country had been experiencing a profound social change thanks to greater connectivity to the rest of the world through social media.
"There is a very influential generation of Afghans who are being exposed to the outside world and these young people are using every opportunity to challenge," he told the ABC.
"This whole campaign of Where is My Name is an example of how a lot of people are using the opportunities that have been made available to them to institute social change."
He said in Afghanistan there was a strong social norm which discouraged people from calling women by their name.
"In general, people who defend this tradition defend it as a way of respecting women," he said.
"I know for a growing number of younger girls and boys, this way of showing respect is not always very acceptable."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WhereIsMyName</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MaihanWali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Niamatullah Ibrahimi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bahar Sohaili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batool Mohammadi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farhad Darya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
