<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401447870714544</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/bombers-chase-historic-high-with-simple-finals-equation-just-keep-winning/news-story/2f371ff56ac1f43ce27cd09ebefb193c</url>
  <title>Lauderdale knows it has to keep winning</title>
  <content>
IT'S an easy equation for Laud-erdale to make history and finish in the top three for the first time in its TSL existence.
Sunday's 13-point win over Glenorchy has given Lauderdale a barrier of two wins over the Magpies. Lauderdale coach Darren Winter acknowledges his side has not done enough to cement a top-three spot yet.

"We are fully aware we need to keep winning," Winter said. "We still have three games left and they [Glenorchy] have a better percentage so it [third position] is still a fair way off, but it was good to get that buffer.
"We have a couple of tough games coming up so if we don't look after those we will find ourselves slipping back down to fourth."
Lauderdale's next match is against Burnie.
"Burnie is a tough place to play footy and we haven't had a lot of success up there over the journey," Winter said.
Another concern for Lauderdale is a calf injury to star Thor Boscott.
"Boscott is probably our most important player [as] he can play in the middle, go across half-back and up forward," Winter said. "He is carrying a little bit of a calf injury so he may need a bit of a spell soon, during the next few weeks."
The Bombers from the north could be dealt their own blow with Richter-Salter being sent to the tribunal after choosing to fight a reduced one-match ban for making contact with an umpire. The hearing is on Wednesday night.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boscott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauderdale</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laud-erdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Winter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richter-Salter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thor Boscott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenorchy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
