<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402092115823082</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/palmo-resident-tees-off-over-pga-event/news-story/63bfef15cdfe53588001cf36ad37487a</url>
  <title>Palmo resident tees off over PGA event</title>
  <content>
IF a reserve in Palmerston continues to be used as a driving range "someone will get seriously injured or killed by a golf ball", residents say.
A drainage reserve between Elrundie Ave and Driver Ave was used as a driving range during the 2016 NT PGA Championship.
The Palmerston Golf Course wants to use the same area as a driving range later this year for the same event, but one local resident has written to the council expressing serious safety fears.
"Using the floodway as a driving range is dangerous and putting peoples lives at risk," he said.
"If the floodway continues to get used as a driving range someone will get seriously injured or killed by a golf ball.
"The floodway was used last year and we had several balls land in our backyard, one of which missed my wife by a metre and hit my neighbour's shed with a lot of force.
"It's putting people's lives at unnecessary risk."
The Palmerston Golf Course said no "drivers" would be allowed on the driving range this year - limiting golfers' abilities to hit long and wide distances.
As a safety precaution, the club will also install 200m of temporary fencing along a bike path to Driver School and do a letterbox drop around the area. Tonight, official manager Mark Blackburn will grant or deny Palmerston Golf Course permission to use the reserve from August 29 to September 3 during the NT PGA Championship. Council senior staff have recommended granting permission.
Mr Blackburn said a practice range was a key tournament facility for professionals to warm up and hone their skills on the day.
He said the council consulted with residents and provided their feedback to the organisers of this year's PGA.
As a result of this feedback, Mr Blackburn said there were several proposed changes to the layout of the temporary practice fairway.
Mr Blackburn said if the proposal was moved, officers would monitor and evaluate the management of the area to ensure all community concerns were addressed.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Driver School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmerston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PGA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Blackburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Blackburn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Driver Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT PGA Championship</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elrundie Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmerston Golf Course</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
