<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401989036605349</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/strathallan-golf-course-la-trobe-uni-reveals-plan-to-release-land-for-housing-development/news-story/6ab7433b7f56252114dbcb09891bd295</url>
  <title>Uni reveals plan for golf course site</title>
  <content>
LA TROBE University has broken its silence over the future of Strathallan Golf Course, revealing a vision that includes residential development, community sports facilities and bike trails.
Vice-Chancellor John Dewar said there were benefits in releasing the 18 ha Bundoora site for "potential development in some areas".
"The site could become ... a home to innovative spaces to live and work," he said.
These would include "exciting new community and recreational facilities, walking paths, cycling trails or outdoor exercise equipment".
He said it would all be integrated within public parkland and bush reserves and the university's wildlife sanctuary.
"We want to hear the community's views on how best to use this piece of land," he said.
The university owns the land and is locked in a dispute with Strathallan Golf Club, which has leased the course since 1996.
The club was given notice to vacate the course by January 2019, sparking a campaign joined by thousands of supporters.
Campaigners, including the Save Strathallan Open Space Community Coalition, fear the land will be sold for urban development.
Darebin Council voted last month to explore buying the site to preserve it as green open space, against officers' recommendations.
The State Government confirmed last week it had begun negotiating a long-term lease with the club for the clubhouse facilities and carpark, which are on Crown land not owned by the university.
A spokesman for Strathallan Golf Club said the State Government had offered a 21-year lease, which would ensure the club would endure, regardless of whether it had a course to play on.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice-Chancellor John Dewar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundoora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Save Strathallan Open Space Community Coalition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Trobe University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathallan Golf Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darebin Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathallan Golf Course</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
