<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401787173138329</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/glencore-extends-lockout-at-oaky-north-20170731-gxmfsz</url>
  <title>Glencore expects national coal union campaign as the lockout continues at Oaky North</title>
  <content>
Miners at Glencore's Oaky North operation  as management at Australia's biggest coal miner digs its heels in over union attempts to recover control over how and when contract and casual workers might be deployed.
On Friday, Glencore told about 190 miners who had been supporting industrial action at the underground mine in Queensland since May that they would be unwelcome at work for a second week running.
Given the duration of the stand-off between Glencore and the coal union, given the fact that Australian workplace law places no limits on how often an employer might lock out workers in response to industrial action and given the reality that the mine is being operated more productively by contractors and staff than it has been by the unionised workforce, it is hard to see the gates at Oaky North being unlocked any time soon.
The Oaky North agreement expired back in 2015 and more than 20 meetings between management and the CFMEU have served only to entrench differences over pay and conditions. With union encouragement, the Oaky North miners started protected industrial action back in May and a month later management responded with a weekend lockout that had the pay of rostered workers docked.

The union responded with a faux middle-ground offer that would have had the financial terms of the expired agreement rolled forward for two years but Glencore accepting shifts in some basic conditions.

Glencore rejected that offer and stuck to its guns on an original offer.
The CFMEU argues that the Glencore pitch would extend existing limits on the right to union representation, allow for unilateral changes to rosters without endorsement by either workers or their union, increase the cost of company-provided accommodation, limit access to dispute arbitration and see some elements of pay set by mine profitability rather than reflect hours worked.
Needless to say, Glencore disputes pretty much all of those claims.
Two to tango

The importance of this stand-off, and the conduct of union and company through its resolution, stretches well beyond the boundaries of the little company town of Tieri, which was built just to the north-west of Rockhampton to host the communities that work at the Oaky Creek and Oak North mining complexes.
Recently , given that the Anglo-Swiss company had somehow found itself dealing with expired employment agreements at five more of its fleet of Australian coal mines.
As we reported recently, the fact that five of Glencore's seven Hunter Valley coal mines are working under expired agreements leaves the company increasingly exposed to the risk of systemic industrial action.
The disappointing fact that at least one of those Hunter Valley agreements expired five years ago and several others have been the subject of renegotiation for more than three years left us wondering whether Glencore had exposed itself to unnecessary risk by allowing this snowball to gather momentum.

But we now recognise that, as Rio Tinto chairman Jan du Plessis noted recently, it takes two to tango when it comes to industrial agreements.
Given the union and their members lose nothing by refusing to settle new agreements, there is a fair argument that says this growing coalition of disputed negotiations is part of a CFMEU plan to make a national contest of Glencore's approach to industrial relations.
If that is the mission then the union's cause might well be advanced as a byproduct of Glencore's successful, last-minute intervention in the deal that will relieve Rio Tinto of its pivotal legacy in the Hunter Valley.
In selling Coal & Allied to Yancoal Australia for $US2.45 billion, Rio Tito has delivered itself the opportunity for a crowd-pleasing capital return and relieved itself of an industrial relations headache.

Coal & Allied runs a coal business of two hubs: the Hunter Valley Operations and Mt Thorley Warkworth. And the enterprise agreements covering both have long expired and given the industry-wide understanding that Rio was a seller of its main coal business, the coal union has long baulked at settling new agreements in preference to dealing with new owners who might need to be rather more obliging.
This is, quite obviously, the commercially sensible thing to do. The coal union is nothing if not savvy in its appreciation and exercise of leverage in negotiations.
Until last Thursday it seemed certain that the union would be sitting down to negotiate its new Coal & Allied agreements with the former Xstrata-cabal that now runs Yancoal.
Adding to the risk

Just weeks after losing Coal & Allied to Yancoal in a brief but fiercely contested auction, Glencore recovered itself a shaping chunk of Rio's unwanted Hunter Valley coal legacy.
In a dazzlingly complicated deal that bore all the hallmarks of the miner's legendarily acute and pugnacious chief executive, Glasenberg agreed to pay $US1.139 billion for 49 per cent of the piece of Coal & Allied that is most aligned with Glencore's existing Hunter mines,
Probably the most unusual part of Glencore's acquisition of just under half of Rio's Hunter Valley Operations hub is that Yancoal agreed to effectively surrender management control of the new joint venture to its new partner.
This was a critical prerequisite for Glencore given that it is the lure of massive, long-identified operations synergies that had it go head to head with China over Coal & Allied in the first place.
But in cutting the deal for control, Glencore has only added to its accumulating IR risk. The unions will appreciate more readily than most that Glencore has paid a premium to recover its place in Coal & Allied and that the pathway to extracting full value of the synergies that justify that premium will be paved with cost-reducing efficiencies and workplace flexibilities.
That the London market lives so uncritically in Glasenberg's thrall has rarely been harder to understand than in the glowing reception offered this second-best and expensive deal with Yancoal.
Yes, sure, Glencore has been able to make something out of defeat. And sure, from the Glencore perspective, the HVO was always the more important of Coal & Allied's two hubs.

But Glencore has ended up paying a healthy premium for less than half of the better half of Coal & Allied. And, given the synergies extracted alignment are shared equally, Glencore will own 74 per cent of the upside.
To get at that value Glencore will pay $US1.139 for the 49 per cent stake in HVO. That position will be collected by paying $US710 million to Mitsubishi for a stake of nearly 32.4 per cent and $US429 million to Yancoal for the 16.6 per cent of HVO needed to get to 49 per cent.
On those numbers it rather seems that Yancoal is being paid a $63 million premium for the release of management rights given that the Mitsubishi metrics imply a value of $US363 million for that 16.6 per cent.
But there is more. Glencore will also cover its 27.9 per cent share of any future royalties that Yancoal has agreed to pay Rio, up to a value of $US240 million. And it has also agreed to cover up to $US300 million in any shortfall on the upcoming rights issue that Yancoal needs to make to cover the balance of the Coal & Allied transaction, which is a little more than $US2 billion.
That rights issue is expected to be confirmed tomorrow and its implications are rich for minorities owners in Yancoal. The biggest of them is Noble Group, which speaks for 13 per cent. But its battling for its life and is in no position to be able to take up its entitlement.
As a result, Noble will be diluted to irrelevance and Glencore's $US300 million of underwriting will be called on. From a Glencore perspective, it is hard to see how that investment is anything but dead money.
The resources team at Barclays was one of the few London houses that did not fall over itself reaching to pat Glasenberg's back on Friday. While identifying the "rare potential" of the deal to release value, Barclays assessed that the Yancoal arrangement valued the HVO assets at $US2.46 billion, which is not far from what Glencore was prepared to pay for the whole business.
"Given HVO only represents 53 per cent of Coal & Allied's production, 57 per cent of revenues (we estimate), 73 per cent of reserves and 59 per cent of resources, we estimate that Glencore is paying (about) $US400 million premium for HVO," Barclays said in a note.

Regrets, we have a few ...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Thorley Warkworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US710</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yancoal</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US429</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsubishi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HVO</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Valley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plessis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Valley Operations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglo-Swiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tieri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barclays</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oaky Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oaky North</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>27</count>
    <score>7.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.139</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oak North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xstrata-cabal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yancoal Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio's Hunter Valley Operations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$300</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US363</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore's Oaky North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US240</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glasenberg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
