<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402100705757809</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/china-military-parade-superior-to-us-by-2030-2017-7</url>
  <title>Beijing's massive military parade could be a sign that China will surpass the US by 2030</title>
  <content>
Chinese President Xi Jinping on Sunday presided over a massive military parade from an open-topped jeep, declaring, "
The world is not peaceful and peace needs to be defended."
And as China's show of force demonstrates, Beijing may have the will and the strength to replace the US as the world's defender of peace.

"Our heroic military has the confidence and capabilities to preserve national sovereignty, security and interests ... and to contribute more to maintaining world peace," Xi said at the parade, just one day after President Donald Trump lashed out at Beijing for its inaction in thwarting North Korea's nuclear and ballistic missile programs.

China's  and  has  in the region, and even as a the  that US power still rules the day, that military edge is eroding.

China showed off new, mobile intercontinental ballistic missiles that can reach the US in just 30 minutes, along with its J-20 stealth interceptor jets, and Xi inspected thousands of troops drawn from the 2 million-strong People's Liberation Army's on its 90th anniversary.

With a nation of 1.3 billion, historian  that by the year 2030, China will surpass the US in both economic and military strength, essentially ending the American empire and Pax Americana the world has known since the close of World War II.

But China can achieve this goal patiently and without violent struggle. China has employed a "" method of slowly but surely militarizing the South China Sea in incremental steps that never warrant a strong military response from the US. However, the end result is that China has de facto control over a shipping lane that sees $US5 trillion in annual traffic.

"The American Century, proclaimed so triumphantly at the start of World War II, may already be tattered and fading by 2025 and, except for the finger pointing, could be over by 2030," McCoy writes in his new book "."

China's J-20 jet also likely borrows from stealth  through a . Though China  in the way the US has, the jet still .

Meanwhile, the US is stretched thin. The US has had been at war in Afghanistan for 16 years, and Iraq for 14. The US has been scrambling to curtail Iranian and Russian influence in Syria while reassuring its Baltic NATO allies that it's committed to their protection against an aggressive Russia.

Under Xi, who pushes an ambitious foreign policy, China's eventual supremacy over the US seems inevitable.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>XI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's J-20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltic NATO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People's Liberation Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mccoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J-20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese President Xi Jinping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Century</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pax Americana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South China Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iranian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
