<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402263914518664</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>15:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-07-31/usrussia-diplomatic-row-kremlin-says-local-staff-can-be-included-in-diplomatic-staff-cuts/1690192</url>
  <title>US-Russia diplomatic row: Kremlin says local staff can be included in diplomatic staff cuts</title>
  <content>
The United States can include its local employees among the 775 diplomatic staff it must cut in Russia, a Kremlin spokesman says, tempering the impact of an ultimatum issued by President Vladimir Putin.

Key points:

Putin ordered US to cut 775 diplomatic staff in retaliation for new sanctions
Kremlin says local staff, including Russian citizens, can be included in total
Analyst says move targets Congress, spares Donald Trump

The clarification from the Kremlin means that there will not necessarily be a mass expulsion of US diplomats as part of Moscow's retaliation for new sanctions that are to be imposed on Russia by the US.
Yesterday .
The vast majority of the United States' roughly 1,200 embassy and consulate staff in Russia are Russian citizens.
Reducing their numbers will affect embassy and consular operations, but that step does not carry the same diplomatic impact as expelling US diplomats from the country.
Still, slashing the US embassy and consular staff by 65 per cent amounts to the most dramatic diplomatic demarche between the two countries since the Cold War.
Commenting on which diplomatic staff would have to go, Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov told reporters on a conference call: "That's the choice of the United States."
He said the number can include people with non-diplomatic status, people hired locally, and Russian citizens who work there, as well as diplomats.
Putin punishing 'Congress's America, not Trump's America'

As of 2013, the US mission in Russia, including the Moscow embassy and consulates in St Petersburg, Yekaterinburg and Vladivostok, employed 1,279 staff, according to a State Department Inspector General's report that year.
That included 934 "locally employed" staff and 301 US "direct-hire" staff.
Forcing the United States to scale back its diplomatic presence will reinforce Mr Putin's reputation at home as a resolute defender of Russia's interests.
That will help burnish his image before next year's presidential election, when he is expected to seek another term.
But the consequences of the Russian retaliation are not so stark that it would permanently alienate US President Donald Trump, according to Alexander Baunov, a senior fellow at the Moscow Carnegie Center think-tank.
By announcing his counter-measures before Mr Trump signed the sanctions legislation into law, "Putin is sending a message that he is punishing Congress's America, and not Trump's America", Mr Baunov wrote in a Facebook post.
"[Putin] has taken Trump out of the direct line of fire and spared his ego."
The Russian measures were announced after the .
The White House said on Friday that Mr Trump would sign the sanctions bill.

Video:(The World)
Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Baunov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Baunov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yekaterinburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dmitry Peskov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow Carnegie Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's America</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Department Inspector General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cold War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Congress's America</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vladivostok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Petersburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
