<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401645439214173</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:55</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/lord-sugar-politicians-should-go-to-jail-if-they-lie-in-manifestos-and-campaign-pledges-2017-7</url>
  <title>Lord Sugar says politicians should go to jail if they lie in campaign pledges</title>
  <content>
Political manifestos should be properly audited and politicians should be jailed if they fail to carry out campaign pledges, Lord Sugar has said.

, "The Apprentice" star said the bosses of public companies would be "put in prison" if they lied in stock market statements, prompting shareholders to buy or sell shares.

He thinks similar rules should apply in Westminster. Sugar said: "If [politicians] lie, which results in massive decisions like leaving the European Union, or gaining votes in a general election, then this should be a criminal offence as it would be in a public company if I lied to my shareholders."

The billionaire said "there must have been a lot of people who believed" the infamous slogan on the Vote Leave campaign bus, which said Britain's weekly £350 million EU membership bill should be spent on the NHS. The £350 million figure was widely discredited during the course of the campaign.

"It's not so bad in a general election because you have got five years to sort it out and the lies and promises will blow back in people's faces," Sugar said. "But Brexit is permanent."

Sugar has also previously attacked Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn over his promise to clear student debt. Corbyn pledged in June to explore ways to  student debt repayment, only to clarify less than two months later that he"" to totally write off borrowing.

In his Sunday Times interview, Sugar, who famously  over its anti-business policies, called Corbyn a "poor leader" and said the Labour Party in "hopeless disarray."

Corbyn's office did not immediately respond to Business Insider's request for comment.

. it's clear you alluded to students refunds to get votes from young impressionable people. You are a cheat and should resign
- Lord Sugar (@Lord_Sugar)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corbyn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vote Leave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord_Sugar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NHS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westminster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Sugar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Corbyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
