<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402401353474940</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>15:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/comment/smh-editorial/transport-a-game-changer-for-the-state--and-the-premier-20170730-gxlzhe.html</url>
  <title>Transport a game changer for the state - and the Premier</title>
  <content>
Premier Gladys Berejiklian has been under fire for backdowns on local council mergers and a fire and emergency services levy. With those about-turns, a perception grows that she is about only winning the next state election in 2019.
The Premier needs to ensure for Sydney's sake, as well as her own, that her biggest strength over the next two years remains just that - a strength.Photo: Peter Rae
At the 2019 election, the former transport minister should be able to say to voters that, on the evidence of the past eight years, hers is an administration that has been able to deliver the transport infrastructure that a growing city urgently needs.
Almost another 1 million people are expected to call Sydney home within the next decade, putting even greater pressure on the city's public transport and road network.
Anyone catching a train in Sydney on a weekday morning can already see for themselves the consequences of a booming population and inadequate provision of new public transport in years past. Overcrowding on trains and station platforms is becoming commonplace.
To its credit, the Berejiklian government has under way the largest transport infrastructure build in the state's - indeed the country's - history.

It is a mix of public transport and road building. Top of the list of road projects is the controversial $16.8 billion WestConnex toll road, which will be completed in stages over the next six years.
On the public transport front, the first stage of a metro rail line from Sydney's north-west to Chatswood is scheduled to open in early 2019. That will be followed by the second stage, a more ambitious component of the $20 billion rail project under Sydney Harbour to the central business district, Sydenham in the south and Bankstown in the west.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

By early 2019, commuters will also be able to catch trams on a light rail line from the CBD to Randwick and Kensington in the south-east. And in the west, the first stage of a new light rail line from Westmead to Carlingford via Parramatta will be under construction.
But Australia's largest city needs more. The onus is on the Berejiklian government to make a success of the projects it has undertaken, in order that it is able to do more.
The $2.1 billion light rail line from the CBD to the south-east is a classic case. There is potential for it to be an unmitigated success, and an example to future governments of the sort of transport projects they should be delivering in Sydney.
But there is also the potential for the project to stand as a warning to governments of not attempting to take on ambitious transport infrastructure.
It is to be hoped that the former scenario eventuates. For that to happen, the state government will need to remain extra attentive to the details - namely, the delivery of these multibillion-dollar projects.
Importantly, it needs to instil confidence in the community that taxpayer money is well spent, and the benefits outweigh the downsides such as disruption from construction.
A report into the inner-city light rail by the state's auditor-general in November found the government's management of the project "suffered many of the same problems" as those with WestConnex and the $38 million Albert "Tibby" Cotter bridge at Moore Park.
They included tight time frames, narrow project scopes and underestimated costs and overestimated benefits.
The Berejiklian government has tough choices ahead about the next generation of projects it pursues, and whether public transport should be prioritised over motorways.
It has to set the ground rules for private sector involvement, and be an informed strategic client.
And it has to ensure it is not held hostage by narrow political and business interests at the expense of city-shaping transport projects that stand the test of time.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bankstown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westmead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tibby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chatswood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WestConnex</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlingford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Rae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
