<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402156540333729</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:54</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/mark-cuban-healthcare-tweets-2017-7</url>
  <title>'Single payer is not the solution': Mark Cuban goes off on early-morning tweetstorm about healthcare</title>
  <content>
Billionaire business mogul Mark Cuban went off on a healthcare-related tweetstorm that stretched from late Sunday night through early Monday morning, pitching some of his own ideas on how to improve the US healthcare system just days after the Republican plan to repeal and replace the Affordable Care Act was killed in the Senate.

Although Cuban, who has teased reporters about making a , said "single payer is not the solution," he mused about how the government could lower healthcare costs by eliminating insurance altogether.

The owner of the NBA's Dallas Mavericks and star of ABC's "Shark Tank" also suggested that the federal government should invest in doubling the capacity of medical schools while offering "needs-based grants" to double the population of medical students.

"Dear politicians. Let me ask a question," he began his string of tweets. "If every person in our country had health insurance, would we be any healthier?"

Read Cuban's tweets:

Cuban has spoken out on the healthcare issue a number of times during the course of President Donald Trump's young administration. In March, , also known as Obamacare, as House Republicans were attempting to pass legislation on the matter.

In a post on his blog, , Cuban outlined a system that amounted to single-payer coverage for chronic physical and mental illnesses and life-threatening injuries, and standard insurance for all other healthcare.

Cuban wrote:

"Whether it's Medicaid or a new program, every single person in this country should be covered 100% for chronic physical or mental illness and for any life-threatening injury.
"The premiums that we are paying to insurance companies as individuals or as company coverage for these significant risks would go from the insurance companies to the IRS. Only the cost of covering the what's left would continue being paid to the insurance companies.
"It would not be hard to do the maths. Every insurance company does this analysis already. The government does this analysis already. We all would end up paying more in taxes, but less in insurance and healthcare costs over time.
"There would be no mandates. There would be no individual penalties. No tax credits. No subsidies. No offsets or deductions for buying higher end insurance. This will be single payer (yes I know it's a dirty phrase in this country) for chronic physical or mental illness and for any life threatening injury.
"Everything not covered by the above can be covered by insurance sold on the free market, managed by the states, sold across state lines, without government interference."

A , Cuban suggested at a recent event that he may seek the presidency if Trump "lasts four years."

"He's not setting the best example," Cuban said of Trump at OZY Fest in New York earlier this month. "If he lasts four years, I'll be there to kick his a-."

Dear politicians. Let me ask a question. If every person in our country had health insurance, would we be any healthier ?
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

I like the ACA for the limits it put on ins comp finances. It took us up to 90pct insured, but why haven't we gotten healthier as a country?
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

Read this/other studies and agree. But the goal is to make healthcare better,cheaper & universal not maxout the # of health ins customers
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

No chance a system where you give an ins comp $, then beg them to spend it among limited options is the way to optimise our healthcare
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

Insurance is a financial instrument. Full Stop. In any negotiation over a financial transaction the party with the cash and leverage wins
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

The problem isn't profits. It's the artificial costs introduced by ins companies to retain control and leverage
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

How do you design a healthcare system that doesn't include insurance?Take them out and costs drop 50pct or more for most services and pharma
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

First thing I would do is invest fed funds to double med school capacity and offer needs based grants to double med students to 40k
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

No one says it happens overnight
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

Single Payer is not the solution.The tax $ paid to gov is = $ to ins comps and both deliver less in healthcare than $ they receive
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

I think there are better solutions than single payer that also get better results
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

Governments send the same letters and make the same kind of decisions when there are tax dollars involved
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

Exactly why single payer won't work. You will get lower cost health care but get taxed into oblivion
- Mark Cuban (@mcuban)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Affordable Care Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IRS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Cuban</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shark Tank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA's Dallas Mavericks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuban</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicaid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obamacare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ozy Fest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
