<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402736360930528</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>17:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/world/china-hits-back-at-donald-trump-dont-blame-us-for-north-korea-20170731-gxmn2p.html</url>
  <title>China hits back at Donald Trump: Don't blame us for North Korea</title>
  <content>
Beijing: China hit back on Monday at Twitter posts from US President Donald Trump over trade and the North Korea crisis, saying the two issues should not be linked and that the US is to blame for Pyongyang's military buildup.
"We think the North Korea nuclear issue and China-US trade ... are in two completely different domains," Chinese Vice Commerce Minister Qian Keming said at a news conference in Beijing on Monday.

Up Next

Xi oversees massive military parade

01:10

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Pence blasts Russia's 'unacceptable' activities

US Vice President Mike Pence confirms President Donald Trump will sign a Congressional bill imposing new sanctions on Russia and warns North Korea that "all options are on the table".

"They aren't related. They should not be discussed together."
He added that trade between China and the US has been beneficial to both nations despite a US trade deficit with China that reached almost $US350 billion last year.

China  in the wake of Mr Trump's latest Twitter posts
China's state-run news agency Xinhua also published an editorial Monday saying China was "actively working with the US side to explore ways to restore the trade balance."

It blamed the North Korea nuclear issue on "the decades-long animosity" between Pyongyang and Washington.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"As a neighbour of the (North Korea), China knows well it has a lot to lose if the Korean Peninsula slides further away from denuclearisation," the editorial said.Photo: AP
"So it has been making strenuous efforts ... to maintain the fragile calm on the peninsula and work toward an early solution to the problem."
Mr Trump has repeatedly claimed that China could easily pressure North Korea into curtailing its missile and nuclear programs. He raised the issue again in tweets Saturday.

I am very disappointed in China. Our foolish past leaders have allowed them to make hundreds of billions of dollars a year in trade, yet...

...they do NOTHING for us with North Korea, just talk. We will no longer allow this to continue. China could easily solve this problem!

North Korean leader Kim Jong-un said last week the his nation's recent missiles tests prove he has .
Some US analysts concur that Los Angeles and Chicago appear to be technically within range of the North's missiles.
China continues to trade with North Korea but says it follows United Nations sanctions aimed at pressuring Pyongyang to back off its military buildup. It has rejected additional US sanctions, saying the standoff must be resolved through dialogue.
Japan, however, sided with Trump. Prime Minister Shinzo Abe said on Sunday he was disappointed in China's response to North Korea's latest tests and agreed with Mr Trump that China must apply more pressure on North Korea.
Karl Dewey, an analyst for Jane's by IHS Markit, said China has political reasons not to turn its back on the North.
"Ultimately it remains in Beijing's interests to support North Korea economically," Mr Dewey said. "A unified peninsula under Seoul's leadership creates a major US ally on China's doorstep."
McClatchy
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IHS Markit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xinhua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Dewey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dewey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China-US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McClatchy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seoul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Vice Commerce Minister Qian Keming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Shinzo Abe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
