<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402740655897905</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>17:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/charlotte-hornets-nike-uniforms-michael-jordan-jumpman-logo-2017-7</url>
  <title>Nike's new Charlotte Hornets uniforms have one detail different than the rest of the NBA</title>
  <content>
The Charlotte Hornets are the latest NBA team to unveil their new Nike uniforms for the upcoming 2017-18 season and this set has one detail that will be different than the rest of the NBA  - their owner's own logo.

The NBA is switching from Adidas to Nike as their official uniform provider this season and several teams have already shown off their new uniforms. While most of the changes have been subtle so far, the biggest difference has been the inclusion of the Nike logo on the front of the jerseys and shorts. Adidas did not have their logo on the uniforms.

But while other teams are using Nike's swoosh on their unis, the Hornets' new uniform set has the "Jumpman" logo of Nike's subsidiary, Jordan Brand. Of course, the Hornets are owned by Jordan Brand's namesake, Michael Jordan.

While the Jumpman logo is used on the uniforms of several NCAA teams,  that the Hornets will be the only NBA team that will be using Jordan's likeness.

In contrast, here is how the Nike swoosh looks on the new Detroit Pistons uniforms:

The Hornets' new uniform unveiling did not include any advertising patches on the opposite side of the jersey. Rovell also noted that the Hornets are still free to sell that space to an advertiser, despite the inclusion of the Jordan Brand logo. So far,  this upcoming season.

Here is the video unveiling the Hornets' new unis:

Yesterday, we unveiled our new  jerseys and a historic jersey partnership with .
Trending has the story
- Detroit Pistons (@DetroitPistons)

THE REVEAL.
Introducing our new Hornets uniforms - the FIRST  uniform for a U.S. pro team.
????????
- Charlotte Hornets (@hornets)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DetroitPistons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Brand</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hornets</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlotte Hornets</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detroit Pistons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adidas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCAA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
