<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402693411256861</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>16:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4824638/shorten-calls-for-state-funeral-for-les-murray/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Shorten calls for state funeral for Les Murray</title>
  <content>
Les Murray. Picture: ANTHONY JOHNSON

Opposition Leader Bill Shorten has called for Les Murray to be awarded a state funeral, labelling the football broadcaster a "national icon" for his role in promoting multiculturalism in Australia.

Murray died on Monday morning aged 71 after a lengthy battle with illness. Shorten has urged NSW premier Gladys Berejiklian to acknowledge his services to the community with a prestigious memorial service reserved for Australia's most distinguished citizens.
Iconic SBS football presenter Les Murray AM has passed away following a battle with illness. Courtesy SBS
"I sincerely hope the state government offers Les Murray's family a state funeral and I certainly think they should," Mr Shorten said. "Les is a national icon who did so much to grow the world game and to champion multicultural Australia. He deserves nothing less than the full symphony of tribute and respect. Ultimately it's a decision for Les' family, but I think the offer should be made at least. I can think of few people as deserving of this high honour."
Murray rose to fame during a 34-year career with SBS where he worked as a football commentator, pundit and journalist beginning with the 1980 National Soccer League grand final until the 2014 FIFA World Cup in Brazil.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull praised his work in promoting the global game in Australia, opening the world to living rooms and using football as a means of telling world stories.
"Farewell Les Murray," Mr Turnbull said. "You championed the beautiful game - the world game - over so many years. You and Johnny Warren really made the world game Australia's game."
Football Federation Australia chairman Steven Lowy praised the work of his close friend, who was inducted into the FFA hall of fame in 2003.
"In Les I have lost a dear friend. My heart goes out to his family and loved ones.
"Les and I spoke the same language - literally. He was born in Budapest; I was born in a small village nearby. We both arrived in Australia in the 1950s.
"We both brought with us a love of football.  Football was our common cause.
"He was one of its most loyal sons and never lost faith in the beautiful game, or its potential in this country. As such he was an invaluable ally and adviser to me, and a tireless promoter of the game.

"There will be another opportunity to pay my respects to Les, and to his legacy, but for now I want to join with the entire football community in mourning the loss of this kind and generous man.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Soccer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Lowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIFA World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
