<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402607511909433</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>16:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4792150/gym-hits-treadmill-for-suicide-prevention/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Gym hits treadmill for suicide prevention</title>
  <content>
ALL DAY: Anytime Fitness, Warners Bay owner Scott Robertson is hosting a 24-hour treadmill challenge, raising funds and awareness for suicide prevention.

Scott Robertson wants the people of Newcastle and Lake Macquarie to adopt a Forrest Gump attitude in support of a nationwide 24-hour treadmill challenge to raise funds and awareness for Suicide Prevention Australia.
Mr Robertson is the owner of Anytime Fitness, Warners Bay, who are taking on the day-night challenge starting at 6pm on July 28.
Individuals do not have to do the whole 24 hours themselves. They can book unlimited 15-minute time slots on a treadmill at the Warners Bay gym for a cost of $15 per session.
It was a cause that had particular resonance for Mr Robertson.
"The idea behind is to get community awareness around suicide," he said.

"It's the biggest killer in 18 to 44-year-olds, particularly males and that's one of the main reasons we got involved because our main membership is 18 to 34-year-old males, that's our core group.
"The statistics are eight people dying by suicide each day in Australia, which I was surprised by.
"There is also that association between physical activity and mental health benefits, so it just fits.
"The idea is we try to get people to register for 15 minutes. Anyone can register and they can register for as many time slots as they want."
Over 200 Anytime Fitness clubs in Australia will be involved in the campaign, with the aim of raising $500,000 for Suicide Prevention Australia. More people die by suicide each than road accidents or skin cancer.
There are 96 spots to fill and you can find out more at  .

Lifeline 13 11 14.
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warners Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forrest Gump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Robertson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suicide Prevention Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Robertson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anytime Fitness</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
