<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402865209951872</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>17:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/tony-blair-did-not-commit-a-crime-by-ordering-iraq-invasion-british-court-rules-20170731-gxmn3x.html</url>
  <title>Tony Blair did not commit a crime by ordering Iraq invasion, British court rules</title>
  <content>
London: Saddam Hussein's former army chief of staff has failed in a bid to prosecute former British prime minister Tony Blair over the 2003 invasion of Iraq.
General Abdulwaheed Shannan Al Rabbat's lawyers had argued that Mr Blair and former foreign secretary Jack Straw should be arrested for 'crimes of aggression'.Photo: AP
Last year's Chilcot report, they said, established that Hussein had not posed an immediate threat to the UK, that the UK's intelligence regarding weapons of mass destruction had been presented with "unwarranted certainty", and that the invasion had been unnecessary and without United Nations authority.
Mr Blair and Mr Straw "should be tried before a court so they could be held to account for their criminal breach of the law", the general's legal team argued.

The English High Court on Monday ruled that it was bound by a previous decision by a higher court that there was no such crime as the 'crime of aggression'.
The general, who lives in Oman and cannot travel to the UK because he doesn't have a passport, had sought the High Court's permission to take the case to the Supreme Court, which could have reviewed and overruled the precedent.

The government opposed the claim, saying it was "hopeless".

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Neither Mr Blair nor Mr Straw took any part in the case - though they would likely have taken a closer interest if it had reached the Supreme Court.Photo: AP
In 2006 the House of Lords, then the UK's ultimate court of appeal, ruled that the crime of aggression, though it did exist in customary international law, did not exist in the criminal law of England.
In that case, a group of activists had been charged over sabotage at an RAF site in 2003. 
They tried to argue that they had been using reasonable means to prevent the commission of a crime of aggression: the bombing of Iraq.
On Monday Lord Thomas of Cwmgiedd, delivering the High Court's judgement, said there was "no prospect of the Supreme Court holding that (the previous) decision was wrong", because its reasoning was "unassailable".
"It is for Parliament to make such conduct criminal under domestic law," Lord Thomas wrote. "Parliament deliberately chose not to do so. The courts cannot usurp that function.
"It is our duty to refuse permission to bring the proceedings for judicial review."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Lords</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Blair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Abdulwaheed Shannan Al Rabbat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Straw</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Blair</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Straw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saddam Hussein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday Lord Thomas of Cwmgiedd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hussein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chilcot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
