<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401452165681896</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>12:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-league/we-hate-the-referee-because-he-chooses-to-be-a-referee--but-should-we-20170731-gxmbx4.html</url>
  <title>We hate the referee because he chooses to be a referee ... but should we?</title>
  <content>
As you approach River Plate's imposing El Monumental stadium in Buenos Aires, and the crush of the crowd starts to squeeze, you are ordered to take everything out of your pockets.
You are then funnelled towards an imposing line of policemen. They frisk almost every square inch of your body like it's a third date before you are allowed to continue past more imposing policemen holding even more imposing machine guns.Photo: AAP
The police are specifically looking for weapons or projectiles and you are told by your friendly tour guide the target isn't necessarily rival fans who watch from behind large fences with barbed wire at the top.
The target is usually the referee.Photo: AAP
He then tells you the story about the elderly River fan who was so incensed about the whistleblower's performance one night that he took out his false teeth and hurled them across the pitch.
He had to throw his teeth because he had nothing else to throw. One of the players picked them up and threw them back to the elderly man, who put his teeth back in and again started yelling abuse  at the referee.

"We hate the referee because he chooses to be a referee," your guide tells you.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

And in that moment, if you closed your eyes and blocked out the sounds of chanting fans and an electric organ, and forgot about the intoxicating aroma of about 20 flares going off all around you (flares aren't considered projectiles, evidently), you could've almost thought you were at an NRL match.Photo: Getty Images
This could've been Allianz. Or ANZ. Or Kogarah. Or 1300Smiles ...
When it comes to hatin' on the referee, nobody quite does it like rugby league, even old men wielding false teeth. For the best part of a hundred years or more, the referees have been in crisis. That's some crisis.
Dragons coach Paul McGregor  following his side's loss to Newcastle on Saturday. The NRL is yet to sanction him but expect a breach notice to come flying out of head office at any moment.
"Embarrassing and incompetent," is how McGregor described two tries that were disallowed by the Bunker.
Watch a replay of McGregor's entire media conference and it isn't really a rant at all. It's controlled and direct. If this is a rant, Canberra coach Ricky Stuart's spray the week before was a nuclear attack.
Stuart doesn't cop a fine but McGregor will? Huh?
Yet another inconsistency in this godforsaken game! Someone must be sacked! Tony Archer! Brian Canavan! Todd Greenberg! David Gallop ... Oh, he's no longer there. Well, sack him any way.
Referees, video referees and referees bosses have been the game's punching bag for decades but as the finals approach and the neck ties of coaches of underperforming sides start to tighten, some are throwing harder punches than usual.
Stuart did it last week. McGregor and under-fire Souths coach Michael Maguire squared them up this week. Archer should book a holiday to Port Douglas for this weekend.
It is too simplistic to say it's just a diversionary tactic, a smother, to take the heat out off a side that's not going to make the finals or, in the case of the Dragons, one that's walking the tightrope in the last five rounds.
More than that, it's part of the brutal culture of rugby league to take a flamethrower to everyone and everything. It's why we equally love and hate the game.
Indeed, when some of us see a cement truck on our roads, we don't think of someone getting a new driveway but former Manly coach Bob Fulton and how he wanted one to run over Bill Harrigan, still regarded as the best referee ever.
Harrigan had his detractors, not least because he worked his way around the field like he was in the middle of a photo shoot for Men's Health, but Harrigan had what the modern-day referee does not.
He had control.
He had confidence in his own ability to send players from the field when he had to. To sin-bin four players in one night in 2002 like he did to Parramatta in their grand final rematch against Newcastle. The Eels kept trying to slow down the game. Billy kept sending them to the sidelines and Brian Smith's eyes started to roll back into his head.
Can you imagine a current referee sin-binning three players for ruck infringements and one for dissent in the one match?
In the attempt to help the referee, the NRL has actually taken too much away from the referee; his role has devolved from being the man in charge to just another avatar in the big PlayStation game that is rugby league.
As a consequence, the men in the middle are too gun shy to make a decision unless the committee of touch judges and those in the Bunker seemingly all agree.
It's why Canberra's Sia Soliola can take off Storm fullback Billy Slater's head but isn't sent from the field. It's why the referee appears too scared to enforce the actual rules, knowing that to do so will bring howls of condemnation for "lacking consistency".
Would referees of the past accept a game in which players try to play the ball mid-tackle? Play the ball on one knee? Merely walk over the ball? Without attempting to strike it with their foot? As markers on the other side stand side by side the bloke playing the ball? And those outside him stand offside? As the bloke at dummy half passes it forward? To a teammate who is offside?  
Would they have allowed defenders to "fall asleep" on ball carriers mid-tackle as their teammates form the defensive line behind them? Would they allow the top defensive teams to give away penalty after penalty on their own tryline with impunity and certainly not the sin-bin crackdown that was promised at the start of the season?
And would referees ...
Stop it! Here you go again, bagging referees. Stop hating the referee. We love the referee because, well, thank God someone actually wants to be the referee.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Gallop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUENOS AIRES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>El Monumental</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrigan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allianz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Archer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra's Sia Soliola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd Greenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Harrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Maguire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Men's Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Plate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PlayStation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kogarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Fulton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
