<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402873799886588</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>17:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/03/32/police-had-to-shoot-vic-teen-coroner</url>
  <title>Police had to shoot Vic teen: coroner</title>
  <content>
Police had no choice but to shoot a radicalised teenager who stabbed officers outside a Melbourne police station, a coroner has found.
Numan Haider, 18, died instantly when shot in the head attacking two counter-terrorism officers in a pre-arranged meeting outside Endeavour Hills police station in September 2014.
Victorian coroner John Olle on Monday made no adverse findings against ASIO, Victoria Police, or Australian Federal Police.
""There was no time or opportunity for the officers to use a lower force to prevent further injuries," Mr Olle said.
Two Victorian and federal police officers had arranged to meet Haider outside the station to assess his attitude and determine whether he was a threat to national security.
At that stage, authorities considered the teen to be a low threat of launching a "lone-wolf" attack, Mr Olle said.
Haider had come to the attention of the Australian Security Intelligence Organisation earlier that year and his calls were being monitored.

Related Articles

He had attended Al-Furqan mosque where extreme forms of Islam were sometimes discussed, and his passport application has been rejected over concerns he had become radicalised.
On the day of the attack, the Joint Counter-Terrorism Team searched Haider's family home but he was not there.
Police then decided to engage in a "soft, non-confrontational approach" and arranged to meet the teen at Endeavour Hills, where he produced a knife and stabbed the officers before one of them shot him.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al-Furqan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Endeavour Hills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Security Intelligence Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haider</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Numan Haider, 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Olle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Counter-Terrorism Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Olle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
