<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402693411256864</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>16:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/2985743/pictures-of-the-past-hunter-war-trophies/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>PICTURES OF THE PAST: Hunter war trophies</title>
  <content>
This photo of a tram in Newcastle East (leaving Parnell Place en route to Adamstown) show some old guns in the park. I've chosen this picture (previously published in the book, Destination Newcastle, because of the response to a recently published photo of a captured World War I German gun at Dudley Beach.

This photo of a tram in Newcastle East (leaving Parnell Place en route to Adamstown) show some old guns in the park.

I've chosen this picture (previously published in the book Destination Newcastle) because of the response to a recently published photo of a captured World War I German gun at Dudley Beach.
Reader Geof Mansfield made these interesting comments on the Dudley photo:
"The gun in the photo appears to be a late-version 77mm light field gun known as FK16 (Field-Kanone 16 or 1916 field gun). German field gun batteries were rearmed with this gun late in the Great War. The gun probably came to Australia as a war trophy and was allocated in the early 1920s to a local community or army unit.
"Dudley was allocated a trench mortar and two machine guns as war trophies, which were dispatched to Dudley Colliery from Sydney in mid-1921. So where did the gun in the photo come from?
"According to the records of the Australian War Memorial, a total of 14 German guns of varying calibres were allocated to the Hunter Region, the lion's share going to the largest towns of Newcastle, West Maitland, East Maitland and Singleton. Smaller rural towns, villages and hamlets generally received a minenwurfer (trench mortar) and/or a machine gun, depending on the size of their population in the 1913 census. Inevitably trophy size became synonymous with civic importance, and as a result some civic leaders went to extraordinary lengths to try and secure their community a gun.
"West Wallsend and Boolaroo were the only communities in Lake Macquarie to receive a gun, but these guns were not FK16s. Further, the West Wallsend gun was scrapped in 1939.

"Two army units based in Newcastle received 77mm guns but one was scrapped in 1941 and the other was removed by the army in 1952.

"Some records indicate that Merewether Council received a 77mm gun but I have been unable to find hard evidence in this regard. Furthermore, the guns allocated to Newcastle Council included the allocation to suburban councils such as Merewether.
"In terms of the gun being located close to World War II bunkers while, in 1942, the Australian army had a plan to recondition former war-trophy guns (including 77mm guns) for operational use in Australia, it would appear the plan was not proceeded with.

"Hopefully, some of your other readers have been able to shed some light on the history of this gun. Today, restored 77mm guns can be found at Muswellbrook and Murrurundi.

"The only war trophy remaining in the City of Lake Macquarie is a 250mm trench mortar, which languishes in poor condition in Speers Point Park, its existence and significance unknown to most of its citizens at a time when Australia is remembering the centenary of the war to end all wars."

Anybody like to identify the guns in this week's photo?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murrurundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War I German</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle East</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wallsend</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muswellbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geof Mansfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adamstown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Speers Point Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dudley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dudley Colliery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dudley Beach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boolaroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Field-Kanone 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian War Memorial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Destination Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FK16</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Region</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parnell Place</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
