<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402401353474872</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>15:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/soccer/les-murray-and-johnny-warren-mr-and-mrs-soccer-20170731-gxmi35.html</url>
  <title>Les Murray and Johnny Warren: 'Mr and Mrs Soccer'</title>
  <content>
The first of the last words on Les Murray, who died on Monday aged 71 following a long illness, belong to his late colleague Johnny Warren.
They sat alongside each other on a panel for SBS each Saturday afternoon, and through the decades, through various styles of suits and bouffant haircuts and oversized spectacles, they navigated a whole generation of fans through the code's blossoming from soccer to the world game appellation, football.

Up Next

Craig Foster remembers Les Murray

04:52

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

The best of Les Murray

Iconic SBS football presenter Les Murray AM has passed away following a battle with illness. Courtesy SBS

Murray, a Hungarian refugee who came to Australia with his family in 1957, and Warren, a former Socceroo who grew up in Botany, became the indomitable face of a code trying to rise above ethnic divisions so its national league could flourish and its national side could qualify for the World Cup finals for the first time since 1974.
"Our lasting testimony is that we walked into the stadium in Adelaide recently and someone called us 'Mr and Mrs Soccer'," Warren jokingly said before his death from cancer in 2004. "I'm just not sure who's 'Mrs' and who is 'Mr'."
Mystery surrounded the news on Monday of Murray's death. He'd been ill for some time but even those who had a long-standing relationship with him were unclear about the cause of his passing. Like Warren, he had been a heavy smoker.
Instead, most people wanted to focus on his legacy and his importance to his beloved code. Federal Opposition Leader Bill Shorten has called for a state funeral.

"He preached footy against the tide," Andy Paschalidis, who worked alongside Murray and Warren on The World Game Show during the 1980s and '90s, said. "His legacy will live on because those foundations he's helped build will never be broken. He was an immigrant but he wanted football to unite us."

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Murray changed his name from Laszlo Urge but remained proud of his upbringing. He began working as a reporter in 1971, including time at Fairfax Media's The Sun, and then joined SBS in 1980.Photo: Anthony Johnson
He joined as a part-time Hungarian subtitler, but two days after the TV network was launched he was teamed with Warren as soccer commentators following a chance meeting with an executive.
From then on, the pair were on a mission to promote the code whenever they appeared on our screens, crossing the line from commentators to evangelists as we lived through every heart-breaking World Cup qualifying loss.
Then, a year after Warren's death, the Socceroos delivered. They beat Uruguay on penalties at ANZ Stadium to qualify for the finals in Germany in 2006.
"That was one of the most epic games I have witnessed and I've seen a few," Murray told viewers post-match. "And one in which we were all emotionally involved and Johnny Warren told us so. I told you so. I told you so. And there it is: he has been proven right tonight."
Then Murray looked up at the heavens.
"Johnny, we hear you."
Said Murray in 2014 at the end of the World Cup in Brazil, when he stepped down from full-time commitments with SBS: "A whole generation of Australians have grown up with SBS and its football coverage. Those born before that scarcely realise what football was like until SBS came along and brought all this beautiful football into their lounge rooms and made Australia a true citizen of the world."
Murray is survived by his partner Maria and his daughters Tania and Natalie.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laszlo Urge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Game Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uruguay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Soccer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Paschalidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday of Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
