<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402869504919216</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>17:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/03/32/accused-bourke-st-driver-due-in-court</url>
  <title>Accused Bourke St driver due in court</title>
  <content>
The case of accused Bourke Street driver Dimitrious "Jimmy" Gargasoulas is due to return to a Melbourne court.
Gargasoulas faces six counts of homicide and 28 charges of attempted murder over the rampage on January 20.
He also faces a 29th attempted murder charge, a count of unlawful imprisonment and intentionally causing serious injury over two incidents at Windsor before the city deaths.
The 27-year-old has not appeared in court in person since he was charged, and his case is scheduled to return to the Melbourne Magistrates' Court on Tuesday for a mention.
A spokeswoman said he is likely to appear via video link on Tuesday.
Gargasoulas is accused of driving through the Melbourne CBD and deliberately striking pedestrians around Bourke and Queen streets as the area teemed with lunchtime and school holiday crowds.
He was arrested by police after being shot and wounded by officers.

Related Articles

The case against Gargasoulas might not reach trial until 2019.
It has previously gone before the Victorian Supreme Court on two occasions for a progress update.
Murder trials are usually heard before the Supreme Court, but it currently has no jurisdiction over Gargasoulas' case, which is still in the early stages of the criminal process.
In June, Director of Public Prosecutions John Champion SC told the Supreme Court that Gargasoulas probably won't face a committal hearing until 2018.
Mr Champion also said Gargasoulas' mental state could affect whether or not he stands trial over the rampage.
The issue of mental impairment has been raised in relation to separate charges unrelated to the Bourke St deaths.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dimitrious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prosecutions John Champion SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Champion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gargasoulas</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
