<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402139360464249</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/trump-might-stay-afghanistan-minerals-2017-7</url>
  <title>Trump might stay in Afghanistan for minerals  --  and it could endanger US national security</title>
  <content>
"We're nation building, we can't do it. We have to build our own nation," then-Candidate Donald Trump  the Guardian's Ben Jacobs in October 2015.

Throughout his presidential campaign, Donald Trump railed against nation building. But now it appears he might be considering doing just that.

Trump is considering staying in Afghanistan to help mine for minerals because he believes it will be a "win-win" for both countries,  to a report in The New York Times.

Trump thinks this prospect "could boost [Afghanistan's] economy, generate jobs for Americans and give the United States a valuable new beachhead in the market for rare-earth minerals, which has been all but monopolized by China," the Times said.

But deploying more troops to help guard mines for American companies would endanger US national security, Laurel Miller, a Rand Corporation analyst and former US diplomat to Afghanistan, told Business Insider.

It "would be an excellent propaganda point for the Taliban," Miller said, adding that "decisions based on sending troops are best made on national security interests."

Miller said that the national security risk would be eliminated if the US opened up bidding to companies worldwide, which would still benefit Afghanistan's economy too.

Opening up bidding, however, would risk American lives and treasure to help build Afghanistan's economy - something Trump said he opposed during the election.

The White House has been trying for months to figure out what to do about Afghanistan, and has been toying with the idea of  3,900 more US troops into the longest running war in American history, which is going on 16 years.

Trump has thus far seemed  to deploy more troops, and even  refused to sign off on H.R. McMaster's deployment plan, devised during a Cabinet meeting that was described as a "sh- show."

But Trump's advisers, as well as Afghan President Ashraf Ghani, appear to have sold him on mining, the New York Times said.

Some of Trump's aides met with Michael N. Silver, the CEO of a chemical company called American Elements, about how to mine the minerals, the New York Times said.

Stephen A. Feinberg, the CEO of Cerberus Capital Management, an investment conglomerate that owns DynCorp, a large defence contractor that could help guard the mines, is also keen on the idea, the New York Times said.

Feinberg, who  more than $US1 million to the controversial Trump Super PAC Rebuilding America Again, has also been informally advising the president. He even  plans with Blackwater Founder Erik Prince to flood Afghanistan with private contractors, but they were declined by Defence Secretary James Mattis.

More than  US troops have died and more than 20,000 more have been wounded since the war began in 2001. There are  more than 10,000 US troops there, where the US is spending roughly $US3.1 billion a month.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DynCorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan President Ashraf Ghani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackwater Founder Erik Prince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurel Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Cerberus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Elements</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael N. Silver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taliban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feinberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defense Secretary James Mattis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen A. Feinberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Candidate Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Super PAC Rebuilding America Again</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rand Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US3.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian's Ben Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H.R. McMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
