<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402878094853908</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>17:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/03/32/qld-roadside-death-trial-set-to-continue</url>
  <title>Qld roadside death trial set to continue</title>
  <content>
The trial of a New Zealander accused of dealing a Queensland man a "heavy blow" to the head before he fell into the path of a rubbish truck and died is set to continue on Tuesday.
Tamate Henry Heke allegedly struck Shane Merrigan, 50, before the local man was hit by the oncoming truck on the Gateway Motorway at Eight Mile Plains on December 1, 2015.
Heke has pleaded not guilty to one count of manslaughter, as well as not guilty to an alternative charge of unlawful striking causing death.
Crown prosecutor Clare Kelly on Monday said both men had been making their way home from work before pulling over to the left shoulder of the road and facing each other "for about 13 seconds".
The New Zealand man is accused of then delivering a "heavy blow" to Mr Merrigan's head, causing him to fall into the path of the truck, which was travelling at 90km/h.
Photographs showing the truck's blood-splattered undercarriage were viewed by Brisbane Supreme Court jurors on the first day of the trial.
The jury also saw graphic footage from a motorway camera showing the two cars pulling onto the road's shoulder, the men getting out and the moment of fatal impact.

Related Articles

But defence barrister Anthony Kimmins said Heke told police he didn't intend to get into a fight when he pulled his Holden Astra over to the road's shoulder.
He said Mr Merrigan had been gesturing at Heke with his middle finger from behind the wheel, with the accused man allegedly telling investigators he thought the other man would "back off".
The trial is scheduled to resume before Justice Peter Applegarth on Tuesday morning.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merrigan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateway Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Merrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eight Mile Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamate Henry Heke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Astra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Kimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Peter Applegarth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
