<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402019101377268</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>14:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/small-business/finance/the-missing-link-in-cecs-collapse-is-access-to-justice-20170731-gxm1ug.html</url>
  <title>The missing link in CEC's collapse is access to justice</title>
  <content>
One of the recurring issues raised with me by small business operators around the country is access to justice.
It's a real problem that legal action to remedy any dispute is expensive, time consuming and often not worth the effort.Photo: Andrew Meares
Whether it's late payment of accounts or disagreements over a contract, there is currently no simple way to have matters arbitrated.
The consequences of a protracted dispute can be severe and potentially lead to insolvency if substantial sums of money are involved.Photo: Brian Cassey
There is also a sense of hopelessness if the other party is a bank or a big business.
Strong, successful banks are vital to the economy. For the most part banks are good corporate citizens, but numerous inquiries have provided examples where their behaviour has sometimes been questionable.

The current Select Committee on Lending to Primary Production Customers has received submissions and heard evidence from family enterprises and small businesses who believe they were unfairly treated.
There are always two sides to every story, but who decides the truth?
Consider the case of former Cardwell prawn farmer Sam Sciacca, who told the select committee he was left with a significant liability after receivers allegedly ran down the business because they lacked professional expertise in aquaculture.
ANZ Bank, which inherited the loan from Landmark, responded: "ANZ did not undertake an overall assessment of the receivers' performance because the receivership was substantially completed before ANZ's involvement commenced."
The bank went on to cite two reports that effectively exonerated the receivers. Mr Sciacca disputes those accounts.
As it currently stands, there is no tribunal or forum outside the courts where Mr Sciacca can get a binding arbitration.
There are always two sides to every story, but who decides the truth?

There has been renewed media interest lately in the collapse of former Cairns-based property development company CEC Group.
Many workers, small businesses and the broader North Queensland community were caught in the aftermath and suffered financially.
I examined this case as part of my  with the assistance of legal and technical experts. We accepted that CBA was within its rights to reduce the bank's loan exposure.
However, we identified issues with how the bank communicated and the haste of its imposed timeframes for debt reduction.
In our view, it's highly likely that CEC Group would have survived if not for the actions of CBA.
Despite not formally responding to my report in March, CBA has now expressed its dissent with the findings via 60 Minutes and Australian Financial Review.
As it currently stands, there is no tribunal or forum outside the courts to get a binding arbitration, which leaves a cavernous gap with regards to procedural fairness.
Banks have taken some positive steps to comply with legislation that protects small business from unfair contract terms. They are also working with ASIC to implement a new Code of Banking Practice.
The missing link is access to justice.
Small businesses and family enterprises need somewhere to go if they feel aggrieved.
Unless the banks can voluntarily resolve this issue themselves it's likely that pressure for a tribunal will continue to grow amid continuing calls for a royal commission.
The problem with a royal commission is that it won't deliver justice in individual cases and the recommendations may take years to implement.
For people like Sam Sciacca and Roy Lavis that's too long to wait.
Kate Carnell is Australia's Small Business and Family Enterprise Ombudsman. Follow MySmallBusiness on ,  and . 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Lavis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Cassey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Code of Banking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Small Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEC Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Sciacca</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Select Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MySmallBusiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sciacca</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primary Production Customers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Carnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Enterprise Ombudsman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
