<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401701273790449</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/sophisticated-traveller/the-seine-uniworld-takes-you-from-paris-to-normandy-20170705-gx4y1y</url>
  <title>The next best thing to living on the Seine? An eight-day river cruise </title>
  <content>
by
Lee Tulloch

Living in Paris for two years in the 1990s, I grew to love the Seine. At first, it was just a river you crossed to get from the Left Bank to the Right. But later, I began to see it as an artery that pumped life into the landlocked city and all the way to the sea, its waterways teeming with activity, from barges to Bateaux Mouches packed with tourists.
I was always envious of those who live on the river, not just in the swanky apartments overlooking the water but also in houseboats docked along its edge. How wonderful, then, to receive an invitation to sleep on the Seine, over 20 years later.
Uniworld's newest river ship, the opulent , embarked on its inaugural voyage from Paris to Normandy this northern spring, with its godmother, Dame Joan Collins, on board briefly to officiate at the christening.
Dame Joan, in a chic suit and broad-brimmed hat, accompanied by her husband Percy Gibson, took enthusiastic selfies and posed for photographs. She has 13 godchildren, she told assembled guests, but this was her first godship. The Joie de Vivre, festooned with balloons and garlands for the occasion, was docked at Quay Andre Citroen with the Eiffel Tower in clear sight from its bow and the replica of the Statue of Liberty, given to France by the United States, nearby.

Steve Dunlop

The new ship will cruise regularly along the Seine to Normandy in northern France, where the river meets the English Channel near Honfleur. The eight-day Paris-Normandy-return voyage highlights the number of landmarks that can be accessed from the riverbank, on foot or by bike (there are complimentary bicycles on board) or by taking short bus rides.

The smorgasbord of destinations includes the Palace of Versailles, Empress Josephine's Chateau de Malmaison, Monet's garden at Giverny, Rouen Cathedral, Mont Saint-Michel and the Normandy D-Day beaches. Even for those familiar with some of the remarkable places, the cruise is the ideal way to see the greatest hits of the Seine in style - eating cake all the way.
Monet's garden

After departing Paris, the SS Joie de Vivre docks at the riverbank village of Vernon. It's only seven kilometres' bicycle ride (or a short bus trip) from the ship to  at Giverny - where the artist is buried - and one of the most famous gardens in the world.
The house, where he lived and worked from 1883 to 1926, has been preserved as a museum, its brightly coloured rooms featuring an eclectic mix of art, including reproductions of Monet's Impressionist works and the Japanese wood-block prints he assiduously collected. The green-painted Japanese bridge and water garden are unforgettable, especially in July and August, when the water lilies bloom.

Steve Dunlop

Chateau du Champ-de-Bataille

The  is an optional excursion for guests at an additional cost. Set amid 30 hectares of formal gardens, it is the home of Jacques Garcia, a designer and architect renowned for his lavish interiors for five-star hotels such as La Mamounia in Marrakesh and Hotel Costes in Paris. Garcia spends weekends in the 30-bedroom chateau, which visitors can tour at other times by appointment. The garden, inspired by 17th-century landscape architect Andre Le Notre, is full of delightful follies and the salons are crammed with extravagant antiques, taxidermy and the most important collection of royal objects in France. Monsieur Garcia's whippets will show you round if you're lucky.
Rouen

Is Rouen better known for the cathedral Monet painted so luminously in the 1890s, or as the place where Joan of Arc was burnt at the stake as a heretic in 1431? The celebrated cathedral, which took four centuries to build and is the tallest in France, is unmissable in this small, elegant city but Joan's legacy pales in comparison. However, she's still a towering presence in the modern church that is named for her and pops up again, rather surprisingly, as a local chocolate treat known as "tears of Joan of Arc".

Supplied

Rouen is also where you'll find camembert cheeses, delicate faience pottery, leaning timber houses that miraculously survived the bombing raids of World War II, and , a 14th-century restaurant where, in 1948, American television chef and author Julia Child had a revelation about French cooking and embarked upon a culinary career. For €65 ($97), the restaurant will serve you a version of the meal Mrs Child enjoyed, although the indifferent service and hordes of tourists would perhaps not meet with her approval.
Honfleur

A favourite of artists Courbet and Monet, the fishing village of Honfleur should come with an alcoholic (and culinary) warning. It's a trading port in the commune of Calvados, where the apple-based liquor of the same name is produced under appellation. Little holes-in-the-wall sell cider and the renowned beverage, offering generous tastings of the digestive to boot. If you want to take some home, look for the twice-distilled version from Pays d'Auge.
The town is easy on the eye. Pretty slate-roofed wooden houses line the waterfront and the medieval streets are full of gastronomic boutiques selling Normandy sea salt, heart-shaped blocks of Neufchatel cheese and tempting fudge. Dozens of restaurants are tucked underneath the tall houses on the dockside. Save your appetite for a dish called the fruits de mer Honfleur, a large seafood platter with dipping sauces.

Supplied

D-Day landing beaches

The Battle of Normandy was fought in 1944 between the occupying German army and Allied troops, more than 320,000 of whom crossed the Seine between June 6 and 11 in the largest seaborne invasion in history. These days, the windswept stretch of five beaches (codenamed Omaha, Gold, Juno, Sword and Utah) is a bleak reminder of the lives lost, with some relics of the equipment used for the invasion, including tanks and landing craft, still chillingly in place. For a different chapter in history, guests on the cruise can choose to combine the D-Day beaches with a visit to the 1000-year-old Bayeux tapestry in the town of that name. The embroidered cloth, almost 70 metres long, depicts the story of the Norman conquest of 1066.
Versailles

Nothing speaks to opulence as does Versailles. And yet, in recent times, the palace has been a far from luxurious experience, being overrun by tourists for much of the year. Get a fresh perspective on the palace by taking a bike ride around the exterior park. Admire the magnificent gardens on the 800-hectare estate, which were , complete with fountains, follies, groves and elegant lanes of horse chestnuts. Cycle past descendants of Marie Antoinette's sheep at her farm, Le Hameau, and , a small chateau commissioned for Madame de Pompadour, the official mistress of Louis XV. Designed by royal architect Ange-Jacques Gabriel, it was completed in 1768.

Supplied

The writer travelled as a guest of Uniworld.
Take me there

Uniworld's all-inclusive eight-day Paris-Normandy-Paris cruises aboard the Parisian-themed SS Joie de Vivre start from $3999 a person. Further information:

Michel Gounot

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giverny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayeux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SS Joie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Versailles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omaha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris-Normandy-return</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Channel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battle of Normandy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dame Joan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rouen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vernon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris-Normandy-Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champ-de-Bataille</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louis XV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marie Antoinette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Child</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dame Joan Collins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courbet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Left Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eiffel Towers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bateaux Mouches</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Child</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ange-Jacques Gabriel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honfleur</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chateau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calvados</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Percy Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palace of Versailles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parisian-themed SS Joie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garcia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D-Day</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monet's Impressionist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Empress Josephine's Chateau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monsieur Garcia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Dunlop</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seine</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Tulloch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacques Garcia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rouen Cathedral</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan of Arc</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marrakesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Normandy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Mamounia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Normandy D-Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Hameau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monet</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uniworld</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mont Saint-Michel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quay Andre Citroen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michel Gounot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neufchatel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andre Le Notre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Statue of Liberty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hotel Costes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
