<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401752813399028</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/world/nicolas-maduro-awaits-us-response-after-violent-venezuela-vote-20170731-gxmjkp</url>
  <title>Nicolas Maduro awaits US response after violent Venezuela vote</title>
  <content>
by
Nathan Crooks and Andrew Rosati

It was political theatre at its best when a smiling Nicolas Maduro arrived at a polling place just after dawn on Sunday to be among the first to vote for members of a National Constituent Assembly that will rewrite Venezuela's constitution, and likely aim to upend six decades of democracy.
For the president, the hand-picked successor to Hugo Chavez, the creation of the so-called constituyente was another step in a stubborn rise to autocratic power in the face of international condemnation, US sanctions, a cratering economy and months of civil unrest that has claimed more than 110 lives. The slate of 545 chosen to staff the new assembly are mostly all Maduro supporters, his wife among the more than 6,000 on the ballot.
Once officially convened, this new assembly will have no set term. It will supersede the National Assembly, the legislative branch that has struggled to be an anti-Maduro bulwark. Maduro will be primed to seize more power than Chavez ever held.
While the opposition has vowed to keep up the pace of near-daily protests, the bigger threat is a stepping-up of sanctions by the US - the largest buyer of the crude oil whose international sales make up around 95 per cent of Venezuela's foreign currency earnings.

"The Trump administration set a red line by announcing sanctions if the vote went ahead, so if his administration wants to be taken seriously some form of sanctions would have to be announced," said Raul Gallegos, an analyst at consultancy Control Risks.

The election sought to "undermine the Venezuelan people's right to self determination", State Department spokeswoman Heather Nauert said at the weekend. "We will continue to take strong and swift actions against the architects of authoritarianism in Venezuela, including those who participate in the National Constituent Assembly as a result of today's flawed election."
Sunday's vote was denounced by the opposition as fraudulent, considering that practically all the candidates were from the Socialist Party or its allies. Two weeks ago, more than 7.5 million Venezuelans cast votes in an unofficial plebiscite against the president and his new assembly plan.
Voter turnout reached 41.5 per cent, the country's oil ministry said on Twitter early on Monday.
Maduro's opponents questioned how many people came to vote. Julio Borges, president of the congress, estimated about 1.5 million Venezuelans had voted by mid-afternoon but said the government was bound to announce a turnout of more than 8.5 million voters. Other estimates mentioned 2.4 million voters.

Sandra Oblitas, a rector at the National Electoral Council, said that voting would be extended into the evening. The opposition alliance posted pictures of empty polling stations across the country on social media throughout the day.
The vote was not without violence as police clashed with demonstrators who blocked roads. Opposition leader Henrique Capriles said on Twitter as many as 15 people lost their lives.
"Today was a monumental failure for government," he said, stating that the opposition alliance would soon announce its next move. "The government is accelerating its own exit."
Colombia, Peru, Argentina and Panama issued statements saying they wouldn't recognise Sunday's vote, while US ambassador to the United Nations Nikki Haley said she would not accept an illegitimate government.

"Maduro's sham election is another step toward dictatorship," she wrote in a Twitter post.
Unlike during the unofficial referendum against the assembly earlier this month, when more than seven million Venezuelans rejected Maduro's assembly, entire districts and many of Caracas' main thoroughfares were deserted on Sunday.
"The line at the bakery near my house to buy bread was longer than the one here," said Leonardo Martinez, 42, a motorcycle taxi driver, as he looked on at a polling station in central Caracas. "Why do we need another constitution? How is it going to solve our problems?"
The vote capped a week of tensions in Caracas, where many of the city's 2 million residents stockpiled food and water amid a two-day national strike. Former Spanish Prime Minister Jose Luis Rodriguez Zapatero met with opposition leaders.

Last week, the US added 13 senior Venezuelan officials to its sanctions list as part of efforts to deter the constitution rewrite. President Donald Trump has warned of "strong" economic actions if Maduro proceeds with his plans.
"I am confident that President Trump will respond swiftly and decisively," US Senator Marco Rubio of Florida said. "I urge him to impose economic sanctions on the Maduro regime that will not harm the people of Venezuela but will deprive the Maduro regime of the resources they need to remain in power."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonardo Martinez, 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugo Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socialist Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julio Borges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Rosati</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra Oblitas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Crooks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raul Gallegos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Electoral Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henrique Capriles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heather Nauert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Control Risks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Constituent Assembly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Nikki Haley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Senator Marco Rubio of Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish Prime Minister Jose Luis Rodriguez Zapatero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
