<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402646166615845</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>16:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/warren-buffets-bhe-renewables-sets-the-standard-for-utility-solar-20170729-gxld60</url>
  <title>Warren Buffett's solar farm shines on</title>
  <content>
Topaz Solar Farm manager Gary Hood doesn't have any solar panels on the roof of his home in San Luis Obispo County in California because he doesn't need to.
Directly outside his two-level homestead, nestled into the foothills of the Carrizo Plain, are 8.4 million solar panels that make up BHE Renewables' Topaz Solar farm. With a capacity of 550 megawatts it is one of the largest solar farms in California.
Given the fast pace of the rollout of solar power across the globe, the $3 billion Topaz Solar Farm, about 270 kilometres north-east of Los Angeles, was the largest utility-scale solar project in the world when it was completed in 2014.
Now it has to settle for being the second-largest solar farm in California, which has embraced renewable energy as part of its push to have 50 per cent clean energy by 2030.

Ben VanderVeen

California has led the rollout of large-scale utility scale solar projects with more than 23,500 gigawatt hours in operation across the state, which, like Australia, is blessed with abundant sunshine.

The state's largest solar project is the 579 megawatt Solar Star project, near Rosamond and also owned by BHE Renewables, which was completed in 2017. The Desert Sunlight project in the Mojave Desert in the state's south-east, is the same size as Topaz, while there are also four other 200 megawatt to 250 megawatt projects in California.
The Topaz solar farm, which was built between 2012 and 2014, was developed by company First Solar before being bought by Birkshire Hathaway Renewables, a subsidiary of the multinational company run by billionaire investor Warren Buffett, which has more than 1400 megawatts of solar projects across the United States.
The rigorous development and environmental approvals for the Topaz Solar Farm by San Luis Obispo County has led to the project being the template for utility-scale solar projects winning over sceptical local communities worried about the impact on local wildlife and flora. The site is close to the Carrizo Plains national park.
"I think a lot of people didn't think it could be done and some environmental groups were against building a large scale project in this area," Mr Hood said in an interview with The Australian Financial Review between rows of solar panels at the Topaz facility.

"But First Solar and Berkshire Hathaway, we showed the world it could be done. There were a lot of big solar projects being built at the same time, but we had a lot more restrictions on it. There were 133 environmental conditions on what we could do."
The Topaz solar plant consists of 22 sections or "blocks" of thin-film cadmium telluride PV panels across 4700 acres. It produces enough electricity to power 18,000 Californian homes and displaces about 377,000 tonnes of carbon, equivalent to taking 73,000 cars off the road.
The barbed-wire steel fences have a double bar at the bottom to allow the endangered kit fox to slip through. Antelopes and elks also live between the solar sections, while sheep graze between the panels to keep the grass under control.
San Luis Obispo County is a renewable energy "sweet spot" with 308 days of sunshine every year.

Unlike most solar and wind projects in regional Australia, which needs to spend hundreds of millions of dollars to connect to the grid, the Topaz site, a former ranch, was chosen because it was right next to a transmission line taht connects to Bakersfield, the sub-station hub for the electricity grid between the north and south of California. It is also linked to the coast via the nearest big town of San Luis Obispo and then connects down to the metropolis of Los Angeles.
Under an advantageous power purchase agreement with the state's largest energy utility Pacific Gas & Electric, Topaz Solar Farm has locked in a deal that delivers about  US60¢ a kilowatt hour for the power it puts into the grid.
With the advent of more solar projects, the price offered for solar power has come down to about US30¢  a kilowatt hour, or about half of what Topaz receives. (The flip side is that the cost of building new solar farms has fallen dramatically in recent years due to new and cheaper technology.)
While the Topaz farm employed about 1000 jobs during construction, it only needs 15 staff now to monitor and replace broken panels. The low level of ongoing jobs on solar projects is one criticism raised by fossil fuel proponents, but the low maintenance and operational costs are an upside compared with traditional fuel sources.

Mr Hood, who has helped BHE Renewable deliver projects across the US including 1 megawatt community solar units, said he was not fussed about losing the mantle of California as the world's largest solar project.
"We would love to expand because the solar resources here are perfect," he said. "But the way it works it was so hard to permit this with the county, it would be a nightmare to go back and try and build more."
Mr Hood is happy with the way the project has been accepted by the local communities, saying it has done more for populations of the kit fox, antelope and elk than if the project had never been built.
Under an agreement with environmental groups, the site will be handed back to the Department of Fish and Wildlife after 35 years.

The reporter travelled to California with the assistance of The Climate Council.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Gas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Hood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben VanderVeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berkshire Hathaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bakersfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Climate Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Luis Obispo County</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosamond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHE Renewables' Topaz Solar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Topaz</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desert Sunlight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solar Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Solars</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Buffett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Fish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Topaz Solar Farm</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHE Renewables</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Luis Obispo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrizo Plain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mojave Desert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birkshire Hathaway Renewables</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
