<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401782878170953</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:27</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/retail/fmcg/organic-fastfood-chain-olivers-real-food-downgrades-profit-forecast-20170731-gxmcof</url>
  <title>Organic fast-food chain Oliver's Real Food downgrades profit forecast</title>
  <content>
ASX newcomer Oliver's Real Food has made a stunning profit downgrade, warning investors it will miss its prospectus forecasts only five weeks after hitting the boards.
Shares in Oliver's, which promotes itself as , collapsed 15 per cent after it told investors that it would miss fiscal 2017 financial targets last confirmed in its June 2 supplementary prospectus.
Oliver's blamed a series of "individual events" for conspiring to push the NSW company to a $3.2 million loss, nearly $1 million more than the $2.4 million it forecast ahead of its June 21 listing.
The company said revenue would slip to $20.4 million, down from the forecast $21.1 million while earnings before interest, tax, depreciation and amortisation would be negative $2.5 million compared to a forecast loss of $1.9 million in June.

Veritas Securities was the float's lead manager.

Oliver's shares closed down 15 per cent, or 5¢, to 28¢. Despite the share plunge the company's stock is trading above its 20c issue price.
About 40 per cent of the company's issued shares are under escrow until September 21.
Unenviable and growing list

The company joins an unenviable and growing list of companies to downgrade in a debut year, including , Wellard and .

Oliver's said store sales met expectations but its net sales were lower than forecast due to "higher intercompany eliminations for the supply chain divisions".
It also blamed the souring profit outlook on delays in opening new stores at Aratula and Bulahdelah, which it is converting from existing businesses.
There were also "year-end inventory adjustments" and one-off costs thrown up from "accelerated growth activities" made since its June prospectus.
This included "additional costs related to store and franchise acquisitions that were not expected".

Chief executive Jason Gunn and chairman Mark Richardson did not return calls from The Australian Financial Review.
The company said, in its statement to the ASX, that its 2018 forecasts outlined in its prospectus remain unchanged. It is forecasting $41.9 million revenue, $4.8 million in earnings and a $2.4 million net profit.
The company's finances remain subject to a final audit ahead of the release of the company's accounts, which are due before August 31.
'A desert for decent food'

As Oliver's rattled the tin to raise up to $15 million from investors at 20¢ per share - after unsuccessfully trying to get the raising away at 30¢ a share - chief executive and founder Jason Gunn told prospective investors people "want to support companies that believe in something that goes beyond maximising profits" but the best way to achieve his vision was to "build a strong and profitable company".
"Oliver's aspires to deliver the healthier food choices, as well as the nutritional information, that gives people the power to take back control of their health, and the health of our planet," he wrote in the prospectus.
Mr Gunn, who founded Oliver's, wants to change the way people eat on the run - offering healthy food along major road arteries to offer drivers something other than fat-laden junk food.
"Nobody was selling the kind of food I wanted to eat," he told the Financial Review in May as he whipped up support for his company's float.

"We are sold on the fast-food idea, but why can't we have some good food? There is no shortage of good food in cities, you can get whatever you want to eat, but try driving from Sydney to Brisbane or Sydney to Melbourne and it's a desert for decent food."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aratula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulahdelah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver's Real Food</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Veritas Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Gunn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
