<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401778583203549</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:26</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/labor-trust-plan-will-drive-use-of-companies-experts-20170731-gxmapb</url>
  <title>Labor trust plan will drive use of companies: experts</title>
  <content>
Labor's  will force savers to re-think their investment structures and encourage greater use of investment companies, tax experts say.
Peter Poulos, a partner at law firm Gadens, said imposing a minimum 30 per cent  would result in more companies being set up within family structures. Other experts said savers might be encouraged to invest more in the personal name of a low-income spouse.
Mr Poulos said that using an investment company inside a family trust would mean franking credits could be distributed directly to low-tax individuals who are not themselves beneficiaries.
"If the end game is that the individual receives a franked dividend from a company instead of a trust distribution, the proposed policy may be redundant absent consideration of complex anti-avoidance issues," Mr Poulos said.

Louie Douvis

"So ultimately the only winners may be the accountants and lawyers tasked with navigating these complex anti-avoidance issues, which begs the question whether a measure which also increases the effective tax rate for small business is in the public interest."

Rocco Musumeci, senior accountant for advice firm Henderson Maxwell, said Labor's proposed tax would have a "big impact" on the use of family trusts, given that many investors used the structures to keep their average tax rate to below 30 per cent.
'Less viable'

"Family trusts will become less viable," Mr Musumeci said, adding that it would make investment companies more attractive, and for some, self-managed superannuation funds, where the earnings are taxed at 15 per cent.
In the case of a small business owner, if the income was distributed to a company, the tax rate at 27.5 per cent would be cheaper than Labor's 30 per cent proposed tax on distributions. Furthermore, he said, the company tax rate was expected to fall.

Ian Gillies, a director at Hamilton Wealth, said in some cases it would make sense for enough money to generate an income of up to $37,000 to be removed from a family trust and invested in the name of an unemployed beneficiary.
Chartered Accountants Australia and New Zealand tax leader Michael Croker said there were many unanswered questions associated with the Labor proposal. How would hybrid trusts with fixed and discretionary entitlements be dealt with, for example.
"People will crunch the numbers now using the Labor party approach and there could be some really strange outcomes," he said.
"Although everyone thinks the reason you've got a discretionary trust is to split income through these multiple low-income earning university students, in many cases you're really only distributing to mum and dad who are heavily involved in the business.

"When [Labor] gave ground to farmers they didn't think about all those active small busineses."
Little impact

Mr Poulos said Labor had cleverly avoided making changes that would have the highest compliance costs, such as taxing trusts as companies.
Other experts said they doubted , given that their main attraction was asset protection for small businesses and professionals, such as doctors and lawyers, and estate planning.

"For the majority of people, trusts will still make sense," said Chris Morcom of Melbourne-based Hewison Private Wealth
Mr Morcom argued the tax advantages of family trusts were overplayed. Only up to $416 a year can be distributed to minors tax free, while there was often only a short window where income can be distributed tax free to adult children, given that the 32.5 per cent tax band kicks in at incomes of $37,000 a year.
"The tax benefits are an additional nice-to-have," Mr Morcom said.
He pointed to the drawbacks of using investment companies, including the fact that there is no tax-free threshold so company tax is paid on the first dollar earned, companies receive no capital gains tax discount on assets that are held for longer than 12 months and money in the company must eventually be paid out as dividends.

"It is a tax deferral methodology," Mr Morcom said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Croker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chartered Accountants Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morcom</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Morcom of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henderson Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton Wealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocco Musumeci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Musumeci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Poulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Poulos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hewison Private Wealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gadens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Gillies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
