<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651401782878170905</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>13:27</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/aviation-security-experts-call-to-beef-up-airport-safety-further-amid-terror-threat-20170731-gxm2o4</url>
  <title>Aviation security experts call for beefed up airport safety amid terror threat</title>
  <content>
Aviation security remains too lax despite the  allegedly targeting a passenger plane, a former head of security at Sydney Airport says.
Security consultant Mike Carmody wants the Turnbull government to require passengers to produce photo identification before they can board domestic flights, and replace private sector security guards with a government security force.
The call by Mr Carmody and other aviation security experts came amid mayhem at the nation's airports as thousands of travellers were confronted with long delays on Monday.
Worst hit was Sydney's T2 domestic terminal, with queues snaking outside the door during the morning rush.

Baz Rao

Swab tests for explosives and inspections of carry-on luggage were stepped up and conducted before passengers reached metal detector security points, while extra Federal Police were also deployed to patrol terminals.

With travellers being advised to be at airports three hours before international flights and two hours before domestic trips to give them time to clear security, Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull and Federal Police Commissioner Andrew Colvin thanked passengers for their patience.
While ruling out a "terror tax" to pay for the new security measures, Mr Turnbull said they would stay in place for as long as the threat remained while Immigration Minister Peter Dutton suggested they could be indefinite.
"It may be that we need to look at the security settings at our airports, in particular our domestic airports, for an ongoing, enduring period," Mr Dutton said.
But Mr Carmody - who is not the same person as the former head of Customs - and other aviation security experts said the Government needed to go further.

Getty Images

Mr Carmody, who was head of security at Sydney airport between 1991 and 1995, said more checks needed to be done to verify the identity of domestic passengers, including linking airline booking systems to security agencies databases to identify potential terror risks and asking them to produce photo ID when they board.
"The scary thing is domestic airlines have no idea who is really on their aircraft," he said.
"There is very little coordination. Unless you happen to be someone who really stands out, you are going to fly right through security."
Mr Carmody said employing private sector security guards was simply aimed at cutting costs and the Australian Border Force should assume responsibility.

Justin McManus

Homeland Security Asia/Pacific founder Roger Henning said the changes unveiled by the government amounted to "window dressing" and echoed the call for photo ID checks.
"You need a photo ID to enter a licensed venue but not board a flight," he said.
Mr Henning pointed out that trace testing at airports did not include looking for "plastic explosives hidden in a toothpaste tube quite capable of taking an A380 out of the air".
Australian Strategic Policy Institute head of border security John Coyne doubted the increased security screening was likely to become permanent.

Dr Coyne described the increased screening as "security theatre" intended to deter terrorist co-conspirators from carrying out an attack, reassure the public that flying remained safe and give agencies time to identify and rectify any vulnerabilities.
"It's in the country's interest for life to get back to normal," he said.
Despite the disruption to business, Australian Chamber of Commerce and Industry chief James Pearson said he recognised the safety and security of the travelling public had to come first.
The increased security presence was ordered after counter-terrorism agencies arrested four men in Sydney on Saturday over allegedly Islamist-inspired plans to either blow up or somehow release poison gas on board a flight bound for the Middle East.

Reports suggest the cell had planned to smuggle the homemade device on board using a kitchen meat mincer. It was initially reported the group was made up of two sets of fathers and sons but this is not the case.
As police continued to search the mens' homes, the suspects were being questioned under anti-terror laws that allow them to be detained for up to seven days without charge.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Carmody</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baz Rao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Carmody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Henning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeland Security Asia/Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin McManus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Border Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Coyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Henning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Coyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's T2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Police Commissioner Andrew Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Strategic Policy Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
