<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402392763540201</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>15:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/3125115/morisset-police-station-closed-for-demolition/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Morisset Police Station closed for demolition</title>
  <content>
An artists impression of the new police station which is expected to open by the end of 2015.

MORISSET Police Station has closed its doors and will be demolished while a new station is built.
The new station will accommodate  general-duties police and officers from the Police Transport Command and State Protection Group's Dog Unit and is due to open by the end of 2015.
A construction fence has been erected around the building to ensure the safety of the public.
"We intend to provide the same level of policing service throughout the construction process, and thank the community in advance for its patience," Lake Macquarie Local Area Commander, Superintendent Brett Greentree, said.

Morisset Police Station is set to be demolished to make way for a new station.
"My staff are looking forward to working in a modern building that meets the challenges of modern-day policing," Supt Greentree said.
Toronto Police Station is the next closest station within Lake Macquarie Local Area Command; it can be reached on phone number 49503699.
In the event of an emergency, members of the community should contact Triple Zero (000).
The Morisset rebuild is part of a wider major building program across Lake Macquarie Local Area Command.
"This includes a brand new police station currently under construction at Belmont, and a further new station at Toronto to be constructed during 2016," Supt Greentree said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie Local Area Command</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Transport Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Protection Group's Dog Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supt Greentree</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple Zero (000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie Local Area Commander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morisset Police Station</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morisset</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Brett Greentree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
