<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403436440612129</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/council-denies-knowledge-of-pisasale-drivers-claim/3207171/</url>
  <title>Pisasale driver's brothel claim: council in the dark</title>
  <content>
IPSWICH City Council chief executive Jim Lindsay insists no formal complaint or allegation was received by him from Paul Pisasale's former driver regarding bombshell brothel allegations made this week.

Driver Stephen Potts has claimed he drove Mr Pisasale to brothels and massage parlours in the mayoral car, owned by Ipswich City Council, while he was employed as the former mayor's driver.

Mr Potts has said that "considerable public resources have been misused for personal benefits" and that "Ipswich City Council systems allow this to continue".

The Brisbane Times reported that Mr Potts said that when he handed in his resignation to Ipswich City Council in June last year he complained about Mr Pisasale's inappropriate use of the mayoral car including visits to massage parlours.

The QT contacted Mr Potts and asked him who he complained to but he has not responded to calls or texts.

Mr Lindsay said yesterday: "As regards the allegations that have now been made by Mr Potts, I can confirm that I have not previously received any formal complaint or allegation from Mr Potts about these issues."

"Given the nature of the allegations that have now been made, I will as matter of due process look to undertake an internal investigation which will include a review of the relevant Council governance arrangements," Mr Lindsay said.

"However, I must also respect the investigation that is currently being carried out by the Crime and Corruption Commission of Queensland. The council is and will continue to fully cooperate with that investigation.

"I will be writing to the CCC seeking advice on the best way to proceed in these circumstances."

The QT asked the council to specifically address the issue raised by Mr Potts that the council's systems allowed public resources, in this case the mayoral car, to be misused. A council spokesperson told the QT that "there is no system in the world that can stop two people allegedly colluding to do something together".

In 2015, Mr Potts told The Courier-Mail this week, he had driven Mr Pisasale behind a car belonging to developer Chris Zenonos to the massage parlour Cloud 9, in East Brisbane.

Mr Zenonos has said he had shown Mr Potts the massage parlour and then left, for the reason that he had been told by Pisasale that "his MS was playing up and he wanted a massage".

Acting Mayor Paul Tully said he was unaware of the allegations about Mr Pisasale until finding out about them in the press.

"All I know is what I have read in the newspapers," Cr Tully said.

"This has come as a bolt out of the blue. All of these claims are seemingly unknown to his family, his friends and colleagues but nothing has been proven and the matter is in the hands of the CCC. If these allegations are ever proven it would seem that Mr Pisasale was leading a double life, unknown to his family, friends and colleagues."

The QT tried to contact Mr Pisasale, who is in a health clinic in Brisbane, for comment.

Despite a long interview he granted last week, he did not reply yesterday.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloud 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QT</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corruption Commission of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Potts</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pisasale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Potts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pisasale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lindsay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Tully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pisasale</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Paul Tully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich City Council</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Zenonos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Lindsay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Zenonos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
