<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403191627471957</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>18:55</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/united-airlines-jet-missed-drone-landing-newark-airport-2017-7</url>
  <title>A United Airlines jet narrowly missed a drone just before landing at Newark Liberty International Airport</title>
  <content>
On Sunday, a drone got dangerously close to a United Airlines jet that was attempting to land at Newark Liberty International Airport.

Flight 135, a Boeing 767-400, was notified of a drone in its vicinity by air traffic control.

Fortunately, the United pilots were able to monitor the drone's position and aircraft landed without incident.

"Upon descent into Newark, air traffic control alerted the flight deck aboard United flight 135 of a drone in the vicinity of the runway," United said in a statement to Business Insider. "Our crew monitored the drone and landed the aircraft safely."

According to the Federal Aviation Administration, the flight crew report seeing the drone two miles southwest of the airport around 11:55 am on Sunday.

"Preliminary information shows that United Flight 135, a Boeing 767, reported a near mid-air collision with a white unmanned aircraft approximately two miles southwest of Newark," a FAA spokesman told Business Insider in an email. "The FAA notified the New Jersey State Police."

According to the same spokesman, the FAA has launched an investigation into the incident.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Flight 135</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing 767</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey State Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newark</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FAA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Aviation Administration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newark Liberty International Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Airlines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
