<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403466505383697</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/ground-staff-should-have-same-screening-as-air-crew-pilots-say/8760646</url>
  <title>Airport security: Ground staff should have same screening process as air crew, pilots say</title>
  <content>
The peak association representing air pilots has warned that some airport staff are gaining access to planes and equipment with minimal security screening.
While passengers are being subjected to  in the wake of the , the Australian Federation of Air Pilots (AFAP) said treatment of ground staff like baggage handlers, caterers, contractors and engineers was too relaxed at some capital city airports.
This is unlike flight crew, who undergo the same screening processes as passengers.
AFAP safety and technical officer Marcus Diamond said air crew and ground crew should be treated in the same manner.
"We are calling for consistency in screening practices at main capital city airports around Australia for different types of staff," he said.
"At one airport you will have ground staff requiring a personal check of their aviation security card [ASIC card] and any bags they are taking airside, whereas at another one they only swipe two doors and they are in.
"Air crew are generally very well-known people, they have been in the system a long time, they have had multiple checks and security access and yet they often have less access to airside, to their own aircraft than the people who are putting the luggage on board."
Discrepancies across terminals

Mr Diamond said the discrepancies were not limited to occupations or cities, with some terminals at the same airport exercising less onerous security measures.
"Sydney probably sits in the middle but there will be specific areas like perhaps the cargo area will be more lax [sic] than say the international terminal but it is in the vicinity of the same terminal space," he said.
"Brisbane has much tighter security at the international airport than at the domestic airport.
"Consistency in access to airside definitely [is needed], if you think about it once you are airside and you are in a car you can drive around the perimeters of an airport and access all areas."
The Office of Transport Security has been contacted for comment.
The call follows revelations from Queensland Police Commissioner Ian Stewart, who said the four men arrested in Sydney over an alleged plot to blow up a plane may have had other targets as well.
It is alleged the suspects planned to smuggle a bomb onto an aircraft, hidden in a kitchen meat grinder.
Mr Stewart said the alleged terrorism cell may have had a broader intent.
"I think that there will still need to be an investigative phase because while I believe that there were clearly intentions around aviation, it doesn't preclude that there may have been other targets as well. And that's what the investigation will be undertaking," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Commissioner Ian Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Diamond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Diamond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federation of Air</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
