<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403256051982630</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/bob-mannings-light-rail-plan-misses-250000-funding-for-study/news-story/79c3162e520d7f7bd80f5ac4c940948b</url>
  <title>Funding snub no barrier to tram</title>
  <content>
A FAILURE to secure a $250,000 grant for a feasibility study into light rail for Cairns has not troubled Mayor Bob Manning, who says the work will go ahead regardless.
The State Government knocked back Cairns Regional Council's request through the Maturing the Infrastructure Pipeline program for "scoping funds" to push forward with the Cairns Transit Network.
Cr Manning announced his billion-dollar vision for a passenger tram network as an election policy in 2016, saying he was confident it would attract state and federal government funding.
He stood by that position yesterday despite the State Government rejecting the council's $250,000 request investigate its viability.
He said the council would fund the review itself if necessary.
"Governments like to be associated with success. Every government wants to take credit," Cr Manning said.
"We just need to get out there and continue to be progressive and successful.
"Governments will jump on board."
The rhetoric framing the transit network proposal has changed since the election, with fewer references to light rail and more talk of electric buses.
Cr Manning said the tramline was definitely on the table.
"Personally, I think it's going to be a combination of the two," he said.
"We just call it the 'green train' and we're still trying to get a better understanding of how this will work."
A meeting between councillors and consultants who have worked on similar projects around Australia is scheduled for the week after next.
"We're also looking at overall smart city options," Cr Manning said.
"Not getting a bit of funding isn't going to slow us down.
"But we would like to see the State Government being more responsive when regional centres like us are trying to get ahead of the game."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infrastructure Pipeline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Manning</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Bob Manning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Transit Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
