<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403273231852109</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/noosa-plays-host-to-10000-foodies-and-wine-fanatic/3206300/</url>
  <title>Noosa plays host to 10,000 foodies and wine fanatics</title>
  <content>
NO LONGER is the Sunshine Coast a place where fish and chips, hamburgers and maybe a Chinese takeaway were the best you could hope for.
Today, we have a much more adventurous palate and enjoy fine foods and wine from around the world.
Nowhere is this more obvious than the Noosa Food and Wine Festival, which this year attracted more than 10,000 foodies and wine fanatics from all over the country.
They attended more than 70 events across the four-day festival, with many functions sold out.
A total of 45 visiting chefs from Australia's best restaurants - plus international sensation Sat Bains from the UK - cooked up a storm for festival-goers.
Festival director Maria Crews said it was great to see so many people having fun and letting their hair down.
"This year's Noosa Food and Wine Festival has been a true success and has set the bar for what can be achieved in future years," she said.
"We held more than 70 events across the festival, in many different locations, and there was something for everyone to enjoy, no matter what their palate desired.
"Noosa Main Beach was a hub of fun, excitement and good food and wine."
The Noosa Woods was transformed into a wine and produce village, where some of the region's best producers, cheesemakers and saluministi came together to offer an array of tastings.
In a festival first, The Noosa Woods hosted the ultimate festival music takeover and Australian dance music royalty teamed up, including Flight Facilities, Empire of the Sun and The Swiss.
"We had more than 3500 visitors to The Noosa Woods who were able to visit 47 stalls, get to know our festival chefs a bit better and see our winemakers go head to head on the main stage," Maria said.
Bar, restaurant to pave way for precinct renewal
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
KEN has more than a passing interest in the evolution of music.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Woods</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Empire of the Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wine Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria Crews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sat Bains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Main Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Food</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flight Facilities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
