<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403286116754383</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:17</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/new-coast-restaurant-bar-forges-way-for-precinct-r/3207068/</url>
  <title>New Coast restaurant, bar forges way for precinct revival</title>
  <content>
THE Coast's newest bar and restaurant is set to forge the way for the renewal of a major dining and retail precinct.
Chances Mooloolaba opens today from 7am, and marks the beginning of the Wharf precinct's revival in the lead-up to Christmas.
"We're the first cab off the rank," owner Bron Noffke said.
Along with business partner Yolanda Antonacci, Ms Noffke has overhauled the existing shop, and took the venue for a test run on Sunday with a soft opening for family and friends.
"I've been building bars for most of my life, we just got to build one for ourselves," Ms Noffke said.
"I love everything about Chances, it's the bar of a lifetime."
The pair have worked to create a community hub, aiming to build an atmosphere where anyone is welcome.
"It's got a heart, it's alive, it's not just a bar," Ms Noffke said.
The venue is firmly family-friendly, with a central kids room visible from most of the dining areas.
Head chef Adam Lugg has been working on creations including breakfast pizza, Eudlo pork, breakfast and lunch platters, reconstructed lemon meringue and reconstructed Snickers.
Ms Noffke and Miss Antonacci aimed to create a menu with something for everyone, from burgers and cakes to fuel for athletes.
"We just fit to what we all like and what our friends like, and went with that," Ms Noffke said.
Patrons will find anything from XXXX Gold to craft beers in the fridge and on tap.
"We're not a craft beer venue, we're just a good beer venue," Ms Noffke said.
The bar offers two other options on tap for those who want their beer coin to make a difference.
For every keg of "Tuff Love" sold, $58 goes to breast cancer research, while $50 from every keg of "Balls Up" goes to prostate cancer research.
During August the venue will be closed on Monday, open 7am-4pm on Tuesday and Wednesday, and open 7am-late Thursday to Sunday.
From September Chances will open seven days a week all day except for Mondays, when it will be open for breakfast and lunch.
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wharf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Antonacci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Noffke</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Lugg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolanda Antonacci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bron Noffke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XXXX Gold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September Chances</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuff Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
