<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403427850677396</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/news/world/2017/08/01/donald-trump-removes-anthony-scaramucci/</url>
  <title>Donald Trump dumps communications boss Anthony Scaramucci</title>
  <content>
President Donald Trump has removed White House communications director Anthony Scaramucci just 10 days after appointing him.
Mr Scaramucci is the latest in a string of high-profile departures from the White House.
Chief of Staff Reince Priebus resigned late last week after a public falling out with Mr Scaramucci and was replaced by John Kelly, whose first day is Monday.
US media have quoted White House sources as saying Mr Scaramucci was removed at the request of Mr Kelly.
"Mr Scaramucci will be leaving his role as White House Communications Director," spokeswoman Sarah Sanders said in a statement Tuesday morning (AEST).
"Mr Scaramucci felt it was best to give Chief of Staff John Kelly a clean slate and the ability to build his own team. We wish him all the best."
Mr Scaramucci made a profanity-filled tirade against Mr Priebus last week, accusing him of leaking to the media.
It was unclear whether Mr Scaramucci had been fired from the White House or simply removed from the communications position.
Mr Scaramucci made his presence feld during his brief tenure at the White House, last week unleashing a profanity-filled tirade against his colleagues for leaking information to the media.
Mr Scaramucci vowed to fire every White House communications staffer, after a The New Yorker reporter refused to reveal his source for a tweet that revealed Mr Scaramucci, Mr Trump and Fox News figures were having dinner at the White House last Thursday.
"What I'm going to do is, I will eliminate everyone in the comms team and we'll start over," Mr Scaramucci told The New Yorker reporter.
"I'm going to fire every one of them, and then you haven't protected anybody, so the entire place will be fired over the next two weeks.
"I'll get to the person who leaked that to you ... I want to f-ing kill all the leakers and I want to get the President's agenda on track so we can succeed for the American people."
Mr Scaramucci insisted current then-chief of staff Mr Priebus was behind the leak, labelling him as a "paranoid schizophrenic".
"Reince Priebus - if you want to leak something - he'll be asked to resign very shortly," he said.
"Reince is a f-ing paranoid schizophrenic, a paranoiac."
The enraged communications director then targeted chief strategist Steve Bannon, saying unlike other Trump administration officials, he had no interest in media attention.
"I'm not Steve Bannon, I'm not trying to suck my own --," Mr Scaramucci said, according to The New Yorker.
"I'm not trying to build my own brand off the f-ing strength of the President. I'm here to serve the country."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Priebus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Communications Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Scaramucci</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
