<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402650461583173</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>16:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/2739805/rest-in-peace-my-little-brother/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>'Rest in peace my little brother'</title>
  <content>
'Rest in peace my little brother'

exit

Australian cricket captain Michael Clarke 'dug in' through tears to celebrate the spirit of his fallen teammate Phillip Hughes in a tribute applauded for its courage. 
Speaking to mourners at Hughes' funeral in his home town of Macksville, Clarke was overcome with grief onlyonce as he delivered a tribute to the batsman he referred to as his little brother.
"He left a mark on our game that needs no embellishment," Clarke said.
"I don't know about you but I keep looking for him. I know it's crazy, but I expect any moment to take a call for him or see his face pop around the corner.
"Is this what we call the spirit? If it is, it's with me and I hope it never leaves."
Clarke had grinned as Hughes' cousin described the batsman's terrible cooking and cleaning, as well as his outstanding ironing skills.
He had listened to Hughes' brother Jason and sister Megan read letters to their brother.
Then the Australian captain took to the lecturn to pay tribute to his friend. 
He told the crowd who filled Macksville High's school hall that on the night Hughes died, he had walked out onto the pitch at the Sydney Cricket Ground, where Hughes had sustained the head injury that killed him.
"It's now forever the place where he fell. I stood at the wicket and knelt down to touch the grass and I swear he was with me, picking me up off my feet to check if I was OK, telling me we just needed to dig in, and get through to tea. 
"Telling me off for that loose shot I'd played, chatting about what movie we'd watch that night, and then passing on a useless fact about cows.

"Is this what we call the spirit? If it is, it's with me and I hope it never leaves": Michael Clarke.
"I could see him swagger back to the other end, grin at the bowler, then call me through for a run with such a booming voice a bloke in the car park could hear it.
"The heart of a man who lived his life for this wonderful game we play, whose soul enriched not just our sport but all of our lives.
"Is this what people indigenous people believe about the spirit of a person being connected on the land he walked? If so, they're right about SCG. His spirit has touched it, and it will forever be a safer place for me."
Clarke said the global tributes for Hughes, from Karachi to Lords in England, had "sustained and overwhelmed" him in equal measure.
He also praised the team and cricketing community, the "baggy green brothers and sisters" who had lifted him up when he felt he could not keep going and said the spirit of cricket would hold them all together.
"Phillip's spirit, which is now part of the game forever, will act as a custodian of the game forever. We must listen to it, we must learn from it, we must dig in, dig in and get through to T. And we must play on.
"So rest in peace my little brother. I'll see you out in the middle."

Clarke and Tom Cooper, the South Australian player who was batting with Hughes' during his final game, served as pallbearers alongside Hughes' family to carry his casket from the school hall at the end of the service.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillip Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarke</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macksville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macksville High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T. And</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughes</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Cricket Ground</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lords</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karachi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Clarke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
