<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402865209951900</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>17:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/03/32/police-officials-to-front-border-inquiry</url>
  <title>Police, officials to front border inquiry</title>
  <content>
Federal police believe arrangements with partner agencies and industry at Australia's major airports are appropriate and effective.
Representatives from the AFP will on Tuesday front a parliamentary committee looking into the integrity of the country's border arrangements.
Officials from the Department of Immigration and Border Protection, Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission, Attorney-General's Department and others are also scheduled to appear in Canberra.
The hearing comes as airport security is tightened across the nation following a foiled plot to bomb or gas a passenger plane out of Sydney.
In a written submission to the inquiry, the AFP said it takes a whole-of-government approach to aviation security.
Last year, it merged its aviation portfolio into its broader protection operations for a more effective response and surge capacity at designation airports.
"The ability to deploy these resources recently occurred at Australian designated airports post the initial advice of attacks at Brussels and Istanbul airports in 2016," it said.

Related Articles

Last year, it agreed to chair a quarterly forum focusing on operational and intelligence aspects of aviation security, after identifying a "gap" in co-ordination and response.
It noted the AFP participates in a number of forums both with government agencies and industry partners, as well as a key US security program.
"The shared work environment and joint management arrangements at designated airports are believe appropriate and effective," it wrote.
Courier company DHL told the committee on Monday it found it "unbelievable" that Australia still relies on paper documents such as birth certificates for security checks.
Security manager Margaret McCormack pointed to the use of biometrics across the world and suggested it should be introduced in Australia when issuing security identification cards to aviation workers.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISTANBUL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General's Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRUSSELS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret McCormack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Immigration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DHL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
