<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403423555710071</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/before-the-bell/bhp-rio-poised-to-lift-asx-ahead-of-rba-rate-call-20170731-gxmn3n</url>
  <title>BHP, Rio poised to lift ASX ahead of RBA rate call</title>
  <content>
by
Timothy Moore

While ASX futures are pointing to a flat open, the US listed shares of BHP and Rio are higher on gains in iron ore and oil. ASX futures up 1 point. The Australian dollar is up 0.1 per cent, sitting just beneath US80¢.
There appears to be some trepidation on Wall Street as a huge week of earnings - more than 1200 over the next five days - unfolds with a key focus on Apple tomorrow. Shares in the iPhone maker drifted 0.6 per cent lower overnight, though they remain up more than 28 per cent so far this year. Chevron and Home Depot lifted the Dow to a fresh record high. The S&P 500 and Nasdaq fluctuated in narrow ranges.
For BHP and Rio shareholders there was good news on both the iron ore and oil fronts.  on bets that supply in China is tightening amid signs construction continues apace. 
As for oil, US oil topped the $US50 a barrel mark overnight on reports some OPEC and non-OPEC members will meet on August 7-8 in Abu Dhabi to assess how the group can increase compliance with production cuts that began on January 1. Compliance within OPEC appears to be slipping.

Later today, the focus shifts to the RBA. 

"Financial stability concerns mean that the RBA will almost certainly keep interest rates" wrote Kate Hickie at Capital Economics in a morning note.
"We expect the central bank to retain its upbeat outlook for economic growth when its latest forecasts are published in the Statement on Monetary Policy on Friday," Ms Hickie said. "And despite the recent surge in the Australian dollar, we doubt that it will alter its forecast that underlying inflation will gradually rise to 2.0 per cent. However, we suspect that both growth and inflation will ultimately turn out lower than the RBA anticipates. As such, we think that interest rates will remain on hold throughout 2017 and 2018."
Today's Agenda

Local data: AiG performance of manufacturing July, CoreLogic house prices July, RBA cash rate decision

Overseas data: China Caixin manufacturing PMI July, Japan Nikkei manufacturing PMI July; Euro zone second quarter GDP; US personal income and spending as well as PCE inflation June, Market manufacturing PMI July, ISM manufacturing July, Construction spending June
Market Highlights

SPI futures up 1 point at 5662
AUD +0.1% to 79.96 US cents (Overnight range: 0.7956 - 0.8002)

On Wall St, Dow +0.4%, S&P 500 flat, Nasdaq -0.3%
In New York, BHP +1.3%, Rio +1.5%
In Europe, Stoxx 50 -0.5%, FTSE +0.1%, CAC -0.7%, DAX -0.4%
Spot gold flat at $US1269.46 an ounce

Brent crude +0.3% to $US56.65 a barrel
US oil +0.9% to $US50.17 a barrel
Iron ore +7.2% to $US73.70 a tonne
Dalian iron ore +3.9% to 555 yuan

LME aluminium +0.6% to $US1918 a tonne
LME copper +0.7% to $US6369 a tonne
10-year bond yield: US 2.29%, Germany 0.54%, Australia 2.67%
From Today's 
Financial Review
: Residential property borrowing continues to grow despite repeated attempts by regulators to jawbone banks and borrowers into cutting back.
: Corporate lending by Chinese banks in Australia has surged 23 per cent over the past year as the big four pull back.
: July is usually a good month for shares but the major S&P/ASX 200 index has just posted its worst July in six years according to Bell Potter's Richard Coppleson.
United States

Tematica Research: "We've got more than 1200 companies reporting quarterly earnings this week, making it the high water mark for such activity this time around. Among those will be 133 S&P 500 companies (including two Dow 30 components)."
All three major US indexes were set for their best monthly gains since February, with the Dow touching yet another record high.
The tech-heavy Nasdaq was, however, trading lower on Monday afternoon weighed down by Apple, Facebook, Google parent Alphabet and Amazon.
"We've been in a little bit of pull-back on some of the tech stocks for the last few days. I think it's just a matter of the fact that they have had a very strong run," said Randy Frederick, vice president of trading and derivatives for Charles Schwab in Austin, Texas.
"The bull market is sort of broadening out and people are taking a few profits off the table on some these stocks that have done exceedingly well."
Of the 289 S&P 500 companies that reported results until Friday, 73 per cent of them beat analyst expectations. This is above the 71 per cent average over the past four quarters, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S.
Apple, a part of the Dow, is expected to report quarterly results after market close tomorrow (Tuesday in the US) and its performance may hold the sway over tech stocks this week.
Europe

Weakness among tobacco stocks and some broker downgrades weighed on European shares, sending them lower on the final trading day of July as analysts dissected what was beginning to look like an "underwhelming" earnings season.
The pan-European STOXX 600 index was down 0.1 per cent while euro zone stocks and blue chips fell 0.3 to 0.4 per cent. Britain's commodity-heavy FTSE 100 index held on to 0.1 per cent gains while France's CAC 40 underperformed, hitting its lowest in three months.
Stocks retreated as financials became a drag on the main European indexes. HSBC ended 1.9 per cent higher, however, after posting a forecast-beating 5 per cent rise in first half pretax profit and announced its third buyback in a year.
As the European second-quarter earnings season gathers pace, around 46 per cent of MSCI Europe firms have reported results, 59 per cent of which have either met or beaten analysts' expectations, according to Thomson Reuters data. 
The STOXX 600 ended the month 0.4 per cent lower, hampered in July by a stronger euro which has weighed on euro zone firms, especially exporters. It was the second consecutive month of losses for the pan-European index.
Asia

Hong Kong stocks closed at a 25-month high on Monday after completing a seventh-straight month of gains, powered by strength in dual-listed resource firms which forecast rises in first-half earnings.
The Hang Seng index rose 1.3 per cent, to 27,323.99, while the China Enterprises Index gained 0.7 per cent, to 10,827.84 points. For the month, HSI was up 6.1 per cent, while HSCE gained 4.5 per cent.

In Shanghai, the blue-chip CSI300 index rose 0.5 per cent, to 3737.87, while the Shanghai Composite Index added 0.6 per cent to 3273.03 points, its highest since mid-April. For the month, CSI300 advanced 2.0 per cent, while SSEC gained 2.5 percent.
The market had a muted reaction to official figures released on Monday that showed China's July factory growth cooled slightly as export orders eased.
Japan's Nikkei ended slightly softer on Monday and at 6-1/2-week lows as a sell-off in index heavyweight stocks SoftBank and Fanuc offset gains in steelmakers and other companies with upbeat earnings.
The Nikkei fell 0.2 per cent to 19,925.18 points, its lowest close since June 15. For the month, the Nikkei shed 0.5 per cent, snapping a thhree-month winning streak.
Industrial robot maker Fanuc Corp dropped 3.1 percent as its upward revision to its earnings fell short of analysts' forecasts, while SoftBank Group shed 2.3 per cent. The two stocks contributed a hefty negative 51 points to the Nikkei benchmark index's fall.
The Topix dropped 0.2 per cent to 1618.61, but eked out a monthly gain of 0.4 per cent. Gains in small cap shares helped it outperform the Nikkei this month.
The Nikkei's underperformance led the ratio of Nikkei versus Topix, the so-called NT ratio, to its lowest since April 2016.
Currencies

The US dollar hit a 2-1/2-year low against the euro on Monday on month-end portfolio adjustments and expectations for a more hawkish European Central Bank, and touched a more than six-week low against the yen on concerns over low US inflation.
A flash estimate of euro zone inflation showed that consumer price rises in July were level with the month before, standing stable at 1.3 per cent and in line with forecasts of economists polled by Reuters. The ECB targets inflation of just below 2 per cent.
"Room for the ECB to continue to deny that the economy is getting better seems to be diminishing," said Thierry Wizman, global interest rates and currencies strategist at Macquarie Group in New York.
Pacific Investment Management Co is hugging the short-end of the Canadian bond market, betting the country's central bank will turn cautious after raising interest rates this month.
Ed Devlin, head of the Canadian portfolio at Pimco, the second-biggest US fixed-income manager, said two-year government bond yields are likely anchored around current levels after soaring since the Bank of Canada unexpectedly turned hawkish in mid-June and raised rates July 12. Ten-year and 30-year bond yields could rise another 25 basis points to 30 basis points, he said.
Commodities

Citigroup preview of Rio's results: "We expect RIO to report underlying EBITDA of $US9.5b vs Vuma consensus of $US9.2b. We forecast underlying earnings to improve yoy to $US4.33b (1H16 $US1.56b) primarily driven by higher iron ore prices offsetting lower volumes. Underlying EPS of US241¢ with a payout ratio of 45 per cent (dividend typically skewed to 2H) drives an interim dividend forecast of US108¢/sh, lower than consensus of US118¢/sh (must be assuming a higher payout). We expect net debt to fall to $US7.8b from $US10.2b at 31 December 2016."

The price of copper hit a two-year peak on upbeat manufacturing data in China, while nickel hit a near four-month high on renewed supply worries and soaring steel prices.
"Confidence in a second-half slowdown is somewhat softening and this is then reflected in a more positive assessment of industrial metals given they are so closely related to the Chinese economy," said Carsten Menke, analyst at Julius Baer.
London Metal Exchange copper closed up 0.7 per cent at $US6369 a tonne, having hit $US6430 earlier, the highest since May 2015.
Nickel ended up 0.1 per cent at $US10,270, having earlier hit its highest since early April at $US10,355.
Russia's Norilsk Nickel (Nornickel), the world's second largest nickel producer, said its second-quarter nickel production fell 8 per cent, adding it could miss its 2017 output target by up to 3 per cent.
Activity in China's steel industry expanded in July at the fastest pace since April 2016, industry data showed, fuelled by strong demand and low levels of inventory.
China's Shangdon Zinfa has halted 530,000 tonnes of aluminium capacity, according to media reports.
Aluminium closed up 0.6 per cent at $US1918 a tonne, zinc closed up 0.7 per cent at $US2795, lead ended up 0.6 per cent at $US2334 while tin closed up 0.2 per cent at $US20,650.

Australian Sharemarket

The benchmark S&P/ASX Index rose 0.3 per cent to 5720.6 points, to end the month marginally lower - its worst July in six years
BHP hit a five-month high, closing up 2.3 per cent at $25.85 while main rival Rio Tinto also finished the session up 2.3 per cent. Fortescue Metals was swept up in the positive iron ore sentiment and closed up 4.3 per cent. ​
Street Talk

with Reuters, Bloomberg, AAP
Comments? Questions? Let us know what you think of Before the Bell. You can reach Timothy Moore at  timothy.moore@fairfaxmedia.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US108</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$118</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Enterprises Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Schwab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMI July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Metal Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Investment Management Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citigroup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US73.70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSI300</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US7.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LME</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Devlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1269.46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBITDA of $US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European STOXX 600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pimco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hang Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julius Baer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Nikkei</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US20,650</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP +1.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX -0.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50.17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSCI Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sharemarket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell Potter's Richard Coppleson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Topix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday, 73</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 50 -0.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow +0.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2334</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio +1.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 2.67</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Depot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Caixin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPS of US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SSEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2795</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq -0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikkei</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD +0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randy Frederick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chevron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SoftBank Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Central Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10,270</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nornickel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>H</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10,355</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's Norilsk Nickel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US56.65</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany 0.54</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US9.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.56</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US 2.29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6430</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fanuc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fanuc Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Shangdon Zinfa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC -0.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai Composite Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6369</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tematica Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten-year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France's CAC 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US4.33</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SoftBank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Hickie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue Metals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thierry Wizman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE +0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2016</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carsten Menke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vuma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1918</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hickie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OPEC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Economics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
