<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403273231852209</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/its-amazing-how-our-eating-is-changing/3206273/</url>
  <title>It's amazing how our eating is changing</title>
  <content>
I REMEMBER driving into Caloundra in October 1989 with three kids, a dog and my hubby Bill. We had a sign on the side of the window made by friends: "The Griswalds do Caloundra".
We made the big move from the northern beaches of Sydney to search for a better life. The Sunshine Coast weather, beaches and laid-back lifestyle were the attractions and that hasn't changed.
I was instantly in love with the town and have fond memories of a much-less populated place with fewer cars on the road. Progress is a good thing and over time I have seen a change in many areas - especially food.
I had no idea as we drove into Caloundra all those years ago that I would be known as "Australia's low-fat queen" or that I would have seven best-selling cookbooks and a range of fabulous breakfast shakes.
Back then I weighed 100kg, so my approach to food was quite different to the healthy Annette of today.
And there's been a huge evolution of cafes and restaurants over the years. No longer do we need to drive to the Bird of Paradise in Kawana to the only Chinese restaurant in the area and takeaways are more refined as people look for healthier options.
We now have an abundance of quality eateries that cater to locals and tourists alike.
Ocean St, Maroochydore, is a great example: a whole street filled with amazing restaurants that are so diverse. Take a stroll down this street to see businesses that are listening to what we want - fun, hip places to eat with interesting foods.
Mooloolaba is one of my favourite go-to places.
There's so many enticing menus to choose from and that view of the beach is amazing.
I remember, back in the day, the main choices on this strip were burgers or fish and chips.
We are spoilt for choice with international restaurants compared to just the local Chinese back in the day.
You can dine on most cuisines: Mexican, Peruvian, Italian, Spanish, Thai, Japanese - you name it, we have it. Then there's the current trend of organic, vegan and raw cafes, which I love.
There's world-class restaurants now. Take Spirit House, for example. Its staff serve award-winning food in a unique rainforest setting and it's a complete dining experience.
We have evolved and are now known for our food and for this, I am so very proud.
There are wonderful independent supermarkets, butchers and fruit shops, who provide local produce and brands. We also have some amazing farmers' markets filled with an interesting array of farm-fresh produce, and I love to support our regional growers.
Sunshine Coast locals of today are much more aware, demanding good-quality, fresh, healthy options. There's been a massive shift to "fresh is best".
I'm so glad that I have been able to create the healthy lifestyle I wanted when I first drove into town 27 years ago.
We have awesome weather, clean beaches and healthy food choices in abundance.
After many years of buffet-style restaurants, we have come of age and evolved into a region of enthusiastic foodies who appreciate good-quality food.
I love to dine out with friends at every opportunity I get, whether it's breakfast, lunch or dinner.
We are now blessed with many fabulous options to choose from.
I am proud to call the Sunshine Coast my home and am grateful to live in such a beautiful part of the world.
Bar, restaurant to pave way for precinct renewal
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ocean St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peruvian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1989</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griswalds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bird of Paradise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spirit House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
