<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403346246297400</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/coast-boys-24-hour-wait-for-arm-snapped-in-half/3207043/</url>
  <title>Coast boy's 24-hour wait for arm snapped in half</title>
  <content>
A SUNSHINE Coast boy has waited for more than 24 hours for treatment after breaking his arm clean in half.

Doonan's Christian Cameron, 9, was playing with friends yesterday morning when he fell from his skateboard, snapping his arm at 10am.

Christian was raced to Nambour Hospital in an ambulance.

From there, Christian and his frantic mother Lieke Cameron were forwarded to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital where they would wait more than 20 hours for treatment for the break.

Ms Cameron said she was appalled by the lack of communication between doctors, nurses and wards.

BROKEN ARM: Christian Cameron's arm was snapped in two after he fell off his skateboard.Contributed

"There was only one student doctor (who visited last night)," she said.

"He promised he was going to come back to tell us what time the surgery was and he didn't even come back."

Ms Cameron said her son didn't eat until late into the night as nurses weren't sure if he'd be going into surgery.

"It's no service and miscommunication," she said.

Ms Cameron also questioned if the newly built hospital was understaffed.

At 11.15am this morning Christian finally went under the knife, with surgeons manipulating the bone into a position so it could heal.

Ms Cameron said she was "relieved" to see her son treated after sitting up all night with him.

Christian woke from his surgery at about 2.30pm and is on the road to recovery.

The Sunshine Coast Hospital and Health Service has apologised for the delay.

"The Sunshine Coast Hospital and Health Service extends its apologies for the poor communication experienced by this patient and his carer about when his surgery would occur," a spokeswoman said.

"The demand for urgent operations changes frequently depending on the type of emergencies in the Emergency Department, and at other hospitals which may refer patients to Sunshine Coast University Hospital.

"This makes predicting surgical timeframes a challenge and can delay some patients if more acutely unwell patients, often with life-threatening conditions, need to be operated on first.

"Systems exist to ensure that urgent surgeries are undertaken at times that are clinically appropriate and that the safety of our patients is never compromised.

"However, we acknowledge the distress this can cause to patients and their carer's and will be looking into how we could have better communicated."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Service</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Cameron</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieke Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doonan's Christian Cameron, 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
