<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403277526819605</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/seachange-dream-is-now-reality/3206265/</url>
  <title>Seachange dream is now reality</title>
  <content>
IN 1976, our family was part of the first wave of sea changers to the Sunshine Coast from Melbourne.
Towing a caravan, we pulled into Cotton Tree Caravan Park, set up camp on the river's edge, and thought all our paradises had arrived at once.
A few weeks later, this "holiday" state of mind was fast evaporating in line with our bank balance. Our two sons needed to be back in primary school and we needed to either find a job or start a business.
On a drive to Kondalilla Falls, we passed through Montville.
The main street then consisted of a general store, a production pottery, an art gallery, a few old houses plus, opposite the one-room primary school, an unoccupied, derelict, three-storey building which had been the original Montville store.
How could we resist buying such an eccentric find?
Six months of renovations later, with zero savings left, we opened Misty's Restaurant in the front of the building and lived at the back. I cooked, Peter waited on tables and after school, the boys helped wash dishes and clean up.
Forty years later, the whole family looks back on those years with great affection. The old building still stands today, continuing to operate as a restaurant.
The local historical society later placed a plaque at the front, stating that Misty's Restaurant and Mr and Mrs Brierty were the founders of modern Montville. Happy memories indeed.
Fast forward to 1995. Planning a quiet semi-retirement (a classic example of "be careful what you wish for"), we purchased five acres of bare paddock at Yandina and started Spirit House restaurant.
The first three years involved a total land makeover, planned and supervised by Buderim landscape gardener Felix Adena.
Clumps of bamboo to give some instant shade, rainforest trees, understorey plants, a large pond excavated and trickling creek systems were created.
There is a photo of this original stage on the wall in the restaurant. We look at that photo today and are in awe at our business bravery and continued naivety.
Today, Spirit House continues to grow, with major input from our now middle-aged sons. With the addition of the cooking school, a dedicated bar and private dining room and the increasingly-popular Asian food tours, the business provides employment for more than 55 staff.
An iconic Sunshine Coast dining destination, Spirit House is proof that it's never too late to turn your dreams into reality.
Bar, restaurant to pave way for precinct renewal
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Brierty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Misty's Restaurant</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kondalilla Falls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spirit House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montville</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felix Adena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree Caravan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
