<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403273231852141</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/good-music-and-great-generosity/3206305/</url>
  <title>Good music and great generosity</title>
  <content>
EVERY community has its constants and for the Sunshine Coast, the local radio station is definitely one of them.
The region was still known as the Near North Coast when 4NA Nambour first hit the airwaves on Thursday, October 9, 1964. Since then, the broadcasters have been 4SS, 4SSS, New Mix 93 FM and now the popular 92.7 Mix FM.
Locals remember 4NA Nambour for its music and generosity to local community groups. It was common to hear funeral announcements on the radio each morning and a farmers' report on a Saturday.
And who over the age of 40 can't remember being glued to the radio, waiting to record the latest hits on a cassette recorder?
These days, Mix-FM caters to all ages with a mix of fun local personalities, community involvement and the greatest hits from the past 50 years.
And the generosity which began all those years ago is still evident.
Mix-FM's long-time breakfast announcer, Caroline Hutchinson, remembers when the hugely-successful Give Me Five For Kids fundraising campaign began.
"It all started in 1999 when my on-air partner at the time, Peter Lang, and I discovered that premature babies were being 'bagged' - manually assisted to breath - when they were being transferred to Brisbane," Caroline recalls.
"We put out the call for transport ventilators and it went nuts. We needed $15,000 to buy one ventilator and we ended up buying two.
"The initiative gets bigger and bigger every year. We are blown away by what is donated, how much people are prepared to bid on air and how much we ultimately raise."
Along with Give Me Five For Kids, Caroline said some of her fondest memories were the celebrity interviews she had done and helping keep communication open during an emergency.
"There is nothing like being on the radio during a mini-cyclone or rain event, when I really feel we can help share information and keep people safe," she said.
"But the stories of sick kids and the community's response to those kids are why I love my job so much."
Caroline said the media was changing and the future was not certain. "Between Netflix, online news and Pandora, I don't think anyone in media knows what the future will hold but I have a lot of faith in being local, telling local stories and the power of community. That's the biggest highlight of my time at Mix - the fact we are part of this town. We're the local you know!"
In many ways, Caroline seems to have been "the local we know" for as long as many people can remember and she has seen plenty of changes over the years.
"Peter Lang and I used to tour bowls clubs on a Wednesday morning to run quiz competitions and hand out prizes to the bowlers. We were usually paid with the roast special! That was back in the days when the Winter Bowls Carnival was the biggest thing on the Coast and we used to announce the results on the air. The Nutri Grain series was huge, too - Clint Robinson and Kerry Thomas were superstars."
But she said the biggest change in her industry had been the evolution of social media.
"It's such a big part of our show these days. It's a great place to find local stories, stay in touch with people and get a handle on what people on the Coast are talking about. I know some people hate it, but I love it."
It's a long way from having teenage listeners waiting to record their favourite songs on cassette but the focus is still very much on good, popular music with Mix-FM still playing all the hits from the 1970s, '80s, '90, "naughties" and now.
What they'll be playing in another 50 years is anyone's guess.
Bar, restaurant to pave way for precinct renewal
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
KEN has more than a passing interest in the evolution of music.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>FM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Give Me Five For Kids</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Lang</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Mix 93 FM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mix FM</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pandora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SSS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nutri Grain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Hutchinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winter Bowls Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NA Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 9, 1964</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerry Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
