<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403281821787005</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/a-time-of-weddings-parties-and-goodbyes/3206258/</url>
  <title>A time of weddings, parties and goodbyes</title>
  <content>
WE COULD have never imagined, when we first moved to Caloundra from Melbourne in 1975 as a young married couple, that we would become the longest-established restauranteurs on the Sunshine Coast.
In 1975, we opened the Coast's first Italian a-la-carte restaurant on Bowman Rd, called Baggins' Bistro. It was a place for lovers of good food and wine to gather. Most patrons called it Bruno's Bistro.
Many people used to get dressed up in long evening gowns to come to dinner at Bruno's. As Bowman Rd was the main road into Caloundra, it was the first stop for people coming from Brisbane.
In 1982, as Caloundra grew rapidly, we decided to move to new, larger premises designed by us on Nicklin Way so we could handle the high demand for our a-la-carte Italian food.
It was called Bruno's Taverna and more suited to catering for the different needs that developed: a larger, cosy restaurant with a fireplace for relaxed a-la-carte, fine-dining Italian cuisine and, next door, a pizzeria for takeaway pizza and pasta. In a short period, we saw many changes to the area.
There was significant growth as well as two recessions which saw many locals leave, then a new cycle of people moving to the Coast for a lifestyle change and more growth.
This new wave brought more patrons from so many diverse walks of life. Many have become friends - part of the extended family - and still come regularly, now having become three and four generations of Bruno's patrons.
In 2003, we decided it was time to hang up the pots and pans and lease the restaurant so we could spend more time with our five children. The new owners changed the business to French/Italian cuisine.
Bruno decided he missed the kitchen and wonderful clientele too much, so in July 2006, "the original Bruno" was back! The name was changed to reflect the different atmosphere, to Bruno's Borgo Antico Ristorante.
In Italy, the "Borgo Antico" is the antique district, historic centre, where the old traditional way is valued and preserved.
In the same manner, Bruno values the traditional method of preparing food, using the freshest ingredients and cooking only the conventional way.
Originally, only the takeaway was re-opened but after our customers and friends insisted, the restaurant re-opened in 2009.
It is exciting and heart-warming for us to have patrons sharing their family celebrations with us year after year, international and interstate customers returning each time they visit, as well as interstate customer's children, now parents themselves, bringing their children, reminiscing about their childhood experiences at Bruno's.
Of the many weddings we catered for, one still brings a giggle. The couple always used to sit by the fireplace and that is where he proposed.
He requested the bride and groom sit on that same table with the fire going throughout the wedding celebration.
Normally that would not be a problem but this was in the middle of a boiling hot summer!
The air-conditioner and fans were going full blast, jackets and ties were coming off and people were just about melting ... but the fire had to be kept full blast. If we tried to let it fizzle out, we got the nod to keep feeding the fire.
We fondly remember Peter, one of our wonderful regular customers who only had a few weeks left to live. When given the choice of being taken anywhere for a farewell dinner with his family, he chose to come to Bruno's. He was delivered by an ambulance, with oxygen tank and all, welcomed by his family who had gathered from all over Australia, to celebrate his life and say goodbyes.
What an absolute gift and honour to be part of such an event! We will never forget him.
It is so awe-inspiring to have three and four generations of wonderful families regularly come to celebrate or just dine with us - families who started with just a couple in 1975 and now are great-grandparents. They come to celebrate the new and the past and anything in between - the birthdays; the life of the generations that are no longer here but make their presence known when they and their birthdays are acknowledged; milestones such as engagements, weddings, anniversaries, promotions, graduations ... or just a dinner out.
We feel so deeply honoured to be and have been part of all these celebrations.
Bar, restaurant to pave way for precinct renewal
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruno</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicklin Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruno's Taverna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Borgo Antico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruno's Bistro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2006</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruno's Borgo Antico Ristorante</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baggins' Bistro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French/Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowman Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
