<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403337656362663</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/uni-sexual-assault-report-to-reveal-extent-of-attacks/8759592</url>
  <title>University sexual assault report to reveal extent of attacks, harassment among students</title>
  <content>
A long-awaited report into sexual assaults at Australian universities is expected to show that minorities on campus are more likely to be attacked or harassed.

Key points:

The Human Rights Commission surveyed 39,000 students from across the country
Report is expected to reveal the proportion of male victims is higher than anticipated
It's also understood it will show a higher than expected level of harassment on public transport

The report, which is scheduled to be handed down this morning, is expected to reveal that groups including the LGBTI community, students with a disability, Indigenous people, and post-graduates are disproportionately represented among victims.
The report is based on a landmark survey of 39,000 students across the country by the Australian Human Rights Commission.
It is expected to show the proportion of male victims of sexual assault at universities is higher than anticipated, particularly among gay men.
Most assaults happened between students and more than half of victims knew their perpetrators, but experts suggest this is lower than mainstream research would predict.
The commission also found a significant proportion of assaults between post-graduate students and their university supervisors.
While many assaults happened at residential on-campus colleges, the report is also understood to show a higher than expected level of sexual harassment and assaults at off-campus locations, such as public transport.
Student groups around the country were briefed on Monday on the report's contents.
They are concerned it may not highlight significant difficulties of reporting sexual assault in regional locations or sufficiently capture the experience of international students who may not have engaged with the survey.
The survey is also expected to raise concerns about a lack of reporting, with many students downplaying the seriousness of their experience and others not knowing how to report or react if they were a witness.
The commission will make a number of recommendations for reform including programs to improve attitudes and behaviour, intensive training for first responders, and a national counselling hotline for victims.
The report was prompted by years of activism by women's groups on campuses amid disturbing claims that universities were responding poorly to incidents of sexual assault.'
He was older, bigger, and I was in unfamiliar territory'

Jane (not her real name) was sexually assaulted at the hands of a classmate. Then, it was her Victorian-based university's response that she said was the "real kick in the groin".
The 23-year-old, who does not want to be identified, was studying a massage course at a joint TAFE-university campus in late 2016 when she said she was assaulted by a classmate.
It happened when she went to the mature-age student's home to practice massage techniques.
"I did tell him beforehand I didn't want to be treated in a certain area, but he breached that boundary," Jane said.
"He was older than me, bigger, and I was in unfamiliar territory so I just allowed it to continue."
The assault continued in a bedroom with the young woman making a number of attempts to leave.
"He would stop me and ... said to me that he's the type of guy he's got to finish things," she said.
"I thought of all those other cases where bodies were found in body bags. I feared that.
"He gave me a lift home afterwards and said, 'let's keep this our little secret'."
The woman was teamed up with the perpetrator for exercises in class the next day when she said he groped her and tried to force her to touch him on two separate occasions.
'They took his side, they believed him'

Two months after the initial assault, the student and her mother went to the university.
The university gave her three options including going to the chancellor, mediation, or writing an email to her perpetrator and blocking contact.
It was at this point staff indicated there was insufficient evidence to support her claims.
"He's doing a course that's going to put vulnerable people in the future at risk," Jane said.
The university indicated it would inform her teachers that the two could not be put together in class - but it didn't happen.
Jane had to individually tell all her tutors what had taken place.
"And I got in trouble with [the university] that I had breached the confidentiality agreement. It just felt like I had been kicked in the groin."
Jane said she failed a practical exam because of the stress but received no allowances from the institution.
She was offered free counselling but it was on a day she didn't attend the campus and not near where she lived.
When she went to the police and obtained a restraining order against the perpetrator, it was used against her during exam time.
"I get an email from one of my teachers letting me know that I should not go to the uni for any reason [that day] because he was doing his final exam," Jane said.
"They had took his side, they believed him. They were able to organise for him to finish but with my situation, I was going back and forth, back and forth, to try and finish my last class."
Report has been 'a long time coming'

The group End Rape on Campus Australia has been a major agitator for change.
Ambassador Anna Hush said she believed the commission's report would confirm a high incidence of sexual assault and harassment among university students.
"In terms of our anecdotal experience, it's huge. Sexual assault is occurring at a really high rate within these communities," Ms Hush said.
"This report has been a long time coming. This type of research is something that students and student representatives have been pushing for a really long time."
Universities have attempted to respond to the increased scrutiny around sexual assault on campus by launching a campaign called Respect. Now. Always to prevent violence and harassment.
All 39 of Australia's universities will also release data today on the incidence of sexual assaults on their respective campuses following a media campaign calling for transparency.
Universities Australia chair Margaret Gardner said vice-chancellors across the country would be meeting with students this week to discuss the report's findings.
"Sexual assault and sexual harassment are not acceptable," Professor Gardner said.
"They are not behaviours that we can tolerate. Sexual assault is a crime. Sexual harassment is a totally unacceptable behaviour.
"We are committed along with our students and staff to actually working to the best of our ability to prevent sexual harassment and sexual assault on our campuses, and to contribute to the prevention of sexual assault and harassment across the wider community."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campus Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE-university</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>End Rape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambassador Anna Hush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
