<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403427850677412</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/locked-out-us-diplomats-in-moscow-say-they-cant-access-diplomatic-property-20170731-gxmnf5.html</url>
  <title>Locked out! US diplomats in Moscow say they can't access diplomatic property</title>
  <content>
Moscow: The US embassy in Moscow accused Russian authorities on Monday of barring diplomatic staff from a property on the outskirts of Moscow, after having earlier granted access until midday on Tuesday for them to retrieve belongings.
The Russian foreign ministry did not immediately respond to requests for comment.

Up Next

Xi oversees massive military parade

01:10

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Russia to expel 755 US diplomatic staff

Russian President Vladimir Putin says Moscow will expel 755 US  diplomats and could impose additional measures against the United States in response to new US sanctions against Russia.

The property, in a picturesque spot on a bend in the Moskva river north-west of the Russian capital, is leased by the US embassy for its staff to use for recreation.
Moscow has said it is taking it back as part of retaliatory measures after Washington approved a fresh round of sanctions against Russia.

A Reuters TV cameraman outside the country residence, known in Russian as a dacha, saw five vehicles with diplomatic license plates, including a truck, arrive at the site. He said they were denied entry.
An embassy spokeswoman said: "In line with the Russian government notification, the US Mission to Russia was supposed to have access to our dacha until noon on August 1.Photo: AP
"We have not had access all day today or yesterday," she said. "We refer you to the Russian government to explain why not." 

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Reuters
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Mission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moskva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
