<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403268936884785</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/rocks-big-names-were-regulars-on-the-coast/3206246/</url>
  <title>Rock's big names were regulars on the Coast</title>
  <content>
BACK in the 1970s and '80s when venues such as Surfair and the Mooloolaba Hotel were playing live music two or three nights a week, it was Ashley Robinson's job to not only book the bands but also make sure their visit went smoothly and then pay them.
"Working at Surfair, on any week you'd have INXS playing one night, then Split Enz the next night and Cold Chisel the night after," he recalls.
"It was a bit like the wild west. There were a lot of fights and a lot of drink-driving.
"I got to know some of the bands quite well and there were some wild boys but most of them were great.
"For Jimmy Barnes and the boys from Cold Chisel, we used to have to cart two rubbish bins full of grog up to the room before the show. There'd be vodka and all sorts of spirits and beer and there was never anything left at the end.
"Jimmy was always easy to deal with. He was a good bloke.
"At the end of the night when we'd closed everything up, we used to sit down with the bands and have a drink.
"Blokes like Max Merritt, our good friend Russell Crowe (his band was terrible but we had a lot of fun sitting there drinking with them after the show).
"My favourite was Dave Gleeson from The Screaming Jets. He was just a good bloke who loved talking about footy and loved having a beer.
"The guys from Screaming Jets and Dragon and The Radiators ... all good blokes. So were the boys from Mental As Anything, Painters and Dockers, The Lime Spiders, The Church, Hunters and Collectors."
Matchbox 20, The Baby Animals, The Cruel Sea, The Sunnyboys, The Cockroaches (later rebranded and relaunched as The Wiggles), The Divinyls and Paul Kelly have all enjoyed some Ashley Robinson hospitality over the years
But not every encounter was friendly. Ashley recalls the night Doc Neeson, lead singer of The Angels, knocked himself out on a beam above the stage at the Mooloolaba Hotel.
"He vowed to never play there again and he never did," he laughs.
He also remembers a previous appearance by The Angels, when hotel owner Roy Thompson told them to turn the music down. They refused and soon the security staff were trading punches with the band's roadies.
"We were all fighting amongst ourselves while the band was still playing," Ashley laughs.
A similar situation arose with Split Enz when they played at Surfair and owner Stan Elson demanded they turn the volume down. When they refused, he literally pulled the plug on their power halfway through a song.
"Everyone was booing us and the place was going ballistic, but they were unbelievable days," Ashley says.
Then there was the time the legendary Molly Meldrum parked his Jaguar in the middle of the bottle shop drive-through at Surfair and refused to move it.
"We told Stan Elson it was Molly's Jag and Stan said, 'I don't care if it's the Queen Mother, get him to shift his car'.
"So we've gone and told Molly and he's said, 'Don't you know who I am?' ... he was not happy, let me tell you!
"They were great days."
Bar, restaurant to pave way for precinct renewal
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly's Jag</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Split Enz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angels</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baby Animals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Divinyls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly Meldrum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cold Chisel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Screaming Jets</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Robinson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan Elson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Crowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaguars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lime Spiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunnyboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doc Neeson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Gleeson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cruel Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Barnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Hotel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Mother</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Merritt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INXS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
