<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403384901003708</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/sport/other-sports/2017/08/01/los-angeles-to-host-2028-olympics/</url>
  <title>Los Angeles reaches deal to host the 2028 Olympics: reports</title>
  <content>
Los Angeles will reportedly host the 2028 Olympics after reaching a deal with IOC in a move that paves the way for Paris to host the 2024 Games.
An announcement from the International Olympic Committee was expected later on Monday.
Los Angeles Mayor Eric Garcetti's office said he and other backers of the city's bid for the 2024 Olympic and Paralympic Games would make an announcement at 9am (AEST).
A formal announcement about which city would host and when was not expected until September when the International Olympic Committee (IOC) is set to meet in September in Lima, Peru.
Los Angeles - host of the Summer Olympics in 1932 and 1984 - had argued that it could host a low-cost Olympics given that it already has all the necessary infrastructure in place, while Paris would need to build several expensive venues.
Recent bids by Paris had been passed over, and many felt the French capital was due to get the nod for the 2024 Games, which will mark 100 years since the last time it hosted a Games.
Paris has said it needed to host in 2024 as the site it has earmarked for the Olympic Village would not be available for redevelopment after 2024.
The two cities were the only ones left in the race for 2024 after Budapest, Hamburg and Rome withdrew.
Mr Garcetti has said that while Los Angeles would prefer to host the Games in 2024, it was not outright opposed to hosting in 2028 instead.
"An Olympic win is an Olympic win," Garcetti told Reuters in May when the city hosted an IOC inspection committee.
- With AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Olympic Committee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IOC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Summer Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paralympic Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garcetti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Garcetti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Mayor Eric Garcetti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
