<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403513750024737</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/bullets-reschedule-first-home-game-to-face-phoenix-suns-as-nbl-joins-forces-with-nba/news-story/8916ca2dc3695eba3822a1142e9f9f85</url>
  <title>Brisbane Bullets to play NBA team</title>
  <content>
THE Brisbane Bullets will bounce into the big time when they play the NBA's Phoenix Suns in October as part of a groundbreaking partnership between the NBL and the world's best basketball competition.
The Bullets will take on the Suns in Phoenix on October 13 in one of three historic matches between NBL and NBA teams that will be announced in Sydney today.
The series of matches has been more than a year in the making with the NBL working overtime to forge strong links with the NBA that could eventually produce the holy grail of an NBA regular season match being played in Australia.
The Bullets were scheduled to play their first home game of the 2017-18 NBL season on the same weekend when they were set to host the New Zealand Breakers at the Brisbane Convention Centre on Sunday, October 15.
That match will be rescheduled for later in the season.
The Bullets will open their NBL campaign against reigning champion Perth in Perth on October 7 then head to the US.
They will resume their NBL season against Cairns in Brisbane on October 20.
The game in Phoenix will be a pre-season game for the Suns who finished at the bottom of the powerful Western Conference last season.
While it is an exhibition match, it will still be one of the biggest games the reborn club has ever played outside NBL grand finals as it will thrust the Bullets onto the world stage.
NBL players and coaches recently beat a path to the NBA Summer League with Bullets import Torrey Craig signed by Denver after starring for the Nuggets.
The NBA deal is the latest triumph for NBL owner Larry Kestelman who has revitalised the once struggling league with a TV deal, the rebirth of the Bullets and a healthy relationship with the rich and rapidly growing Chinese market to make the competition relevant once again.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Conference</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrey Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Breakers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA Summer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA's Phoenix Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Convention Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
