<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403595354405064</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/sport/sally-pearson-out-to-win-medal-at-world-athletics-championships/news-story/9239c9da16602b25a790c30c7e42bcb2</url>
  <title>Pearson: I'm going out to win</title>
  <content>
Australia's comeback queen of the track Sally Pearson says she is going out to win a medal at the world athletics championships which start in London on Friday, even though she acknowledges the additional pressure such a bold statement has placed upon her.
Pearson, the London 2012 Olympic gold medallist, said she didn't have to prove anything to anyone except to satisfy an inner knowledge that she is capable of putting it all together once again.
After two bad years dealing with injuries to her wrist, hamstring and Achilles, Pearson said her recent London Diamond League meet time of 12.48s - matching times she was running five years ago - has been a huge confidence boost. It also rocked the expectation that the United States hurdlers, including world record holder Kendra Harrison, would have the 100m hurdles medals sewn up.
Added to Pearson's breakthrough hot form, was some tweaking of her start since being in Athletics Australia's Tonbridge camp, near Kent, in the past week. Some of the Australian coaches have "had eyes on her training'' and helped her dial back her electric start so that she is approaching the first flight of hurdles in a more technically correct manner.
"To be fair on myself, I could say 'go out and have fun', but the other side of me says 'no, you are going out to win','' Pearson said of her Championship expectations.
"Deep down I would love a medal, any colour, that would be huge success, and I would be very satisfied with a final place.''
For the past year Pearson has been coaching herself, including writing her training program. She acknowledged that such an experience was bewitching.
"The hardest part is keeping up for competitions,'' she said, citing a series of European indoor races earlier in the year where she ran heats and finals in a day.
"Keeping myself up, that was first test,'' she said.
"You have to analyse things while keeping the athlete head on, you are trying to be the athlete and to be the coach when you have to coach.''
Pearson, 30, will spearhead the chances of Australia's medal chances at the world championships, held on the same track as the London 2012 Olympics.
Australian head coach Craig Hilliard said the championships would be a triumph if the team returns with two medals. The benchmark performance demanded by the Australian Sports Commission is 0-1 gold medals and 2-4 medals of any colour.
"I'd be happy if we got two medals at these games,'' said Hilliard, adding that the team of 62 was largely inexperienced.
"This is our next crop (of athletes) for the next four year cycle, and that's important in terms of expectation; although we have got core group of medal hopes.''
Hilliard said one of the other big medal hopes, star walker Jared Tallent, wasn't in the same shape as he was at the Rio Olympics.
"Jared had a protracted break after the Olympics and he's a dad, he's juggling fatherhood and few little niggles and some minor things have impacted (his form), he is not in Rio shape,''warned Hilliard.
Tallent, along with his wife Clare Tallent, have been finishing their final training in St Moritz before flying into London this week. The couple have their baby son, Hervey, also travelling with them.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearson, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Hilliard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Achilles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tallent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendra Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Tallent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hervey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sports Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilliard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London 2012 Olympic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare Tallent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athletics Australia's Tonbridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Moritz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
