<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402873799886560</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>17:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/03/32/attempted-murder-trial-for-mum-nears-end</url>
  <title>Attempted murder trial for mum nears end</title>
  <content>
A jury is expected to begin deliberating a verdict in the trial of a Queensland mother accused of trying to suffocate her baby on three occasions.
Ashleigh Meagan Watterson has pleaded not guilty to the attempted murder of four-month-old Sarah, who suffered catastrophic brain injuries when she was deprived of oxygen in late 2010.
Sarah died in March 2012 from unknown causes that are not part of the allegations against Watterson.
Crown prosecutor Danny Boyle said in his closing submissions on Monday that it was "beyond coincidence" Sarah suffered three life-threatening episodes only while she was left alone with her mother.
"Not once, not twice, but three times that these unexplained events happened," Mr Boyle said.
"That's an affront to common sense."
Mr Boyle also urged the jury to accept Watterson's confession made to police in August 2013 after she had been charged with attempted murder.

Related Articles

Watterson testified she lied about harming Sarah because she wanted to be "locked up" and spare her Christian family the "turmoil" of criminal proceedings.
Her defence team have argued Watterson was suffering an adjustment disorder when she was making false statements to police and loved ones.
"I didn't ever harm Sarah," Watterson told the Brisbane Supreme Court.
"I just started dribbling nonsense at people."
The jury will begin to consider its verdict after Justice Martin Burns finishes his final directions on Tuesday.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashleigh Meagan Watterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Boyle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watterson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Martin Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
