<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403595354405053</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/taringa-tricare-aged-care-development-debate-brisbane/8760656</url>
  <title>High-rise aged care development proposal for Brisbane suburb sparks height debate</title>
  <content>
A towering high-rise aged care development proposed in a south-west Brisbane suburb is prompting debate about how high is too high.
Provider TriCare is planning to build three glass-panelled towers of nine to 16 storeys in Taringa, which is double the current heights in the suburb.
It is to be fast-tracked for assessment by the Brisbane City Council under developer incentives that were introduced last year to help boost aged care and retirement beds in Brisbane.
The plan is possible because the location in Seven Oaks Street is a former pathology site, which is deemed community use/medical purpose.
Therefore the site is not limited to just three levels as residents had always believed.
About 100 locals, at the average age of 70, have begun protesting claiming the plan it will "kill the area".

Architect Lester Ehrlich says the design is a "blight on architecture" because of its sheer size.
"At 16 levels this is just the developer saying 'up yours to you guys we don't care'," he said.
Kay Hogan, who has lived in the apartment block above the site for 22 years, has made an impassioned plea to the council to scale down the development.
"Please don't do it, please don't approve it, you are breaking our hearts," she said.
It is creating a dilemma for the council trying to cater for the ageing population, with projections showing the city needs an annual increase of more than 3,000 beds.
Height issue a double-edged sword: expert

TriCare's property and planning manager Simon Dwyer said he understood the angst in the community, but the company was looking at filling the aged care void.
"There is a dire need for these kind of developments," he said.

"TriCare bought the site with the understanding the zoning is community purposed for aged care and retirement.
"There is no prescribed height limit currently on the site within the town plan."
QUT planning expert Professor Doug Baker says how high depended on how close a suburb was to the inner-city, which could be a double edged sword.
"My view is the inner suburbs have a duty to in terms of integrating other uses besides million-dollar houses," he said.
"I think we are going to have to deal with this as the city densifies.
"We have a need for aged care facilities do we push them out? is that the game and not care about access?"
Local real estate agent Daniel Lee said he had no doubt the development would decrease the value of neighbouring properties.
"A lot of these people will also lose their views which could see properties drop by tens of thousands of dollars," he said.
Since council introduced the developer incentives in September 2016, there have been more than 2,000 beds and units approved across 19 aged care and retirement developments, but none above 10 storeys.
A decision on this Taringa proposal is due within months.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Doug Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taringa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lester Ehrlich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tricare</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kay Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Oaks Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
