<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403569584600693</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:23</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/opinion-trying-to-get-through-sydney-airport/3207075/</url>
  <title>OPINION: Trying to get through Sydney airport</title>
  <content>
AS A frequent flyer I noticed the increase in airport security and its impact almost immediately as I stepped into Sydney's domestic terminal yesterday.

Bag drop queues for some airlines snaking all the way to the doors, online check-in stations swarming with people and worst of all the lines to get through security trailing behind all the bag drop stations.

The vibe of Sydney's domestic terminal was not like I have ever seen before, with most patrons confused about the cause of all the mayhem.

Lucky for me I didn't have a bag to check so my waiting time was cut in half compared to others, with my only obstacle for getting to my flight on time being the security screenings.

What agitated travellers the most was the persistence of the bag checks, with majority of people having the contents of their bags removed and rescanned numerous times, which was ultimately the cause of such a long queue.

My bags were amongst some of the lucky ones pulled apart in front of their owners looking for specific items that has shown up in the screening.

Staff proceeded to empty the entire contents of my handbag and carry-on to find the 'mysterious' object that had them confused, which turned out to be a decorative key chain on my clutch.

Once cleared the staff proceeded to hand me my belongings in multiple stacks and piles which I then had to repack.

Whilst this was happening my travel companion was swabbed for random detection testing, which the staff members explained was happening "a lot more than usual".

Whilst I respect the procedures in which security and police have to take to ensure all our safety, I felt particularly frustrated with the length of time and manner in which my bags were searched, and I was not the only one.

I felt the general consensus of people at Sydney's Domestic Airport were completely unaware of why there were so many delays keeping them from their gates and scheduled flights.

The Federal Government has since made various public statements urging travellers today to give themselves ample time to get through check-in and security, two hours domestic and three hours for international.

Based on my personal experience I would say this time allowance should be the absolute minimum, as reports from today's patrons have stated longer waiting times than I would have experienced yesterday.

This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Domestic Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
