<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403565289633288</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/hammer-stuck-teens-mouth-after-dare/3207207/</url>
  <title>Hammer stuck in teen's mouth after dare</title>
  <content>
THE mother of a teenage girl who got a hammer stuck in her mouth has had to "hide the toolbox" after her daughter's dare went viral on Twitter.

Kaley, 14, from Louisiana, USA, was challenged by a pal to put the hammer head in her mouth and uploaded pictures to social media after it got stuck.

The teen had been fangirling over members of Korean boy band BTS when she described one of them as "so beautiful I could shove a hammer in my mouth," reports the New York Post.

After her friend egged her on to do it, the tool became lodged behind her lips and she posted a hilarious image online with the caption: "how do u tell ur mom that u got a hammer stuck in ur mouth".

"It was a little too big to fit in my mouth in the first place, but getting it out was even more of a problem," Kayley told Buzzfeed News .

Luckily, after 10 minutes of yanking, the hammer came free.

The mother of a teenage girl who got a hammer stuck in her mouth has had to "hide the toolbox" after her daughter's dare went viral on Twitter.Twitter

Thousands retweeted the image and the teen even admitted she put the hammer back in her mouth a few times to show her friends.

Her baffled mum is now reportedly "hiding the toolbox" from her daughter.

"I'm now going to be known as the Hammer Girl's mother," she said.

But Kaley seemed slightly more relaxed about her viral stunt.

"There are ways to channel your excitement, and shoving a hammer in your mouth probably isn't the best," she said.

This article was first published in the New York Post.
The Ring Style Wake Up Prank:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaley, 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buzzfeed News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter.Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louisiana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ring Style Wake Up Prank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hammer Girl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
