<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403659778915755</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:44</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/01/scaramucci-interview-inappropriate-trump</url>
  <title>Scaramucci interview inappropriate: Trump</title>
  <content>
Less than two weeks into the job outspoken communications director Anthony Scaramucci has been shown the door at the White House.

1 MIN AGO 

US President Donald Trump felt comments by Anthony Scaramucci, whom he fired as his communications chief less than two weeks into the job, in a magazine interview were inappropriate, the White House says.

"The president certainly felt that Anthony's comments were inappropriate for a person in that position and he didn't want to burden General Kelly," White House spokeswoman Sarah Sanders said at a briefing, referring to John Kelly, who was sworn in as the new White House chief of staff earlier on Monday.

Scaramucci, appointed to the communications post by Trump 10 days ago, had attacked then-White House chief of staff Reince Priebus and Trump's chief strategist Steve Bannon in profanity-laden terms in an interview with the New Yorker magazine last week.

Hoping to turn the page on a tumultuous opening chapter to his presidency, Trump had insisted earlier on Monday that there was "no chaos" in his White House as he swore in the retired Marine general as second chief of staff.

An earlier White House announcement said he was leaving because he "felt it was best to give Chief of Staff John Kelly a clean slate and the ability to build his own team".

The two-sentence release concluded: "We wish him all the best."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIN AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
