<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402650461583152</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>16:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/1383190/spyrdz-sees-red-as-manly-line-up/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Spyrdz sees red as Manly line up</title>
  <content>
Spyrdz sees red as Manly line up

Ivan Spyrdz

exit
NEWCASTLE Basketball general manager Ivan Spyrdz hopes the Hunters take out their frustrations on the court when they host Manly-Warringah in their first home game of the Waratah Basketball League season at Broadmeadow tonight.

Spyrdz complained to Basketball NSW on Monday asking why the Sea Eagles were allowed to continue playing in the men's championship when they had committed a "flagrant breach" of competition rules by not fielding a women's team in the WBL, State League or Youth League.
Basketball NSW chief executive Danny Martinez responded by saying Manly nominated a team in the women's championship but Basketball NSW refused to accept their application as the Sea Eagles would not be competitive.
Manly were grand final runners-up in both the WBL women's championship and Youth League competitions last season.
"Manly put in a women's side, so they complied. We didn't allow their women's side to play, so having made that decision, I can hardly zap the men," Martinez said.
"Having said that, we're working with them on how to revitalise their women's program and they're very confident they'll have one next year."
Martinez said Basketball NSW management made the decision in consultation with the Waratah league executive committee, which Spyrdz sits on, but Spyrdz rejected this.
"There appears to be some liberty taken when recalling the process," Spyrdz said.
"The Waratah executive recommended Manly not be permitted to re-enter the championship competition after they flip-flopped a few times in pre-season on entering a team.
"Manly were granted an exemption for 2013 due to not meeting other criteria pertaining to referees. They were in, then decided to withdraw from their own volition, then they wanted back in again. How many times do we accept that?
"If Manly wanted to enter a Waratah women's team made up of youth and experience, they could have entered a Waratah State League team, but they voluntarily chose not to. Their own choice should void their right to compete in the Waratah men's championship competition by not meeting the criteria.
"I think the most distressing part of Danny's response was the admission that Basketball NSW have apparently now started to accept teams in competitions based on their competitiveness.
"Basketball NSW needs to ensure compliance to competition criteria is met, then let the teams compete with results speaking for themselves. It's obvious this situation will not change, but the Hunters will simply go out and play our hardest on Saturday night."
The 7pm game against the Sea Eagles, who opened with a 74-55 home victory over Illawarra last Saturday, will be the first chance for Newcastle supporters to see the new-look Hunters team coached by Trevor Gallacher.
Meanwhile, reigning premiers Norths Bears will return to the scene of their grand final triumph when they play Maitland Mustangs at Maitland Federation Centre at 7pm tonight.
The Mustangs and Bears women's teams meet at 5pm.
● With a little bit of luck and a lot of Corey Brewer down the stretch, Denver kept their NBA winning streak alive.
Brewer poured in a career-high 29 points, including three free throws with 2.1 seconds left, and the Nuggets ran their NBA franchise-best winning streak to 14 games after a dramatic 101-100 victory over the visiting Philadelphia 76ers on Thursday night.
Trailing by five with 14 seconds left, Brewer buried a three-pointer from the left.
Evan Turner blew two free throws at the other end then Brewer knocked down the go-ahead shots from the stripe.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norths Bears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Federation Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Mustangs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratah State League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mustang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WBL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia 76</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brewers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martinez</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evan Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEWCASTLE Basketball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spyrdz</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly-Warringah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basketball NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Gallacher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Martinez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratah Basketball League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Brewer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Spyrdz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
