<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403513750024728</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/romper-stompers-violent-neonazi-skinheads-to-run-riot-again-in-series-for-stan-20170731-gxmdgi.html</url>
  <title>Look who's back: Romper Stomper's neo-Nazi skinheads to run riot again in series for Stan</title>
  <content>
The violent skinheads of Romper Stomper are set to terrorise Australia once again, as they take to the streets in a new six-part miniseries for Stan.
Geoffrey Wright, the writer-director of the controversial 1992 film that helped make Russell Crowe a star, will revisit the violent neo-Nazi scene he depicted so unflinchingly 25 years ago, writing and directing two of the episodes.

Up Next

Trailer:
It

02:23

More Trailers Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

01:21
Trailer: Romper Stomper

Trailer: Romper Stomper

The original 1992 film that tells the story of the downfall of a neo-Nazi group in blue-collar suburban Melbourne.

Up Next

Trailer:
It

02:23

02:23
Trailer: It

Trailer:
It

The new adaptation of Stephen King's iconic work. In Derry, Maine, seven friends come face-to-face with a shape shifter, who takes the form of an evil clown who targets children.

Up Next

Trailer:
Kiki, Love to Love

01:52

01:52
Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Trailer:
Kiki, Love to Love

Director Paco LeA³nas vibrant new comedy follows a collection of lovers through a series of intertwined stories, delivering an outrageously provocative take on what can happen behind closed doors.

Up Next

Trailer:
Thor: Ragnarok

02:25

02:25
Trailer: Thor: Ragnarok

Trailer:
Thor: Ragnarok

Imprisoned, Thor must battle a former ally and race against time to prevent goddess of death Hela from destroying his home.

Up Next

Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

01:54

01:54
Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Set in Madrid, ordinary couples with real passion investigate their own sexuality through five intertwined stories.

Up Next

Trailer: A Monster Calls

02:26

02:26
Trailer: A Monster Calls

Trailer: A Monster Calls

A boy who is experiencing trauma from his single mother's terminal illness seeks the help of a tree monster.

Up Next

4 Corners: Pumped

00:30

Trailer: Romper Stomper

The original 1992 film that tells the story of the downfall of a neo-Nazi group in blue-collar suburban Melbourne.

Some key cast members will return too, though Crowe, whose character, Hando, died at the end of the film, is not among them.
"Someone suggested bringing him back, but we weren't going to do that," the director said on Monday. "I'm not interested in a parallel universe where characters who are dead come back to life."Photo: Ken Leanfore
Among those who will return are Dan Wyllie, who played gang member Cackles, and Jacqueline McKenzie, whose Gabe was at the centre of a love triangle completed by Hando and his best mate Davey (Daniel Pollock, who died shortly before the film was released).
Rising star Toby Wallace (the young Michael Hutchence in Never Tear Us Apart: The INXS Story) plays Kane, a drifter who gets drawn into a hard-right Australian nationalist group.

"The idea is what if some of those characters from the film had children, and if those children are now in their early 20s, what would happen," said Wright. "The old characters are in positions of personal power now, involved in intriguing little suburban subterfuges or high-flying corporate gambits. It might surprise people to learn that some of them really did land on their feet."
The series, which begins filming in Melbourne late next week, is being produced by John Edwards - whose extensive past credits include Police Rescue, The Secret Life of Us, Tangle and Offspring - and son Dan under their new venture with Roadshow, Rough Diamond.
"It's contemporary, set in a post-Brexit, Trump world, where the right-wing politics of then have come into the centre in a much more menacing way," Edwards senior said. "We've got an anti-fascist point of view and a secular Muslim point of view and the characters from back then - the ones who are still alive - are still with us and active in the world, and a new wave of nasties are afoot."
Wright shares directing duties with Daina Reid (Paper Giants, Never Tear Us Apart) and New Zealander James Napier-Robertson (The Dark Horse). Writing duties are shared between Wright, Napier-Robertson, poet and rapper Omar Musa, and Fairfax journalist and author Malcolm Knox.Photo: Rodger Cummins
Wright said revisiting the characters was a "very stimulating" exercise that had been in play for about 12 months, with interest in the project coming from multiple directions.
"I wouldn't say there was a bidding war exactly. It was more a question of who was going to be the most gung-ho about executing it with us."Photo: Bonnie Elliott
Although the original film was condemned by some upon its release - including, famously, David Stratton - Wright says the cultural landscape into which the series will be launched is far less forgiving.
"I think we're in more PC times now than in the old days. There's more pressure to not do this, not do that."Photo: Roadshow
So what concessions has Wright, once considered the enfant terrible of Australian cinema, made to keep everyone on side?
"The right-wingers in our story aren't the only violent people," he says. "We throw a light on a group on the other side of the fence that really hasn't been exposed much before." The left, in other words.
So  should we expect Romper Stomper redux to be a violent romp that stomps on everyone's sensibilities equally? That sounds about Wright. 
Facebook:  
Twitter: 
​
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tear Us Apart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Wyllie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqueline McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thor</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daveys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealander James Napier-Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodger Cummins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonnie Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dark Horse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monster Calls</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Rescue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Never Tear Us Apart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Life of Us</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoffrey Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hando</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Pollock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paco LeA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Crowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omar Musa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INXS Story</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Knox.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ragnarok</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trailers Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Stratton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Napier-Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daina Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MADRID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hutchence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paper Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiki</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Leanfore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roadshow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
