<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403565289633334</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:22</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/kev-de-vere-folds-up-his-tent-as-community-says-fa/3207007/</url>
  <title>Kev de Vere 'folds up his tent' as community says farewell</title>
  <content>
THE man they called the architect of a region, Kev de Vere was delayed on his final journey by a about 200 people wanting to say good-bye.

St Patrick's priest Pat Cassidy said Mr de Vere was on his way to Heaven but there were many who wanted to pay their respects before they finally let him go.

"When the tent that we live in on earth is folded up, there is a house built by God for us," he told yesterday's funeral service, quoting the Book of Corinthians.

At the request of his widow, Faith, Kev de Vere's son Chris read a poem, Funeral Blues, by WH Auden, summing up the grief of loved ones:

"He was my North, my South, my East and West,

"My working week and my Sunday rest,

"My noon, my midnight, my talk, my song:

"I thought that love would last forever; I was wrong."

And that was it. No speeches at a final ceremony where so many people had a recollection or a comment, too many probably.

"Everyone can have a talk to each other at our place later," Chris de Vere said as his father's coffin was placed in the hearse, prior to being taken for a strictly family-only burial, to be followed by the wake at Chris and Karyn de Vere's Rife Range Rd home.

Mourners included the late Mr de Vere's colleagues on the former Widgee Shire Council, ex-Gympie Mayor Mick Venardos and several councillors from Cooloola Shire, formed from the amalgamation of Widgee Shire and Gympie City councils.

That amalgamation was follwed by the merging of Cooloola Shire with Kilkivan and the southern part of Tiaro Shires, to form the current Gympie Regional Council.

Mr de Vere was a councillor and later chairman of Widgee Shire.

He pioneered what is now Southside, lobbied hard to achieve the Cooloola Coast road to Maryborough and the road to Rainbow Beach, as well as building much of the kerb and channel at Tin Can Bay, financing much of it with compensation money from the federal government's Cooloola and Fraser Island sand mining ban.

He maintained close contacts at the highest levels of Queensland politics and bureaucracy and became noted as a person who got things done.

He did not always win.

As he told it, his plan to have a major central works depot at the Showgrounds did not get through and nor did his idea of having an underpass for Monkland St at its intersection with what was then the newly re-routed Bruce Hwy.

He said the people running Gympie City in that long ago era did not want it to be too easy for people (and business and investment) to get over the river to Southside.

At that time, the highway we now know as a congested through-town traffic route, was the new by-pass carrying vehicles which had previously been forced to travel up Mary St to go north.

This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Cassidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Widgee Shire Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie Mayor Mick Venardos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kev</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Patrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Book of Corinthians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vere</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WH Auden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vere's Rife Range Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tin Can Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monkland St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooloola Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooloola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiaro Shires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kilkivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooloola Shire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rainbow Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Widgee Shire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
