<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403518044992148</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/disaster-management-plan-vital-for-all-sporting-cl/3206924/</url>
  <title>Disaster management plan vital for all sporting clubs</title>
  <content>
IN recent years Queensland has been hit by a number of major natural disasters involving high winds, floodwaters and fires.
No matter where your club is located, it is vital that you are well prepared.
A Disaster Management workshop will examine the issues surrounding natural and man-made hazards focusing specifically on 'PPRR' - Prevention, Preparedness, Response and Recovery.
Topics include writing an effective disaster management plan for the future; best communication tools for a disaster; insurance - what is covered and what isn't; effects of a disaster on the club's future financial health and membership; how to achieve a quick recovery effort and working through the maze of help and support potentially available.
The workshop is on Wednesday, August 16, from 6-9pm at Goodna Bowls Club.
Visit  for more information or to register.
Get Going clubs
A LOT is said about the infrastructure funding program Get Playing Places and Spaces, but has your club looked into Get Going Clubs?
Get Going Clubs provides funding to support not-for-profit local sport and recreation organisations to create and provide access to participation opportunities for Queenslanders.
Some examples of projects that received funding last round include: Purchase of equipment and scoreboards; courses for umpires, coaches and first aid; come and try programs.
Eligible not-for-profit sport and recreation organisations can apply for funding of up to $7,500 (GST exclusive).
Visit  for more information.
Junior Oz Tag
IPSWICH Oz Tag are again running their junior summer season starting September.
They run a tiny taggers program for 3-5 year olds as well as under 6 through to under 16.
This is a great social sport so grab some friends together and get tagged.
Visit  for more information.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Going Clubs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPSWICH Oz Tag</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oz Tag</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Get Playing Places</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPRR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodna Bowls Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disaster Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Get Going Clubs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
