<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403853052447628</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4824651/security-concern-as-mates-swap-tickets/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Questions over airport security after man flies between Newcastle and Gold Coast using his mate's name</title>
  <content>
Increased security: Newcastle Airport asked passengers to arrive earlier than normal on Monday after terror raids in Sydney on the weekend.

A money-saving stunt among friends has revealed a huge hole in domestic airport security.
A Hunter man, who Fairfax Media will not identify, said a mate had recently flown between Newcastle and the Gold Coast under his identity, because airport security was known not to check names on boarding passes against photo ID.
The Hunter man said he had originally planned to fly to the Gold Coast with a group of mates but was unexpectedly sent to Queensland for work a few days early.

Instead of paying the $55 fee to change the name on the ticket, the Hunter man checked-in online under his own name before he gave the ticket to his friend.

The pair took the gamble that airport security would not check the boarding pass against photo ID, given the man using the ticket had no check-in luggage. 
The friend made the return journey under the Hunter man's name without any trouble.

Increased security: Police on patrol at Sydney Domestic Airport on Sunday, after an alleged terrorism threat was revealed. Picture: Michele Mossop
"People who fly domestically enough know they don't check your ID," the Hunter man said.
"If you don't have a checked in bag, there's no reason to go to the counter.
"They do search you through security screening, but knowing who's on your flight at the time - you could be flying with anyone."
Newcastle Airport referred Fairfax Media's questions to the federal Office of Transport Security.
Federal Infrastructure and Transport Minister Darren Chester said the public should be confident in the airport security measures that are in place.
Mr Chester said the government constantly reviewed aviation security and would consider whether further measures were necessary.
"At all major airports, 100 per cent of travellers and their baggage are screened before boarding a flight to prevent prohibited items and weapons from being taken on board," he said.

"It is also an offence under Commonwealth law to use a false identity to obtain a ticket on a commercial passenger aircraft."
It comes amid a heightened focus on airport security after four men were arrested during a series of raids in Sydney on Saturday after authorities received a tip-off about plans to allegedly blow-up a passenger plane after it left Sydney Airport.

on Monday morning, as security measures were beefed up.

A Newcastle Airport spokesperson posted a message to travellers on Facebook on Monday morning asking passengers to
Fairfax Media understand no flights from Newcastle were delayed on Monday.

The Herald, Newcastle
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Darren Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Infrastructure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Airport</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MICHELE MOSSOP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Domestic Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
