<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403513750024718</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/factfinding-mission-brings-opposition-to-far-north/news-story/a61ebc4aed934ed839ea881576a2e9f6</url>
  <title>Shorten's NAIF pledge sparks Clare visit</title>
  <content>
LABOR Leader Bill Shorten's pledge to quarantine $1 billion from the Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility for tourism projects has prompted a quick fact-finding mission to Cairns from shadow minister Jason Clare.
The Opposition spokesman for Northern Australia visited members of Tourism Tropical North Queensland and Advance Cairns to gauge what kind of Far North tourism operations could use the NAIF loans.
"Some (tourism operators) have approached NAIF and have decided not to submit bids," he said.
"But there's not one tourism project currently being considered by NAIF.
"What rules need to change to make it easier for investment in the sort of infrastructure here in Cairns?"
The Cairns Airport has not made any bid for NAIF funding following the cancellation of its former plan for a $1 billion expansion program over two decades.
"The bigger and better the airport is, the more tourists we can attract," Mr Clare said. "Last time I was here we talked about getting the superyacht industry here in town.
"But that's just the start. Business usually has the best ideas.
"We want to make sure we hear from them over the next 12 months."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism Tropical North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Clare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten's NAIF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Clare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LABOR Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advance Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
