<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403938951795004</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/mining-and-resources/iron-ore-surges-in-largest-daily-leap-since-november-20170731-gxmn5n.html</url>
  <title>Iron ore surges in largest daily leap since November</title>
  <content>
The spot price of iron ore surged to near $US74 a tonne overnight as mid concerns about tightening supplies and resilient construction activity in China.
The supply concerns reflect Beijing's strong resolve to wipe out the production of substandard steel as well as environmental inspections in Hebei province gave the seaborne iron market a boost on Monday, according to Metal Bulletin.Photo: Asim Hafeez
Chinese Premier Li Keqiang reiterated on the weekend that the central government's determination in eliminating backward capacity and halting the production of substandard steel after two mills in Tianjin city and one in Hunan province were found to have resumed production of inferior products. 
Li's statement boosted sentiment in the market led to across-the-board increases for all ferrous futures, Metal Bulletin reported. Apart from this, Hebei's provincial government last Friday began another round of inspections to check on industry emissions, which raised concerns of possible disruptions to steel production.
"Environmental inspections have caused great impact on iron ore prices. Production in some mines, processing plants and mills are being disrupted," an iron ore trader in Beijing told Reuters.
"The whole supply chain has been affected by the inspections," she said.

Spot ore with 62 per cent content in Qingdao ended up $US4.97 or 7.2 per cent to $US73.70 a tonne on Monday, according to Metal Bulletin.  to $US70 a tonne from $US55, and the year-end target by $US5 to $US60.
Also bolstering positive sentiment, a continuing construction boom.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

jumped to 62.5 from 61.4 in June, boosted by government spending on infrastructure and stronger-than-expected property investment despite new regulations to curb runaway prices.
"At the beginning of the year most people had a pessimistic view on the outlook for the property market but that has changed with the stronger data releases," said Qiu Yuecheng, an analyst at steel trading platform Xiben New Line.
Futures surge too

Chinese iron ore futures surged near 8 per cent, hitting their trade limit-up with their best daily performance since November 2016.
China has been sending out environmental inspection teams to iron ore mining operations across the country since late April, and more teams will be sent out by early August, according to local media reports.
At the same time, steel mills are continuing to show increased activity.
Data from the China Federation of Logistics& Purchasing showed on Monday that the Purchasing Managers' Index (PMI) for the steel sector rose to 54.9 in July, the fastest pace since April 2016.
"Mills are actively buying raw materials preparing to seal profits," said Xu Bo, a steel analyst at Haitong Futures.
The most-traded iron ore contract on the Dalian Commodity Exchange surged nearly 8 per cent to 570.5 yuan ($US84.82) a tonne, going trade limit-up and hitting its highest mark since April 6, 2017.
Steel rebar, coke futures higher

The most-active steel rebar contract on the Shanghai Futures Exchange gained 4.7 per cent to 3733 yuan a tonne, hitting a top of 3740 yuan, highest since December 12, 2013.
China has eliminated around 120 million tonnes of low-grade steel capacity and 42.39 million tonnes of crude steel capacity, equivalent to 84 per cent of its target for the whole year, in the first half of this year.
Other steelmaking raw materials also posted big jumps on Monday on the sector's PMIs. September coking coal futures rose 5.7 per cent to 1344 yuan a tonne.
Coke futures gained 5.9 per cent to 2064 yuan a tonne, hitting an intraday peak at 2075 yuan a tonne, highest since April 2012.
Spot rebar prices rose just 0.02 per cent to 3946.59 yuan a tonne on Friday, according to data on the Mysteel website.
With wires
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Federation of Logistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Li</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US73.70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haitong Futures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 6, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metal Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai Futures Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mysteel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 12, 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qingdao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US84.82</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tianjin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hebei</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xu Bo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Premier Li Keqiang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qiu Yuecheng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metal Bulletin.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xiben New Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asim Hafeez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US4.97</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Purchasing Manager Indices</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US74</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian Commodities Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
