<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403264641917393</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/drive-ins-made-way-for-cinema/3206256/</url>
  <title>Drive-ins made way for cinema</title>
  <content>
BIRCH Carroll and Coyle bought the Maroochydore Drive-In (in the Peppertree Crt area behind where the IGA on Maud St now stands) in 1979, then the Maroochydore Cinema in 1982.
The cinema was a single-screen building in Aerodrome Rd where the ANZ bank is now and held about 500 patrons.
I joined BCC in 1989 as assistant manager to Beryl Madsen.
I worked between the drive-in and the cinema which, on weekdays, had morning and lunchtime sessions then closed before re-opening for evening sessions.
Wednesday to Sunday nights, I worked at the drive-in - greeting the carloads of patrons, selling tickets and then at interval, helping in the cafeteria.
We had many funny incidents, especially at the all-night sessions. Many patrons would arrive with their partner in panel vans and fall asleep. It was my job to wake them in the morning and send them home.
One couple, who had decided to be amorous, asked me if I could give them some more time as "they hadn't finished".
Some of the couples who frequented the drive-in would also come to the cinema and there were a couple of incidents where I was introduced to a baby "who'd been conceived at the drive-in".
When Queensland experienced daylight saving, I had a number of patrons complaining about having to start the movie an hour later - somehow they couldn't fathom that they wouldn't be able to see the movie in daylight.
Soon after the drive-in closed, Birch Carroll and Coyle decided to build a multiplex and we were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
Beryl retired soon after and I became manager.
It was soon realised that the cinemas were too small. The six cinemas then became 12 in 2002.
Some of my fondest memories of the cinemas was the relationship we had with Australia Zoo. Steve and Terri Irwin were regular attendees and when Bindi was born, Steve would bring her to see all the latest animated movies.
He would bring her to the candy bar and ask her what she wanted. It was always the same: "A packet of snakes, please."
We had several fundraisers for Australia Zoo including Cat in the Hat with an appearance from the first tiger cubs to arrive at the zoo.
In order to get them "show ready", we had to get them used to the cinema and surroundings so they were brought in prior to opening a few times in the lead-up.
They would stroll around and sharpen their claws on seats (I never told head office).
The funniest incident was when an innocent person was walking past the front of the cinemas about 8.15am and happened to glance inside. He did a double-take when he saw the tigers.
He walked away, came back, walked away again then came back and stared inside. His jaw was literally dropped to the ground.
We also had the launch of The Crocodile Hunter movie where Steve, Terri and Bindi arrived by dinghy and moored outside the cinemas, then climbed up the boardwalk, into the foyer and into the cinema to introduce the movie.
The foyer was packed with animals - camels, koalas, snakes, birds etc.
The lost property was also a source of amusement. You wouldn't believe what people left behind. One old lady left her false teeth. She took them out as they were uncomfortable and left them on an adjoining seat. It was pretty obvious what she wanted when she came back the next day.
After Beryl retired, I had a variety of assistant managers but I was then lucky enough to have Brooke Doughty appointed and she was instrumental in helping run the cinemas efficiently and also with helping achieve the outstanding results that Maroochydore was renowned for.
We won record numbers of Film Distributor awards for a variety of movies from Tarzan to Me Myself & Irene.
Bar, restaurant to pave way for precinct renewal
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maud St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coyle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brooke Doughty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beryl Madsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bindi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Drive-In</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aerodrome Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crocodile Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarzans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BIRCH Carroll</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Zoo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Cinema</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terri Irwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peppertree Crt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Film Distributor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beryl</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
