<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403934656827700</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/8ateight/8eight-asx-seen-flat-ahead-of-rba-decision-20170731-gxmo15.html</url>
  <title>8@eight: ASX seen flat ahead of RBA decision</title>
  <content>
The story that has caught the headlines is that of freshly appointed White House communications director Anthony Scaramucci being removed from his role after just 10 days in the post.
Anarchy reigns over the Oval Office, although you have to feel for "The Mooch" as he has had as bad a week as anyone could imagine, if we also include missing the birth of his child. Still, Donald Trump may have had to take a further step back to push forward. The message has resonated loud and clear that new chief of staff John Kelly is the boss and is going to forge a team of his choice and he has the President's full support in doing so. Perhaps this is the start of more stable times ahead, we shall see, but it's been a fascinating few days for those following US political circles.

The news of further personnel changes in the White House caused some buying in US fixed income and subsequent selling of US dollars. USD/JPY fell a touch to ¥110.21 and the price continues to work lower within the bearish channel (that started on July 10). I had been looking at the potential for upside in this pair, specifically on a close through ¥112.08, but this clearly hasn't eventuated and the trend, seemingly, is your friend. EUR/USD has been the pair to be long though, with the price trading higher to $US1.1845. This seems more fitting, with signs of further stability in eurozone data, with core inflation just beating expectations at 1.2 per cent. The ECB's Lautenschlager also talked up the need for a deeper discussion on an exit strategy.

With the strength in the euro in mind, and the key event risk today being the Reserve Bank of Australia meeting (at 2.30pm AEST) put EUR/AUD on the radar, as the price has traded through and could close above $1.4777. This level has been a ceiling on the pair since mid-July and the move through here could open up an extension into $1.5000 over time. Of course, AUD/USD will get the lion's share of attention from clients today and we see the pair trading just above the 80 handle going into the RBA meeting, having found buyers easy to come by thanks to the Scaramucci news and also the lazy 7.2 per cent gain in the spot iron price. Iron ore futures are on fire at the moment and the retail trader momentum juggernaut is alive and well. The old fear of missing out (FOMO) trade is driving new money into iron ore futures seemingly every day and if you are not long you're wrong. Expect Fortescue and Atlas Iron to find strong buyers again on the open.

A number of traders I've spoken to are somewhat concerned about holding Aussie dollar longs ahead of today's RBA meeting.  The idea is that the statement could show increased disdain around the level of the AUD, resulting in perhaps a tweak from its current language of "an appreciating exchange rate would complicate this adjustment" to something a touch more punchy. Personally, I'm not sure we do see a change here and there is also a good chance the weaker headline inflation read will be dismissed as transitory, so this in theory could disappoint those positioned on the bearish side of the ledger. How the AUD reacts is unclear here and the risks are symmetrical, but I sense traders will need to see a far stronger level of concern for the market to materially mark down the AUD here. Recall, the communication of late has really centred on trying to convince the market that while other G10 central banks may be moving away from an ultra-accommodative policy stance (as their economies don't require it any longer) the RBA never had to go to that level and these central banks are merely moving in line with the level of stimulus seen in Australia. We are not them and these nations moving on rates does not imply we will move - a separation speech of sorts.

In equity land, we have seen the S&P 500 closing on a flat note, with signs of increased indecision from market participants. There doesn't seem to be the conviction here to push the market into new highs, but the bears are just too frustrated because the market doesn't want to go down and every pullback is bought.

The ASX 200 will feed off this US lead and an unchanged call is our base case here with SPI futures closing up two points and trading in a meagre 19 point range in the night session. A new month though for the local market and of course new opportunities and the key questions on my radar at an index level are: 1. Will the ASX 200 then break the 5850 to 5650 trading range? Moves in the S&P 500 and Aussie earnings will dictate; 2. The monthly chart of the ASX 200 has seen two months of indecision (best seen as a "doji" candle), with the price closing close to where it opened the month, although there has been a strong contraction in the trading range in July relative to June; and 3. Will SPI futures hold 5600, as this has been huge support since June 21? A break below would be bearish development. I suspect we will actually see some answer to these questions and they will resolve themselves far more clearly. How these issues play out only price will tell, but on what information we know now I would still be a very willing seller of the market into 5850 and a seller if SPI futures close through 5600.

Keep an eye on the energy sector as well today as US crude (closed at $US50.29 +1.1%) has broken into and closed through the $US50 level. I had been a willing buyer of oil of late and happily held a long bias and see no reason to be short the barrel here. Just focus on the daily chart of crude. Price did have a modest dip through trade but found buyers at the five-day exponential moving average, which is what I'd expect in the trending market. The ASX 200 energy sector remains a 'buy' here given the strong underperformance relative to the crude price, really since mid-June.  

Market highlights

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Can earnings shake life back into the ASX 200?

What to expect this week as the corporate reporting calendar starts. This video was produced in commercial partnership between Fairfax Media and IG Markets.

SPI futures up 2 points at 5663

AUD +0.2% to 79.99 US cents (Overnight range: 0.7956 - 0.8002)

On Wall St, Dow +0.3%, S&P 500 -0.1%, Nasdaq -0.4%

In New York, BHP +1.3%, Rio +1.7%

In Europe, Stoxx 50 -0.5%, FTSE +0.1%, CAC -0.7%, DAX -0.4%

Spot gold flat at $US1269.46 an ounce

Brent crude +0.3% to $US56.65 a barrel

US oil +0.9% to $US50.17 a barrel

Iron ore +7.2% to $US73.70 a tonne

Dalian iron ore +3.9% to 555 yuan

LME aluminium +0.6% to $US1918 a tonne

LME copper +0.7% to $US6369 a tonne

10-year bond yield: US 2.29%, Germany 0.54%, Australia 2.67%

  This column was produced in commercial partnership
   between Fairfax Media and
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US73.70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD/JPY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LME</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.1845</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1269.46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlas Iron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50.29 +1.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500 -0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP +1.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX -0.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50.17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IG Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EUR/AUD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G-10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 50 -0.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow +0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio +1.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 2.67</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPI</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECB's Lautenschlager</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq -0.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD/USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US56.65</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EUR/USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany 0.54</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US 2.29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC -0.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6369</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOMO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX 200</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE +0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1918</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
