<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403651188981021</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/bubbly-sharon-was-truly-an-angel/3206960/</url>
  <title>Bubbly Sharon 'was truly an angel'</title>
  <content>
NOOSA is mourning the loss of bright, bubbly mother of two, Sharon Cuthbert, who tragically died after being hit by a truck on Thursday evening.

Tributes have poured in for the 39-year-old Noosa Council employee, who grew up in Noosa.

It's clear the mother-of-two had a profound impact on the community with many taking to Facebook to mourn an "amazing, lovely, caring friend" that "blessed their lives".

Council CEO Brett de Chastel said Mrs Cuthbert would be 'sorely missed'.

"Our Council is in shock following the tragic loss of Sharon in last Thursday's accident," he said.

"Sharon was a much loved member of our staff having worked at Noosa Council for over 10 years.

"Sharon will be sorely missed.

"Her radiant smile and friendly approach made her so popular with both her colleagues and our customers.

"Our thoughts at this time also go out to her family who are in deep shock at what has happened."

Friend and Noosa News employee Nadia Colbourn said Mrs Cuthbert's maiden name had a special meaning to those who knew her.

"Her first (maiden) name was Angelo, which is Italian for angel," Ms Colbourn said.

"She truly was an angel. She was a sweetheart."

Donations to the family can be made by calling 0431558333.

This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Cuthbert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nadia Colbourn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chastel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council CEO Brett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Colbourn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
