<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403771448067379</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/team-of-the-week-r19-did-we-get-it-right</url>
  <title>Team of the week, R19: Did we get it right?</title>
  <content>
PORT Adelaide's last-gasp win over St Kilda has inspired a teal flavour to this week's Team of the Week, brought to you by Accor Hotels.

It was impossible to leave Paddy Ryder and Robbie Gray out of the side after they combined to kick the match-stealing goal with less than 10 seconds left on Saturday at Adelaide Oval.

Their teammate Jared Polec also snagged a guernsey for his hard-running game, while Jasper Pittard was unlucky to miss out on a backline spot.

Ahead of Pittard was one of the Power's cross-town rivals in Brodie Smith, who was one of two Adelaide players to make the cut (along with Matt Crouch), while Pearce Hanley did enough in a losing Gold Coast side to fill the other back flank.

Pies duo Daniel Wells and Taylor Adams cracked the starting midfield, while Dom Sheed, Aaron Hall and Mitch Duncan were unlucky to miss out on a place in the team.

It was a high-scoring forward line with big bags from Tom Hawkins, Ben Brown, Joe Daniher and Josh Kennedy making it tough for the little guys to crack in.

Raging Brownlow Medal favourite Dustin Martin took the final spot on the bench after edging out superstar Bulldog Marcus Bontempelli.

•

Shane Biggs (Western Bulldogs): Got things moving for the Dogs with 570m gained and 29 disposals, including seven rebounds. Also took 11 marks and was clean with his disposal.

James Sicily (Hawthorn): Combined beautifully with his fellow defenders to stifle the Swans' attacking structure. Topped his team for metres gained with 557m, and took a huge 14 marks for 26 disposals.

Nick Haynes (Greater Western Sydney): Made his 19 disposals count with 94.7 per cent efficiency. Also took six marks, won nine one per centersand booted a cracking goal in the Giants' win over Freo.

Nick Haynes with the lovely goal around the body.

Pearce Hanley (Gold Coast): Impressed, along with Aaron Hall, in the Suns' loss to the Tigers. Overcame a shaky start to have 31 disposals and eight rebounds in an important performance in a young backline. 

Jake Carlisle (St Kilda): Intercept marking was a highlight against the Power. Had 16 possessions at 81 per cent efficiency with eight marks (four contested). Also did the tough stuff with nine one per centers.

Brodie Smith (Adelaide): Influential across half-back with 26 possessions and eight marks, and kicked a final-quarter goal that was significant in the Crows' gritty fightback that forced the draw with the Magpies.

Jared Polec (Port Adelaide): Had 30 touches and seven inside 50s in the Power's thrilling win. Generated plenty of attack with 570m gained - the most in his side.

Matt Crouch (Adelaide): Typically tough game from the midfielder; 36 disposals, 15 contested possessions, nine clearances and 10 tackles as he did all he could to drag his team back into the contest against the Pies.

Taylor Adams (Collingwood): Three goals from the midfielder - a career-best haul - complimented his 34-disposal, eight-clearance, seven-mark game. Also put up six tackles and six inside 50s in Scott Pendlebury's continuing absence.

Taylor Adams is up and about!

Jason Johannisen (Western Bulldogs): Was a talking point of the round with an inspired move into attack that reaped four goals. Also had 18 disposals and moved the ball smoothly with nearly 89 per cent efficiency.

Tom Hawkins (Geelong): Huge game from the hulking forward, overshadowed only by Patrick Dangerfield's costly tackle. Booted six goals and finished with a career-high 27 disposals after contributing seven score involvements to half-time. 

Ben Brown (North Melbourne): Booted four goals and took a stunning one-handed grab in the first quarter that has been nominated for Woolworths Mark of the Year. Took eight marks - five inside 50 - and was the difference in the win over the Demons.

Josh Kennedy (West Coast): Hard to leave him out after he kicked three of his six goals in the last quarter to blow the Eagles' winning margin over the Lions out to 68 points. It was the second week running he's booted six, which leaves him in contention for the Coleman medal. 

Joe Daniher (Essendon): But, while Kennedy remains in touch with the top three in the race for the goal-kicking prize, the young Bomber has one hand firmly wrapped around it after also kicking six against the Dogs. Daniher leads with 53 for the season from Lance Franklin and Brown (51 each), and Kennedy (49). 

Robbie Gray (Port Adelaide): Deserves to be in the team for his 27-disposal (13 contested) game anyway, but his last-quarter heroics require special mention. Was in the right spot to collect a tap from Ryder and slot the match-winning goal with less than 10 seconds remaining.

What an incredible finish!

Paddy Ryder (Port Adelaide): Artfully placed the ball in Gray's safe hands at the final throw-in of the game, which saw the Power turn a four-point loss into a two-point win with seconds left. Had 45 hit-outs all up, eight clearances and 15 disposals in a standout game. 

Daniel Wells (Collingwood): Was best on ground in Sunday's draw with an inspiring first-half performance that set the Pies up, only to carry it through to finish with three goals and 34 disposals in one of the best games of his career.

Dayne Beams (Brisbane Lions): His team might have lost but he topped the League for disposals with 41. Could not have done more as he stood up in the absence of fellow midfielder Dayne Zorko, winning nine clearances and laying six tackles. 

Stephen Coniglio (Greater Western Sydney): Impressive all afternoon but namely in the last quarter when the Giants stormed home. Ended up with 27 disposals - 12 contested - and nine clearances.

Jarryd Roughead (Hawthorn): Played a significant part in the Hawks' thrilling six-point win by kicking a goal at the 18-minute mark of the last quarter to stretch their lead to 13 points after they fell behind early in the term. Took eight marks, kicked two goals all up, and collected 24 disposals.

Nat Fyfe (Fremantle): Booted two goals and had 31 touches as the Dockers had a big crack against one of the premiership favourites. Also had an influence around the stoppages with five clearances. 

The fans' pick

Dustin Martin (Richmond): Won the social media fan vote from Marcus Bontempelli with 54 per cent. In an even team performance, the dynamic midfielder was the Tigers' best with 34 touches and seven clearances.

The selectors need your help to finalise the Team of the Week thanks to . Dusty or the Bont for the last spot in the middle?

•
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Ryder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldog Marcus Bontempelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Pendlebury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jasper Pittard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Wells</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Accor Hotels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths Mark of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Polec</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pittard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown (51</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Carlisle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Coniglio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sicily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Beams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce Hanley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Adams</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Zorko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team of the Week</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nat Fyfe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Haynes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy (49</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Bontempelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Biggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hawkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Crouch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
