<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403857347415023</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/police-struggle-against-year-long-crime-onslaught-/3207236/</url>
  <title>Police struggle against year-long crime onslaught on Coast suburb</title>
  <content>
POLICE are struggling with a surge in crime at one Sunshine Coast suburb, as officers urge residents to lock up and report anything suspicious.
Senior Constable Ann Jessop said there had been a continuing issue with property offences in Pelican Waters for the last year.
"A number of these offences have been committed by offenders from outside the district with no apparent links to Pelican Waters in particular," Snr Const Jessop said.
Sunshine Coast Crime Prevention Unit Sergeant Yvette Tarrier urged residents to keep security in mind.
"Please take a moment to take simple safety precautions to check that your property is locked and secured," Sergeant Tarrier said.
Property on Sovereign Circuit, Sylvie St and Tilney St have all been targeted over the last few weeks with break and enters, unlawful use of motor vehicles and thefts from vehicles.
Residents have been told to contact police immediately if they see anything suspicious and in an emergency, call 000.
Anyone with information for police can contact Policelink on 131 444 or provide information using the  24 hours a day.
To report crime anonymously to Crime Stoppers, call 1800 333 000 or visit .
This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Architect of a region stops briefly on his final journey.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sovereign Circuit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snr Const Jessop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Policelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pelican Waters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Crime Prevention Unit Sergeant Yvette Tarrier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Tarrier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tilney St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvie St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constable Ann Jessop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
