<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403818692708636</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/more-30000-muslims-gather-condemn-isis/3207229/</url>
  <title>More than 30,000 Muslims gather to condemn Isis</title>
  <content>
MORE than 30,000 Muslims from 100 countries gathered this weekend to "promote the true, peaceful teachings of Islam" at the largest Islamic convention in the UK.

The Jalsa Salana event, held on a 200-acre farm in Hampshire, saw tens of thousands of Ahmadi Muslims come together to condemn "misinterpretations of Islam" and denounce extremism and terrorism.

Ahmadiyya Muslim Community head Hazrat Mirza Masroor Ahmad called for believers to "reject all forms of extremism" in the last of his five speeches.

"It is up to Muslims to stand up and reject all forms of extremism and terrorism. It is the task of Ahmadi Muslims to show the true teachings of Islam which are of peace love, mercy and compassion," he said.

The Jalsa Salana event, held on a 200-acre farm in Hampshire, saw tens of thousands of Ahmadi Muslims come together to condemn extremism and terrorism.INM

The Caliph, who is the spiritual leader of the community's followers, regularly comments on religious extremism.

He has previously spoken out about the threat of terrorists entering Europe pretending to be refugees.

The three-day gathering saw men and women's proceedings conducted in separate tents. On Saturday, the Caliph conducted a prizegiving ceremony from the women's tent to honour academic achievements.

The proceedings were also broadcast to more than 80 million people worldwide, according to the organisers.

More than 300,000 naan breads were made for the weekend, with 270,000 meals prepared on site.

Education secretary Justine Greening was in attendance, along with Richmond Park MP Zac Goldsmith. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond Park MP Zac Goldsmith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hampshire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hazrat Mirza Masroor Ahmad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmadi Muslims</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jalsa Salana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmadiyya Muslim Community</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justine Greening</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
