<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403771448067299</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/les-murray-analysis-tracey-holmes/8762146</url>
  <title>Les Murray was the impeccably-dressed migrant who taught Australia to love football</title>
  <content>
He cast a giant shadow, yet in stature he wasn't all that much taller than me.
How else can you describe an individual that arrived on our shores in a refugee boat and forever changed this country for the better?
Hungary's Laszlo Urge became Australia's Les Murray, Mr Football.
He arrived as an 11-year-old unable to speak English. He left it forever yesterday, as a 71-year-old who'd .
This well-dressed man with a velvet voice loved life.
Everything he loved about it was contained in a game he wanted us to love too.
He made it his mission to clear a space in this sports-crowded landscape for the game they played everywhere - yet was largely ignored in his adopted home.
The odd couple

But he couldn't have done it without his great mate, former Socceroos captain Johnny Warren.
They were an odd couple - dubbed Mr and Mrs soccer.
Les called Johnny his soulmate.

The freckly faced Aussie in a tracksuit, and the impeccably-suited European with an elegantly held cigarette in one hand and a short black in the other.
Together they celebrated, shouted and despaired in equal measure. They described, dissected and analysed the game they loved.
Like a patient teacher with a wayward child, they persisted until we got it.
When we did, we tuned in to SBS in record numbers to watch the world's ultimate single-sport event, the FIFA World Cup.
Now at Fox Sports, Andy Harper was a former colleague of Murray's at SBS.
The author of Johnny Warren's biography, Sheilas, Wogs and Poofters, and Mr and Mrs Football, said from the US overnight that he felt dislocated, being so far away from home.
"How does one pay adequate tribute to someone so profoundly significant?" he said.
"A great Australian in the truly modern sense of the word. Les wrote and spoke - the tools of his journalistic craft - so beautifully.
"It gave him a rare and enduring ability to express his love for football and in so doing bring the multitudes into its orbit.
"Australia is a better place for Les Murray. He embodied the bounty available to Australia through immigration. He lived a full life and he's died way too soon".

At the last four  Les shared the commentary couch with former Socceroo Craig Foster.
"I'll remember him as someone who changed the country. He said to Australia, 'this is the global game, you need to understand it, this is how we relate to the world and actually, without it, we are diminished'," he said.
"He embodied a love of football, that's why they call him Mr Football, because the way he carried himself showed what we thought about the game, that's why he was the great man Les Murray."

Les's dream was to call a World Cup in the home of the "beautiful game". That dream was realised at the most recent World Cup - Rio 2014.
He said at the time that if he died then, he'd be a happy man. As it turned out, it was to be his last.
Les always was a happy man. He could, and did, talk football with anyone, anytime.
He'd share moments with strangers as easily as with colleagues and friends he'd had for decades.

Hard to imagine football without Les

It's hard to imagine now what Australia must have been like without football.
It's almost impossible to imagine a football landscape .
But then we don't have to, do we? He will always be there.
He will be at every major tournament; at every A-League or W-League game; in the commentary box; watching on from the sideline.
Since his passing I've had messages from people I don't know; from students at university; from people in the taxi queue at the hospital where Les died; from friends overseas.

They all have memories of Les. The tournaments. The teams. The moments. The commentary. The face. The voice.
I have many memories of Les, too, but they're all the same.
It's of Les laughing, as he often did.
Impeccably dressed, cigarette in one hand, short black in the other.
How very European.
He arrived as Laszlo Urge. He departs as Les Murray.
How very Australian.
Mr Football. The man that embodied the best of both worlds.
Tracey Holmes was a long-time friend and colleague of Les Murray, covering two FIFA World Cups alongside him in France '98 and Germany '06.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany '06</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laszlo Urge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WOG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary's Laszlo Urge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Harper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheila</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIFA World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France 98</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroo Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W-League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
