<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403277526819549</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/grabbing-a-bite-to-eat-coast-style/3206268/</url>
  <title>Grabbing a bite to eat, Coast-style</title>
  <content>
VISITING my grandma's home in Anzac Ave, Maroochydore, from our Eudlo farm, an integral part of my childhood was hanging out at Cotton Tree where lots of what I thought were cool places mostly related to food.
At Cotton Tree, the Cotton Tree Inn was the place to be in the 1960s and '70s.
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo, where the only shop was the general store that still stands today.
A big night for us was to go to the Maroochydore Hotel for dinner and listen to some really cool dudes playing saxophones, while I sucked down red drinks.
Nearly on a par with that excitement, as I was partial to Coke and chips, was the Boomerang Cafe at Alexandra Headland, opposite the surf club. For a fat kid, it was epic.
The only way my parents could get me to Brisbane and back without whinging too much was a pit-stop at the Bald Hills pub for a red drink on the way down and a pie and peas at Lindy's Roadhouse at Tanawha on the way back.
Even more exciting than the pie was the fact Lindy's had a wishing well where I got to throw dad's money in and make a wish - probably for another pie.
Visiting my grandad in Caloundra, there were two main highlights: a fish and chip shop behind his house on top of Bulcock St and White Fleet fish and chips on the site where Rumba Resort now stands.
Heading north to Nambour was definitely a highlight, visiting what was a thriving metropolis of shops, chain stores and cafes with undoubtedly the most prestigious being Collins Cafe. It was the place to be.
Their own in-house bakery, burgers and all the gear plus Coke spiders (ice-cream and the soft drink of your choosing) was another fat kid's paradise.
As I got a licence in the mid-70s, the Chuck Wagon, which was just near Maroochydore Surf Club, was a late-night hang-out for a pretty good burger and chips and sometimes a late-night scuffle.
Then there was the Boolarong, where Grand Palais now stands. It was a classy accommodation and fine-dining venue to the point that if you wanted to impress someone, the Boolarong was the go.
Mrs Coates, who owned it was a class act, as was the venue. I remember the fans, the bamboo furniture in real plantation-style look. It was wonderful.
My very first experience in a restaurant was the Boolarong in 1975. I was still going to school but felt very important with a date just after my 18th birthday (slow learner) in my 1962 VW.
What about the wine list? I had no idea what I was doing so I ordered a bottle of Blue Nun. Can you believe it? I was so sophisticated.
Actually, I wasn't sophisticated but the Boolarong and Mrs Coates were.
As I got older, it was John Douglas at Smugglers Cove in Mooloolaba and the many cool restaurants and bars that he created over a couple of decades, along with other great operators who owned wonderful venues like Rusty's Mexican at Maroochydore, Pisces Seafood at Alex Headland and Bullockies Steak House at Maroochydore.
I could write pages on this stuff but it's making me too hungry.
Bar, restaurant to pave way for precinct renewal
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Fleet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rumba Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cokes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindy's Roadhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bullockies Steak House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Coates</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pisces Seafood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smugglers Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree Inn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bald Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chuck Wagon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rusty's Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boomerang Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulcock St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Palais</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Nun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanawha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Surf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boolarong</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
