<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403685548720077</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/television/bachelors-belinda-in-odd-sexpo-tape-as-three-contestants-reveal-lesbian-encounters/news-story/3930a3ea729dcc123d50359fd9365aa7</url>
  <title>Bachelor hopeful's bizarre Sexpo tape unearthed</title>
  <content>
THREE of Matthew "Matty J" Johnson's potential suitors on The Bachelor have revealed they have been with women before entering the show.
Midwife Natalie Holmberg, 26, was the first to admit to being in a long-term relationship before she signed up to win over the hunky 30-year-old.
"We dated for nine months and it was a good relationship," she said on The Bachelor's first episode.
"But at the end of the day I knew I wanted to be with a man, even though I loved her."
Love coach Belinda Rygier, 34, who was in a bizarre Sexpo audition tape which emerged last week, told she had been intimate with a woman.
"I wouldn't date a woman but I have been intimate with one before," she said.
In the short audition  uploaded two years ago, Rygier is shown eating whipped cream, dipping strawberries in chocolate and wearing sexy lingerie.
"Hi, my name is Belinda Rygier, like a tiger, and I am the love trainer," she is heard saying.
"I am witty, charismatic, can think on my feet, articulate and a combination of sugar and spice.
Meanwhile Tahitian fitness trainer Elora Murger, 27, told Matty J that she had an odd same-sex relationship during their first date.
"I did have a strange relationship as a teenager with a woman older than me," she said.
"I was in love with someone.
"She loved me and I was embarrassed because she was a girl."
All three women are still in the running to win over Matty J's heart.
The Bachelor airs on Wednesdays and Thursdays at 7.30pm on Channel 10.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Rygier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexpo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tahitian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elora Murger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Rygier, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Holmberg, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rygier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
