<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651402908159625565</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>17:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/world/deutsche-banks-long-and-winding-road-20170731-gxm8cq</url>
  <title>Deutsche Bank's long and winding road  </title>
  <content>
by
The Lex Column

German cars are well known for their performance and build quality.
The country's banks rather less so.
Deutsche Bank once aimed for rapid revenue growth buttressed by the reliability of the German economy. The global financial crisis put paid to that.
Years of rebuilding its balance sheet has left it with too little return on its capital base. Top-line growth is once again the priority for investors.

Knowing this, market-watchers are highly sensitive to how Deutsche's revenues move in each quarterly report.

Analysts, much like car mechanics, ran their diagnostics to reveal the failings: equities, for example, did poorly, particularly prime brokerage.
Other bits of good news were ignored. Provisions against loan losses continue to fall. This pre-tax cost fell to €79m in the period, well below the five-year quarterly run rate of €357m. More than €4bn of provisions for future credit losses sit on the balance sheet, unused.
, plus no clear sign of bad loan recoveries improving, keeps investors focused on organic profits, not recoveries.
Worse, Deutsche does not see credit costs falling further this year.

In the meantime, lifting revenues is partly out of Deutsche's control. Higher interest rates and a steeper yield curve could add €1bn to its top line, thinks UBS.
Deutsche cannot do much there. It could possibly reap another €1bn from market share gains in businesses such as investment banking and asset management, the latter due for an IPO.
Strong US rivals, though, will fight hard. Squeezing more from a formerly moribund domestic German banking sector, in the middle of a consolidation, requires better economic growth in its home country.
It looks to be a tough haul for Deutsche.

Drivers of performance cars like long, winding roads. Equity portfolio managers less so.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lex Column</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
