<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403689843687492</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>20:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/dodgers-trade-for-yu-darvish-ranger-2017-7</url>
  <title>Dodgers reportedly trade for Yu Darvish in what could be MLB's scariest reclamation project</title>
  <content>
The Los Angeles Dodgers landed right-handed starting pitcher Yu Darvish in a trade with the Texas Rangers before the trade deadline on Monday, .

According to ESPN, the Dodgers sent the Rangers three minor-league prospects.

The move should bolster an already-stacked Dodgers team that boasts the best record in MLB and give them one of the league's most interesting reclamation projects.

Darvish has struggled this season, going 6-9 with a 4.01 ERA and 1.17 WHIP. Most recently, Darvish allowed 10 runs in a 22-10 loss, his last start with the Rangers.

However, Darvish is only four seasons removed from leading MLB in strikeouts and was a Cy Young candidate early in his career before struggling with injuries. Darvish was considered the biggest name available at the trade deadline.

As the team awaits the return of Clayton Kershaw, who is out with a bad back, the Dodgers now have an extra arm - one with significant potential if he can recover. If Darvish begins to look like his old self with the Dodgers, they will have a formidable addition to a rotation that already leads the league in ERA and shutouts.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MLB</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cy Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dodgers</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yu Darvish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clayton Kershaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Dodgers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darvish</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas Rangers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
