<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403775743034717</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/showdown-will-have-extra-bite-says-hombsch</url>
  <title>Showdown will have 'extra bite', says Hombsch</title>
  <content>
Jack Hombsch kept Josh Bruce quiet last week

THIS weekend's highly-anticipated Showdown will have some "extra bite" to it, according to Port Adelaide defender Jack Hombsch.

Adelaide Oval will be packed to the rafters when the Power aim to end a four-game losing streak to ladder leaders Adelaide on Sunday.

The Power are fifth and a win would keep their hopes of an all-important top-four berth alive.

"They're already big games as it is, so there will be a bit of extra bite to it," Hombsch told AFL.com.au.

"They're top of the ladder and the best team in the competition.

"It's a funny thing, Showdowns, you can be top and bottom, and it's still going to be a pretty even game anyway.

"It brings out the best in both sides."

The Crows showed tremendous fight to rally back from a 50-point deficit to earn a draw against Collingwood last weekend, while the Power are still buzzing after Robbie Gray's late goal snatched a dramatic two-point victory over St Kilda.

Hombsch played his role as part of an impressive Power backline after spending the past two weeks in the SANFL.

"It was a good chance to go back and work on some things in the Magpies," he said.

"Coming back in and winning like that is amazing and shows you why you play the game of footy.

"I tidied a few things up and I've got to keep working on a few things, but it's great to be back in and to contribute to a win like that."

Hombsch had established himself as a regular in the Power's backline over the past three seasons, but was dropped to work on his one-on-one defence.

"Obviously you don't like hearing that you're not playing, so it was disappointing, but I knew it was coming in a way," Hombsch said.

"I hadn't been happy with how I was playing myself either.

"It gives you a chance to go back to basics and work on your defending and play basic footy in a way and focus on a couple of key areas.

"It gave me the freedom to do that and get back to defending."

Hombsch spent the majority of his time on Saints spearhead Josh Bruce and received great support from Tom Jonas and Tom Clurey.

"The boys as a back six helped each other out aerially and there was a lot of guys coming across to spoil," Hombsch said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Jonas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Clurey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hombsch</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Bruce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SANFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Hombsch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
