<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403264641917429</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/teaching-our-kids-to-shine/3206276/</url>
  <title>Teaching our kids to shine</title>
  <content>
IT WAS only 17 years ago that established actor and producer Robyn Ernst was asked to take over the running of the BATS youth theatre group in Buderim.
In no time, the theatre group grew from 25 children to 200 and Robyn was ultimately offered the chance to take it on as a private enterprise.
And so BYTE - the Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence - was born. Today it boasts an enrolment of 360 young people and employs 10 staff.
BYTE now provides much more than just acting lessons for local youngsters. Robyn sees it as the type of safe haven she didn't have as a child when her love of theatre made her something of an outcast.
"It's a haven for children who may not have that outlet or, in their own schools, may not have the peer group around them who are as passionate as they are," she said.
"They can meet up with kids from all over the Sunshine Coast who are just as passionate and committed and enjoy it and love it as much as they do.
"What essentially happens at BYTE - and this is the really special thing - is the kids form their own peer group.
"So even if they've had a really crappy day at school and kids have turned on them or their own friends and peer group at school may not be supportive of them, they have this alternate peer group that are also really important to them.
"That probably is the most amazing thing to me."
Of course, there are the performances, with each level staging two productions a year. Every child gets a part in every show, whether it's a lead or as part of the ensemble.
They also learn the entrepreneurial skills required to stage a performance - from ticketing to publicity and marketing.
But there is a sometimes harsh reality behind the scenes.
Despite what some parents might think, Robyn says not every child is going to be a star and there's no point pretending otherwise.
"You have to give everyone a chance to shine but you don't do anyone any favours if you unrealistically tell a kid they are up for something when they're not," she said.
"I think the education system has evolved to believe that everybody can do anything but the sad thing is that everybody can't do it.
"That doesn't mean they don't enjoy it or love being involved in a show or enjoy the whole process, and they might be just as happy being in the ensemble.
"I've had lots of kids through BYTE who have been happy doing that and get enough warm, fuzzy feelings out of that.
"But I've also had some kids who desperately will always want to be the lead and will be disappointed if they are not cast in that role.
"But if they are not right for that role, I'm not going to put them there and they have to learn that.
"It's a life lesson. That's not being harsh, that's being realistic. I would like a dollar for every parent who says their child is born for the stage.
"I really would like to think that children don't just look at it as their only option."
Robyn is delighted to have an influence on so many young lives.
"Just the joy of being able to do something together - something that's great and wholesome.
"They're up there doing something they love. They're not sitting in front of a computer screen all day.
"For kids to actually make the effort of applying themselves and putting the time in, makes me very proud of them.
"The shows are just the icing on the cake."
Bar, restaurant to pave way for precinct renewal
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
Charles said it was his right to have a mistress
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robyn Ernst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robyn</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
