<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403857347415040</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/snake-so-desperate-be-tv-he-invaded-nine-news/3207226/</url>
  <title>Snake so desperate to be on TV, it invaded Nine News</title>
  <content>
NINE News Darwin had an unexpected visitor when a feisty snake was found warming itself behind one of the office computers.

According to a Facebook post a "senior cameraman found (the) visitor in his edit suite (Monday) afternoon".

News Director Kate Limon later tweeted the video, tagging the NT News and suggesting the broadcaster dealt with scarier animals than the paper did.

"My first suggestion to get rid of it was to burn the place down but no one else went for it," she tweeted.

Ms Limon said she had turned to the internet for help when the snake was discovered.

"I was googling (a snake catcher) to call ASAP but turns out our program manager is a wildlife warrior," she said.

"She lives on a property and wasn't scared at all.

"In her bloody floral dress and heels - she put us all to shame.

"One of our sales executives also helped, he's the one who the snake tried to bite the face off. "He was very brave too."

The feisty snake is relocated from the Nine News Darwin office. Picture: Channel 9/Twitter

The snake was released into bushes outside the office after its capture.

For the record, the reason snakes aren't found in the NT News office is that the paper is protected by resident crocodiles.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT News</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine News Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9/Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Director Kate Limon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Limon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
