<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403857347415030</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/all-the-hallmarks-of-an-infomercial-abc-under-fire-over-sam-dastyari-australian-story-episode-20170731-gxmmgq.html</url>
  <title>'All the hallmarks of an infomercial': ABC under fire over timing of Sam Dastyari episode</title>
  <content>
The ABC is under fire from a diverse group of politicians - including a Labor MP - who are accusing the public broadcaster of allowing a flagship current affairs program to promote a book designed to help the political rehabilitation of Labor senator Sam Dastyari.
Veteran Labor MP Michael Danby, Greens senator Peter Whish-Wilson, government minister Zed Seselja, crossbencher Cory Bernardi and Liberal backbencher James Paterson all called for the ABC to explain Monday night's episode of Australian Story, which they described as a "puff piece", "propaganda", and an "infomercial".

Up Next

Terror plotter had aviation links

01:57

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Sam Dastyari's China newspaper praise

The now ousted Labor frontbencher Sam Dastyari appeared in promotional video for the official newspaper of the Chinese Communist Party in 2015.

Senator Dastyari is a prominent Labor figure who enjoyed a stunning rise in the media and opposition as general secretary of the NSW Labor Party and then a Labor senator, until he was forced to resign from the opposition frontbench .
One of the Parliament's most prolific media performers, Senator Dastyari has now penned a book about his Iranian heritage, One Halal of a Story, published by Melbourne University Publishing. MUP has launched a major PR blitz to spruik the book's release.

Senator Dastyari took to social media to directly link Monday night's Australian Story to encourage sales of his book.
Greens senator Peter Whish-Wilson described the program as "soft promotion" and vowed to take up the matter with ABC management at the next Senate estimates hearing.

"Call me cynical, but this Australian Story seems nicely timed to promote Sam's book and his full political comeback," he said.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I'm disappointed the ABC didn't stop to think that this looks like soft promotion for a sitting MP and the Labor Party."Photo: ABC
Labor MP Michael Danby said it was only natural a "PR and social media whiz" like his colleague would "exploit an ABC opportunity to the hilt".
"His self promotion is so brazen it's almost endearing," Mr Danby said.
"By contrast no one at the ABC is interested in my views on China's jailing and killing of its only Nobel peace Prize winner Liu Xiao Bo."Photo: ABC
Fairfax Media has submitted a number of questions to the ABC, including whether it arranged the episode through the publicity department of Senator Dastyari's publisher, MUP. 
It's understood the airing of the episode so close to the book launch has caused unease among some journalists at the public broadcaster. 
He claims to have one halal of a story to tell but he's also got one Huang of a story that still needs to be told.

Australian Conservatives leader Cory Bernardi said the ABC had to explain the timing of the Australian Story episode.
"It had all the hallmarks of an infomercial and a sterilisation of the murky history of Sam Dastyari," he said.
"Sure he claims to have one halal of a story to tell but he's also got one Huang of a story that still needs to be told," he said.
Last year it was revealed Senator Dastyari asked a Chinese donor with deep connections to the communist government to pay his bill after exceeding taxpayer-funded travel entitlements. Members of Parliament are expected for pay personally for any overspends but Senator Dastyari had Chinese businessman and donor Minshen Zhu pay back the Commonwealth.
It then emerged Senator Dastyari  - contradicting the ALP policy.  during his time as general secretary.
Assistant Minister for Social Services and Multicultural Affairs Zed Seselja demanded to know who in the ABC ticked off on what he called "propaganda."
"I congratulate Sam Dastyari for co-opting the ABC to promote his new book - five minutes of re-hashed critique to cover for 25-minutes of puff," he said.
"I'm not sure who in the ABC approves this propaganda."
Liberal senator James Paterson said the ABC had failed to ask tough questions given Senator Dastyari's history.
"They should be particularly wary and ensure they ask tough questions to one on a image rehabilitation tour," he said.
"The public deserve better than a soft touch interview that only serve the politicians' interests."
On Monday, , in breach of the ALP's ban on all donations from tobacco interests..
The Greens have referred the matter to the NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption and NSW electoral authorities. Senator Dastyari has described himself as one of the "weapons suppliers" in the political donations "arms race" but now claims all donations should be banned.
That idea has been rejected by Labor leader Bill Shorten, who also appeared in Monday night's program describing Senator Dastyari's links with Chinese donors as "poor judgement."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MUP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Conservatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MP Michael Danby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Story</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Communist Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minshen Zhu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Danby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne University Publishing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Paterson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dastyari's China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dastyari</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nobel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zed Seselja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huang</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Whish-Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Multicultural Affairs Zed Seselja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Dastyari</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liu Xiao Bo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cory Bernardi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iranian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
