<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403771448067361</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/desperate-need-to-drive-change-in-car-culture/3206973/</url>
  <title>Desperate need to drive change in car culture</title>
  <content>
PROFESSOR Ian Lowe (Daily, July 24) rightly points out the immense discrepancy between Sunshine Coast Council's budget allocations for public transport and road and highway construction.
The latter simply subsidises the private motor car industry.
To address chronic and morbid traffic congestion, unnecessary car ownership, accidents and road deaths, diesel and tyre particulate pollution, carbon emissions, parking problems, unwanted noise abatement, then the council must become smarter and more targeted in their vision for the future.
France has decided to eradicate the use of the noisy and polluting combustion engine by 2040, only 22 years away, and replace their car fleet with electric vehicles.
Both Norway and Holland are doing the same.
Ten thousand people die in Europe from particulates each year.
Australia continues to follow the United States in a damaging and wasteful car culture.
Whereas America has about 32 different vehicle makes on their roads, we have more than 60, despite the great discrepancy in populations.
Yet given the dangers flagged by pathological car use, young men think they are heroes by drag and sports car racing, doing doughnuts and wheelies, and producing clouds of diesel and rubber particulates.
They are not 'heroes' but car club morons with no environmental consciousness which this planet urgently needs.
MICHAEL HENDERSON
Maroochydore
This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Architect of a region stops briefly on his final journey.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MICHAEL HENDERSON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PROFESSOR Ian Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
