<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403853052447666</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/position-of-cathy-otoole-on-adani-unclear/news-story/a5c618ff9173e22ceb0bb88c904212d2</url>
  <title>Position of Cathy O'Toole on Adani unclear</title>
  <content>
LETTER: I thank the Federal Member for Herbert, Cathy O'Toole, for responding to my comments in the Townsville Bulletin (31/07), regarding her position on Adani, but unfortunately she didn't answer my question. Does she unequivocally support Adani?
I wasn't aware that as well as working for Government for much of her previous career, she also operated her own small business. I apologise for that fact.
But as a small business owner, she should understand the importance of Adani, and the need to help struggling small businesses in Townsville.
Around 10,000 direct and indirect jobs in regional Queensland will flow from this project, which will have very positive effects for small -businesses.
I am not sure what Ms O'Toole's reference to Cyclone Debbie is. I was in the Whitsundays within days of the cyclone and have been working with my colleagues, George Christensen and Jason Costigan, the local Federal and State MP's, and the Queensland Industry Tourism Council to get support for the Whitsundays.
In fact, just this past weekend I spent some time with the Whitsunday Mayor, Cr Andrew Willcox, trying to work through some issues.
Ms O'Toole's support would be appreciated as natural disasters are, or should be, non-politically partisan, and above cheap political point scoring.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Christensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Bulletin (31/07</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Industry Tourism Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathy O'Toole</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Andrew Willcox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyclone Debbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Costigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms O'Toole</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Member</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitsunday Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitsundays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
