<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403346246297393</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/why-we-cant-ignore-true-cost-1-litre-milk/3207127/</url>
  <title>Why we can't ignore the true cost of $1 a litre milk</title>
  <content>
OUR SAY: As consumers, it's easy to be oblivious to the true cost of $1 a litre milk.

But as a farmer, the cost is a livelihood which has forced generational producers to close and put at risk an industry which once thrived.

The Darling Downs has about 150 dairy farmers left and statewide, the 420 remaining producers can produce just 70 per cent of Queensland's milk supply.

The industry has been in decline since 2000 but was further gutted when the milk price wars hit home in 2011, and raged on ever since.

Now China and its massive demand for a quality product could bring a revival to the industry but it won't be without major investment in the sector.

The 300,000 litre a day fresh milk export figure, based on the current industry numbers, is not viable and puts further pressure on the already at-risk domestic supply.

But a market exists which has shown it is willing to pay $19 a litre for milk produced right here on our doorstep.

It's a leap of faith for our farmers to get on board the China market demand, but the Asian centre is increasingly within reach with Wellcamp airport and big business willing to back the milk export industry.

China wants a safe product, our dairy farmers want a safe industry, and we, as consumers, have to want more than just a cheap bottle of milk or it will end up costing us more in the long term.

Family face life in limbo
State Government approves the council's planning scheme changes
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellcamp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
