<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403260346950006</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/height-limits-rise-to-accommodate-new-coast-hotel/3207145/</url>
  <title>Height limits rise to accommodate new Coast hotel</title>
  <content>
HEIGHT restrictions in a busy Coast precinct are on the rise to accommodate a new five-star hotel.
Sunshine Coast Council has adopted major amendments to the Sunshine Coast Planning Scheme 2014 to allow taller buildings in the Mooloolaba and Alexandra Headland areas.
The changes, which the council agreed to in April, have since been approved by the State Government and came into effect on Monday.
They will allow for the 37.5m height restriction on a block of land opposite the Mooloolaba Surf Life Saving Club to be extended to 50m above sea level.
The new restrictions will extend the maximum building height at the Club Eatery site to between 44.5m and 47.5m above ground level.
A council spokeswoman said the site, bounded by Mooloolaba Esplanade, River Esplanade and Burnett St, was one of the last remaining beach front lots at Mooloolaba with significant development opportunities.
She said extending the height and ground coverage would be an incentive for delivery of a five-star international hotel.
"It is intended that this would accommodate rooftop facilities, an expansive lobby, architectural elements and streetscape works," the spokeswoman said.
Building heights in the planned Mooloolaba Heart street area have also risen, from 15m to 25m.
The area is bounded by Walan St, Muraban St and Smith St.
"It is also proposed to include the land fronting Walan St in a new local plan precinct to provide for business activities such as small food and drink outlets and retail uses," the spokeswoman said.
"This will support the activation of this street frontage."
She said the Place Making Mooloolaba Master Plan identified Muraban and Smith Sts as the heart of Mooloolaba.
She said the intent for the area was to provide high density residential and mixed use tourist accommodation and a community hub with improved pedestrian connectivity.
Height restrictions have also been raised from 15m to 25m along the southern side of First Ave, between Venning and Meta Sts.
"This is more reflective of the predominant built form along the southern side of First Ave and provides an appropriate transition in building height from the Mooloolaba Esp through to the Mooloolaba State School."
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Place Making Mooloolaba Master Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Surf Life Saving Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club Eatery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meta Sts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Esp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Planning Scheme 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith Sts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Heart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walan St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muraban St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muraban</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Ave</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnett St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
