<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403775743034733</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/trump-thought-scaramucci-tirade-was-inappropriate-2017-7</url>
  <title>Trump thought Scaramucci's expletive-filled tirade to a reporter was 'inappropriate'</title>
  <content>
White House press secretary Sarah Huckabee Sanders said Monday that President Donald Trump believed Anthony Scaramucci's  to New Yorker reporter Ryan Lizza last week was "inappropriate" for a White House communications director.

"The president felt Anthony's comments were inappropriate for a person in that position," Sanders said during Monday's press briefing, adding that Trump didn't want to "burden" his new chief of staff John Kelly.

Sanders declined to elaborate on what exactly Trump had found to be inappropriate about Scaramucci's comments.

Scaramucci was ousted from his position earlier on Monday, reportedly at the request of Kelly.

Last week, Scaramucci was incensed that news of his private dinner with Trump and conservative Fox News commentator Sean Hannity had been leaked to Lizza, and called him on the phone to try to get the reporter to reveal his source.

When Lizza refused to do so, Scaramucci threatened to fire everyone in the White House communications office and then pinned the blame on former chief of staff Reince Priebus, calling him "a f-ing paranoid schizophrenic, a paranoiac."

Scaramucci also went off on White House chief strategist Steve Bannon, implying that Bannon was only interested in getting attention from the media.

"I'm not Steve Bannon, I'm not trying to suck my own c-k," Scaramucci said to Lizza.

Kelly was reportedly  by Scaramucci's attitude and felt he lacked discipline and squandered his credibility.

As a result, Kelly had a  with Scaramucci immediately after being sworn in as the new chief of staff and informed him that he was being dismissed.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lizza</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Hannity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Lizza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
