<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403857347415006</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/children-still-in-need-of-protection/news-story/ad39976f61dac91bf1a589d6e409d12d</url>
  <title>Children still in need of protection</title>
  <content>
EDITORIAL: One child abused is one child too many.
Unfortunately it is impossible to eradicate all harm done to children, as much as we would like that.
But that must not stop all of us doing what we can to strive for that unattainable goal.
And it is up to all of us, not just the Government or police.
We will never have enough government workers or police to conquer this scourge. They need every citizen also committed to the cause of helping our defenceless kids.
That's one of the messages that will be shared when the city hosts the North Queensland Child Protection Symposium next month.
In any case, the number of children in the region who are subject to ongoing child protection intervention is both heartbreaking and infuriating.
It is now more than four years since Queensland Child Protection Commission of Inquiry commissioner Tim Carmody, QC, delivered his groundbreaking final report.
Yet as we learn in today's Bulletin, there are still nearly 1400 children requiring protection.
How many of those children would be safer if the Carmody Inquiry's recommendations had already been fully implemented?
The figures also remind us there is no quick fix to child abuse.
One positive is the upcoming North Queensland Child Protection Symposium, which aims to shine the spotlight on what Carmody recommendations have been implemented and how effective they have been.
Yet while the Government has a responsibility to put child protection structures in place to protect our vulnerable children, that does not absolve any member of our community to accept we all have a role to ensure any suspected cases of child safety breaches are reported.
We must also continue to implement, and build on, the 10-year road map recommended by the Carmody Inquiry by responding to what research tells us about what works and what we can do better.
One child saved would make that worthwhile.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Carmody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Child Protection Commission of Inquiry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmody Inquiry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Child Protection Symposium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
