<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403260346950058</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/onyxs-foster-mum-to-hold-garage-sale/3207110/</url>
  <title>Onyx's foster mum to hold garage sale</title>
  <content>
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy, stress-free life.
And it was no different for foster mum Bree Logie and her bull-arab-cross Onyx.
The Coolum local has been fostering Onyx for just over two months, since she was rescued from a Rockhampton pound earlier this year by Bull Arab Rescue. Still a puppy at 18 months, Onyx has been through more than most dogs would in their lifetime.
She was left with a lame back leg from an existing injury when she was younger and Bull Arab Rescue had to make the tough decision of whether she would have her leg amputated or receive surgery. With a whole life ahead, the organisation opted to treat her with surgery, giving her the chance to lead a full and abundant life.
In early June, Onyx undertook major femoral osteotomy surgery, where her femur was cut and rotated to realign the bone, followed by the insertion of plates and screws to hold it in position while it healed.
Treating Onyx as her own, Bree is hosting a garage sale with the hope of raising at least $5000 to go towards the rising vet bills and Onyx's future plate removal surgery.
"She is such a beautiful dog," Bree said.
"She's been amazing through all of this. She's really special."
With an estimated cost of $10,000 to $12,000 by the time Onyx is fully recovered, Bree wants to use this as a way of helping Bull Arab Rescue, and ensuring that Onyx receives the proper care she needs throughout her recovery.
She is receiving on-going physiotherapy and rehabilitation, and also has the upcoming plate removal surgery and x-rays.
In order to lengthen her leg and build strength following the surgery, she is taking underwater treadmill treatment every fortnight.
But Bree said Onyx really should be taking it more frequently but that was restricted by funds.
Ten underwater sessions amount to $360, and physio can cost up to $150 per session.
"If this goes well, she shouldn't need surgery in the future," Bree said.
"So far it's going well and looking quite positive.
"If she can keep up with her physio and the home routine, she should be a very strong dog."
Local businesses have already started showing community support through the donation of items to go towards the garage sale and potential raffles.
Onyx is still under foster care with Bree, although Bull Arab Rescue is taking applications to find her a forever home after her recovery.
"She's so friendly and intelligent," Bree said.
"Any family would be lucky to have her."
Make donations or contributions to the sale by calling Bree on 0477 700 354, or visit the Call Me Onyx Facebook page for more information.
The garage sale will take place on August 12 and 13 at 53 Yandina-Coolum Rd, Coolum Beach.
Family face life in limbo
Lexis English secures new riverside offices in CBD
Mum hits out at hospital for 20 hour wait
TODAY we have a much more adventurous palate
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
Live music was still king.
CLASSIC Aussie film Romper Stomper will be revived with a TV sequel.
WARNING: Nudity. Australian Survivor turns X-rated tonight.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Onyx</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brees</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Call Me Onyx Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bree Logie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEXIS English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina-Coolum Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bull Arab Rescue</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
