<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403938951795067</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/anthony-scaramucci-threw-plenty-of-punches-in-fight-house-cameo/8762230</url>
  <title>Anthony Scaramucci threw plenty of punches during his cameo at the Fight House</title>
  <content>
"I'll be brief," Anthony "The Mooch" Scaramucci said as he addressed the White House press corps for the first time.
The colourful Wall Street financier and long-time friend of President Donald Trump came to the role as White House communications director  and called himself a "straight shooter".
and to add insult to injury the news leaked out before it could be announced.
The Mooch won't be quickly forgotten though - his short tenure was filled with extraordinary developments.
First, Sean Spicer, the former press secretary and interim director of communications resigned because he refused to report to Mr Scaramucci.
The communications director then set his sights on long-time rival and the president's chief of staff Reince Priebus.
Mr Priebus had repeatedly blocked Mr Scaramucci's appointment to a variety of White House roles since Mr Trump won the election.
With his tough New York commitment to stabbing in the front, The Mooch didn't miss as he immediately used his new platform for revenge.
In a bizarre 30-minute interview with CNN's New Day, Mr Scaramucci pointed the finger at Mr Priebus as the White House leaker.
Hours later, The New Yorker reported a  where he described Mr Priebus as a "f***ing paranoid schizophrenic".

There was a memorable description of White House chief strategist Steve Bannon - one that will live long in the political memory and is unlikely to be repeated.

External Link:

NYPost Survivor tweet
According to the White House, Mr Priebus offered his resignation the same day.
The loss of both Mr Spicer and Mr Priebus marks the end of the strongest links to the Republican establishment.
Now, the departure of Mr Scaramucci is seen as a nod to the power of the new chief of staff John Kelly (formerly the secretary of homeland security).
Will the new chief of staff continue to swing the axe? It remains unclear.
However, in a tweet on Monday morning Mr Trump said, "No WH chaos".
But if they wanted to challenge the narrative the White House is functioning like a reality television show, they've failed.
Already the New York Post has had to twice update its front page referencing the show Survivor.
The red pen won't be put back in the desk drawer any time soon.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN's New Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Priebus</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Scaramucci</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fight House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NYPost Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
