<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404033441077336</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/live-music-was-king-of-the-coast/3206241/</url>
  <title>Live music was king of the Coast</title>
  <content>
I LEFT Melbourne. I was 22 years of age. My ageing Mark IV Zephyr was packed with guitar, dog (a German Shepherd puppy named Taj) and a couple of suitcases of clothes.
When I arrived, it seemed that the Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene for locals and visitors alike. It was by far the biggest public venue around and had become a unofficial tourist information centre. It was the only licensed pub in Noosa. There was also the Royal Mail in Tewantin.
The Reef was where you heard where the parties were on Friday and Saturday nights and where most of the visiting students, teachers and young nurses would go.
The pub was where you could go on a weekend to get a good, cheap meal and free entertainment.
At a gig recently, a chap came up, grabbed my hand and told me it was the first time he'd been back to Noosa since 1974 and did I remember Doodies.
Doodies! What a flood of memories that place brought back. Doodies was an institution. It was the place to go in the quiet, easy-going Hastings St of those days, when it had more houses than restaurants and real estate offices.
The backpackers, students, nurses, visitors and locals would stroll up from the beach or the Woods and sit around on whatever chairs were available or on the floor to listen to our interpretations of J.J. Cale, Dylan, Moody Blues, David Bowie, Pink Floyd, The Band and our originals.
I doubt it was legal for Ernie, the proprietor, to stage live music but those were the carefree days before regulations,or at least before they were enforced.
No amplification was needed in Doodies in those days. I remember how intently people would listen - the only background sounds were the whispered orders, the gentle rattle of crockery from the kitchen and the dull pounding of the nearby surf.
Around 1974 and 1975 we were really developing our own original music and ways of performing it. We had all come from working bands in Melbourne and had experienced playing different musical genres.
Gavan Anderson, lead guitar from a country rock and blues background. Andy Tainsh, bass guitar from a contemporary rock background, as was our drummer Rick Matson. Myself from a soul and rock background. Also musicians like David Allerdice, with a jazz background, and Colin de Luka, with years of country rock experience.
Our originals could be anything from funky soul to upbeat country rock and a social comment number might have a reggae flavour.
The whole band really threw a lot of energy out to our audiences. I would leap around the stage, careful not to go straight through the plywood stage. We dressed as casually as we could get away with: t-shirts, singlets, jeans and more often than not, bare feet, although occasionally thongs or sandshoes.
The Rockets did gigs at Tinbeerwah, The Reef Hotel, Maroochy Pub, Noosa Surf Club, Thommo's Tavern at Alexandra Headland, Chifley's, the Northern Hotel in Gympie, the Royal Mail in Tewantin and the Country Life in Kin Kin.
Some became semi-regular. Others were one-offs, like The Pearl Hotel in Caloundra.
Maroochydore Pub was for some time a regular Rockets gig. We developed quite a following among Maroochydore locals, although we had an ongoing battle with the owners of the next-door supermarket over noise. I vividly remember some very wild parties that carried on after some of our gigs there.
Some time into the heady days of Noosa in the 1970s, we were looking to try "something different". I went looking for other venues and discovered the Belli Hall. We'd been discussing the possibility of staging a laid-back daytime event and the hall looked like the perfect venue.
It was an attractive little timber community hall. The acoustics were great and it even had a stage and a changing room for performers. There was also projection room for showing films.
It was 15 minutes west of Eumundi on a sealed road but we were a bit worried if people would come out from Noosa. The idea of a bus was suggested, starting at Noosa Woods and picking up people along the way. A bus was found and renamed The Rocket Express, with its own banner.
Between 1973 and 1989, I must have performed at almost every hall on the Coast, from the heady days of The Rockets performing at Tinbeerwah to the series of Lamington Show concerts that I started at the Verrierdale Hall.
The hall radiated a certain energy. It was located centrally between Noosa, Coolum and Eumundi and set on a lovely bush block: tennis courts to one side and space enough for parking on the other.
The Verrierdale shows started on November 14, 1987, with The Lost Lamington Show. The country halls always brought back childhood memories of CWA meetings with cups of tea and lamingtons, so I called them Lamington Shows.
I held regular Lamington Show concerts at Verrierdale Hall from 1987-1996: four and occasionally five times a year, as close to the full moon as possible.
Sometimes they were themed along the lines of the charity or community group that manned the bar and food outlets, or of the different musical groups. The door take paid for the musicians and the bar and food was for the community organisation who had the willing workers. One of the criteria was that lamingtons were on the menu.
Audiences discovered they could experience something different in the way of music and energy at Verrierdale.
Donald Greenfied as "Major Mangrove" was the master of ceremonies and musicians of all genres performed.
The little hall with the push-out timber windows and wide back verandah became very popular and patrons came from as far away as Cairns and the Central Coast of NSW. Busloads of backpackers, bikies, hippies, surfers and local tradesmen came along and the glitzy in rhinestone-studded denim arrived in stretch limos.
The Verrierdale Lamington Show concerts are remembered for music jams and nights ending in huge line-ups of six guitarists, two drum kits and up to eight singers.
I have recordings of some of these shows. Full of excesses but wonderful.
Reprinted with permission from You Had To Be Out There: a short history of music culture by Barry Charles.
This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Architect of a region stops briefly on his final journey.
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
GREAT venues and great people.
MEMORIES of Surfair, Thommo's and Stewart's.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark IV Zephyr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinbeerwah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thommo's Tavern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hastings St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Surf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavan Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verrierdale Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Pub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moody Blues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>German Shepherd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doodies</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verrierdale Lamington Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tewantin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major Mangrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verrierdale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Matson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Greenfied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Allerdice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J.J. Cale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Tainsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lamington Show</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lost Lamington Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lukas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eumundi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LEFT Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearl Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Pub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belli Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kin Kin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocket Express</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chifley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pink Floyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Mail</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CWA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
