<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404110750489993</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/more-sports/wwe-star-the-undertaker-has-a-shocking-phobia/news-story/6955ab8539ba444ea3cd158a9d2d6df9</url>
  <title>WWE star The Undertaker has a shocking phobia</title>
  <content>
WWE Sasha Banks visits Australia
0:28

US WWE superstar Sasha Banks visits The Project and talks about her costumes which are designed by her husband. Courtesy: Network Ten

July 13th 2017
19 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/Television/

WWE legend The Undertaker.

Tom FordyThe Sun

Share

FOR 27 years The Undertaker was one of the most dominant and feared superstars to step in a WWE ring.
He struck terror into the hearts of his opponents with the supernatural-like presence and knack for stuffing his victims into caskets. But in real-life, The Undertaker had a fear of his own - he was scared of cucumbers.
It's long been one of the great urban legends of the wrestling world, but this story appears to be absolutely true.

The Undertaker taking on Shawn Michaels.Source:Supplied
Paul Bearer - longtime onscreen manager and travel partner of The Undertaker - confirmed the rumour in an interview before his death in 2013.
"He cannot stand cucumbers ... I saw The Undertaker throw up all over a waffle house because there was a cucumber floating in his iced tea," Bearer told Jim Cornette.
Bearer also confessed to pranking The Undertaker by sticking cucumber slices in his hat and gloves. But Bearer - real name William Moody - could only speculate about the cause of the Deadman's greatest phobia.
"It was something to do with when he was a kid ... I guess his mother made him eat them when he didn't want them, or something," Bearer said. "He just hates cucumbers."

The Undertaker's greatest fear.Source:News Corp Australia
Long-time WWE official Bruce Prichard also talked about it on his "Something To Wrestle" podcast, during an episode about infamous backstage prankster Owen Hart.
"Owen put cucumbers in the bottom of the iced tea so that when Taker drank the tea and drank it back, he didn't realise the cucumbers were in there until it was looking at his face," Prichard said.

"Something To Wrestle" co-host Conrad Thompson recounted rumours he'd heard, about how Hart slipped cucumbers into Taker's boots so they'd squish into his feet.
Another story was that Hart would go out to wrestle Undertaker with cucumber slices concealed in his tights.

USA wrestler Owen Hart lifting dumbbell weight.Source:AP
He would then hold the Deadman in a headlock and surreptitiously produce the cucumbers to hold in Taker's face - forcing the Deadman to face his fear or break character.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Cornette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasha Banks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Network Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Undertakers</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Bearer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conrad Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prichard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWE</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Prichard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deadman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWE Sasha Banks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shawn Michaels.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom FordyThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owen Hart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Moody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US WWE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
