<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404119340424749</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/01/level-university-assaults-heartbreaking-national-union-students</url>
  <title>Level of university assaults 'heartbreaking': National Union of Students</title>
  <content>
National Union of Students president Sophie Johnston says findings in a new report on sexual assaults and harassment at universities are 'heartbreaking'.

38 MINS AGO  UPDATED 9 MINS AGO

Findings from a landmark report into the level of sexual assaults and harassment have been described as "heartbreaking" by National Union of Students president Sophie Johnston.

She said the report, which is due to be released on Tuesday at 10am AEST, shows significantly more women than men are assaulted and harassed, there is also a disproportion of LGBTI students affected.

"It was heartbreaking when I saw the results," Ms Johnston told ABC TV.

"I think it wasn't necessarily because they were different or any more severe than what I expected, I guess it was just, after decades and decades of silence from so many victims, to actually hear the voices and see these stories is very confronting."

The report was commissioned by Universities Australia to gauge the level of sexual assaults and harassment amid claims the institutions were involved in covering up claims made by victims.

The Human Rights Commission was commissioned to survey thousands of students from 39 unis last year and produce the report, which is the largest of its kind.

Recommended reading

Ms Johnston said the report was compiled after another survey in 2015 found two thirds of respondents reported some form of sexual assault or harassment.

She said the fact that universities were very small communities where lots of partying involving alcohol took place had contributed to the problem.

"There is also a serious lack of education around consent and respectful relationships," she said.

"That goes back to primary school and high school where the sex education we provide to young people in Australia just isn't doing the job."

Part of Universities Australia's initial response to the report has been to announce a 10-point plan to help prevent assault and harassment, better support students, and more training for staff.

Australian National University vice-chancellor Brian Schmidt says people should be shocked the report's findings.

"They will tell us an ugly truth about how young people, in particular, are affected by sexual violence," he said.

"It is not an issue that we can simply acknowledge, then move onto the next thing. It is an issue that we must deal with."

Ms Johnston will join Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins and Universities of Australia chair Prof Margaret Gardener to release the report in Sydney.

National 24-hour support line for university students 1800 572 224, with access to Rape and Domestic Violence Services Australia counsellors.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 9 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Johnston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Margaret Gardener</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Union of Students</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domestic Violence Services Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Johnston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
