<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404033441077333</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/hbo-has-been-hacked-and-upcoming-game-of-thrones-material-has-been-stolen-2017-8</url>
  <title>HBO has been hacked and upcoming Game of Thrones material has been stolen</title>
  <content>
Hackers have caused the ultimate spoiler alert for Game of Thrones fans.

HBO has confirmed it has been hacked and episodes of Game of Thrones, along with a script for a forthcoming show may be among stolen data.

The cable TV station has released the following statement about the attack:

HBO recently experienced a cyber incident, which resulted in the compromise of proprietary information.
We immediately began investigating the incident and are working with law enforcement and outside cybersecurity firms.
Data protection is a top priority at HBO, and we take seriously our responsibility to protect the data we hold.

The company did not give specifics on what shows might be involved, or how much material, but the hackers claim they stole 1.5 terabytes of data.

HBO chairman and CEO Richard Plepler wrote to staff saying the hack included "some stolen proprietary information, including some of our programming".

that it was among several media organisations to receive an anonymous email, allegedly from the hackers:

Hi to all mankind. The greatest leak of cyber space era is happening. What's its name? Oh I forget to tell. Its HBO and Game of Thrones......!!!!!! You are lucky to be the first pioneers to witness and download the leak. Enjoy it & spread the words. Whoever spreads well, we will have an interview with him. HBO is falling.

Entertainment Weekly reports that future episodes of the shows Ballers and Room 104 have been put online, as well as part of the script for next week's episode of Game of Thrones. No GoT episodes have appeared online at this stage.

The theft follows the hacking of Netflix in April, when an episode of Orange Is the New Black and leaked online before its scheduled release.

Entertainment Weekly has .

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Room 104</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Richard Plepler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Weekly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orange Is</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
