<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404033441077343</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/mass-exodus-businesses-in-mall-given-marching-orde/3207147/</url>
  <title>MASS EXODUS: Businesses in mall given marching orders</title>
  <content>
BUSINESS owners in the CBD spent the weekend frantically packing up after being given their marching orders.

About 20 businesses have either left their premises in the mall or are preparing to leave.

Many were involved in the Activate Ipswich program, offering businesses cheap rent to encourage the establishment of start-up businesses.

They were given a month's notice and told to hand the keys back into the Ipswich City Square Centre Management by 5pm Monday.

Yesterday, the Australian Motorsport Museum was also given notice to vacate by September 30.

The council says the Activate Ipswich Program has wrapped up, prompting the notices to vacate.

It wants to free the space up for full paying tenants, as the mall redevelopment enters full swing.

The Activate Ipswich Program - in which businesses were given free rent but had to pay costs such as electricity - relied on property owners offering the space and only Ipswich City Properties, owned by Ipswich City Council, chose to participate.

But not all who are leaving the mall were part of the Activate Ipswich Program.

The QT spoke to about eight different business owners, most of whom did not want to be quoted for fear of backlash, and some were on commercial contracts.

Michael Crosswell from Prettyz A Picture moving out of his Ipswich Mall store due to the redevelopment.Inga Williams

Prettyz A Picture framing owners Michael and Andrea Crosswell have operated their business in the mall since 2014.

They were not part of the Activate Ipswich program.

Yesterday they were busy packing up the last items from the shop.

Shops are closing down during the redevelopment of the Ipswich Mall.Inga Williams

Their business will now move to Rifle Range, near Lowood, and will offer a mobile service within 30km of Ipswich.

Ms Crosswell said they knew the notice to vacate would come sooner or later.

"We were notified a month ago, that we would have to leave because of the mall redevelopment," Ms Crosswell said.

"We're excited for the mall redevelopment because the town really needs it.

"It's a new beginning for us and there is less competition where we are going."

Dominique's Bakery and A Lot of Books bookshop, opposite the construction walls at the bottom of the mall, confirmed they would stay for now.

They will move when the next stage of the redevelopment goes ahead. While the Australian Motorsport Museum has to go, Ipswich City Council says it is working to find the museum a new space.

"Under the original terms of the program tenants agreed to a month to month rent free arrangement on a short term basis to establish business viability," a council spokesman said.

"Not all existing paying tenants are required to vacate at this time. Some will have several months before there is a need to move."

Shops are closing down during the redevelopment of the Ipswich Mall.Inga Williams

Ipswich City Square Centre Management, Knight Frank, was approached for comment.

Knight Frank's contract has also been terminated as of next Monday, following a 90 day notification period from Ipswich City Properties.

Open for business

WHILE some businesses are leaving the mall, it's trading as normal for many others.

If you walk into the Ipswich mall you'll see the shops on the right hand side are generally still operating and it's not hard to spot which ones want to be noticed.

Big cardboard signs have been placed in shop windows to ensure Ipswich residents know, the city heart is still beating despite the demolition works taking place behind the fencing.

Cassie Doherty from Schudio Studio, in Nolan's Corner, said "all the sticky beaks" should come and have a look at the demolition and visit the remaining the businesses.

"There has been a drop in sales but we are still positive," Ms Doherty said.

"We (at Nolan's Corner) are not the only ones still trading.

"Come have a look."

Shops are closing down during the redevelopment of the Ipswich Mall.Inga Williams
Businesses no longer in the mall

Casket shop (small newsagent)

Andrew Jarvie Photography: Still operating elsewhere 

Anime Exchange

Autographed Memorabilia: Moved to Yeerongpilly

Dingshen Health Massage

FSG Australia (left earlier in the year)

Inspirations Ipswich

Joli Bluebird: Home business, Bellbowrie

Les Hill Training: Still operating  

Studio 7: Still operating elsewhere

Totoya Hair: Moving to 1/7 Bell St, reopening on August 15

HS Ipswich: Moved to Fire Station 101
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassie Doherty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeerongpilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anime Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dingshen Health Massage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inga Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich City Properties</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lot of Books</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellbowrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Mall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MASS EXODUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Totoya Hair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire Station 101</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Activate Ipswich Program</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Motorsport Museum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich City Square Centre Management</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schudio Studio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight Frank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Doherty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joli Bluebird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Activate Ipswich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rifle Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich City Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nolan's Corner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Jarvie Photography</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Crosswell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Crosswell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prettyz A Picture</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Hill Training</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Mall.Inga Williams</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Crosswell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dominique's Bakery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HS Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FSG Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
