<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404067800816497</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/television/bachelor-hopeful-revealed-as-a-former-topless-waitress-was-pictured-partying-with-warnie/news-story/cf3bce11e639eafe2e5685ebb91775ec</url>
  <title>Topless waitress Bachelor star partied with Warnie</title>
  <content>
Fashion highlights from The Bachelor

PHOTOGRAPHS of former topless waitress and The Bachelor contestant partying with ladies™ man Shane Warne have emerged online.

Office admin worker Simone Ormesher, 25, who was forced to open up about her controversial past on Facebook just days ago, has now been linked to the cricket star.

The pair have been pictured at a dress-up pool party in 2015, before the blonde beauty signed up to win Matthew "Matty J" Johnson's heart.

"And..... The Angels too," Warne captioned a photo with Ormesher at the time.

Another group shot said: "The party has properly started, only complaint is my 80's music !!! Hahaha."

Ormesher defended her topless waitressing past on Facebook on Friday after photographs emerged on the internet of her chatting to blokes at a buck's party.

She hashtagged "haters gonna hate" and "not gonna let this get me down" in the lengthy online post.

"From the bottom of my heart I just want to thank everyone for being so loving caring and supportive of the whole situation," she wrote.

"When the news first came to light I felt ashamed, embarrassed and just wanted to jump into my bed cry uncontrollably, pull my blankets over my head thing blew over.

"I just now come to realise with the help of my friends and family that sometimes we do things in life we are not proud of, and in life you have to do what you have to do to survive!

"Sometimes you can't let life get you down or crush you, you have to be strong enough to adjust, move on and adapt to your situation.

"That's how I Iearnt about perseverance and courage is all about it's also being about to move forward and adapt when life can become difficult. These are the life lessons I have learnt from my mum being such a strong positive independent women and I know if I can be half the women (sic) that she is I know she would be proud. I'm just trying to be the best version of myself and sometimes to have to go through adversity to get there. So thank you!"

Ormesher is still in the running to win Matty J's heart.

The Bachelor airs on Wednesdays and Thursdays at 7.30pm on Channel 10.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warnie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ormesher</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone Ormesher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iearnt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Warne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
