<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404024851142504</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nba-star-chandler-parsons-steps-out-with-ufc/news-story/9240292cf8e807e077b84d6de973400d</url>
  <title>NBA playboy spotted with UFC stunner</title>
  <content>
CHANDLER Parsons isn't doing much to squash rumours surrounding his personal life.
On Thursday, the womanising Memphis Grizzlies star hit Hollywood hot spot Craig's with UFC's million-dollar ring girl and supposed flame Arianny Celeste.
The dashing duo, who were first linked earlier this month, were photographed leaving the cozy eatery, with Parsons, 28, walking a few paces behind Celeste, 31.
Sports site Terez Owens captured one of pair's initial outings on social media, where Celeste played co-pilot to Parsons during a night-time drive.
Parsons' public outing with Celeste marks a potential milestone for the emerging couple, as the NBA playboy, whose long list of exes include Bella Thorne, Kendall Jenner and Toni Garn.
As Busted Coverage points out, Parsons did find time over the weekend to like a swimsuit photo of Mallory Edens. She is the daughter of Bucks co-owner Wes Edens.
The UFC'S top ring girl has reportedly made her first million dollars from being the eye-candy for the MMA promotion.
The organisation is reportedly paying its glamorous assistants around $28,000-a-year and star attraction Celeste has boosted her earnings with a number of deals that have made her over a million dollars
Celeste began appearing as a UFC Octagon Girl at the Hard Rock Cafe and Casino in Las Vegas in 2006 and became a sensation among fans.
She has also won a handful of awards like Sports Illustrated's 2010 Lady of the Day, Ring Girl of the Year 2010 by the MMA Awards and the Hottest UFC Octagon Girl by Maxim in 2010.
The brunette has 459,000 Twitter followers and was rated no. 23 on Maxim's Hottest 100 List in 2010.
Back in 2015, when Ronda Rousey was at the top of her game, she complained about the pay in the UFC's female divisions and claimed ring girls were, in some instances, paid more than fighters.
Rousey said: "I don't know if the ring girls get paid too much or the fighters don't get paid enough.
"But, yeah, there's definitely a lot more in what the fighters do than what they do.
"So, I think that's one thing that's unfair."

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni Garn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hard Rock Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Girl of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parsons, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC Octagon Girl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arianny Celeste</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terez Owens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rousey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports Illustrated's 2010 Lady of the Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendall Jenner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHANDLER Parsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bella Thorne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memphis Grizzlies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Busted Coverage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hottest UFC Octagon Girl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parsons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maxim's Hottest 100 List</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mallory Edens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronda Rousey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celeste</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wes Edens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
