<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404024851142537</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4824545/topics-despite-dinner-no-reining-in-robbo/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Topics: Despite dinner, no reining in Robbo</title>
  <content>
CIVILISED: That time Jeff McCloy got Allan Robinson a new suit. Picture: Brock Perks

DOES Robbo need reining in? It depends who you ask.
The champion jockey and TV larrikin-turned-Newcastle councillor stunned a few in City Hall last week when he walked out of a council meeting.
"Can we have a welfare check on councillor Robinson?" Labor deputy mayor Jason Dunn asked the chamber.
"I'm sure he's not just having dinner while we're in here having a meeting."

Greens councillor Therese Doyle had had the floor and resumed speaking for what seemed like an age before, you guessed it, Cr Allan Robinson returned, chewing, remarking that "the beef's good tonight".
It wasn't Robbo's first contribution.

Before Liberal councillor David Compton had arrived late, he'd earned the quip "he's in the McDonald's drive-through". 

When Liberal Brad Luke and Labor's Declan Clausen sparred dryly over council investments, Robbo intoned "does Cr Clausen and Cr Luke need to have a sleepover?"

Lord mayor Nuatali Nelmes pointed out the sitting council only meets once more this term and, while "there's a place for humour" at meetings, some things might be better left unsaid.
"It wasn't meant humorously," Cr Robinson replied.
So where does that leave us with Robbo? 
The mayor wasn't thrilled, but pushed on. The deputy mayor, who Robbo once told by text to "put your skirt back on", turned to the press area and said "this needs to be reported".
Speaking to Topics, Robbo complained about the meeting agenda that was stuffed by Labor and the Green with pretty non-Robbo issues, like the recommendations of the cycling committee, and the merits of being a United Nations Global Compact City.
"Have a look at the product they were putting up," he said. 
"What were they putting up in the 12 minutes or whatever it was I was out? They had the numbers. Did they just need me to stand against it?"

SHARP: Jeff McCloy takes the blade to Allan Robinson. Picture: Brock Perks
He wasn't the only one struggling with the meeting - Cr Andrea Rufo interrupted one Cr Doyle oration to plead, "is... time up?"
Topics gets the impression Kath Elliott, the lord mayoral candidate who'll lead the Newcastle Independents at next month's council elections with Cr Robinson heading the ticket in ward four, won't be issuing edicts about pulling heads in.
"I'm not commenting on Robbo's behaviour. I wasn't there, and I don't know what happened," Ms Elliott said (hopefully this recap helps).
"Allan Robinson's been an excellent councillor in ward four. It's not about council meetings, it's how you actually deliver the goods for the community."

If she gets the top job Ms Elliott might learn from former lord mayor Jeff McCloy, who once talked Robbo into some new threads and a trim at the barber's.
DOOR TO BLAME FOR BLOOD BATH

WOUNDED: Newcastle council interim boss Jeremy Bath. Picture: Simone De Peak
NEWCASTLE council interim general manager Jeremy Bath sported a heavy bandage on his hand at a press conference in Broadmeadow on Monday.
Turns out Mr Bath has a nasty cut with heaps of blood, which Topics will spare you a picture of over your Weeties.
The gruesome moment shattered a Sunday morning outing at Redhead with his cattle dogs Harvey, Charlie and Belle, and happened when Charlie ran the wrong way.
"I quickly slammed the car door and it bounced straight off my finger," Mr Bath said.
"In that moment I was pretty sure I'd lost the finger."
Was Charlie in the doghouse for a while? 

No. After a heavy mopping-up job with a towel, Mr Bath still gave his best mates an hour at the beach.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's Declan Clausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Perks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff McCloy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Andrea Rufo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Independents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Clausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weeties</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DOES Robbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Allan Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Bath</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Robinson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Brad Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nuatali Nelmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBBO</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations Global Compact City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Robinson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone De Peak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Therese Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bath</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Compton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BLAME FOR BLOOD BATH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Elliott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
