<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404115045457440</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/stage/melbourne-stage/jesus-christ-superstar-review-key-cast-lack-gravitas-20170731-gxm2q2.html</url>
  <title>Jesus Christ Superstar review: Key cast lack gravitas</title>
  <content>
THEATRE
JESUS CHRIST SUPERSTAR ★★ 1/2
 
The Production Company
Arts Centre Melbourne, Until August 13
Reviewed by Cameron Woodhead

The Production Company has always valued performers over bells and whistles, and in some ways that ethos is suited to Jesus Christ Superstar.Jesus Christ SuperstarPhoto: Jeff Busby
It was conceived as a rock oratorio rather than a musical, and seems to be resurrected once a generation in an arena spectacular - my first encounter with it was the 1992 version, with John Farnham as Jesus and Kate Ceberano as Mary Magdalene - that's closer to a concert than musical theatre.
If you go in expecting that kind of experience, this revival is likely to disappoint, in part due to the casting.Photo: Jeff Busby
Rob Mills is a bit lightweight for Jesus, both vocally and histrionically. I don't mean to sound too dismissive: Mills has shone playing the man-boys of musical theatre in some big-time shows - as the self-absorbed love interest in Wicked, say, or Danny in Grease - but he doesn't have the heft, nor the authority, for a tortured incarnation of the Messiah.
Fulsome over-emoting isn't a substitute for either. Director Gale Edwards should rein it in before poor Mills pops a vein trying to convince us of his torment.

I'm not sure anything can be done about his piping falsetto, though. It's much too thin and strained. When Jesus banishes moneylenders from the Temple (in this production, inexplicably, they're dressed as pop culture icons from Andy Warhol to Wonder Woman), the climax of his righteous wrath resembles nothing so much as a fangirl's squeal.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

As Judas, Zoy Frangos doesn't fare much better. He comes to the party in the title track, but you need a real rock voice to make the rage and anguish stick, and again, you can't compensate through overacting.
Other roles are better served. Alinta Chidzey's Mary Magdalene achieves a soulful, sensuous sound that's almost bewildered by her newfound purity. Trevor Ashley out-Herods Herod as a glitter-bombed cabaret grotesque; Michael Cormick sings his way into the doomed Pontius Pilate and Michael Paul Hughes and Stephen McDowell provide great vocal contrast as the sinister Pharisees. The chorus work can be fine, too.
Still, Edwards has created a show that makes a spectacle of itself, with frivolous camp order of the day. Lavish lighting dazzles; yet the costumes are a source of bemusement. Why are the Romans  dressed as space Nazis? Or the Pharisees like poor cousins of Ming the Merciless? Why do showgirls in angel costume ditz and shimmy from on high during the final number? Who knows. Such extravagances would doubtless be more fun, and less fatuous, if as much attention had been paid to fine-tuning the performances.
If you've never seen Jesus Christ Superstar performed, this production is worth a look, and may well improve through the season.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts Centre Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herods Herod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JESUS CHRIST SUPERSTAR ★★ 1/2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wonder Woman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Temples</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Paul Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pharisees</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Farnham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Ceberano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Warhol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pontius Pilate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Ashley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen McDowell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alinta Chidzey's Mary Magdalene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Production Company</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Magdalene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus Christ Superstar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gale Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoy Frangos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cormick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus Christ Superstar.Jesus Christ SuperstarPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Woodhead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Busby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
