<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404020556175175</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/game-of-thrones-s07-e03-recap/8762188</url>
  <title>Game of Thrones chat Episode 3: Some family reunions, a brood-off and a serve of queen's justice</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

With precious few episodes left to wrap things up, HBO hit fast-forward on Game of Thrones this week.
So fasten your seatbelts and join your Westerosi correspondents Pete Marsh and Dan Miller to see what you might have missed.
Before we begin, if you're after even more Game of Thrones fun, come join  You'll probably want to recruit some friends too.
There's a battle coming, and you'll need all the armies you can get.
Let's get into Episode 3: The Queen's Justice.
**SPOILER WARNING**
These recaps are dark and full of spoilers, so only continue reading if you've caught up on the latest episode of the show.
We won't be spoiling anything from the books if you haven't read them or any production leaks that have found their way onto the internet.
DAN: And so, after all these years of waiting, of theorising, we finally get the fated meeting. Ice and fire, Stark and Targaryen - together at last. I was half expecting sparks, but what we got was an icy reception.
But don't all the best unions seem to start with breakdowns of communication anyway? I think we can expect these two the grow on each other ...
Emilia Clarke as Daenerys was imposing, showing us very much what sort of Queen this young Targaryen is. Jon was slinking into the throne room looking rather awkward to be involved in a political situation he had no love for.
Davos falters as well, but soon backs his king with another trademark endorsement of his.
PETE: Davos is just the best hype man in Westeros Dan.
He's got a bit of a habit of backing kings who are terrible when it comes to winning powerful foes to their cause, but  and  ya boy Davos delivers.
DAN: The other reason we were so looking forward to this meeting, besides wanting to ship Jon and Dany, is their ancestry. It was spectacularly confirmed last season that Jon is not the bastard son of Ned Stark but instead his nephew, son to Lyanna Stark.
She gave birth some time after she was "kidnapped" by crown prince Rhaegar Targaryen, which started Robert Baratheon's whole rebellion (Robert was betrothed to Lyanna).
We don't know for certain who the father is, but since the list is pretty much only one name long a lot of people have taken a very sharp stab at it.
Lyanna knew the truth would see Jon killed, so she made Ned promise her he would keep it secret - nothing else fits. And so it seems like Jon may have just met his aunt, Daenerys Targaryen.
Don't you just love a good family reunion? (Shippers rejoice! Incest is no barrier for a Targaryen).
PETE: Speaking of ships, missing ones to be precise ... Dan we got a brood-off!

External Link:

It's the worst when someone steals your favourite brooding spot.
I ate up the Jon/Tyrion banter this episode and finally Jon admitted he's a bit rubbish when it comes to this diplomacy thing. But Tyrion, Dan, well, he's A LOT better.
DAN: I loved this exchange. Here we have two outsiders from their own families, now thrust into important roles. Tyrion is probably as close a friend as Jon is going to get in this lonely game.
PETE: We went into this season wondering how exactly King's Landing was going to stand against the might of Daenerys Targaryen.
I think we all underestimated the fury that is Cersei Lannister.
With a prize delivered to her thanks to Pirate Pacey ... I mean Euron Greyjoy ... she brutally repaid some debts to Ellaria Sand, she deftly promised to repay some more to the Iron Bank and she took what was hers in the bedroom.
In the space of a few episodes Cersei has struck two significant blows against Daenerys, leaving her without the Dornish and Tyrell allies that were supposed to win the hearts of the people of Westeros.
Wow.
Honestly, this was the most fun I've had watching a villain on Game of Thrones since Joffrey.
Lena Headey has always played Cersei with a barely-concealed contempt for those around her. There's no need to hide it now, and watching her in full flight is terrifying and exhilarating.
It was Cersei who said that when you play the game of thrones you win or you die and no one plays it better than she does. Not even dragons will save you if you come for her.

External Link:

It is known.
But ... while Jon may have worried about Daenerys turning into her father, the Mad King Aerys, Cersei has been making some pretty solid steps down this path already.
From the finale last season we know about her love of wildfire. It was the Mad King's old stockpile she used to blow up the Great Sept.
And this season you've heard characters (Sansa in the last episode and Jon himself in this one) reference Aerys burning Rickard Stark (Ned's father) while his son Brandon (Ned's older brother) was made to watch and strangled himself.
The brutal fate of Ellaria and Tyene Sand isn't too dissimilar. Cersei has her sanity and wits about her now while she's winning, but what happens if/when she starts to lose?
DAN: Cersei's Mad King MKII is going to be a lot of fun to watch as we see things unravelling this season.
But away from all the unpleasantness of King's Landing we had a family reunion to be happy about. Or did we?
Sansa and Bran have reunited, throwing two more Starks together. But things were definitely ... tense. This Bran is no longer a lord's son or a loving brother - this is the three-eyed raven.
Knowledge of all the events past and present has made his objective clear. He needs to tell Jon something. I suspect this might be prophecy and perhaps parentage related. Don't worry Sansa, your assassin sister Arya might still be happy to see you.
PETE: I knew the show was on fast-forward but Sam curing greyscale in a week? I've got whiplash. Was Jorah ever headed anywhere else once he was cured?

External Link:

Jorah's got a hot new post-greyscale bod and he's going to win back bae's heart.
I am really digging Jim Broadbent as Archmaester Ebrose this season. Game of Thrones has had success bringing in incredibly accomplished actors that don't necessarily have the profile to match for supporting roles (think Charles Dance's turn as Tywin).
Broadbent probably sits just outside that MO given his role in the Harry Potter films, but he just inhabits this universe so well. Still, Sam got a rough deal. Not even a single link in his chain for curing a guy of incurable greyscale? What a rip.
DAN: What a rip? What a RIP? Oh Pete, you sweet summer child.
Let me tell you about the biggest rip-off in practically the entire series.
For SEASONS I have been hoping to see a glimpse of Casterly Rock, the legendary home of the Lannisters.
Not the TV show nor the books have ventured to that castle. So when it finally looks like a massive battle is brewing and we'll see a siege at The Rock ... they film a cute exterior shot and a couple of spear throws inside.
The battle is over. WHAT?

OK, to say I'm disappointed is an understatement. At least the producers can salvage this with the Lannister army heading to Highgarden for a massive battl ... oh I blinked and missed it.
Shame. I'm smouldering enough to hatch a dragon egg.
PETE: Dan you are saltier than a sailor on Pyke, but at least we got that final confrontation in the tallest tower of Highgarden. Fans should know never to expect anything good when
What a wonderful exchange between the two Kingslayers Jaime Lannister and Olenna Tyrell. The Queen of Thorns (and shade) fittingly went out with some vicious final barbs, putting to rest any doubt she was the one who poisoned Joffrey and seeding some serious doubts in Jaime about the Queen his sister had become.
Here's a hot tip fans: Watch for Jaime to steer back towards the conflicted figure you unwittingly fell for in season three. Just look at the way he let Olenna Tyrell make a dignified, painless exit versus the way Cersei dealt with her enemies this episode.
There's clearly more distance between the Lannister twins than first thought.
This was one of my favourite Game of Thrones episodes in a long time (Euron's magical teleporting armada of ships aside).
With some massive conflicts happening off-screen and some ripping writing between major players left to do the heavy lifting, it felt like a season one episode in the best possible way.
But aside from that, it left us no doubt who rules these seven kingdoms.
It is our Queens, whether they be on the Iron Throne, in Dragonstone, ruling Winterfell or recently departed in High Garden. A toast to them. Long may they reign.
Best Quote

PETE: "Tell Cersei. I want her to know it was me." - Olenna Tyrell, throwing shade until the very end. Slay.
DAN: "How do I convince people who don't know me that an enemy they don't believe in is going to kill them all?" - Jon Snow, hitting the nail on the head.
Bastard Moment

PETE: Just about all of Euron this episode. But especially his chat with Jaime. Dude ... just go read the sealed section of a Westeros Cosmo.
DAN: The producers finally showing us Casterly Rock and then giving us THAT battle sequence ... *slow clap*
Who we lost this week

Some Unsullied, a smattering of Lannister soldiers, the third and final Sand Snake and our Queen of Thorns, Olenna Tyrell.
What you missed

Cersei promised the Iron Bank that Lannisters paid their debts. But with the King's Landing credit card maxed out and the gold mines under Casterly Rock empty, she needed a new way to do it.
Turns out, the second richest house in Westeros was the Tyrells, who gathered their considerable wealth in Highgarden. Which now belongs to the Lannisters.
Debt. Paid.

External Link:

She came to King's Landing to kick ass and pay debts ... and she's all outta debts.
What we missed in the last episode

Remember last episode when Archmaester Ebrose was telling Sam he was writing a history book on King Robert's rebellion?
"You don't like the title? What would you call it then?" he asks Sam.
"Possibly something a bit more poetic?" Sam replies.
Sooooo ... there's this fantastic theory that's been going around in Game of Thrones circles for a while that Sam could in fact be the narrator of this whole tale.
The series might end with old man Archmaester Sam writing the last of the story down in a history book (ala Bilbo writing The Hobbit) titled something very poetic indeed: A Song of Ice and Fire (the title of the Game of Thrones book series).
Up until now there has been very little to point to this being true, but that one quick exchange last episode has ignited a fire!
Best of the Web-steros

Everyone. Take a seat. You're sitting down? Good.
We have a glorious story to share this week. Ben Hawkey, the actor who plays the purest boy in Westeros, Hot Pie, ACTUALLY OPENED A BAKERY IN REAL LIFE.
And I know you won't believe it, You know Nothing Jon Dough Hot Pie baked for Arya.
Stick a fork in me, cause I am done.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh Pete</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tell Cersei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archmaester Ebrose</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobbit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euron Greyjoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyanna Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rickard Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon-Tyrion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bilbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casterly Rock</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ned Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lena Headey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bran</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna Tyrell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyene Sand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACTUALLY OPENED A BAKERY IN REAL LIFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highgarden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archmaester Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winterfell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrells</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jorah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellaria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Targaryen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dornish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPOILER WARNING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brandon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joffrey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Sept</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arya</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pirate Pacey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tywin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sand Snake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingslayers Jaime Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragonstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEASONS I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hawkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emilia Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad King Aerys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Baratheon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyanna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys Targaryen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Song of Ice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei's Mad King MKII</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nothing Jon Dough Hot Pie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web-steros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen of Thorns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westerosi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aerys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Episode 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhaegar Targaryen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellaria Sand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Dance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros Cosmo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Landing</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Throne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros Dan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unsullied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
