<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404029146109957</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/reality-tv/this-time-next-year-botched-stunt-does-40000-worth-of-damage/news-story/14b33594ec5ac720939e585292ed375c</url>
  <title>This Time Next Year: Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage</title>
  <content>
Stunt woman comes out on fire on 'This Time Next Year'
0:44

Mel Goh comes out covered in flames after 12 months training to be a professional stunt woman. Courtesy: This Time Next Year/Channel Nine

August 1st 2017
5 minutes ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Karl Stefanovic hosts This Time Next Year.

Share

NOT everything went to plan during the taping of Karl Stefanovic's new TV show, This Time Next Year.
As Nine's Head of Production and Development revealed to news.com.au, $40,000 worth of damage was done to the set when a fiery stunt went wrong.
If you missed last night's premiere episode, here's the premise of the show:
Everyday Aussies sit down on a couch opposite Karl Stefanovic and tell him about "monumental" personal goals that they want to tackle and overcome in the next 12 months. Then they disappear backstage and through the magic of television, it's suddenly a year later and the same people come back onto the stage to reveal if they achieved their goals.
Last night's debut episode featured a 33-year-old office worker named Mel Goh who made the vow, "This time next year I'll be a stuntwoman".
"Presuming Mel was successful, we had always intended that she would perform some sort of stunt when she came back the next year," Nine's Head of Production and Development, Trent Chapman, told news.com.au.
"We looked at all sorts of options for the reveal and somehow the discussion came around to her being on fire."
Mr Chapman said they rehearsed the stunt outside for a month or so prior to filming with a stand-in before testing it out several times indoors and eventually on the stage.
"It was all perfect but then of course in the heat of the moment, so to speak, there was a small problem."

Mel Goh's on set stunt.Source:Channel 9

Mel Goh.Source:Channel 9
On the actual night of filming, Mel Goh walked out onto the stage covered in flames and was flanked by two safety officers who eventually doused the flames with extinguishers.
"Some of the foam spray went onto the very, very expensive LED screen at the back [of the stage] and they were ruined," Mr Chapman said.
"I think it was about $40,000 worth of damage. Sorry to our insurers."
Mel Goh's achievement of becoming a qualified stunt person was just one of the many positive stories featured on the show last night.
An overweight couple left Karl Stefanovic  they'd lost over 100kg between them, and a couple from South Australia who had previously had 10 failed rounds of IVF vowed to have a baby within a year. They ended up with twins.
Viewers took to social media to praise the positivity of This Time Next Year with many saying the show had reduced them to tears.
Less than 5 minutes in and I've teared up three times. I'm worried this show is about to consume me...
Great show  with   emotion mixed with happiness in the matter of moments.
This is one of the amazing show  ✨ My heart was moved by some incredible people!!!😍✨ I realized that we can do everything😉
that was one of the most courageous pieces of T.V I've seen. Wow!
What a beautiful reminder of how wonderful life can be sometimes. Let's not forget to take anything for granted
Bugger. Actually had tears in my eyes watching . I was planning on hating it. Damn.
Switched over to  - what a fantastic feel good show.  the perfect host.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Head of Production</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel Goh</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Stefanovic</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IVF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Next Year/Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Chapman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine's Head of Production</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Next Year</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Chapman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel Goh.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T.V I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
