<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404282549184408</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/entertainment/confidential/louise-van-de-vorsts-former-bestfriend-michelle-leslie-ranoff-with-her-exboyfriend-daniel-johns/news-story/70dbd83b0c4a665024ab5deb9b5f78f6</url>
  <title>Leslie loses BFF, gains boyfriend</title>
  <content>
FIVE years ago model Louise van de Vorst stood next to former jailbird Michelle Leslie as her best friend and bridesmaid when she wed her ex--husband Adam Zammit.
Now less than five years after the nuptials Leslie has run off with van de Vorst's former boyfriend of four years, ex--Silverchair frontman Daniel Johns.
Johns and Leslie have managed to keep themselves out of the social pages since their romance blossomed in recent months, but

Leslie - who rose to prominence in 2005 after she spent three months in jail for possessing two ecstasy tablets - was pictured for the first time with a diamond ring on her wedding finger at the airport, sparking rumours the pair is engaged.
But Confidential can reveal Leslie and van de Vorst are no longer friends, so the chances of the model resuming bridesmaid duties if Leslie and Johns were to walk down the aisle are slim to none.
"Michelle used to be BFFs with Louise, including for the big chunk of time Louise was engaged to Johns," a source said. "So Michelle has shacked up with her former mate's ex which is incredible."
The pair was pictured arriving in Los Angeles airport, where Leslie was detained by authorities for allegedly failing to declare her prior drug conviction, before being released.
It is believed Johns split from his Australian management in recent months, while Leslie runs her own interior design company.
One former friend and business partner told Confidential Leslie had requested she not discuss her personal life publicly.
Van de Vorst has since moved on from her four-year relationship with Johns announcing her engagement to former Neighbours actor and musician Jaime Robbie Reyne in July 2015.
She gave birth to their first child Roosevelt in March last year. "We'll always be friends," van de Vorst told Confidential after her split with Johns in 2012.
Johns, 38, was previously married to singer Natalie Imbruglia.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BFF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johns, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Zammit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime Robbie Reyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosevelt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Leslie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silverchair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BFFs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vorst</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Confidential Leslie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Imbruglia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
