<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404239599510776</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/i-would-be-one-of-them-serena-williams-pens-essay-on-underpaid-black-women-20170731-gxmo3n.html</url>
  <title>'I would be one of them': Serena Williams pens essay on underpaid black women</title>
  <content>
Serena Williams has promised to "give a voice" to women in Silicon Valley and across the workforce in an essay highlighting the gender - and racial - pay gap for black women in the US.
The tennis Number One, who recently joined the board of tech company SurveyMonkey and is engaged to Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian, wrote for Fortune magazine on July 31, a day known as Black Women's Equal Pay Day.Photo: AP
In the essay, titled How Black Women Can Close the Pay Gap, Williams acknowledged her own privileges, saying she has been "financially successful beyond [her] imagination" but that she is not the reason the day exists.
"Today isn't about me. It's about the other 24 million black women in America," she wrote. "If I never picked up a tennis racket, I would be one of them; that is never lost on me."

In the US, black women earn 17 per cent less than their white female counterparts, and only 63 cents for every dollar earned by a man.
Williams said the issue had been in existence for "far too long with no consequence". 

"Through decades of systematic oppression, black women have been conditioned to think they are less than. In many cases, these women are the heads of households. Single mothers. The issue isn't just that black women hold lower-paying jobs. They earn less even in fields of technology, finance, entertainment, law, and medicine."
The athlete concluded by calling on black women to "be fearless" and "get back those 37 cents".
"I've long said, 'You have to believe in yourself when no one else does,'" she said.
It is not the first time Williams, who is pregnant with her first child, has written on gender equality.
In December 2016, she wrote an open letter in Porter magazine's Incredible Women Of 2016 issue asking why female athletes were not viewed as equal to their male counterparts.
 "When I was growing up... my dream was to be the best tennis player in the world. Not the best 'female' tennis player in the world," she wrote. 
Daily Life
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexis Ohanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Incredible Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serena Williams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Women Can Close</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Women's Equal Pay Day.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SurveyMonkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pay Gap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Number One</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
