<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404243894478115</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>ABN Newswire</source>
  <url>http://www.abnnewswire.net/press/en/89388/White-Cliff-Minerals-Ltd-(ASX-WCN)-Drilling-Resumes-Aucu-Gold-Deposit-89388.html</url>
  <title>White Cliff Minerals Ltd (ASX:WCN) Drilling Resumes - Aucu Gold Deposit</title>
  <content>
Perth, Aug 1, 2017 AEST (ABN Newswire) - White Cliff Minerals Limited (ASX:WCN) ("White Cliff" or "the Company") is pleased to announce that the 2017 field season drill program has commenced at its 90%-owned Aucu Gold deposit in north-west Kyrgyz Republic.
Phase one drilling focusing on the deposit's high grade Quartz Zone consists of 15 holes (1200 metres) of RC drilling. The drilling is targeting the Quartz Zone structure along strike from previous drilling which defined an inferred resource of 244,000 tonnes at 9.5 g/t containing 75,000 ounces. Once the strike extent of the Quartz Zone has been defined the Company will drill a series of deeper holes to test the mineralisation at depth.
The drill rig has completed ERC17-001, a 60-metre deep hole located 50 metres along strike from last year's drilling (see figure 1 in the link below) and has moved to the second hole ERC17-002, a 90-metre hole designed to test the mineralised zone underneath ERC17-001.
Mineralisation was identified in drill hole ERC17-001 where malachite (a copper oxide) was identified from 12 metres to 26 metres. Native copper was identified at 34 metres and was associated with goethite, an iron oxide typically associated with gold mineralisation. The samples will be dispatched to the laboratory this week when ERC17-002 is completed.
Mineralisation was also identified in outcrop 12 metres northeast of ERC17-001 where channel sampling in 2016 identified a zone three metres wide with channel sample assay results of 2 metres at 5.4 g/t and 1 metre at 0.7 g/t gold within sandstone. The zone consists of a small quartz vein surrounded by an alteration halo dominated by the iron oxides limonite and goethite which were originally sulphides. The zone also contains traces of the copper oxides azurite and malachite.
On the next drill section 50 metres further southeast, the Quartz Zone was identified in outcrop where channel sampling identified 4 metres at 3.5 g/t including one metre at 9.5 g/t gold.
Ongoing Exploration
In conjunction with the current drilling program the Company has undertaken an extensive geochemical sampling program covering outcropping mineralised zones identified in bull dozer tracks, prospecting traverses and trenching.
The results of these programs and the current drilling program will be reported as they become available.
The Company has also mobilised a second RC rig to the project site which will commence drilling shortly. The second drill rig will focus on the Eastern Gold Zone (6 holes) and the Lower Gold Zone (8 holes) where drilling in 2015 identified 6 metres at 38 g/t gold in LGZ15-29a. This target is hosted in a quartz vein with the same orientation as the Quartz Zone. The vein has been mapped along strike for 250 metres. Several bulldozer tracks and drill pads are currently being completed to facilitate this drilling program.
Aucu Gold Deposit-Inferred Resource Summary
In April the Company reported an updated inferred resource reported in accordance with the JORC Code (2012) for the Aucu gold deposit (refer to ASX announcement 21 April 2017). The estimate above a cut-off grade of 1 g/t gold is:
1.8 million tonnes grading 5.2 g/t gold, for 302,000 ounces of contained gold.
The new resource represents a 93% increase in contained gold ounces and a 23% increase in average grade over the previous gold resource using the same cut-off grade reported in April 2015.
Importantly the new resource contains a new very high grade zone (Quartz Zone) of 244,000 tonnes at 9.5 g/t gold containing 75,000 ounces of gold, which starts at surface. Surface extensions of the high grade Quartz Zone have been identified and will be drilled in the coming field season.
This latest resource estimate also identified a new inferred copper resource reported in accordance with the JORC Code (2012), using a cut-off grade of 0.25% copper, of 608,000 tonnes at 0.64% copper, containing 3,870 tonnes of copper.
The new gold and copper resources start at surface, have only been drilled to 100 metres vertical depth and remain open along strike and at depth.
The reported gold resources represent less than 5% of mineralised faults identified by rock-chip sampling to date. Approximately 95% of the mineralised faults identified by rock chip sampling are still to be drilled. The gold bearing mineralised structures extend beyond the current resource estimate area over a length greater than 3,000 metres and occur as multiple lodes (see Figure 8 in the link below).
To view tables and figures, please visit:

About White Cliff Minerals Ltd
 () is a Western Australian based exploration company with the following main projects:

Kyrgyz Aucu Gold Project (90%): The Project contains extensive porphyry related gold and copper mineralisation starting at the surface and extending over several kilometres. Drilling during 2014 has defined a major gold discovery with an initial inferred resource of 1.15Mt at 4.2 g/t containing 156,000 ounces of gold. Additional drilling in 2015 identified extensions of known high grade gold mineralisation with intersections as high as 8 metres at 55 g/t gold. In addition drilling has also defined a significant copper deposit at surface consisting of 10Mt at 0.41% copper containing 40,000 tonnes of copper. Extensive mineralisation occurs around both deposits demonstrating significant potential to increase the existing resources.

The project is located in the Kyrgyz Republic, 350km west-southwest of the capital city of Bishkek and covers 83 square kilometres. The Chanach project is located in the western part of the Tien Shan Belt, a highly mineralised zone that extends for over 2,500 km, from western Uzbekistan, through Tajikistan, Kyrgyz Republic and southern Kazakhstan into western China.

Merolia Gold and Nickel Project (100%): The project consists of 771 square kilometres of the Merolia Greenstone belt and contains extensive ultramafic sequences including the Diorite Hill layered ultramafic complex, the Rotorua ultramafic complex, the Coglia ultramafic complex and a 51 kilometre long zone of extrusive ultramafic lava's. The intrusive complexes are prospective for nickel-copper sulphide accumulations possibly with platinum group elements, and the extrusive ultramafic rocks are prospective for nickel sulphide and nickel-cobalt accumulations.

The project also contains extensive basalt sequences that are prospective for gold mineralisation including the Ironstone prospect where historical drilling has identified 24m at 8.6g/t gold. Soil sampling in 2016 has identified multiple mineralised gold trends at Burtville East, Comet Well and Ironstone which will be drilled in 2017.

Bremer Range Nickel Project (100%): The project covers over 127 square kilometres in the Lake Johnson Greenstone Belt, which contains the Emily Ann and Maggie Hayes nickel sulphide deposits. These mines have a total resource of approximately 140,000 tonnes of contained nickel. The project area has excellent prospectivity for both komatiite associated nickel sulphides and amphibolite facies high-grade gold mineralisation.

Lake Percy Lithium Project (100%) and Joint Venture (reducing to 30%): The Lake Percy tenement (E63/1222i) is the subject of a Joint Venture arrangement where Liontown Resources (LTR) can earn up to 70% via expenditure of $1.75 Million. Substantial lithium anomalism has been identified within outcropping pegmatites and drilling will be conducted in 2017. The Company also holds 100% of the adjacent 20km2 tenement (E63/1793) which also contains untested outcropping pegmatites.

Laverton Gold Project (100%): The project consists of 136 square kilometres of tenement applications in the Laverton Greenstone belt. The core prospects are Kelly Well and Eight Mile Well located 20km southwest of Laverton in the core of the structurally complex Laverton Tectonic zone immediately north of the Granny Smith Gold Mine (3 MOz) and 7 kilometres north of the Wallaby Gold Mine (7MOz).

   

Related Companies
         

Social Media
Share this Article

ABN Newswire
This Page Viewed:  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laverton Gold Project (100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aucu Gold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LTR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merolia Greenstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Percy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E63/1222</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 1, 2017 AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liontown Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Well</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN Newswire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eight Mile Well</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burtville East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nickel Project (100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aucu Gold Deposit-Inferred Resource Summary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrgyz Aucu Gold Project (90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drilling Resumes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comet Well</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E63/1793</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aucu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WCN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uzbekistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JORC Code (2012</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Johnson Greenstone Belt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Gold Zone (6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower Gold Zone (8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Percy Lithium Project (100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tien Shan Belt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tajikistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Venture</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quartz Zone</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallaby Gold Mine (7MOz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Ann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kazakhstan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotorua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merolia Gold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrgyz Republic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maggie Hayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laverton Greenstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Cliff Minerals Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Page Viewed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Cliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diorite Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Cliff Minerals Ltd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coglia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Figure 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laverton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Granny Smith Gold Mine (3 MOz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bremer Range Nickel Project (100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laverton Tectonic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aucu Gold Deposit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
