<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404325498858280</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/lavar-ball-loses-another-potential-partner-after-referee-incident/news-story/ef743dbf40977fb9a558c06f796ecfa1</url>
  <title>America's worst basketball dad hit again</title>
  <content>
THE hits keep coming for America's worst basketball dad, LaVar Ball.
In the latest controversy involving the highly outspoken father of Lonzo Ball, he lost one of his only remaining advocates.
Ball got into an altercation Friday with a female referee during an AAU game he was coaching and demanded she be removed after she hit him with a technical foul. Ball threatened to take his team off the court - which he's done on multiple occasions - and went on an angry rant after the game, clearly targeting the referee's gender.
Adidas, the company in charge of the AAU tournament, dutifully complied at the time and brought in another official to finish the remainder of the contest.
Ball received another tech and was ejected, but the issue was not put to bed.
Monday, Adidas expressed its regret for taking such seemingly inappropriate actions.
"The referee substitutions made during our tournament last week are not in line with our company values," the company said in a statement. "It was the wrong decision. We regret the situation and are looking into the matter to make sure our standards for sportsmanship, equality and fair play are met in the future."
Predictably, Ball would not let Adidas have the last word, reasserting his claim that officials are targeting him.
"Of course I'm being unfairly targeted, but it's OK. Why wouldn't I be?" Ball said on "Mornings with Keyshawn, Jorge and LZ" on ESPN LA 710. "They say I got a big mouth anyway. They say we bad as heck. Of course you want to try to quiet me up. That's the way I've been coaching all the time. It's just entertainment. Instead of going to the movies, people are coming to the AAU game to watch a game."
Ball continued his rant when speaking to USA Today following the match, criticising the female referee for her appearance and refereeing ability.
"She's a woman who's trying to act," Ball said. "I get that she's trying to break into the referee thing. But giving techs and calling fouls, that's no way to do it.
"If you're going to be qualified, you better be in sharpen abd you better know the game.
"And she's bad on both of them. She's not in shape, she's not calling the game right, and she don't understand, now she's trying to make a name for herself."
In the aftermath of the game, Court Club Elite - the company that supplied the tournament's refs - terminated its deal with Adidas.
And for anyone who thought Adidas originally was siding with Ball for a potential shoe deal with Lonzo, the newest Lakers hope, this statement should quell that speculation.
Ball's behaviour has also been condemned by the NBA referees, who took to social media to slam LaVar.
"This appalling story about the female referee removed during an AAU game warrants serious discussion," the NBA referees account tweeted.

2/ First, the misogynistic comments and intimidation by the coach have no place in basketball - or anywhere.

3/ The actions by Adidas show what happens when an organization does not support those tasked with protecting the integrity of the game.
The same account also called out Adidas for removing the referee following Ball's complaints, but retracted their comments after the brand apologised.
"We appreciate Adidas apologising and acknowledging the "wrong decision" made be removing the referee last week," they tweeted.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN LA 710</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Court Club Elite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jorge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaVar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonzo Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaVar Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA TODAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonzo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adidas</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keyshawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
