<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404196649837113</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/accounting/paranoid-pwc-chief-executive-luke-sayers-boosts-revenue-figures-20170731-gxmdlq</url>
  <title>'Paranoid' PwC chief executive Luke Sayers boosts revenue figures</title>
  <content>
PwC's focus upon building the "greatest depth and breadth" of service offerings of any firm in Australia, and paranoia about competitors, has helped it boost revenue and partner numbers, according to CEO Luke Sayers.
In an annual trading update, PwC, one of the big four accounting and consulting firms, grew revenue by 10.4 per cent to $2.12 billion in the year to June 30.
"I put the growth to [our] greater relevance in the market, which is attributed by our wonderful depth and breadth of people," Mr Sayers said.
"We see ourselves as uniquely positioned as there is no other professional services firm in Australia that has the depth and breadth of capability we do."

He also said that the firm watched what competitors did in the market.

"We are paranoid about all competitors. Our traditional competitors are strong and challenging us each and every different day," he said, adding "we don't rest on our laurels for one second. We continue to play the leadership role that we are very grateful to have today."
He added that he had greatest respect for rivals - citing rival big four outfits Deloitte, EY and KPMG, strategy houses the Boston Consulting Group and McKinsey, and technology consultancy Accenture.
The firm is a partnership and, like its big four peers, does not break out figures beyond revenue. This makes it difficult to ascertain its underlying financial performance. Asked about profitability, Mr Sayers said the firm has had "good profit growth over the last 12 months, but that's all I'll give you".
Solar project

He revealed "chargebacks" or "disbursements", expenses incurred as part of their advisory work that is passed on to clients at cost, made up between 5 per cent and 10 per cent of fee income, a similar level to  and the .
In June, .
Mr Sayers highlighted the firm's growing legal, ,  as all contributing to the final result.
He declined to break out the proportion of revenue within the various service lines but did reveal PwC's legal service, which has 23 partners and 105 lawyers, grew revenue by 68 per cent into the "tens of millions".

He also highlighted the firm's work on the Bungala Solar project, where the firm did work across areas including legal, advisory, tax, risk and governance, as an example of the future of consulting. The project, which had fees at risk, had generated "multiples of millions" in fees across multiple years for PwC, he said.
PwC revealed in June that it had appointed . Of the new partners about 40 per cent, or 36, are women. The firm now has 620 partners, up from 553 last year, with 24 partners leaving during 2016-17. Women make up 24 per cent, or 149 partners, of the firm's total 620 equity and salary partners.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston Consulting Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Luke Sayers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sayers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PwC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Accenture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bungala Solar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPMG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Sayers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
