<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404325498858340</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/mouthing-off--why-children-dont-need-to-be-on-tv-20170731-gxma4s.html</url>
  <title>Mouthing off ... Why children don't need to be on TV</title>
  <content>
I have sympathy for the commercial networks in their desire to be relieved of the requirement to produce children's programming. It is an onerous obligation, and the money spent on editing scripts to be as uninteresting and banal as possible could definitely be better deployed elsewhere. But the call to have less TV for kids is obscuring a much more urgent need: the need to have less TV with kids.
Let's be honest: children don't need to be on TV. How many shows can you name that became better after a child joined the cast? Whenever a TV character falls pregnant, all discerning viewers feel a chill run down their spine, because they know things are going to get irritating. Not that a baby is so bad: they don't need to be given lines. Once a child is old enough to talk, though, everything goes to hell. Remember how Full House was the worst show you've ever seen, but as the Olsen twins aged, it somehow got worse?
The amazing thing is the way TV keeps trying to cram kids down our throats. Shane Jacobson's Little Big Shots was mercifully held over so as not to run up against Australian Ninja Warrior - a proper TV show about real people confronting real problems, including weird-shaped walls - but it was a temporary stay of execution.
Little Big Shots is coming, bringing an avalanche of nauseating "cuteness" as it strives to convince us that children have talent. But they don't. They only seem to have talent when allowance is made for the fact that they are not people yet. And until they are people, they shouldn't be allowed on TV.
A minimum age of 16 should be legislated with all possible speed, before we have to suffer any more of the juvenile plague destroying our viewing experience.
Ben Pobjie is a comedian and satirist.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Shot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Pobjie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Jacobson's Little Big Shots</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Full House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
