<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404282549184452</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/01/08/39/cop-handbrake-skid-uk</url>
  <title>UK cop arrives to investigate disturbance in epic fashion</title>
  <content>
Urgency when it comes to police responding to a situation is usually a good thing - but the way this UK cop arrived at a disturbance has been criticised for endangering lives.
The officer's arrival on a busy residential street in Gillingham, Kent was captured on an iPhone - with the police car hurtling down the street before skidding and spinning 180 degrees.
The video, which was posted on Facebook after being shot in Canterbury Street on July 30, begins with police responding to a disturbance, with two officers seen speaking to those involved.
Sirens can then be heard before the police car snaps into view, complete with blue flashing lights.
As the car comes to a rest, startled onlookers can be heard, with one man shouting: "What the f--k is that about? Do you want to kill people?"
Kent Police have tweeted to confirm the incident was under investigation.
A spokesperson told Kent Online: "Kent Police was called at 3.03am on Sunday 30 July to Canterbury Street in Gillingham following reports of a disturbance. Patrols attended and officers called for assistance".

Related Articles

"A police patrol vehicle attending the urgent call skidded on the wet road whilst it was coming to a halt and it was involved in a minor collision with some railings. Nobody was injured as a result of the collision.
"Two men were arrested following the disturbance and have since been released without charge.
"As with any collision involving a police vehicle, an investigation will be carried out to establish the circumstances."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kent Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillingham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday 30 July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kent Online</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
