<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404239599510717</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/venezuela-maduro-a-dictator-after-vote-white-house-says/8762162</url>
  <title>US hits Venezuelan 'dictator' Nicolas Maduro with sanctions after 'sham election'</title>
  <content>
The White House says Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro is now effectively a dictator after "seizing absolute power" through what Washington said was a "sham election" of the country's National Constituent Assembly.

Key points:

Sanctions freeze any US assets of Nicolas Maduro
Monetary impact of sanctions unclear
US warns of further sanctions against Maduro allies

"Maduro is not just a bad leader. He is now a dictator," national security adviser HR McMaster said.
"Recent actions culminating in yesterday's seizure of absolute power through the sham election of the National Constituent Assembly represent a very serious blow to democracy in our hemisphere."
The Trump administration announced financial sanctions would be imposed on Mr Maduro.
The sanctions freeze any assets Mr Maduro may have in US jurisdictions and bar Americans from doing business with him.
"By sanctioning Maduro, the United States makes clear our opposition to the policies of his regime and our support for the people of Venezuela who seek to return their country to a full and prosperous democracy," Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin said.
The monetary impact of the sanctions was not immediately clear as Mr Maduro's holdings in US jurisdictions, if he has any, were not publicised.
However, imposing sanctions on a head of state is rare and can be symbolically powerful, leading other countries to similarly shun such a leader.
Monday's move follows through on a US threat of action last week against Mr Maduro and his socialist Government if they went ahead with Sunday's election.
Mr Mnuchin warned of further US penalties against Maduro allies.
"Anyone who participates in this illegitimate [constituent assembly] could be exposed to future US sanctions for their role in undermining democratic processes and institutions in Venezuela," he said.
Election was a power grab: opposition

Officials had said the sanctions could target Venezuela's oil sector, including possibly its state-owned petroleum company.
But after the announcement, an official said Mr Trump's administration held off on sector sanctions due to possible complications, including some involving subsidiaries.
The assembly will draw up a new constitution that many believe is aimed only at securing Mr Maduro's increasingly authoritarian rule.
Venezuela's opposition calls it a power grab.
Anti-government demonstrators barricaded streets on Monday and promised a fresh wave of protests.
The Government said the election had given it a popular mandate to dramatically recast the political system, despite widespread claims of low voter turnout.
"The people have delivered the constitutional assembly," Mr Maduro said on national television.
"More than 8 million in the middle of threats ... it's when imperialism challenges us that we prove ourselves worthy of the blood of the liberators that runs through the veins of men, women, children and young people."
Reuters/AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Maduro</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR McMaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mnuchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Constituent Assembly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters/AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
