<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403762858132545</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/06/46/rogue-liberal-mps-reignite-push-for-marriage-equality</url>
  <title>Rogue Liberal MPs reignite push for marriage equality</title>
  <content>
Same-sex-marriage could be legislated within weeks as more Liberal MPs abandon Malcolm Turnbull's plebiscite promise.

Five Liberal MPs including openly gay Brisbane politician Trevor Evans have reignited the push to pass the reforms, which have been in limbo since the prime minister's costly "people's vote" was rejected by parliament last year.

The push has incited ire from within the Liberal ranks as conservatives maintain their commitment for a plebiscite.

reports the new push for a conscience vote is an attempt to put the issues of marriage equality to rest once and for all, after the prime minister received a wave of support from the general population.

Liberal backbenchers that expressed their willingness to cross the floor on the divisive issue include Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson, Warren Entsch, Trent Zimmerman and Jason Wood.

A private member's bill drafted by Western Australian Senator Dean Smith is expected to have bipartisan support from Labor and the Greens.

Yesterday Mr Turnbull said that Liberal backbenchers "had the right to cross the floor".

Related Articles

"It's always been a fundamental principle in the Liberal Party, and indeed the National Party. So it's a very different political culture to the very authoritarian and centrally controlled culture of the Labor Party," the PM said.

Liberal MP Craig Kelly, Queensland Nationals Senator Barry O'Sullivan, Tasmanian senator Eric Abetz and Victorian MP Kevin Andrews have condemned the rogue backbenchers' actions saying it undermines Mr Turnbull's election promise to hold a plebiscite on marriage equality.

Senator O'Sullivan warned a breaking of the ranks and a conscience vote would destroy any hope of the Coalition being re-elected, News Corp reports.

MPs in favour of a free vote on marriage equality would be able to secure at least 76 of the 150 votes in House of Representatives to amend the Marriage Act.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Nationals Senator Barry O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian MP Kevin Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP Craig Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rogue Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
