<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404200944804547</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/hunter-angry-animals-dumped-near-darwin-airport/news-story/fc5eb15462828860380de7e53525ff07</url>
  <title>Dead animals dumped near Darwin roadside</title>
  <content>
A TERRITORY hunter was disgusted to find the mutilated bodies of wild pigs dumped on a track off Osgood Drive near Darwin airport.
Millner resident Norm Allan was out on a bike ride last Tuesday night when he spotted the three discarded pig carcasses. It's not the first time Mr Allan has found dead animals in the area - but he wants it to be the last.
"A lot of people do a lot of dumping there - there's a 'no dumping' sign about 10m away," he said.
"If you're going to go out and hunt be prepared and dispose of what's left correctly so you're not spoiling it for the rest of us doing the right thing." Mr Allan said the legs of the pigs were removed but the bodies were left behind.
When he stumbled across them, Mr Allan said the pigs had attracted flies and were riddled with maggots.
"Apart from the disease factor, you're bringing it into suburbia - it's not far from homes," he said.
Mr Allan is urging hunters to dispose of animals properly.
"When you're out there you bury the bodies - or take the meat and burn the carcasses," he said. "We're very lucky to be able to do it (hunting)."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norm Allan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Osgood Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Allan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
