<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403771448067341</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/brisbane-couple-sell-dream-home-after-an-offer-too-good-to-refuse/news-story/11b5ba14436d01fbaed6a2f771768006</url>
  <title>Brisbane couple sell dream home after an offer too good to refuse - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
This home at 22 Voyagers Ct, Raby Bay, has sold for $4.08m. Picture supplied by LJ Hooker Cleveland.

A BRISBANE couple will leave their dream home with little more than their clothing after reluctantly selling their brand new house - and everything in it - in an offmarket deal worth more than $4 million.
Owner-builder Glenn Bolger and his wife Toni had barely finished building their amazing property at 22 Voyagers Court, Raby Bay, when a local resident in the area made them an offer too good to refuse.

This property at 22 Voyagers Court, Raby Bay, has sold for $4.08 million. Picture supplied by LJ Hooker Cleveland.

Mr Bolger, who owns CastleGlenn Homes, said he initially told the buyer the home wasn't for sale.
"We've only been in it for two months - if that," he said.
"The guy came along and said 'look, I'll give you this' and I said 'well that's too good to knock back'.
"I'd be silly not to take it."

One of the bedrooms at 22 Voyagers Court, Raby Bay. Picture supplied by LJ Hooker Cleveland.

The house was sold within three days but Mr Bolger negotiated a 90 day settlement so he and his wife could at least enjoy the fruits of their labour for a few months.
The $4.08 million transaction marks the biggest sale of a home on less than 1000 sqm in the Raby Bay and Cleveland area.

The outlook from 22 Voyagers Court, Raby Bay. Picture supplied by LJ Hooker Cleveland.

Mr Bolger said he had poured "blood, sweat and tears" into the home, which is being entered in the HIA-CSR Australian Housing Awards.
The home was completely custom designed for the Bolgers, with the highest quality features and modern conveniences.
It features a gym, spa, pool, built-in wine cellar and theatre room.

One of the bathrooms at 22 Voyagers Court, Raby Bay. Picture supplied by LJ Hooker Cleveland.

The house is on an 847 sqm block, which is east-west facing, but the house was designed to accommodate the views to the north.
Mr Bolger said his wife played a large role in designing and decorating the home, down to having the cushions made individually to suit the personalised decor.
The couple also own a number of one-off pieces of furniture.

The theatre room at 22 Voyagers Court, Raby Bay. Picture supplied by LJ Hooker Cleveland.

Most of the furniture will be sold with the house.

"I'm just grabbing my smalls and I'm out of there," Mr Bolger joked.
"(The buyer) wants the lot."

Aerial view of 22 Voyagers Court, Raby Bay. Picture supplied by LJ Hooker Cleveland.

The Bolgers bought the original property for $1.4 million in April 2015.
The existing Tudor house on the site was removed and the 1900 sqm block was split in two to make way for two new homes.
Jade Hale and Karen Renouf of LJ Hooker Cleveland negotiated the offmarket sale of 22 Voyagers Court.

The wine cellar at 22 Voyagers Court, Raby Bay. Picture supplied by LJ Hooker Cleveland.

Ms Renouf said the area had been experiencing some strong buying and selling activity.
The house next door at 24 Voyagers Court is on the market for $3.5 million and another property around the corner at number 23-25 also for sale for $3.49 million.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tudor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CastleGlenn Homes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LJ Hooker Cleveland</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voyagers Ct</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voyagers Court</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jade Hale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raby Bay</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIA-CSR Australian Housing Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bolger</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Bolger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Renouf of LJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Renouf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooker Cleveland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
