<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404411398205941</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/thousands-of-queenslanders-are-at-risk-of-defaulting-on-home-loans/news-story/b3b2343785dd7ecdc9eddf73f2d57d35</url>
  <title>Thousands of Queenslanders are at risk of defaulting on home loans - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
New figures show a small rise in interest rates could force thousands of Queenslanders to default on home loans.

EVEN a small rise in interest rates would put more than 10,000 Queensland households at risk of defaulting on their home loans.
Ahead of the Reserve Bank of Australia's board meeting today, figures reveal more than 144,000 homeowners in the state are in mortgage stress and about one in five are close to default.
Just a 0.5 per cent increase would throw more than 150,000 Queensland homeowners into stress and 10,191 would be close to being forced to default or sell up, according to analysis by Digital Finance Analytics.

The Reserve Bank of Australia is expected to leave interest rates on hold in August. Picture: AAP/Dean Lewins

Increasing rates by 2 per cent would put more than 12,200 people at risk of losing their homes.
The areas most at risk are in Brisbane's north and south, Redbank, Wide Bay-Burnett region, Darling Downs and Mackay.
Across the nation, a quarter of households, or more than 820,000, are estimated to be in mortgage stress, which is up from 810,000 in July.
Nearly 53,000 households across the country risk default in the next 12 months.
Digital Finance Analytics principal Martin North said flat incomes and underemployment meant rising costs were not managed by many homeowners.
"Despite the record low cash rate, many households are only just managing to pay the bills, and rising power and childcare costs are making this more challenging," Mr North said.
"We are on a knife edge, and even small lifts in rates will have a significant impact."

More households are in mortgage stress, according to Digital Finance Analytics.

The RBA is expected to leave interest rates on hold when it meets today, with all 35 economists and experts interviewed by finder.com.au predicting the cash rate will stay at 1.5 per cent in August.
Those surveyed believe household debt, wage growth and the high Australian dollar are the greatest concerns for the central bank.

Finder.com.au insights manager Graham Cooke said a rate rise was likely early next year.
"It looks as though April and May next year may be the most likely months a rate cut will be enforced," he said.
"If the economy continues to stabilise, we can expect to see more rate rises throughout 2018."​
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Cooke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/Dean Lewins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance Analytics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wide Bay-Burnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Digital Finance Analytics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
