<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404286844151832</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/09/00/200-young-people-employed-from-internships</url>
  <title>200 young people employed from internships</title>
  <content>
In the first four months of the federal government's much-hyped youth jobs program, just 200 young Australians have secured full-time work.
But the government is adamant those numbers will shoot up, with thousands more working their way through the three steps of the prepare-trial-hire (PaTH) scheme.
The program seeks to encourage jobseekers under 25 to take part in 4-12 week internships by paying them $200 a fortnight on top of dole payments and giving employers $1000 upfront.
If a full-time job comes out of the internship, the government will give the business up to $10,000 in wage subsidies.
Since the program began on April 1, just more than 1000 young people have started internships and 200 have ongoing jobs, Employment Minister Michaelia Cash says.
Another almost 7000 have started preparatory training.
"The fact that to date, in a very short period of time, we've got 200 kids off welfare and into work should never be underestimated," Senator Cash told ABC radio on Tuesday.

Related Articles

The government aims to have up 30,000 internships a year in the program.
It has just signed a deal with the Australian Hotels Association for 10,000 placements over four years.
In the program's first two months, 582 internships were advertised and 185 young people hosted, department officials told a Senate estimates committee.
The program has come under fire from Labor, the Greens and trade unions for in effect allowing young people to be paid as little as $7.60 an hour with no guarantee of ongoing work.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Michaelia Cash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Hotels Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Cash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
