<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404196649837161</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/cochlear-ceo-chris-smiths-early-exit-blamed-on-longhaul-travel-20170731-gxmaj2</url>
  <title>Cochlear CEO Chris Smith's early exit blamed on long-haul travel </title>
  <content>
Cochlear chief executive Chris Smith's departure after just two years in the job follows a failed understanding that the Denver-based executive would move to Australia, chairman Rick Holliday-Smith said.
Cochlear cushioned the blow to investors by confirming its full year earnings guidance at $210 million-$225 million, up from $189 million in 2016. But news of Mr Smith's premature retirement wiped $130 million - about 1.6 per cent - off the hearing implant maker's $8.2 billion market value. Its shares fell $2.32 to $142.85.
Mr Holliday-Smith said he "was led to believe and it was important to me" that Mr Smith and his family "were committed to come to Australia" from Denver, Colorado, when Mr Smith was appointed to .
Mr Holliday-Smith said the board had been willing to allow Mr Smith and his family a reasonable transition but about nine months into his term it became clear "he was not coming". They began discussing the terms of his departure 10 to 12 weeks ago.

Ben Rushton

Howitt new CEO

The Macquarie University-based hearing implant maker told the ASX on Monday that Mr Smith will retire on January 2, 2018. He will be replaced by Dig Howitt, who became chief operating officer about a year ago.
Mr Holliday-Smith said it was Mr Smith's decision and that the constant travel entailed by trying to run an Australian multinational from Denver had taken its toll. "For my part I had expectations of a CEO. He fulfilled those expectations but the expectations required a lot of extra travel," Mr Holliday-Smith said.
Mr Smith was unavailable for comment. He is one of a small band of CEOs criss-crossing the oceans regularly at the helm of successful Australian-based multinationals.
, and spends much of his time in Australia and Europe. Building materials maker ,  and Treasury Wine Estates Mike Clarke spends much of the year in California.

Louie Douvis

'Uncomfortable period'

Mr Smith will receive $1.45 million extra pay in lieu of a 12-month notice period, as well as his normal pay at the rate of $1.6 million a year plus short-term incentives, which totalled $1.4 million for a full year in 2016. But he will not receive long-term incentives.
Mr Holliday-Smith said Mr Smith had attempted to run Cochlear, which has most of its sales outside of Australia, from his US home base but it had been "an uncomfortable period".
"To his credit he has done that for two years but he came and saw me a little while ago [and said] 'it's too hard and we need to have an end date' - what I call a retirement discussion," Mr Holliday-Smith said.

Wayne Taylor

Mr Smith's departure comes only a few months after new chief financial officer Brent Cubis took the reins from another Cochlear long-termer, Neville Mitchell.
Mr Howitt will earn $1.64 million base salary and short and long-term incentives worth up to $3.2 million and short-term incentives, giving total potential pay of $4.94 million.
Priorities remain

Mr Holliday-Smith said Cochlear's priorities of growing its core hearing implant and sound processor business and building a service business around that "remain our priorities". On July 13, Cochlear announced its first foray into , capital of China's Sichuan province.

Rachael Dere

Andy Gracey, portfolio manager at Australian Ethical Investments, said Cochlear was one of a handful of large ASX-listed companies with strong growth and it was "priced to perfection".
He said the sudden news of a chief executive's departure after just two years "makes you scratch your head" and is disappointing and puzzling coming so soon after the change of CFO.
But he said it would probably take an earnings setback to put a big dint in Cochlear's $8.2 billion market capitalisation, even though the company's shares are priced at a heady 37 times next year's earnings.
Issue is earnings

"Whether its [shares are] $144 or $160 this thing is still priced for perfection. But even when it's on that type of multiple the issue is not so much news of the CEO departing - it's around earnings and delivering," Mr Gracey said.
"Trading at 37 times next year's earnings you don't need much of a blip or a disappointment to see 20 per cent knocked off [the market value]. We have not had an earnings disappointment, you could say, but a CEO two years and one month in and he's leaving, and we have got to get used to a new CEO and his take on things might be different."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rushton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury Wine Estates Mike Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachael Dere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neville Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colorado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Sichuan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dig Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear's $8.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Holliday-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear's CEO Chris Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Cubis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie University-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Howitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Gracey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Holliday-Smith</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEOs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ethical Investments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cochlear</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gracey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
