<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404454347879720</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/southwest/silver-birthday-for-boomtown-no-one-wanted/news-story/4787dc8980f15409f26e7ea2a4545627</url>
  <title>Unwanted boom town turns 25</title>
  <content>
IT is hard to believe that more than 25 years ago, the vacant land that is now one of the fastest-growing regions in the state was largely regarded as worthless.
Greater Springfield celebrates its silver birthday this month.
"At the time any big company could have bought it for petty cash but no one wanted it," Greater Springfield founder and Springfield Land Corporation chairman Maha Sinnathamby remembered.
He said like a sculptor who could see a magnificent face in a slab of harsh rock, he saw "the face of a future city" in the 7000-acre site.
With business partner Bob Sharpless, Mr Sinnathamby created the blueprint for a masterplanned city built with health, education and technology at its core.
Greater Springfield now has 10 schools, a university, Orion Springfield Central shopping centre, the state headquarters of General Electric and Mater Private Hospital Springfield.
But Mr Sinnathamby said these achievements equated to only a tenth of its potential.
Looking to the future, he saw energy solutions and technology advances as vital to supporting further growth.
Short term, he hoped that would include the construction of a sports arena to house the Brisbane Lions; and long term the successful integration of the 10,000 apartment Garden City development.
But as it was on day one of planning, his vision today holds steadfast on the importance of health and education.
"Expansions to our Education and Health Cities precincts are well and truly in the pipeline and that will generate not just amazing learning opportunities but thousands of jobs," he said.
"It's a great privilege to do what we are doing.
"It's hard work and it takes an around-the-clock commitment to long-term results."
MILESTONES:
1992 - Bushland bought for $7.9m by Maha Sinnathamby and Bob Sharpless.
1998 - Woodcrest State College (formerly Springfield State School) and Springfield Anglican College open.
February 2006 - Classes begin at University of Southern Queensland Springfield.
March 2007 - Orion Springfield Central opens.
2010 - Greater Springfield receives FIABCI Prix D'Excellence award for world's best masterplanned community.
December 2013 - Trains come to Springfield with two stations opened.
September 2015 - Orion Lagoon officially opens.
October 2015 - Mater Private Hospital Springfield welcomes its first patients.
June 2017 - $1b Aveo Springfield retirement village opens first stage of development.
July 2017 -  announced for Orion Springfield Central
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Southern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Cities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orion Springfield Central</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017 - $1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maha Sinnathamby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springfield Anglican College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sinnathamby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2006</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Sharpless</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springfield State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springfield</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIABCI Prix D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Springfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodcrest State College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Electric</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orion Lagoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Springfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aveo Springfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mater Private Hospital Springfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springfield Land Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garden City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
