<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404505887488040</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/world/anthony-scaramucci-listed-as-dead-in-the-new-harvard-law-alumni-directory-20170731-gxmnti.html</url>
  <title>Anthony Scaramucci listed as 'dead' in the new Harvard Law alumni directory</title>
  <content>
Washington: Pity poor Anthony Scaramucci: reportedly getting divorced, sacked from his job after a mere 10 days - and now there's an erroneous report that he's dead.
The blink-and-you-missed him former White House communications director is listed as deceased in the new Harvard Law School alumni directory, which arrived in alums' mailboxes the very week that "The Mooch" became the most talked-about guy in all of politics.

Up Next

Deadly protests mar Venezuelan election outcome

01:38

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Trump removes Scaramucci

US President Donald Trump's communications director, Anthony Scaramucci, is out after just ten days on the job, the White House said on Monday.

An asterisk by the 1989 graduate's name indicates that he was reported dead since the last directory, which was published in 2011.
Unclear whether he was the victim of a prank - or just a typo. Harvard Law didn't say, but the school was apparently crimson-faced over the flub.

"Regrettably, there is an error in the Harvard Law School alumni directory in the listing for Anthony Scaramucci," a spokeswoman told us in an emailed statement.
"We offer our sincere apologies to Mr Scaramucci. The error will be corrected in subsequent editions."

Scaramucci did not immediately respond to a call seeking comment, but in fairness, his Monday afternoon had been a tad eventful.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

He might be dead to Harvard Law, but in his oh-so-brief tenure as President Donald Trump's top spokesman, Scaramucci, 53, had often name-dropped the prestigious school.Photo: AP
He told CNN's Jake Tapper he wouldn't have attended the now-infamous meeting with Russians claiming to have dirt on Hillary Clinton because of his law degree. Later in the same interview, he boasted about getting an A-minus in Harvard Law professor Laurence Tribe's constitutional law class.
Washington Post
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard Law School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurence Tribe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci, 53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN's Jake Tapper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard Law</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
