<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404548837161811</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/cruise-passengers-roll-in-to-mark-coasts-50th/3207336/</url>
  <title>Cruise passengers roll in to mark Coast's 50th</title>
  <content>
THE Sunshine Coast has officially turned 50 today with a number of events planned across the region to celebrate the milestone.
They started at Mooloolaba Wharf with the welcoming of about 1800 cruise ship passengers who stepped off P&O's Pacific Jewel for the day.
Sunshine Coast Councillor John Connolly and a team of representatives from the council and tourism bodies welcomed the visitors with birthday cake and Coast-branded paraphernalia.
Sydney visitor Carole Brown appreciated the welcome and wished the region a happy birthday.
"We've never been here before so it is exciting to come to see the place," Ms Brown said.
She brought her daughter Melanie and grandson Jackson with her.
"I know it is the 50th birthday so congratulations."
Cr Jason O'Pray will also host a morning tea to celebrate the 50th anniversary with community groups at Suncare Community Centre Hall in Maroochydore.
Cr Connolly said it was great to welcome visitors to the region while marking 50 years since it was named.
"We're happy to be sharing celebrations with P&O guests and hope they enjoy the community activities organised for their visit," Cr Connolly said.
This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Noosa is mourning the loss of bright, bubbly mother Sharon Cuthbert
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Wharf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carole Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Councillor John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast-branded</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncare Community Centre Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Jason O'Pray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Connolly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melanie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O's Pacific Jewel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
