<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404462937814487</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>ABN Newswire</source>
  <url>http://www.abnnewswire.net/press/en/89395/Mithril-Resources-Limited-(ASX-MTH)-Drilling-results-reinforce-Nanadie-Well-copper-potential-89395.html</url>
  <title>Mithril Resources Limited (ASX:MTH) Drilling results reinforce Nanadie Well copper potential</title>
  <content>
Adelaide, Aug 1, 2017 AEST (ABN Newswire) - Mithril Resources Ltd (ASX:MTH) is pleased to advise positive assay results have been received from diamond drilling recently carried out at the Nanadie Well Deposit and adjacent Stark Prospect which are both located on the Company's  Murchison Project located 80 kms SE of Meekatharra, Western Australia.
Drilling results reinforce Nanadie Well copper potential
- Drill hole within central portion of the Nanadie Well Copper Deposit returns:
o 4.90m @ 1.80% copper, 0.25g/t gold, within a broader intercept of 127.75m @ 0.40% copper, 0.11g/t gold
- Southernmost drillhole at the Stark Copper Prospect returns:
o 5.40m @ 1.25% copper, 0.26% nickel, 1.21g/t gold + platinum + palladium ("3PGE's") within a broader intercept of 30.40m @ 0.52% copper, 0.13% nickel, 0.36g/t 3PGE's
- Latest drilling in combination with previous results demonstrates the presence of two very large copper mineralised systems that remain open in all directions
- 13 kilometres of untested magnetic anomalies extending south from Nanadie Well and Stark to be focus of future exploration
Three holes (NDD17001 - 003 / 656.7 metres) were drilled to confirm previous mineralised intercepts and better understand the geological setting of the deposit and test the significance of new bedrock EM conductors ("M1" and "M3") at
Stark.
At Nanadie Well, NDD17001 was drilled within the central portion of the deposit and intersected a broad zone of copper - gold mineralisation. This is the first diamond drillhole into the deposit and confirmed the mineralisation is hosted within  a structurally - deformed sequence of mafic intrusive rocks (gabbro and amphibolite), assaying of which returned (downhole widths - Figure 2);
- 4.90m @ 1.80% copper, 0.25g/t gold from 88.40 metres, within a broader intercept of 127.75m @ 0.40% copper, 0.11g/t gold from 42.80 metres
At Stark, NDD17002 was drilled at the southern end of the prospect to test the M1 EM conductor and intersected a zone of copper - nickel mineralisation at the modelled conductor depth. Assays returned (downhole widths - Figures 3 and 4);
- 5.40m @ 1.25% copper, 0.26% nickel, 1.21g/t (gold + platinum + palladium "3PGE's") from 257.70 metres within a broader intercept of 30.40m @ 0.52% copper, 0.13% nickel, 0.36g/t 3PGE's from 248.50 metres.
NDD17003 was drilled at the northern end of Stark to test the M3 EM conductor and intersected a zone of copper - nickel mineralisation at the modelled conductor depth. Assays returned (downhole widths);
- 10.70m @ 0.41% copper, 0.09% nickel, 0.28g/t 3PGE's from 92.00 metres.
Management discussion and regional exploration targets
The diamond drillhole at Nanadie Well has provided critical geological information about the deposit and also a context to the previous mineralised intercepts and untested targets identified along strike to the deposit.
At Stark, by intersecting further mineralisation south of that previously identified, the diamond drilling clearly demonstrates the presence of a very large copper mineralised system that remains open in all directions.
The new geological knowledge this drilling has provided will underpin future exploration throughout the project area.
Recent interpretation of newly reprocessed aeromagnetic data has identified a series of discrete linear magnetic features (that are spatially associated with existing mineralisation at both Nanadie Well and Stark) that extend for 13 kilometres along strike to the south from Nanadie Well and Stark under a thin soil veneer (Figure 5).
These southern magnetic features have not been previously explored and are compelling targets that will be a priority for Mithril's ongoing exploration within the Murchison Project.
Table 1 drillhole specifications and significant Intercepts are in the link below.
About the Nanadie Well Copper Deposit and Stark Copper Prospect
The Nanadie Well Copper Deposit and Stark Copper Prospect lie within Mithril's Murchison Project (500 km2 area and located 80 kms SE of Meekatharra, WA) which covers a NW trending belt of Archaen mafic and metasedimentary units with demonstrated prospectivity for both magmatic copper - nickel - PGE mineralisation and lode - gold mineralisation.
The project also contains the Fenceline Gold Prospect.
Intermin Resources Limited (ASX:IRC) estimated a 2004 JORC Code Compliant Inferred Resource for the Nanadie Well Copper Deposit in September 2013 (see Intermin's ASX Announcement "Initial Resource Estimate for the Nanadie Well Cu-Au Project" dated 19 September 2013).
Nanadie Well Inferred Resource
2004 JORC Code Tonnes (Mt)  Cu%  Au ppm  Contained Cu (t)  Contained Au (oz)
Inferred         36.07     0.42   0.064    151,506            74,233

The information pertaining to the Nanadie Well Copper Deposit Inferred Resource was prepared and first disclosed by Intermin under the JORC Code 2004. It has not been updated since to comply with the JORC Code 2012 on the basis that the information has not materially changed since it was last reported.
The Inferred Resource is within a few meters of the surface and has been defined over 1 kilometre strike length, 50 - 150 metres (true width) and to a maximum depth of 220. The deposit remains open in all directions and lies within a broader 2 kilometres long mineralised zone that has been identified by wide spaced reconnaissance drilling.
Nanadie Well's prospectivity is enhanced by the Stark Copper Prospect which lies within a parallel mineralised belt 1,000 metres east. At Stark, massive copper - nickel sulphide mineralisation lies within a poorly constrained south - plunging "shoot" that has been drilled down to 250 metres (vertical) beneath a zone of surface mineralisation.
At Fenceline, a zone of sub-cropping ferruginous and brecciated quartz veining has been mapped and sampled over approximately 120 metres strike length with rock chip results ranging from 0.43 g/t gold to 8.22g/t gold. The zone which has never been drilled has an estimated surface width of up to 5 metres and remains open along strike, to the south east where it passes under an area of alluvial sheet wash and drainage.
The Nanadie Well Deposit and Stark lie on tenements subject to a Farmin and Joint Venture Agreement (Nanadie Well Joint Venture) with Intermin Resources Limited (ASX:IRC). Under the terms of the joint venture, Mithril can earn a 60% interest in the tenements by completing expenditure of $2M by 14 April 2019, and an additional 15% by completing further expenditure of $2M over a further 2 years.
The Fenceline Gold Prospect and southern magnetic targets referred to in this Report lie on tenements 100% - owned by Mithril Resources.
To view tables and figures, please visit:

About Intermin Resources Limited
() is a gold exploration and mining company focussed on the Kalgoorlie and Menzies areas of Western Australia which are host to some of Australia's richest gold deposits. The Company is developing a mining pipeline of projects to generate cash and self-fund aggressive exploration, mine developments and further acquisitions. The Teal Stage 1 gold mine is currently in production.

Intermin is aiming to significantly grow its JORC-Compliant Mineral Resources, complete definitive feasibility studies on core projects and build a sustainable development pipeline.

Intermin is targeting the definition of significant high grade open cut and underground gold deposits, has acquired highly prospective tenure and will continue to actively pursue consolidation and value-adding joint venture opportunities for the benefit of all stakeholders.

 

About Mithril Resources Limited
() is an Australian resources company whose objective is the creation of shareholder wealth through the discovery and development of mineral deposits.

The Company is actively exploring throughout two highly prospective areas of the Western Australian Goldfields, namely the Kalgoorlie District for gold and nickel deposits and the Meekatharra District for copper-nickel deposits.

The Company is also exploring South Australia's far western Coompana Province for magmatic nickel - copper deposits with OZ Minerals Limited.

  

Related Companies
     

Social Media
Share this Article

ABN Newswire
This Page Viewed:  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archaen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian Goldfields</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murchison Project</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MTH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JORC Code Compliant Inferred Resource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanadie Well Inferred Resource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M1 EM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanadie Well</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inferred Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IRC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mithril Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OZ Minerals Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stark Prospect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NDD17003</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NDD17002</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NDD17001</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 1, 2017 AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SE of Meekatharra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meekatharra District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN Newswire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanadie Well Cu-Au Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coompana Province</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanadie Well Copper Deposit</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teal Stage 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M3 EM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JORC Code 2004</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JORC Code (2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PGE</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intermin Resources Limited</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mithril's Murchison Project (500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mithril Resources Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fenceline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanadie Well Deposit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2013</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mithril Resources Limited</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intermin's ASX Announcement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mithril</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stark Copper Prospect</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resource Estimate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Page Viewed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanadie Well Joint Venture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intermin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JORC Code Tonnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanadie Well Copper Deposit Inferred Resource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fenceline Gold Prospect</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JORC-Compliant Mineral Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Figures 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Figure 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Figure 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NDD17001 - 003 / 656.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Contained Cu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Contained Au</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Venture Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
