<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404458642847116</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/health/2017/08/01/09/42/australians-concerned-about-blood-cancers</url>
  <title>Australians concerned about blood cancers</title>
  <content>
With 35 new cases diagnosed every day more Australians than ever are turning to Dr Google for information on blood cancers.
Research has revealed a spike in online searches for 'leukaemia', 'lymphoma' and 'myeloma'.
The data reflects a "troubling" increase in the number of blood cancer diagnoses and related deaths in Australia and a need for greater patient support, says The Leukaemia Foundation CEO Bill Petch.
Analysis of search traffic conducted by the cancer charity found there were an average of 56,842 searches per month in 2016-17.
It's a 44 per cent increase on the average 39,547 monthly searches in 2013-14.
In March this year alone, there were over 69,600 searches nationally - a four-year monthly high.
The number of Australians diagnosed with blood cancer has also increased.
According to The Leukaemia Foundation, 35 people are diagnosed every day, up from 31 people just four years ago.
While the cause for the increase in online searches is unclear, Mr Petch says the data raises concern that the country's "60,000-strong blood cancer community" is in need of greater support.
"This new data paints a troubling picture about the growing problem of blood cancer," Mr Petch said.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Petch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leukaemia Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leukaemia Foundation CEO Bill Petch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
