<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404540247227045</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/north/builder-glenn-savage-to-sell-triplestorey-home-with-private-road-access/news-story/2029d5ddeb830a48f0f71f970a17e90e</url>
  <title>Builder Glenn Savage to sell triple-storey home with private road access - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
868 Samford Road, Mitchelton.

Brisbane builder Glenn Savage is selling his stunning masterpiece after seven years.
His home at , feels somewhat empty at the moment with only he and his partner living there.
Mr Savage, who runs Glenn Savage Building Services, is selling the five-bedroom, four-bathroom home to retire and move to the coast.
"This home is far too big for just the two of us," Mr Savage said.
"With the three levels, it's actually ideal for two families."

868 Samford Road, Mitchelton.

Mr Savage said he would love to see another family buy the home.
He said standout features of the property included the 180 degree views to the city and out to Moreton Bay.
"We can see the cruise ships leave at 3pm on a Saturday afternoon," Mr Savage said.
"We really love sitting on the back deck in summer with a beer," he chuckled.
"In the winter we pull the shades down and enjoy the fire."

868 Samford Road, Mitchelton.

868 Samford Road, Mitchelton.

Mr Savage, who enjoys swimming, said he loved the saltwater swimming pool and so do his family when they visit.
He said the main reason for buying the land was the access to a private road.
The home features guest quarters which could be perfect for friends, family or visitors who need a place to sleep.

868 Samford Road, Mitchelton.

The private guest quarters has a huge bedroom with an ensuite and walk-in robe.
Mr Savage said his family had enjoyed many gatherings at his home over the years.
"My daughter loves to have pre-drinks here with her friends before going out," he said.
He said once the front door to the home was closed it was an extremely quiet property.
"You can't hear a thing outside," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Savage</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samford Road</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Savage Building Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Savage</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchelton</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
