<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404497297553324</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/berwick-arts-group-misses-out-on-funding-after-casey-councillors-redirect-money-to-berwick-business-group/news-story/0212526e71b9a2dc0795fe4dd18ab1df</url>
  <title>Business trumps art for Casey money</title>
  <content>
AN ARTS group wanting to hold 'Berwick's Greatest Art Show' has lost out on council funding to a business group.
In a last minute turnaround on July 18, councillors backed a push by Cr Tim Jackson for a $3000 grant officers had recommended for the Provenance Artists Inc art show to instead go to Berwick Business Group for Christmas in Berwick.
The move shocked Provenance Studio's Calvin Bell, who told Cranbourne Leader he thought Cr Jackson supported the arts.
He said the show, which was one of the best in Melbourne, would now have to be cut back.
"The business group are people who have money and we have none," he said.
The Berwick Business Group includes shops, banks, land development groups, real estate agents and restaurants.
Officers did not recommend he business group's application, saying the proposed Christmas activities did not score highly enough under the criteria for how well the project met the Casey's priorities or community needs.
"The Berwick Business Group hosted a wonderful Christmas event for the community and local business which I attended - this was attended by more than 2,500 people," Cr Jackson said.
"While it would be great to be able to fund every event and every community group, it just isn't feasible to do so.
"The only relationship I have with the Berwick Business group is through my professional work with the council and shopping at their local stores, I try to shop local where I can.
"Should more funds become available, I hope to be able to financially support the art group again."
Berwick Business group, co vice president Casey May said the Christmas festival would include 'ugly jumper' photos, Santa photos, market stalls, performances from local groups plus giveaways and sampling from Berwick businesses.
She said the festival would be a free event and tickets would go on sale later in the year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berwick Business Group</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Provenance Artists Inc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Tim Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berwick Business</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berwick's Greatest Art Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Provenance Studio's Calvin Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>santA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Jackson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
