<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404553132129172</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/rev-up-for-bras-and-bikes-charity-motorcycle-ride/3207112/</url>
  <title>Rev up for Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride</title>
  <content>
THE three-month countdown is on for the 2017 Bras and Bikes fundraising ride and now with their major sponsor on board, organisers are revving up for the big day.
Girl Torque group leader Judy Noakes last week received the sponsorship cheque from Col Clarke, owner of TourOz Trikes in Yandina.
Dressed appropriately for the occasion, Mr Clarke said he was delighted to be supporting the event, which is planned for October 29.
"TourOz Trikes is thrilled to be on board with Girl Torque to raise valuable funds for Bloomhill Cancer Care," Mr Clarke said.
"An event like this is a fantastic way to bring the community together and we hope it attracts hundreds of riders and support on the day."
TourOz Trikes offer tour rides around the Sunshine Coast hinterland as well as hire trikes and trikes for sale. The popular vehicles come in two and three seater versions.
Bras and Bikes is an annual fundraiser now in its 16th year. The event brings riders and pillions out in their hundreds with the requirement to wear a pink bra and create a colourful dedication to the cause, with all proceeds going towards Bloomhill Cancer Care in Buderim.
Ms Noakes said while Girl Torque was a women's riding association, there were certain exceptions in the annual calendar where "the blokes are allowed to join in" and Bras and Bikes was one.
Riders start and finish at the Yandina Bowls Club. Start time on the day is 7.30am, with a departure at 9.30am.
Registration is just $20 per bike and can be bought online at http://www.bloomhill. com.au/online-shop
This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Noosa is mourning the loss of bright, bubbly mother Sharon Cuthbert
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Thank Your Lucky Stars luncheon concert is coming to Eumundi
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Girl Torque</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy Noakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Noakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Col Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thank Your Lucky Stars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina Bowls Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Clarke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TourOz Trikes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eumundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomhill Cancer Care</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
