<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404540247227048</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/george-and-amal-clooney-to-open-schools-for-syrian-refugees-20170731-gxmpcc.html</url>
  <title>George and Amal Clooney to open schools for Syrian refugees </title>
  <content>
George and Amal Clooney may be busy with their twins Ella and Alexander, but parenting is definitely not keeping the pair away from their advocacy and philanthropic work. Yesterday, the Clooney Foundation for Justice announced plans to open seven public schools for Syrian refugees in Lebanon as part of a $2.25 million (A$2.81 million) partnership with UNICEF.
In conjunction with Google, computer company HP (who made a A$1.25 million technology grant) and UNICEF, the new initiative will help provide education to more than 3,000 refugees, in an attempt to prevent young people from becoming part of "a lost generation."Photo: Jordan Strauss
The schools are expected to open this year.
"Thousands of young Syrian refugees are at risk-the risk of never being a productive part of society," the couple wrote on their . 
"Formal education can help change that. That's our goal with this initiative. We don't want to lose an entire generation because they had the bad luck of being born in the wrong place at the wrong time."
In a statement given to , the pair highlighted the importance of education and leadership in giving children the opportunity to break out of cycles of "geography and circumstance," and also to push equality in other areas including health.

"Our goal with this initiative is to help provide Syrian refugee children with an education and put them on a path to be future leaders their generation desperately needs."
According to  there are currently around 200,000 Syrian children who are not receiving any form of education in Lebanon. UNICEF Executive Director Anthony Lake said the organisation was "deeply grateful for this critical funding."
"How can children become the workers and leaders of their countries someday if they have not had the education and support they need to reach their full potential?" he wrote in a
"By supporting the work of UNICEF and our partners to deliver education to every child affected by the conflict in Syria, the Clooney Foundation for Justice is not only investing in the futures of individual children, it is investing in the future of the entire region."
Taking on many UN cases in her work as an human rights and international law barrister, Amal last year represented ISIS survivor Nadia Murad on behalf of thousands of victims of Yazidi genocide. George also met Murad at the time.
"I think one of the ways to take action is to expose their brutality and their corruption, and partly you can do this through trials," she said to Vanity Fair.
"I met her, and just thought, 'I can't walk away."
The couple established the Clooney Foundation for Justice last year to support equity in courtrooms, classrooms and communities around the world.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanity Fair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yazidi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nadia Murad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebanon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Strauss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNICEF</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clooney Foundation</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNICEF Executive Director Anthony Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amal Clooney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
