<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404497297553306</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/thanks-for-like-saving-my-life-and-stuff-boy-overboard-reunited-with-rescuer-20170731-gxmpd7.html</url>
  <title>'Thanks for like saving my life and stuff': Boy overboard reunited with rescuer</title>
  <content>
An emotional reunion between the boy who spent two hours treading water after falling from his grandparents' yacht and his rescuer this was not.
"Thanks for, like, saving my life and stuff." 14-year-old Lochlan Brodie managed to say.Photo: Seven News
"No worries. No probs," boatie Steve Cartwright said, as Seven's Sunrise brought the pair back together.
Lochlan looked pretty relaxed as he recounted his terrifying experience, even as he said he saw a shark just a few metres away while battling to stay afloat off the coast of Queensland.Photo: Seven News
"It feels like you're gonna die at least," he said.
"You didn't know where to swim, you're out there in the middle of the ocean you don't know where to go. You don't know what to do.

"Yeah, it's terrible."

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

off the coast of Gladstone before Mr Cartwright and his wife, Michelle, spotted him and hauled him to safety.
He was battered by waves and had swallowed a lot of water near the mouth of the Gladstone Marina.
"The average person could tread water without much difficulty for about 30 minutes. For the boy, he was very, very lucky to survive," ambulance service spokesman Chris Pereira said.
His grandparents only realised he was missing after returning to the marina, sparking a panicked call to authorities and an air search.
The 14-year-old said he just slipped and fell as he was walking along the boat's deck.
"I was like right next to my gramps but he was too busy concentrating on where to drive sop he didn't hear anything," he said.
"He didn't see anything what happened to me so I just fell in the water without him knowing."
Luckily the Cartwrights were nearby and responded to a radio call to help with the search.
"Yeah I'm feeling OK. I'm not the hero. This bloke's the hero," he said.
"But yeah me other half Michelle, she's the one who actually spotted him after we got the radio call so we were in that vicinity.
"...We spotted a head and thank god, yeah, he was just right here, flapping his arms."
Dad Neil Bevan, who also joined the rescuer and rescued on morning TV, said he did not find out about the accident until his son was in hospital.
"We got the phone call about seven o'clock at night from a gentleman named doctor Frank," he said.
"And at first I thought it was just a cruel joke, until he explained that they had Lochlan and he was safe but they'd found him in the water and basically that's how we found out.
"We just jumped straight in the car and drove straight into the hospital."
-  with AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lochlan Brodie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeah I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven's Sunrise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cartwrights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone Marina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cartwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Bevan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Pereira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Cartwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lochlan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
