<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404458642847132</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/markets-live/markets-live-aussie-jumps-as-rba-meets-20170731-gxmpcx.html</url>
  <title>Markets Live: Iron ore's eye-watering rise</title>
  <content>
The Australian dollar pushed back above US80¢ early Tuesday morning, an unwelcome development for the Reserve Bank of Australia, which it meets later today.

The Aussie nudged 0.2 per cent higher overnight to reach US80.04¢, the second time in as many weeks that it has broken above that threshold to trade at over two-year highs. In Tuesday morning trade, it continued to hover around US80¢.

RBA governor Philip Lowe and his predecessor have frequently expressed a desire for the local currency to be weaker as it aids the economy's continuing transition away from a once-in-a-generation mining investment boom.

But Mr Lowe has refrained from "jawboning" the dollar lower, which suggests the central bank remains broadly comfortable with the dollar at these levels. That's despite an 11 per cent surge against the greenback in 2017.

Economists are now wondering whether the RBA will express more concern in its statement accompanying this afternoon's monetary policy decision, where the cash rate target is expected to remain unchanged at a record low of 1.5 per cent.

"The market will be interested in whether they change the language around the exchange rate, other than to again note that a low rate would be helpful," NAB economists David de Garis said.

"The market understands that the bank wants to see a weaker currency, but what can be said without inflating property?"

An improving economy would give the RBA "a degree of comfort and ability to be patient to let the market sort itself out", Mr de Garis said.

Strengthening commodity prices are likely to have also supported the local currency in recent weeks, including an incredible 40 per cent climb in the spot price of iron ore since mid-June.

But those moves - - in the bulk commodity has left it broadly flat for the year against the 10 per cent lift in the Aussie.

Instead, analysts have largely blamed the weakening US dollar for the strength in the local currency.

The spot price of iron ore surged to near $US74 a tonne overnight as mid concerns about tightening supplies and resilient construction activity in China.

The supply concerns reflect Beijing's strong resolve to wipe out the production of substandard steel as well as environmental inspections in Hebei province gave the seaborne iron market a boost on Monday, according to Metal Bulletin.

Chinese Premier Li Keqiang reiterated on the weekend that the central government's determination in eliminating backward capacity and halting the production of substandard steel after two mills in Tianjin city and one in Hunan province were found to have resumed production of inferior products. 

Li's statement boosted sentiment in the market led to across-the-board increases for all ferrous futures, Metal Bulletin reported. Apart from this, Hebei's provincial government last Friday began another round of inspections to check on industry emissions, which raised concerns of possible disruptions to steel production.

"Environmental inspections have caused great impact on iron ore prices. Production in some mines, processing plants and mills are being disrupted," an iron ore trader in Beijing told Reuters.

"The whole supply chain has been affected by the inspections," she said.

Spot ore with 62 per cent content in Qingdao jumped $US4.97 or 7.2 per cent to $US73.70 a tonne overnight, according to Metal Bulletin.

 to $US70 a tonne from $US55, and the year-end target by $US5 to $US60.

Also bolstering positive sentiment, a continuing construction boom.

PMI's subindex jumped to 62.5 from 61.4 in June, boosted by government spending on infrastructure and stronger-than-expected property investment despite new regulations to curb runaway prices.

"At the beginning of the year most people had a pessimistic view on the outlook for the property market but that has changed with the stronger data releases," said Qiu Yuecheng, an analyst at steel trading platform Xiben New Line.

The Dow Jones hit a record high on Wall Street overnight, helped by Boeing, while selling in Facebook, Alphabet and other technology companies kept the S&P 500 flat and pulled the Nasdaq lower.

The S&P 500 information technology dipped 0.5 per cent, with Facebook falling 1.8 per cent and Alphabet , Google's parent company, down 1.4 per cent.

"The bull market is sort of broadening out and people are taking a few profits off the table on some these stocks that have done exceedingly well," said Randy Frederick, vice president of trading and derivatives for Charles Schwab in Austin, Texas.

Boeing rose 1 per cent and hit a record high of $US243.60 after JPMorgan raised its price target on the world's biggest plane maker to $US280. The stock was the largest contributor to the Dow's gains.

Apple, which is expected to report quarterly results after market close on Tuesday, dipped 0.6 per cent.

Investors have been counting on earnings to support high valuations for equities.

S&P 500 earnings are expected on average to have grown 10.8 per cent in the second quarter, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S.

"We're probably seeing peak earnings," said Ed Keon, portfolio manager at QMA, a multi-asset manager in Newark, New Jersey. "I think we'll be a little slower in the second half."

The Dow Jones added 0.3 per cent while the S&P 500 slipped 0.1 per cent. The Nasdaq Composite dropped 0.4 per cent.

The National Association of Realtors said its Pending Home Sales Index, based on contracts signed last month, jumped 1.5 per cent to a reading of 110.2.

Snap fell 2.5 per cent as some investors were allowed for the first time to sell shares following the Snapchat owner's March initial public offer.

Discovery Communications dropped 8.8 per cent after it said it would buy Scripps Networks Interactive for $11.9 billion.
Good morning and welcome to the Markets Live blog for Tuesday.

Your editors today are Jens Meyer and Patrick Commins.

This blog is not intended as investment advice.

Fairfax Media with wires.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Schwab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Keon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Li</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US73.70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US243.60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metal Bulletin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pending Home Sales Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scripps Networks Interactive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Markets Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qingdao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tianjin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hebei</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Premier Li Keqiang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Commins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Association of Realtors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qiu Yuecheng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randy Frederick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapchat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jens Meyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xiben New Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq Composite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US4.97</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80.04</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US280</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US74</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
