<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404325498858264</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/whats-on-tv-thursday-august-10-20170728-gxl2fj.html</url>
  <title>What's on TV: Thursday, August 10</title>
  <content>
Photo: BBC Worldwide
Pulse
ABC, 8.30pm
It's about time Australian TV produced a medical drama - now if we can just get the networks to do something about lawyers, we'll really have a vibrant industry. The twist here is that the lead character, Frankie Bell, dodged death eight years ago, inspiring her to change her life and become a doctor to save the lives of others. This leads to ethical dilemmas, difficult relationships and frantic attempts to resuscitate patients followed by the angry tearing off of scrubs and deep soul-searching as the doctor ponders what it means to be human. It's not like every other medical show ever made - just most of them. BP
pay Prince Harry in Africa
UKTV, 8.30pm
This eye-opening little special follows Prince Harry as he returns to Lesotho to visit the charity he set up after visiting the country on his gap year between school and the army in 2004. It's immediately clear that the tiny African country faces enormous challenges - as many as a third of its children are orphans, HIV/AIDS is a huge problem, and many of those infected refuse to take medication because of the stigma surrounding the disease. But it's also clear that Harry's charity, Sentebale - which he built in partnership with Prince Seeiso of Lesotho - is taking practical steps to help improve things. The picture of Harry that emerges is one of a humble but confident young man who is intent on honouring his mother's commitment to charity work in his own way. The commentary from Elton John and Coldplay's Chris Martin isn't entirely necessary. BN
movie Dick Tracy (1990)
Action Movies (pay TV), 10.15pm
The great gift of Warren Beatty - last seen wreaking havoc at the Academy Awards - was to craft as a writer, producer and director parts that suited his standoffishness on screen, whether it was the impotent bank robber in Bonnie and Clyde or the passionate ideologue of Reds. In a career given over to social commentary interspersed with romantic comedies, Dick Tracy is the great curiosity. Adapted from Chester Gould's 1930s comic strip, it's a tribute to American iconography, including the gangster films of the original era and the pop art movement. Beatty directs and stars as the noble crime fighter, with Al Pacino, Madonna and Dustin Hoffman (as a henchman named Mumbles for his lack of diction) opposite him, but the true stars are legendary cinematographer Vittorio Storaro and production designer Richard Sylbert, who turn the flat panels of the source material into a bold metropolis. CM
Car Wars
Seven, 10.30pm
It's quite a popular trend in reality TV, the practice of giving a show an interesting name so as to save money and time on making an interesting show. Car Wars should obviously be a rip-off of either Mad Max, Transformers or The Fast and the Furious, but it is none of these. In fact, it's just another show about police officers doing police work, and not even the fun kind of police work: it tries to show "the real face of policing", which means there are no murder mysteries or CSI or slow-motion balletic shootouts. It's just cops bouncing dolefully around grim British streets in pursuit of incredibly uncharismatic villains. There's the occasional car chase, but it turns out even they aren't as much fun as the movies make them look. They kind of just look like when you're going somewhere you've never been before so you just say you'll follow your friends, but they show no consideration whatsoever. We also get a glimpse at the training of elite "car cops", which involves, like, driving and stuff. The most entertaining thing about the show is the adorable accent of the officers. BP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clyde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick Tracy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankie Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lesotho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV/Aids</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Beatty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester Gould's 1930</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UKTV, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Hoffman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Sylbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Pacino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV), 10.15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonnie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coldplay's Chris Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vittorio Storaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Seeiso of Lesotho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sentebale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick Tracy (1990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madonna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC Worldwide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beatty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elton John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
