<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404282549184384</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/08/58/boy-barrelling-through-tiny-opponents-reignites-age-vs-weight-debate-in-junior-rugby-league</url>
  <title>Boy barrelling through tiny opponents reignites age vs weight debate in junior rugby league</title>
  <content>
An eight-year-old boy has found himself at the centre of a passionate debate over junior rugby league regulations.
Video posted to Facebook this week shows the eight-year-old Samoan boy playing in the under nines St Johns Eagles team, despite being more than twice his teammates' size.
The boy barrels through the pint-sized opposing team, who have no hope of slowing him down.
The footage has sparked a fierce debate online about size versus weight within the league, and whether regulations should be changed.
The St Johns Eagles chairman, Nasser Matta,  his club is "just following the rules" and added that "there are some even bigger kids playing".
"This boy's a gentle giant," he said.
"He's aware of his size. He could pick up kids with one hand if he wanted to but he's just a nice gentle boy. He's a good kid from a good family who just loves playing footy.

Related Articles

"I don't want the kid to think he doesn't deserve to play footy because of his size."
A parent from the opposing team, the Berala Bears, posted videos of Saturday's match to Facebook, including one showing the team banding together to tackle him to the ground.
"It can be done," he said triumphantly.
The proud parent said the St Johns Eagles team are "such an awesome side to play against".
The NRL has faced calls to change the regulations for the junior league for years.
A change of policy, to create division using weight instead of age to prevent children from getting injured, is being trialled in Sydney's west.
Canterbury Bulldogs chief executive Raelene Castle said the differing sizes of children is a "realistic" problem faced by the sport.
"This is one of the realistic challenges we face in our game," he told News Corp.
"You move these boys up an age group and while their bodies are big enough to deal with it physically, they are not old enough mentally. It's a tough one that the NSWRL is now looking at."
The parent who posted the videos declined to comment when contacted by 9news.com.au.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raelene Castle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSWRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasser Matta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Johns Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berala Bears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
