<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404153700163577</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4824719/sushi-staff-underpaid-70000/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Sushi staff 'underpaid $70,000'</title>
  <content>
The Fair Work ombudsman will take a Newcastle sushi operator to court over allegations workers were underpaid workers more than $70,0000.
The matter is headed to the federal circuit court. 
Tokyo Sushi's Kiyoshi Hasegawa is alleged to have been involved in underpaying 31 workers across three Hunter and Central Coast sushi outlets. 
Companies Hasegawa & Ye International Pty Ltd and Heiwa International Pty Ltd, of which Ms Hasegawa and her husband are the sole directors, also face penalties over the alleged breaches. 

The Tokyo Sushi outlets were audited in 2016 as part of a crackdown covering more than 40 outlets in NSW, Queensland and the ACT. 
"It is alleged inspectors found that pay rates at the three Tokyo Sushi outlets at Newcastle and the Central Coast did not comply with the Fast Food Industry Award 2010, with workers instead paid flat hourly rates ranging between $9 and $19 on weekdays, plus an additional 25 per cent on Saturdays and an additional 50 per cent on Sundays," the ombudsman said in a statement. 
"The approach allegedly led to underpayment of the minimum weekday rates, casual loadings and penalty rates for weekend and public holiday work.  

"Superannuation and minimum engagement entitlements were allegedly also underpaid and record-keeping laws were allegedly contravened."

Ms Hasegawa faces maximum penalties of up to $10,8000 per offence if they are proven. 
The companies Hasegawa & Ye International Pty Ltd and Heiwa International Pty Ltd each face penalties of up to $54,000 per contravention if proven.
The ombudsman alleges 16 Erina Fair branch workers were underpaid $48,318 between January and July 2016. 
Between January and September, it is further alleged that 15 employees at the Fletcher store were underpaid $22,567. 
Seven of the workers at the Newcastle outlet were aged between 16 and 20, the ombudsman said. 
Ombudsman Natalie James said legal action began due to the involvement of young staff and the blatant nature of the alleged offences. 
"Employers should be aware that we treat the underpayment of young and overseas workers particularly seriously," Ms James said.
"Young workers and workers from migrant backgrounds can be more vulnerable to exploitation as they are often reluctant to complain or are less aware of their rights.
"My agency is committed to sending a message to all business operators that anyone who attempts to capitalise on these vulnerabilities can expect to face serious enforcement action," Ms James said.
Orders are also being sought for full repayment for the workers, who the ombudsman said have only been partially reimbursed. 
A directions hearing is scheduled for Friday in Sydney. 

Employers and employees seeking assistance can visit www.fairwork.gov.au  or call the Fair Work Infoline on 13 13 94. An interpreter service is available on 13 14 50.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo Sushi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ombudsman Natalie James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Infoline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heiwa International Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erina Fair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo Sushi's Kiyoshi Hasegawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hasegawa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms James</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fast Food Industry Award 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasegawa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ye International Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
