<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404712045921249</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/how-the-gay-marriage-ambush-would-work-20170731-gxmq3v</url>
  <title>How the gay marriage 'ambush' would work</title>
  <content>
The Coalition's policy is that there can be no vote in  unless there is a plebiscite first.
Malcolm Turnbull, who agreed to that policy as a condition of taking the leadership from Tony Abbott, scheduled a plebiscite for February this year. But it never occurred because the legislation to establish the vote was blocked in the Senate.
Subsequently, proponents of same-sex marriage in the Liberal Party believe the Coalition has discharged its obligation to hold a plebiscite and feel the matter should now be put straight to a parliamentary vote with everyone given a conscience vote. A parliamentary vote has been the longstanding position of Labor, the Greens and independents.
Coalition conservatives argue this would be a breach of an election promise and say that if the party is to change policy to a free vote, this should be taken to the election first.

In the next few weeks, the proponents plan to vote on a private members bill that will be introduced in the Senate by WA Liberal Senator Dean Smith.

That bill should pass the Senate where the government is in minority but, to become law, it also needs to pass the House of Representatives where the government has a one-seat majority.
For the bill to be even debated in the lower house, it must be approved by a government-controlled Bills Selection Committee. Mr Turnbull can instruct his MPs on the committee to veto the bill for debate.
The only way to circumvent this obstacle is for an absolute majority of lower house MPs to vote for the bill to be debated, which is 76 MPs.
At the moment, there are 75 Coalition MPs and 74 Labor and crossbench MPs. One of those crossbenchers, Bob Katter, opposes gay marriage so the numbers start at 76 notionally against gay marriage and 73 for.

For an absolute majority to be achieved, at least three Liberals will need to cross the floor to achieve the 76 votes needed bring on the bill for debate.
One complication is that Labor's Kate Ellis is on maternity leave so unless she returns, a fourth Liberal will have to cross the floor to achieve 76 votes.
There are at least four Liberals reportedly prepared to do so - Trent Zimmerman, Trevor Evans, Warren Entsch and Tim Wilson. But others are also believed to be prepared to cross if need be.
Mr Entsch will travel to the United Nations in September for a three-month secondment so there is a sense of urgency about getting this done in August.

If enough MPs cross the floor to enable debate, it is guaranteed there will be enough to pass the bill.
Passage does not require a absolute majority of 76 votes, just a simple majority which is more votes for than against.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Katter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's Kate Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bills Selection Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
