<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404153700163556</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/ffa-cup-darwin-rovers-v-sydney-fc-clash-to-help-grow-game-in-territory/news-story/8ad2156c8b36bf66d514e736ed9f1e2c</url>
  <title>Sydney FC prepare to light up Darwin</title>
  <content>
FOOTBALL NT boss Bruce Stalder wants tomorrow night's big FFA Cup clash between local side Darwin Rovers and A-League giants Sydney FC to act as a beacon for the round ball game.
Sydney FC's captain Alex Brosque is the only major doubt among the Sky Blues, with the birth of his third child yesterday likely to keep him in the harbour city.
More than 4000 fans are expected to fill Darwin Football Stadium at Marrara for Territory soccer's third attempt at advancing past the national competition's Round of 32.
Darwin Olympic in 2015 and the Rovers last year were on the wrong end of some big losses to interstate clubs.
"This is a massive opportunity for us to highlight the best of our game,'' Stalder told the NT News last night.
"You always want to test yourself against the best and we've got the very best up here this week.''
"When you have the national champions in Darwin against our local tradies who have done it hard, it's a great result for football.
"It also gives us a chance to profile these superstars from Sydney FC among our junior players, those weekend warriors who play our game with all their heart and soul.'' More than 120 children will fill various roles in tomorrow night's game, including playing Mini Roos games at halftime, ball persons and mascots.
"Basically we want to share this experience among as many of our football family up here in the NT as possible,'' Stalder said.
"On the pitch it should be a great occasion. Sydney is bringing up a very strong side with their coach (Graham Arnold) indicating he wants to put some time into the legs of his marquee players.
Stalder has guaranteed the Sky Blues a sublime playing surface, unlike many of the grounds they play on through the A-League season.
"The surface at Darwin Football Stadium is as good as anywhere,'' he said. "It's a credit to our groundsman who has done a fantastic job getting it up to scratch.''
Meanwhile, Stalder has advised football fans to book their tickets online or purchase them at the Football Federation's head office at the Italian Club at Marrara to avoid long queues at the gate.
Fans can also save money by pre-purchasing up until 1pm today, with savings of up to 30 per cent for a family grandstand pass - $65 down to $52.
Individual grandstand tickets can be purchased for $20 online or over the counter.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Football Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marrara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Stalder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARWIN Rovers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Arnold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Blues</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stalder</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mini Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Brosque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
