<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404712045921242</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/spirituality-centre-has-open-day-to-mark-30-years-in-cairns/news-story/427203d29b339ac254d8bcb38f4cb078</url>
  <title>Many paths over 30 years</title>
  <content>
THEY are not a cult. They are not a church and they certainly don™t judge the sceptics.

The people behind the not-for-profit Cairns Spiritual Centre offer alternative treatments - from tarot card reading to reiki therapy - but the centre's holistic focus is on helping others to find their way.

This year, the centre has reached its 30-year milestone in Cairns and, to celebrate, an open day is being held on Saturday, August 5.

There will be guest speakers, healing, tarot readings and market stalls, along with some spiritual therapies that would be foreign to many, such as shamanic circles, astral medicine, bio field resonance and quantum healing meditation.

Regardless of the form it comes in, according to Cairns Spiritual Centre secretary Dot Sweeting, "there are many pathways to spirituality".

"We are a community group run by volunteers," she says.

"We've been going for 30 years so it's had slightly different directions depending on who is on the committee. We will get people who have been in Cairns for 15 years and haven't known we are here. I will say 'that's because you haven't needed us but now you need us, you've found us'.

"Because we are not mainstream, people have tried all the mainstream stuff and then they think there has got to be a better way, there has got to be something else out there. So they come here and look for the alternatives.

"Some people get the wrong idea, they think it's a cult."

Astrology and meditation practitioner Hazel Leung backs up this common assumption, saying people also think the centre is a church.

"They can think it's a church but it's not," she says.

"It's just open to the essence of who everyone is, which is the spirit of the person."

Hazel says the focus of the centre is on helping those who are drawn to it, to find themselves. She says all walks of life and all ages have walked through their doors.

"We are all guided but so many people don't listen to themselves," she says.

"When you start coming here you start opening your intuition. It actually helps people to listen to their own inner guidance.

"Some people come here and have been through quite traumatic circumstances and might stay six months, we might never see them again, but once they've got what they needed they move on."

Both Hazel and Dot say people benefit massively from their interactions with the centre. For many, it is the end of the line after a long search through doctors, psychologists and other forms of western medicine.

"We frequently have people who get heaps out of coming here," Dot says. "They really benefit because if you compare the spiritual centre with mainstream ... In mainstream (medicine or therapy), if there is something wrong with your body, you go to the doctor.

"If there is something wrong with your mind you go to the psychiatrist and if there is something wrong with your spirituality, you go and see the priest, whereas here we are holistic.

"Everything is within you and that's where you have to go. It's not about treating the body separately because the body, mind and soul make up the whole."

Dot's path to the spiritual centre began later in life.

"Things were happening - marriage, divorce, marriage, divorce, and I was thinking 'what's going on' and then someone gave me a copy of Louise Hay's book You Can Heal Your Life," she says.

"That is where quite a few people start, and that book just made so much sense to me.

"She teaches the mind-body connection and it just resonated with me. Once you can see the pattern is repeated ... it's all about the lessons you've come here to learn.

"If you change the way you look at things then what you are looking at will change. If you change your thoughts then everything around you will change.

"What you are putting out is what you want but if your vibration doesn't match that, you are not going to get it. You have to change something within you that is stopping you.

"Then I just got on the spiritual pathway and was reading everything I could."

A grandfather with healing hands and a grandmother who read gypsy tarot cards was the world Hazel grew up in.

"My grandmother used to say 'you will have a job in three days' and you did, so I have been exposed to it for a long time. I always used to wonder why I knew things. You actually know things are going to happen before they happen but it confused me.

"If you were thinking something and couldn't get the words out, I could tell you what those words were and it was scaring the sh- out of me. It's one of the reasons we like the open day because people are going through that, like me, and they have no proof. So they come here and realise they are not abnormal.

Hazel says over the 30 years in Cairns, the spiritual centre has evolved, depending on the practitioners volunteering.

"It's always been about teaching people about spiritual things and teaching them about their own spiritual identities and about their intuition and at an affordable rate," Hazel says. As for Dot, she says spirituality is a philosophy, not a religion.

"If people are religious we respect their pathway. There are many roads but generally one destination. We are all heading for the same spot but by many different routes."

The Cairns Spiritual Centre Open Day is on Saturday, August 5, from 10am-4pm, 1/194 Spence St, Bungalow. Visit:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Hay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dot Sweeting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Spiritual Centre Open Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hazel Leung</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spence St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Spiritual Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Can Heal Your Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hazel</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
