<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404591786835500</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/technology/technology-news/snap-shares-tumble-after-insiders-get-first-opportunity-to-sell-20170731-gxmnms.html</url>
  <title>Snap shares tumble after insiders get first opportunity to sell</title>
  <content>
Snap shares fell Monday after some inside holders got their first opportunity to sell since the March initial public offering.
The shares tumbled as much as 5.1 per cent to $US13.10 in New York, .

Up Next

Why Martin Shkreli Is on trial for making millions

01:22

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Snap misses forecasts for new users and sales

Snap Inc.'s Snapchat app added fewer users than projected in the first quarter, a sign that the young company may have trouble expanding its audience as Facebook Inc. copies its most popular features.

Inside holders, such as executives and investors from the company's days as a private start-up, are barred from selling their shares for a certain period after the IPO. JPMorgan Chase had estimated that as many as 400 million shares could be sold in the first lock-up expiration.
While some early investors are finally able to cash out on their holdings, putting more stock into the market also puts pressure on the price.

Snap, the maker of the Snapchat app for sending fun, disappearing photos and videos, has already seen its value decline since the IPO.
Investors have voiced concerns that Snap won't be able to grow its user base quickly enough to claim a strong position in an increasingly competitive digital advertising market, especially as Facebook's properties copy some of Snapchat's most compelling features.

"Sentiment around Snap remains at ghastly levels," Brian White, an analyst at Drexel Hamilton, wrote in a note to investors this month.

You will now receive updates from

Technology Daily Newsletter

Technology Daily Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But once all the lock-ups have expired, the weakened stock could be "a buying opportunity for investors that can look out 12 months," he said.Photo: Bloomberg
Snap reports earnings for the second time as a listed company on August 10.
Bloomberg 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook Inc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drexel Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Shkreli Is</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US13.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapchat</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan Chase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
