<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404673391215108</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/one-in-five-students-sexually-harassed-at-university-landmark-report-reveals-20170731-gxmhye.html</url>
  <title>One in five students sexually harassed at university, landmark report reveals</title>
  <content>
University students are experiencing "unacceptable" rate of sexual assault on campus, a survey of 31,000 Australian students has found, after students reported being assaulted on the way to university, inside residential colleges and by the staff supervising them. 

Up Next

Same sex marriage division

01:20

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Universities brace for sexual assault report

A landmark survey of 31,000 students by the Australian Human Rights Commission is likely to raise further allegations of sexual assault on campus.

The report, released by the Human Rights Commission on Tuesday, found women were four times more likely to have been sexually assaulted than men in a university residence, while post-graduate students were more likely to have to been harassed or assaulted by a staff member. 
"The unavoidable conclusion of the data we have gathered across all 39 Australian universities is that incidents of sexual assault and sexual harassment are occurring at unacceptable rates at Australian universities," said Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins.Photo: Paul Jeffers
The commission found 21 per cent of students were sexually harassed in a university setting in 2016 and 1.6 per cent of students were sexually assaulted. 
Despite decades of reports of sexual assault on campus, many victims remain unaware of where to report their assault, while two thirds of students who witnessed assaults two took no action. 

Only 6 per cent of students surveyed thought their university was currently doing enough to provide clear direction on sexual harassment procedures and support services

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

On Tuesday, Ms Jenkins released nine recommendations for reform, including establishing a sector-wide independent investigation into residential colleges.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
"We found that college settings are a particular area of concern, particularly for women who were four times as likely as men to have been sexually assaulted in this setting," she said. 
In February,  after it was revealed there had been just six  despite more than 500 official complaints, including college students referring to an oval as a "rape oval", calling cask wine "slut juice" and residential quarters "slut alley".Photo: James Brickwood
Universities Australia has also taken aim at colleges in its 10-point action plan, released on Tuesday, while developing new principles for postgraduate staff and student interaction in response to the new figures. 
Chief executive Belinda Robinson said the peak body would also be extending first responder training to frontline university staff. 
"We know that the way a disclosure of sexual assault is handled in the very first instance can make all the difference to the recovery of the victim or survivor," she said. 
"This work will help ensure that all students will receive a compassionate and supportive response if they choose to disclose their experience to a university staff member."
But sexual assault advocates have condemned the peak body for failing to mention either perpetrators or disciplinary measures in its response. 
"Universities Australia's complete silence on offenders and disciplinary reform makes victim-survivors question just how committed they really are to taking firmer steps towards making campuses safe for students," said End Rape on Campus ambassador Nina Funnell. 
"Implementing trauma-informed reporting channels is all well and good but if universities have no intention of ever disciplining offenders there is little incentive to report." 
University administrators have been awaiting the survey's findings since the survey was launched in November. All 39 institutions are set to release their individual results on Tuesday morning . 
" and "betraying" the students who participated in the survey because they would not release data on individual universities.
The figures are set to have an impact on Australia's third largest export, the $20 billon international student market. 
Donaldson Law director Adair Donaldson said unless universities fundamentally changed their culture of dealing with sexual assault, a wave of victims could come forward seeking damages due to breaches of duty of care.  
"Universities must be prepared to acknowledge and support survivors of sexual assault and abuse, or the result to these academic institutions could be serious financial distress due to legal claims," Mr Donaldson said.
"My experience working with survivors of institutional abuse is that nobody wants to embark on aggressive and protracted legal action, there is an opportunity for the universities to work together with survivors, rather than against them."
If you or someone you know is impacted by sexual assault or family violence, call 1800RESPECT on 1800 737 732. In an emergency contact 000.
Universities Australia has also established a new university dedicated counselling hotline on 1800 572 224.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nina Funnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>End Rape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Brickwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Donaldson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donaldson Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adair Donaldson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
