<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404626146574245</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4825066/half-of-australian-university-students-sexually-harassed-report/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Half of Australian university students sexually harassed: Report</title>
  <content>
The University of Newcastle will publicly respond to the findings of a Human Rights Commission report about the rates of sexual harassment and sexual assault in Australian universities.

More than half of the students at Australian universities are sexually harassed, while almost 7 per cent experience some form of sexual assault or rape, the Human Rights Commission has revealed.
The commission's national report on sexual assault and sexual harassment in Australian universities was released on Tuesday morning.
It found that 51 per cent of Australian university students experienced sexual harassment - 63 per cent of whom were women.

It also found that 6.9 per cent of students experienced sexual assault or rape.
"Today students will finally see their experiences reflected in the data, universities can no longer bury their heads in the sand and ignore sexual assault and harassment," National Union of Students women's officer Abby Stapleton said.

The University of Newcastle will publicly address the report's findings on Tuesday morning.
More to follow.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Union of Students</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abby Stapleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
