<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404673391215100</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/10/33/sexual-assault-and-harassment-at-unis</url>
  <title>Sexual assault and harassment at unis</title>
  <content>
SEXUAL ASSAULT AND HARASSMENT ON CAMPUSES
* The Human Rights Commission surveyed more than 30,000 students across Australia's 39 universities.
* 51 per cent of university students sexually harassed at least once in 2016.
* One in four students was harassed in a university setting (on campus, while travelling to university, at a university-endorsed social event or in university employment).
* One in three harassment incidents happened on university grounds or in classrooms.
* 6.9 per cent were sexually assaulted (about one in 15).
* 1.6 per cent of students were assaulted in a university setting (almost one in four of the total who were sexually assaulted).

Related Articles

* One in five of these assaults happened at university or residence social events.
* Women almost twice as likely as men to be harassed, and more than three times as likely to be assaulted.
* Men overwhelmingly reported as the perpetrators.
* 51 per cent of those who reported assault or harassment knew the perpetrator - most likely to be a fellow student.
* 94 four per cent of those harassed and 87 per cent of those assaulted at university did not make a formal complaint or report.
* Six in 10 students said they didn't know how to formally report or complain about incidents.
Australian readers seeking support and information can contact:
*National university support line: 1800 572 224 (From 31 July to 30 November 2017)
* 1800 RESPECT: 1800 737 732
* Lifeline: 131114
* Beyond Blue: 1300 224 636
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's 39</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RESPECT: 1800 737 732</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASSAULT AND HARASSMENT ON CAMPUSES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue: 1300 224 636</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
