<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404669096247726</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/damning-sexual-assault-and-harassment-figures-released/news-story/169683e8f7bf972498abfe917af2cee9</url>
  <title>Damning sexual assault and harassment figures released</title>
  <content>
A NEWLY released report has revealed that about half of all university students were sexually harassed on at least one occasion in 2016, while one in five were harassed in an university setting.
The findings have this morning been released by the Australian Human Rights Commission on the back of a first-ever national survey on the prevalence of sexual assault and sexual harassment at Australia's universities.
The Change the Course: National Report on Sexual Assault and Sexual Harassment at Australian Universities is the result of a national survey measuring the experiences of more than 30,000 students across all 39 universities and 1849 written submissions.
Data from individual universities, including James Cook University and Central Queensland University, will be released later this morning.
Human Rights Commission president Rosalind Croucher said the project was a significant one.
"The report is both an acknoweldgement of the continuing problems for universities but it's also a beginning," she said.
The survey results show that 51 per cent of students were sexually harassed one at least one occasion in 2016 and 6.9 per cent of students were sexually assaulted on at least one occasion in 2015 or 2016.
One in five students were sexually harassed in a university setting in 2016, excluding travel to and from university, while 1.6 per cent of students were sexually assaulted in a university setting including travel to and from university in 2015 or 2016.

Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins said the commission received reports of sexual assault at O-Week camps, university parties and in residential colleges.
"Perhaps most worrying, there was a perception that colleges were aware of this behaviour and did nothing to prevent this," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O-Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosalind Croucher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cook University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexual Assault</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Universities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Queensland University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexual Harassment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
