<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404681981149801</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/south-west-beaches/west-lakes-home-attracts-23-bidders-and-sells-102500-above-reserve/news-story/ca0a2e1bbfab2a375a009952e1255f13</url>
  <title>West Lakes home attracts 23 bidders and sells $102,500 above reserve - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
1 Birkdale Grove, West Lakes

IT was families versus developers in one of Adelaide's most contented auctions this year so far.
With 23 registered bidders and more than 5000 views on realestate.com.au, 1 Birkdale Grove, West Lakes sold under the hammer for $647,000 - $102,500 above its reserve price.
The winning bid came from a local developer who is looking to replace the original three-bedroom home with two new dwellings as part of an ongoing push to rejuvenate and modernise the sought-after suburb.

1 Birkdale Grove, West Lakes

Listing agent Sarah Sheppard of Harcourts Sheppard, said the home's `near' lakeside location and proximity to Westfield shopping was what attracted the large number of bidders.
Set on a 700sqm block, the brick home was 100m from the lake and about a five-minute walk from the beach.
"We quoted $495,000 for the home with a reserve price of $544,500," she said.
"In the end, the home sold for $647,000 with bidders primarily consisting of families and developers.
"It was a developer who won it in the end. I believe he's going to pull (the house) down and build two new, three bedroom, two bathroom and double garage homes."

1 Birkdale Grove, West Lakes

Despite the suburb's approximate population of 5730, Core Logic figures show only 11 houses and 10 units sold within West Lakes between May 1, 2016 and April 30, this year.
The suburb is tightly held: according to Core Logic, the average number of years between sales for a house in West Lakes is 9.6 years, compared to 8.8 years Adelaide-wide.
Ms Sheppard said new developments were particularly popular with buyers.

1 Birkdale Grove, West Lakes

"There are a lot of empty nesters who raised a family in the suburbs and generally enjoy living there and don't leave.
"So new homes are always well sought after."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide-wide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birkdale Grove</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Lakes</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Sheppard of Harcourts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Core Logic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Sheppard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheppard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
