<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404626146574229</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/entertainment/new-burnie-hq-for-tasmanias-ten-days-on-the-island-arts-festival/news-story/6504ef48ed3513849f4f534b3ca21cfd</url>
  <title>Burnie arts boost as Ten Days moves in</title>
  <content>
The new  headquarters has been established at Burnie's Makers' Workshop, which is now part of the University of Tasmania's West Park campus.
It will be officially launched at 3pm today, with a small administration office to remain in its previous home of Hobart.
The move is expected to boost regional employment opportunities in the arts, festivals and event industries.

Festival chairman Saul Eslake said the festival would continue to bring international arts experiences to all regions of the state but from 2019 would include more commissions and collaborations with local companies and artists.
"We're excited to be refocusing our approach as a regionally-based operation with a program that is sourced from Tasmania's regions, developed within a worldview and presented across the state," he said in a statement.

The State Government committed extra funding to the festival in the 2017 Budget to build its regional base and increase local support.
"The move to Burnie is expected to be a boost for skills and employment in the arts," Mr Eslake said.
"As we develop our new model we will be looking to build the festival team in Burnie and there will be opportunities for locals to be part of the growing arts, festivals and event industries."
The festival will also partner with UTAS in terms of study and qualifications as well as research and creative collaborations.
Me Eslake said Facing North - a key work in this year's festival which was a collaboration between UTAS, composer Dean Stevenson and many local musicians - was a great example of how the festival could work in the future.
The next Ten Days on the Island festival will be held in 2019.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eslake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Days</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTAS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facing North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saul Eslake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Stevenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Eslake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnie's Makers' Workshop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
