<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404587491868076</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/canberras-champion-gelding-fell-swoop-prepping-for-historic-10-million-everest-20170730-gxlzpr.html</url>
  <title>Fell Swoop galloping into Australian racing history</title>
  <content>
 Canberra's champion gelding Fell Swoop has began his preparation for the world's richest race on turf - the $10 million Everest.
ACT trainer Matt Dale said things are heating up for his stable star ahead of the inaugural 1200m weight-for-age race at Royal Randwick on October 14.Photo: Karleen Minney
Fell Swoop was bough for $45,0000 and the five-year-old has returned more than $1.6 million in a dazzling nine-win career.
Dale admits he's still pinching himself ahead of the historic moment in Australian racing which will see Fell Swoop line up along the world's best sprinters in the 12-horse epic.
"If you asked me five years ago my chances of being involved in a concept like this I'd say very slim, so you've got to pinch yourself and I just feel lucky to be involved," Dale said.

"The enormity probably hasn't dawned on us yet. Sometimes when you're involved you don't have time to let it sink in and sometimes you need to step back and look at it from a different point of view and enjoy it.
"As it gets closer the hype and promotion around it will be massive and I'm sure it will become quite apparent over the next couple of months.
"It'll be 12 horses running the first edition of the Everest and the concept has been received very well and looks like it's something that's going to build and stay in the future, so it's very exciting."
Fell Swoop has started galloping and will jump in his first of two barrier trials in two weeks, before racing first-up in an 1100m Group Two at Randwick on September 16.
The bookies have listed Fell Swoop at $26 for the Everest but Dale said you only need to look at his placings at the past two TJ Smith Stakes to know he's a genuine contender.
"We're prepping him a in similar way to the TJ which prior to the Everest was the biggest sprinter race in Australia and this is going to be at the same track and over the same distance," Dale said.
"He's always ran really well under weight-for-age Group One races at 1200m and if he can reproduce his form over the past 18 to 24 months then he'll be very competitive.
"I think with the odds there's just a lot higher profile horses in the race with the likes of Chautauqua and some Golden Slipper winners.
"But it's always the same, in the last two TJs he's been $15 or $20 and ran right out of his skin."
Dale remains a strong chance to collect in the record-breaking sprint but the experienced trainer has been in the sport long enough to know it doesn't always go to plan.
"In this game I think people remain quite grounded because racing is a great leveller, you can be on a high one day and knocked right back down the next," Dale said.
"There is no leveller like the racing game and people who have won big races in the past tend to stay quite grounded because the harsh reality is you lose a hell of a lot more than you win."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>TJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group Two</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everest</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Dale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chautauqua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TJs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TJ Smith Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Slipper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karleen Minney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fell Swoop</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group One</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
