<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404712045921217</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-01/us-vice-president-mike-pence-reassures-nato-allies-in-estonia-amid-russian-threat/1690256</url>
  <title>US Vice President Mike Pence reassures NATO allies in Estonia amid Russian threat</title>
  <content>
US Vice President Mike Pence has reaffirmed Washington's commitment to the security of the Baltic states if they face any aggression from Russia.

Key points:

Mike Pence visits Estonia, Montenegro and Georgia
Vice President says "America first does not mean America alone"
US says it will continue to hold Russia accountable

Speaking in Estonia, Mr Pence said the US was behind its NATO allies and labelled Russia their biggest security threat.
"At the heart of our alliance is a solemn promise that an attack on one is an attack on all," he said.
The red carpet was laid out for Mr Pence as he began the whirlwind Baltic tour in the Estonian capital, Tallinn.
"The President has made clear, and as my presence here today demonstrates, America first does not mean America alone," he said.
Members of the US, French, British and Estonian militaries were there to hear Mr Pence's speech, as were the presidents of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania.
The address was clearly intended to reassure the Baltic states following US President Donald Trump's early lukewarm support for NATO.
"A strong and united NATO is more necessary today than at any point since the collapse of communism a quarter-century ago," Mr Pence said.
The Vice President's visit to the region came after .
It is seen as retaliation for new US sanctions against Russia, which were punishment for the annexation of Crimea and for interference in last year's US election.
For an administration that has been sending mixed messages on Russia, Mr Pence tried to set the record straight.
"The President and our Congress are unified in our message: A better relationship and the lifting of sanctions will require Russia to reverse the actions that caused the sanctions to be imposed in the first place," Mr Pence said.
"The United States will continue to hold Russia accountable for its actions."
Russia unlikely to be concerned: analyst

Analysts said Russia would not be too concerned by the new sanctions.
"I think [Russian President Vladimir] Putin has just sensed this is a dysfunctional administration," said John Lough, associate fellow of the Russia program at Chatham House.
"It has no Russia policy. In fact he can really start to call the shots so I think from his point of view he is winning hands down.
"And that in a bizarre way sanctions are great for him."
Mr Lough said he doesn't think it is how Mr Trump wanted his foreign policy to play out.
"He had hoped he would be able to transform this relationship and do things that the Obama administration hadn't done," he said.
Mr Pence was also visiting Georgia and Montenegro before flying home.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estonia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chatham House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lithuania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montenegro</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian President Vladimir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latvia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TALLINN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estonian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Lough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Pence</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crimea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
