<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404557427096529</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/eel-takes-aim-at-josh-mcguire-over-dirty-play/3207333/</url>
  <title>Eel takes aim at Josh McGuire over 'dirty play'</title>
  <content>
BRONCOS enforcer Josh McGuire has blue and gold blood boiling over his alleged "intentional" stomping of Parramatta skipper Tim Mannah in the fiery Eels win that put them on the premiership map.

Footage of McGuire treading on Mannah has done the social media rounds over the weekend and was panned as a "low act" by Parramatta star Michael Jennings when he was quizzed by reporters on Monday.

"That shouldn't be in our game. That's dirty play," Jennings said when shown the 78th-minute incident.

"You can see it's intentional ... [he's] trying to tread on his ankle. It's good that no one came out hurt out of it. But those intentions, you don't need that in our game."

McGuire was not penalised for the incident during the game and has not been issued a concerning act notice by the NRL.

The Brisbane forward's latest act will do nothing to dull a reputation as one of the game's most polarising figures, with NSW prop Andrew Fifita accusing McGuire of diving at his legs during Origin II, while he has also been at the centre of training blow-ups and the infamous "rat in the ranks" scandal at Red Hill last year.

Last Friday's 28-14 win for Parramatta was already making waves around rugby league thanks to both the Eels' impressive upset victory and Kenny Edwards' shot on a defenceless Jonus Pearson as he lay dazed on the turf.

Broncos coach Wayne Bennett declared that incident as "not a good look for the game" while the match review panel hit Edwards with a $1100 fine for contrary conduct under the NRL's revamped judiciary system.

Jennings also took issue with Adam Blair's late tackle attempt on him as he chased a second-half kick at ANZ Stadium.

The Eels centre emerged unscathed from Blair's effort, later branded a "cheap shot" by club great Gorden Tallis, but the tackle ultimately landed teammate Andrew McCullough with a season-ending knee injury that threatens to derail Brisbane's premiership tilt.

The incidents set the two finals-bound sides up for an explosive return clash at Suncorp Stadium in round 25.

This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Noosa is mourning the loss of bright, bubbly mother Sharon Cuthbert
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonus Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gorden Tallis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fifita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh McGuire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McCullough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
