<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403805807806512</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/game-of-thrones-hit-by-noconfederate-tweet-storm-over-hbos-slavery-drama-20170731-gxmnu6.html</url>
  <title>Game of Thrones hit by #NoConfederate tweet storm over HBO's slavery drama</title>
  <content>
The #NoConfederate rallying cry of those opposing HBO's recently announced present-day slavery series Confederate trended on Twitter throughout the latest Game of Thrones broadcast.
Activist April Reign, the creator of #OscarsSoWhite, made a call on the weekend for the Twittersphere to tweet using the new hashtag to "send a message" to the premium cable network during the episode.

Up Next

Life after Pitt: Jolie reveals

01:26

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Entertainment news highlights

Bitchiness on The Bachelor, Dr G Yunupingu's marvelous career, talk shows take on Trump's transgender ban, fans' anger at Australian Ninja Warrior and Ringo and Paul back together again.

Game of Thrones creators David Benioff and D.B. Weiss are behind the planned HBO series set in an alternate reality in which the South seceded from the Union and slavery still exists.
After last week's announcement, critics objected on many fronts, including the show's intention to depict slavery as a legal institution and that two white men, Benioff and Weiss, would be running the series.

HBO program chief Casey Bloys acknowledged the network erred in how it released news of the series.
"HBO's mistake was that we would be able to announce an idea that is so sensitive and requires such care and thought on the part of producers in a press release. (That) was misguided," Bloys told writers at the summer TV press tour last week.

Prior to the start of Game of Thrones, Reign shared a screenshot, stating that #NoConfederate was second in line for most trending topics in the United States.
She tweeted throughout the show, supporting one Twitter user's suggestion that HBO instead pick up Underground, a cancelled series about the Underground Railroad starring Jurnee Smollett-Bell and executive produced by John Legend. She also retweeted users protests, like one who reasoned, "Because we are your customers too #NoConfederate."Photo: HBO
Following the episode, HBO released a statement to The Hollywood Reporter in response to the swelling backlash.
"We have great respect for the dialogue and concern being expressed around Confederate," the network said in the statement. "We have faith that (writers) Nichelle Tramble, Dan, David and Malcolm Spellman will approach the subject with care and sensitivity. The project is currently in its infancy so we hope that people will reserve judgment until there is something to see."
Reign later appeared on CBS This Morning explaining her immediate resistance. "There are times when things are so egregious, that you don't need to wait for them to come to fruition before you object to them," she said. "Our goal is to have the show Confederate not see the light of day - that's the bottom line."
In an interview with Vulture published this month, Spellman attempted to calm the concerns of Confederate opposers. "This is not a world in which the entire country is enslaved," he said. "Slavery is in one-half of the country. And the North is the North. As Nichelle was saying, the imagery should be no whips and no plantations."
Production for Confederate isn't expected to begin for at least a year, according to Bloys.
USA Today
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS This Morning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood Reporter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurnee Smollett-Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April Reign</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OscarsSoWhite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jolie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NoConfederate</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twittersphere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr G. Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spellman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benioff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitchiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Spellman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Legend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Confederate</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nichelle Tramble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA TODAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vulture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nichelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Underground Railroad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Benioff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D.B. Weiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey Bloys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
