<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404759290562400</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/money/super-and-funds/australian-shares-only-fifthbest-performing-asset-class-over-10-years-20170728-gxkpgq.html</url>
  <title>Australian shares only fifth-best performing asset class over 10 years</title>
  <content>
The  confirms what most people are likely to know already - that Australian residential property is the best-performing asset class over the past 10 years.
Australian bricks and mortar has produced an average annual compound return of 8.1 per cent.

Up Next

How realistic is hyperloop travel?

02:28

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

The stand out listings traded on the ASX captured at key moments through the day, as indicated by the time stamp in the video.

That's the return on a population-weighted average return across major capital cities.
The report gives the return of the major asset classes on the basis of "total" returns, which means changes in the value of the investment, but also any income it produces, such as rents from property or dividends from shares. Photo: Salty Dingo
There are big variations between regions, dwelling types and suburbs.
Most likely those with Sydney or Melbourne investment property will have done better than 8.1 per cent.  

What will surprise most is that Australian shares produced an average annual compound return of 4.3 per cent over the 10 years to the end of last year.

You will now receive updates from

Money Newsletter

Money Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

That's despite . 
That makes Australian shares only the fifth-best performing investment over the 10 years.
The 10 years capture the global financial crises. And Australian shares prices fell November 2007 and March 2009, by about 55 per cent, the worst "bear", or falling, market since the 1970s.
However, global shares, those that are hedged to remove the currency exchange rate effects, produced a return of 5.5 per cent.
Australian bonds returned 6.1 per cent and hedged global bonds produced a return of 7.4 per cent - all better than Australian shares over the 10 years. 
It's not quite the complete story, as the returns are before-tax and before fees and some asset classes, like residential investment property and Australian shares, are taxed more lightly than others such as bonds and cash. 
The actual returns that end up in the investor's pocket will depend on the tax regime in what they are held, be that at the investor's marginal rate of income tax or whether the investment is held inside concessionally taxed superannuation.
The results are another argument for diversification, but not in the way you may think. 
The report shows that a balanced managed fund with 70 per cent in growth assets, like shares and property, and 30 per cent in defensive assets, like fixed interest, returned 5.4 per cent.
The balanced managed fund is a rough proxy for a diversified portfolio of traditional assets; though, the property exposure will be listed property, such as commercial property, rather than residential property.
It suggests that if investors want to do better than that they should be diversifying with some exposure to asset classes beyond the traditional ones. 
With the advent of exchange traded funds, which are listed on the Australian sharemarket and track the returns and prices of all sorts of markets, that's easy to do.
Of course that leaves unanswered the subject of a future column - which alternative investments to add to the usual ones. 
Follow John Collett .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salty Dingo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Collett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
