<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404720635856077</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/afl/st-kilda/scott-watters-defends-junior-footy-coaching-tactics/news-story/407c388515d3d3a951c4a2a350b62c56</url>
  <title>Scott Watters defends junior footy coaching tactics</title>
  <content>
Riewoldt close to tears during retirement speech
1:31

AFL: Riewoldt close to tears during retirement speech.

July 31st 2017
20 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/AFL/

Former St Kilda coach Scott Watters.

Share

A FORMER AFL coach has taken the unusual step of outing himself as the subject of a rumour about controversy in junior footy ranks.
Scott Watters has defended his tactical moves after "The Whisper" in today's Herald Sun revealed a former AFL coach was playing loose men in defence at under-11 level.
While the coach wasn't named, the team at Triple M's Hot Breakfast took a stab that the coach in question was Watters, who coached St Kilda in 2012-13 and is now in charge of the East Brighton Vampires in the South Metro Junior Football League.
WHISPER CONFIRMED!
Former Saints coach fesses up, defends junior tactics:
When they phoned Watters, he fessed up.
"Has this gone through the mighty East Brighton Vampires media department?" he joked.
Watters said he coaches the under-9s and under-11s teams, and co-coaches the under-13s with former Saint Trent Dennis-Lane.
He said all kids played in zones in under-9s but coaches had more freedom after that.
"We certainly don't flood the backline. That would go against actually kids learning the games.
"But I make no apologies for teaching kids how to actually hold their position in defence.

"We'll (also) have a midfield sweeper that will hold a little bit off the ball.

Scott Watters during his short tenure at St Kilda.Source:News Limited
"You have to (teach the kids how to play) otherwise you end up with 18 players around the ball and it doesn't even resemble footy.
"The results and winning is irrelevant in junior footy. It's actually about teaching the kids and making sure they come back every training session inspired to learn."
Watters was sacked as St Kilda coach after leading the Saints to 17 wins from 22 matches.
Saints champion Nick Riewoldt said there was "nothing sinister" in him skipping Watters when he thanked a number of past coaches.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Metro Junior Football League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watters</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Brighton Vampires</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WHISPER CONFIRMED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Watters</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saint Trent Dennis-Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M's Hot Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FORMER AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
