<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404720635856119</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/opinion/opinion-prison-not-the-place-for-our-criminals/news-story/27d650388944da8b97d7033dfcaaa2df</url>
  <title>Prison not the place for all criminals</title>
  <content>
Qld police demand more anti-terror weapons

QUEENSLAND™S reappointed police commissioner is copping flak for insisting jail time is oenot the answer to making Australia a great nation".

Go easy. Ian Stewart is right.

Prison is not a place for rehabilitation, but reinforcing learned criminal behaviour and deviant thinking.

Just look at the number of criminals who bluff their way out on bail only to finish what they started and kill someone.

Australia's family violence tapestry is littered with these supposedly "reformed" thugs for whom jail doesn't work one iota.

was murdered by her estranged partner after he was released on bail - and the authorities claimed they "saw no sign of the fact he would offend".

Incompetent? You bet. A just result for the innocent? No way.

Commissioner Stewart has been attacked for his comments - but as often happens with highly inflammatory issues - people are going off half-cocked and missing the point he makes.

He is not saying to release reprobates into mainstream society and let them effectively "win" by getting away with their crimes.

Nor is he suggesting that violence offenders be cut loose.

His words were: "Serious recidivist offenders can expect nothing but the strongest reaction from us.

"But for those people who commit minor crime, who get involved with minor amounts of drugs, there are programs already in place, like the drug courts and diversion programs through courts, where we can start to move people out of the system."

This, to me, represents a modern, socially responsible approach to creating better communities.

Stewart goes on to say that we, as a society, need to look at "smarter ways of dealing with people who make minor errors and ones that can be perhaps diverted from the criminal justice system rather than being subsumed by it".

These could include expanding crime-prevention programs rather than acting after the fact.

Youth for whom poor parenting and a woeful home life characterised by violence, addiction and a chronic lack of discipline and respect are prone to falling foul of the law.

Whether through boredom, peer pressure, or a broken moral compass, they are on the fast track to becoming career criminals.

Throwing them in jail will ensure they succeed.

Being surrounded by hardened offenders has been shown to exacerbate bad behaviour not counter it. As if it could possibly be the other way around.

Andrew Day, a professor of psychology at Deakin University, says the recent, popular "get tough" approach on crime that relies on punishment alone has failed to make communities safer.

Rather, they have resulted in an expanded - and costly - prison system.

Dr Day, writing in The Conversation, says psychologists have been studying punishment under well-controlled laboratory conditions with both animals and humans for nearly 100 years.

For punishment to work, it has to be predictable, intense and immediate. In reality, these three factors rarely exist in any justice system.

Where there is genuine opportunity to correct behaviour is in good policies and programs that focus on rehabilitation.

Cognitive-behavioural therapy, Dr Day says, targets a narrow range of crime-producing desires - thoughts and values that support criminal conduct. It tries to change personality traits, such as low self-control, hostility, pleasure- or thrill-seeking and lack of empathy.

Certainly, not everyone can be successfully treated.

But Dr Day says "substantial evidence now exists to suggest that this type of approach does produce socially significant reductions in re-offending".

The challenge then becomes delivering the right type of programs to the right people at the right time.

And this, I believe, is what Ian Stewart is taking about.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Day</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Stewart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
