<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404450052912353</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-01/the-bullet-in-the-neck-was-only-the-start-of-the-nightmare-for-abc-correspondent-adam-harvey/1690212</url>
  <title>The bullet in the neck was only the start of the nightmare for ABC correspondent Adam Harvey</title>
  <content>
Getting shot was not the most frightening thing to happen to me in Marawi.
The terrifying moments came later, when I was transferred from a medical clinic on the edge of town to a hospital in the centre of the contested city, that then came under attack by Islamic State.
I was lying on a gurney, still a bit shocked at seeing an X-ray of my neck featuring a perfectly-formed M16 bullet lodged deep in the tissue, not too far off my spine.

Photo:(ABC News)
As I was being pushed through the hospital, the gunfire began to get louder.
And then it became impossible to ignore the gunshots. The single cracks became loud crashes - like someone had dropped a metal tray beside us - then became sustained, heavy gunfire, the sounds bouncing off the interior walls of the hospitals as a platoon of soldiers stationed there began returning fire.
The doctor treating me paused for a moment. "Oh my God that is close," she said, looking rattled, which in itself was a bit bracing.
A chaotic battle where snipers lurked in narrow streets

It would take quite a bit to unnerve the medical staff at the Amai Pakpak Hospital.
They'd been working in a battle zone for a month, since local Islamists aligned with IS took the city on May 23.
Plenty of civilians stayed - either to guard their homes, or because IS wouldn't let them leave - and more wounded were coming in each day.

External Link:

X-ray tweet
Philippine soldiers began running through the hospital, peering out through the windows to try to work out where the Islamists were.
Cameraman Phil Hemingway, who had continued filming since I was shot, dropped the camera for a moment and caught producer Geoff Thompson's eye.
"We need to get out of here," Phil said. Geoff nodded.
It was frightening and dangerous. But the whole city felt like this - confused and chaotic, with 'safe zones' turning out to be nothing of the sort.
The army controlled the roads leading to IS-held areas, but it was clear that the battle lines were porous, and snipers had got behind the government positions.
In this ghost town we were able to walk up to the army positions, often not knowing there was anyone there until we walked past a doorway and saw the soldiers sheltering inside the darkened two-storey buildings that crowded the city's narrow streets, as some protection from constant sniper fire.
One young soldier clutched a 50-year-old M16 that could well have been used in the Vietnam War. A lot of surplus US Army equipment ends up in the Philippines.
"These guns are very bad," he said. His weapon overheats after a few shots and then jams.
He had spare ammunition strapped to his chest, just in case the weapon kept going in a firefight, but he'd bought it all himself - the military forces its soldiers to buy their own spare ammunition.
"They have new guns," he said, nodding towards the IS positions on the other side of the Agus River.

Video:(ABC News)
Real people, real stories ... but the danger was real as well

Unrestricted access is a journalist's dream, but the days are long gone when correspondents could jump on a military chopper and ride to the heart of any hot zone they wanted, like Michael Herr in Dispatches.
You're mostly miles away from the action, on the wrong side of a roadblock, arguing fruitlessly with some guy with a clipboard.

External Link:

Tweet from Adam Harvey with photo: "What a legend - Dr Emmanuel Ibay - spent an hour teasing bullet from my neck. It stopped 1cm from the cartoid artery. 'Home run' if hit."
But sometimes, on big, chaotic stories, if you're there early enough, you're free to gather the most compelling material - like after the first Bali bomb in 2002, when I could accompany families searching for the bodies of their friends and relatives in the open-air morgue in Denpasar.
Or in New Orleans in 2005, after Hurricane Katrina, when I drove unimpeded through an abandoned city to the squalid convention centre, where thousands of African-American refugees had been stranded for three days without help.
They needed food, water and toilets. What they got was a lone medical team of a couple of doctors who sprinted in as if they were under fire, surrounded by a nervous posse of soldiers who aimed their weapons at the passive crowd.
In Marawi, there were few restrictions. Our safety was up to us.
Bullets came very close three times: twice they hit a street a couple of metres away just as Phil and I were about to step into it, and once a single sniper shot dinged a metal sign just above our heads.
We both looked up, realised what just happened and ran, exhaling with relief when we finally got around the corner.

Photo:(ABC News: Eliza Harvey)
Working in the hot zone was the only way to do what we'd come for: trying to make people in Australia care about what was happening in a city they'd never heard of.
We needed to find real people and tell their stories - like the soldier with the jamming rifle who bought his own ammunition.
At one forward checkpoint we found a group of police officers who'd just escaped after three weeks hiding in a basement in the battle zone.
. All of them would have been murdered if IS had caught them.

Photo:(ABC News: Eliza Harvey)
Later, we filmed the interrogation of three evacuees who were being treated as IS suspects, mainly because they were suspiciously clean, well-fed and healthy.
We came to tell these people's stories, but when I got shot I became the story too.
It wasn't meant to be that way but my injury allowed us even closer to the fighting and gave us crucial access to people. Like the doctors at the hospital and the civilian patients, including a woman with raw, seeping gunshot wounds to her legs.
She didn't have a team of people organising to get her out of Marawi and into the best care available in Manila like I did.
The scenes from the hospital have allowed us to put this Foreign Correspondent story to air with rich, compelling material.
Getting shot was just unlucky, but I'd go back in a heartbeat

I'd go back to Marawi in a heartbeat.
The story about IS taking a foothold in our region is important and one that I'll continue to report on, particularly after this gang of militants are eventually beaten and people can tell us what it's like to live with the murderous thugs.
I'm not cavalier about the risks but I'm not traumatised by the incident either. I was unlucky.
But there's a price to assignments like this, other than the scar on my neck.
Our families - Phil's, Geoff's, our fixer Boy's and driver Nor's - were all terrified, long before the bullet found me. They weren't so worried about us being shot by a random IS bullet.
I know  about the area's lucrative cottage industry of kidnap for ransom.
When I was shot Eliza dropped everything except our baby daughter and flew to Manila.
There's one shot on the raw camera footage of Eliza, holding nine-month-old Isla, pleading with my surgeon, the extraordinary Emmanuel Ibay.
"Can you please tell Adam not to go back to Marawi," she says.
"I have!" Dr Ibay replies.
"We've had enough now," she says.

External Link:

Facebook video
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Emmanuel Ibay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Hemingway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M16</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marawi</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denpasar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hurricane Katrina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Ibay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eliza Harvey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amai Pakpak Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Herr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emmanuel Ibay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MANILA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Orleans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Harvey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agus River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eliza</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Correspondent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
