<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404763585529858</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-students-drug-shame-shock-figures-reveal-pro/3207357/</url>
  <title>Coast students drug shame: Shock figures reveal problem</title>
  <content>
CHILDREN as young as nine are being suspended from the region's schools for misconduct involving drugs, tobacco and alcohol.
According to the Department of Education and Training in 2016 two suspensions were dolled out in the North Coast region (including the Sunshine Coast) to Year 4 students for misconduct involving illicit substances and two Year 6 students were excluded - 10 drug-related suspensions were recorded overall for primary school students.
As for high school, experimental Year 8 students accounted for the majority of problems with illicit substances, racking up 55 suspensions and 10 exclusions.
There have been two high-profile cases of drugs in Coast schools this year, with one incident requiring several girls be taken to hospital.
In May, three Coolum State High School Year 11 and 12 students were hospitalised after taking Lyrica - a drug used to treat nerve pain and seizures - during a lunch break.
One of the girls was knocked unconscious by the drug and suffered seizures.
Less than a week later, four girls from Nambour State College were suspended after footage from Snapchat showed them smoking a bong on school property while in uniform.
It's not just drugs that have students missing school - tobacco, alcohol and other legal substances are also a big issue.
In 2016 the youngest children in the region to be suspended for misconduct involving tobacco and other legal substances were in Year 4, with four incidents recorded.
Year 10 students were seemingly the problem children with 107 suspensions and one exclusion for the same reason.
The next highest offenders were Year 11 students with 88 suspensions.
The Queensland Department of Education and Training have been contacted to provide a break-down of misconducts in Sunshine Coast schools.
This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Noosa is mourning the loss of bright, bubbly mother Sharon Cuthbert
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Department of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 4</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum State High School Year 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapchat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyrica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
