<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404716340888693</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-advice/travellers-stories/adorable-kid-fistbumps-everyone-on-his-flight/news-story/10da92645ac76ee44e02711d56c1cf40</url>
  <title>Adorable kid fist-bumps everyone on his flight</title>
  <content>
Fist-Bumping 2-Year-Old Boards Airplane in Style, Wins Hearts of Other Passengers. Credit - Instagram/mamaj1822 via Storyful
0:54

A toddler made sure he boarded his Southwest Airlines flight from Kansas City International Airport in style, if a video shared by his mother on July 21 is any indication. Two-year-old Guy walked down the plane's aisle, gleefully fist-bumping everybody he could. His mom, Alya Jakubowicz, shared an adorable clip of his grand entrance to her Instagram account, writing, "My son on the campaign trail, attempting to win the hearts of airline passengers in the hopes of becoming the next Southwest ambassador." A version of her video was posted to the Southwest Airlines Facebook page, who later shared the video of Guy themselves. Southwest's post had over 68,000 likes on Facebook at the time of writing. According to Jakubowicz, who spoke with KGTV about her video, Guy learned about fist-bumping while on a flight to Dallas when he was 18 months, and has been obsessed with it ever since. Credit: Instagram/mamaj1822 via Storyful

August 1st 2017
8 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

A little boy named Guy has made everyone's day on a flight. Picture: Instagram/mamaj1822

Share

AIR travel can seem scary at times - but this kid is here to remind us everything is great.
An adorable two-year-old boy has been filmed by his mum walking up the aisle of a plane, stopping to offer a friendly fist-bump to everyone he passes.
Alya Jakubowicz posted the Instagram video of her son, Guy, greeting passengers on their Southwest Airlines flight from Kansas City to Chicago.

A post shared by Alya J (@mamaj1822) on

The little fella can be seen tottering down the aisle, dragging his blanket behind him and giving a friendly fist-bump to everyone he passes. Passengers can be heard laughing and commenting on how cute he is, in what must have been a delightful start to their hour-long flight.
Alya said little Guy was "on the campaign trail, attempting to win the hearts of airline passengers in the hopes of becoming the next Southwest ambassador".
"He is making the flying the friendly skies even friendlier with one fist bump at a time," .
Alya's post was later shared by Southwest Airlines on its Facebook page, where Guy won over a whole new legion of admirers.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southwest Airlines Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alya Jakubowicz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bumping 2-Year-Old Boards Airplane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KGTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southwest Airlines</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alya J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alya</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kansas City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kansas City International Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hearts of Other</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southwest</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jakubowicz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
