<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404720635856165</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/geelongs-dangerfield-challenge-decision</url>
  <title>No challenge: Danger's Brownlow hopes over</title>
  <content>
Kreuzer left dazed after Danger tackle
Matthew Kreuzer has left the ground after a hard tackle from Patrick Dangerfield.

The MRP offered Patrick Dangerfield a one-match ban for his tackle on Matthew Kreuzer

PATRICK Dangerfield's Brownlow Medal hopes are over after Geelong decided not to appeal his one-match ban for a tackle on Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer that left the Blues ruckman concussed.

The suspension means the Cats superstar is ineligible to win a second successive Brownlow.

If the Cats had chosen to challenge the ban they would have risked Dangerfield missing a second match, with Friday night's clash against Sydney followed by a crunch game against top-four rival Richmond in round 21.

Richmond midfielder Dustin Martin is now the hot favourite to win the league's best-and-fairest award.

has the Tiger a massive 13 votes ahead of the next eligible player, Hawthorn's Tom Mitchell, with four games remaining.

More to come

PATRICK Dangerfield's Brownlow Medal hopes remain alive for the moment after Geelong decided to appeal his one-match ban for a tackle on Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer that left the Blues ruckman concussed.

The decision means the AFL Tribunal will on Tuesday night to decide the Cats superstar's fate.

If the challenge is unsuccessful Dangerfield will miss a second match, with Friday night's clash against Sydney followed by a crunch game against top-four rival Richmond in round 21.

Dangerfield has been in stellar form in 2017, with he and Richmond midfielder Dustin Martin the standout challengers for the Brownlow.

has Martin eight votes ahead of Dangerfield, with Hawthorn's Tom Mitchell a further five votes back, with just four rounds remaining.

More to come

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn's Tom Mitchell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danger's Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PATRICK Dangerfield's Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
