<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403767153099860</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/game-of-thrones-thrown-into-chaos-as-hackers-leak-top-secret-scripts/news-story/1a36efbd6b41b746d1cdc5b903f7a5b4</url>
  <title>GoT in chaos: Hackers leak secret scripts online</title>
  <content>
LEAKED scripts from upcoming episodes of Game Of Thrones have been released online - throwing the hit series into chaos, The Sun reports.
Hackers, who breached HBO's systems,  and, according to Entertainment Weekly, have threatened to leak more.
In a statement, HBO said: HBO recently experienced a cyber incident, which resulted in the compromise of proprietary information.
LISTEN TO OUR GAME OF THRONES PODCAST
"We immediately began investigating the incident and are working with law enforcement and outside cybersecurity firms.
"Data protection is a top priority at HBO, and we take seriously our responsibility to protect the data we hold."
As well as, it's reported scripts form popular shows, including Ballers have also appeared online.
Entertainment Weekly published a letter sent to the company's staff by the HBO chairman Richard Plepler.
In the note, he told staff their teams were working "around the clock" to stop the hackers.
They also revealed the letter sent to reporters after the hackers gained access.
The anonymous email said: "Hi to all mankind. The greatest leak of cyber space era is happening. What's its name? Oh I forget to tell.
"You are lucky to be the first pioneers to witness and download the leak. Enjoy it & spread the words.
Whoever spreads well, we will have an interview with him. HBO is falling."
In total, there will be eight series of the fantasy epic - meaning this series will start tying up loose ends.
There are seven episodes in this season, andthat the final season will only have six instalments.
Maisie Williams, who plays Arya Stark, has also revealed season seven will end on a "massive cliffhanger".
She made the confession in a chat with Time Out magazine, revealing the storyline will "crash down" as Game of Thrones moves towards its conclusion.
The final eighth season will air in mid-2018.
This story originally appeared on  and is republished here with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maisie Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Weekly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arya Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Plepler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
