<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404720635856156</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/beauty/zoe-kravitz-appointed-ysl-global-ambassador-proving-its-her-best-year-yet-20170731-gxmq63.html</url>
  <title>Zoe Kravitz appointed YSL global ambassador, proving it's her best year yet</title>
  <content>
Ever since the scene in Big Little Lies in which Zoe Kravitz's character dances in front of all the shell-shocked dadbods at a kid's birthday party it's been hard to shake our Zoe Kravitz obsession. 
I mean: talk about mesmerising. Photo: Elodie Daguin
And it seems the worlds of beauty and luxury can't get enough of the starpower of Lenny Kravtiz and Lisa Bonet's daughter either, with the actress just appointed as the global ambassador for YSL Beauty. It follows Kravitz' appearance in campaigns for the likes of Calvin Klein and Tiffany & Co and her anointment from Vogue UK as . Proof that this is Kravitz' year and we're just living/ogling her in it.
In a statement, YSL said Kravitz is "the perfect fit for YSL's own inventive, defiant and stylish heritage".
And Kravitz herself said she was delighted to be working with one of her "favourite brands."
"Their ability to combine the chicest [sic] of style with a raw edge has always been to me one of the best ways to express yourself through fashion and beauty. Nothing is forced, nothing is fake but everything is bold, strong and unafraid."

Kravitz's new gig will kick off in August with a campaign for the Tatouage Couture range.
Earlier this year Kravitz  to Net-a-Porter's The Edit on the challenges that she still faces in casting.

You will now receive updates from

Daily Life Newsletter

Daily Life Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"When my name is brought up in a casting office, I'm sure the fact that I'm black comes up in discussions. I just read a script in which there were two couples, and one was written as black. When I talked to the directors, they said I should play the wife of the black guy. It's insane that they still think the black girl needs to be married to the black guy, and everyone else is white. Their thinking is so compartmentalised," she said. 
The actress is set to star in Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them 2 and most recently appeared in the female comedy, Rough Night which also starred our other fantasy BFF, Ilana Glazer from Broad City. 
Until then, guess we're just googling images of Kravitz and practising her dance moves in the mirror?  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BFF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calvin Klein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YSL Beauty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elodie Daguin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatouage Couture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Little Lies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vogue UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Find Them 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Bonet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Net-a-Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broad City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YSL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ilana Glazer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kravitz</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fantastic Beast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiffany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lenny Kravtiz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Kravitz</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
