<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404458642847124</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/southwest/yeerongpilly-mp-mark-bailey-wants-brisbane-city-council-to-fund-duplicate-walter-taylor-bridge/news-story/536e185f03fad47e634a20762ed3b332</url>
  <title>Pressure mounts for second bridge</title>
  <content>
HUNDREDS of people are expected to turn up for a public rally this Saturday in a bid to pressure Brisbane City Council to build another bridge over the Brisbane River at Chelmer.
State Labor MP for Yeerongpilly, Mark Bailey, said it was disgraceful that the council was prepared to spend $650 million "goldplating'' Kingsford Smith Drive when no money had been set aside for a duplicate Walter Taylor Bridge.
Mr Bailey distributed 5500 flyers in the area last weekend calling on residents to back his #TaylorTwo campaign.
He has also launched a dedicated Facebook page and Twitter account, a petition and e-petition, which he expected would draw thousands of signatures because traffic congestion was the number-one issue for people in his electorate.
"Under this proposal Walter Taylor Bridge, which is currently one lane in each direction, would be two lanes northbound only,'' Mr Bailey said.
"TaylorTwo would be two lanes, southbound.
"The LNP council are spending $650 million turning two lanes into three lanes on Kingsford Smith Drive right now, yet nothing at all on dealing with just one lane across the river on the
Walter Taylor Bridge. It's time our local area on the southside got the same respect, attention and funding as the northside.''
Mr Bailey said traffic was so bad during the morning peak period car stretched back several kilometres on the southside of the river.
He said developments in Chelmer, Sherwood and Graceville, some up to seven storeys high, were putting increasing pressure on the existing bridge.
Mr Bailey, who until recently was the transport minister, did not comment on whether he believed the State Government would be prepared to contribute to the cost, but insisted the council had the capacity to fund it as its budget was similar to that of Tasmania.
Councillor Nicole Johnston (Tennyson) supported longterm planning for another bridge, but said it was unfunded and the proposed route funnelling cars towards Coonan St was a vague "dotted line on a map for a new park''.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelmer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeerongpilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillor Nicole Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coonan St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Taylor Bridge</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Bailey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingsford Smith Drive</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tennyson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graceville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bailey</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Labor MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TaylorTwo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
