<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404205239771917</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/01/comment-how-know-what-youre-getting-when-you-buy-free-range-eggs</url>
  <title>Comment: How to know what you're getting when you buy free range eggs</title>
  <content>
Even when egg cartons are legally accurate, the government definition of 'free range' might not mean what you think it does.

By

Heather Bray
Source:

The Conversation

9 MINS AGO  UPDATED 3 MINS AGO

Last week, egg producer Snowdale Holdings was penalised A$1 million for . Snowdale, one of the biggest producers in the Australian market, owns brands including Eggs by Ellah, Swan Valley Free Range, and Wanneroo Free Range.

Given the significantly higher prices generally charged for free range eggs, you could be forgiven for having doubts over what you're getting in the supermarket. Even when egg cartons are legally accurate, the government definition of "free range" might not mean what you think it does.

But you don't need to shop blind: there are a range of resources that can help you find egg producers that follow best-practise standards, avoid farming practices that concern you and understand what government guidelines really mean.

Related reading

What's in an egg label?

has shown that people buy free range eggs for a range of reasons, including taste and quality, as well as concern for animal welfare.

But unlike other labels such as nutritional information panels or best-before dates, the "free range" claim is not regulated by Food Standards Australia New Zealand (FSANZ). In fact, no claims about production methods are subject to this kind of regulation.  by FSANZ is about what a food contains, rather than how it is produced.

However, there is an , created in March 2016 under Australian consumer law. Essentially, it means that the chickens have "meaningful and regular access to the outdoors" and that outdoor stocking densities are no more than 10,000 birds per hectare.

This has been , with  and  arguing that this is not what most people would consider free range, while producer groups have .

The new regulations also requires producers to "prominently disclose" the outdoor stocking density, and we are now starting to see that on packaging.

Related reading

What does free range really mean?

In practice, stocking chooks at 10,000 per hectare and giving them regular access to the outdoors, might not result in animals that are especially free (or "cruelty-free" - another claim showing up on an increasing number of egg cartons).

For a start, CSIRO has published a  that recommends farmers should have no more than 1,500 birds per hectare. If you want to buy from producers that meet that standard, the consumer group Choice has an app called  that can scan egg cartons in the store and give immediate feedback on the brand's farming conditions.

Choice also provides a table of . Reading that table - and from my own discussions with Australian egg producers - it's clear that price is not a totally reliable indicator of stocking density.

However, stocking density is only one factor in how hens are treated. Some independent certifications have more stringent guidelines. The , as well as specifying a maximum of 1,500 birds per hectare for set stocking systems and 2,500 for rotational systems, also prohibits practices like withholding feed and water to induce moulting.

The Australian Organic certification indicates a lower stocking density, and more stringent cruelty-free practises, than the government definition of 'free range'. Australian Certified Organic

Hens naturally moult in autumn, when they  while their reproductive tract rejuvenates. For greater control over when hens produce eggs, as well as extending their hens' laying lives, farmers can induce moulting by . Although heavily regulated at the state level in Australia (hens may not go without food entirely for ), it is .

Similarly  recommends a maximum of 1,500 birds per hectare. And unlike the government definition of free range, which calls for "meaningful and regular" access to the outside, Humane Choice standards specify that hens can "forage on the land, move untethered and uncaged".

Of course, it is important to note that free range farms are not free of animal welfare issues, such as , where hens pull out the feathers of other birds. There are further challenges is managing exposure to weather or predators to consider.  that consumers should be able to choose from a range of production methods.

However, if animal welfare, sustainability, and labelling are things that you are concerned about, then do your own research and identify the products that align with your values. Don't rely on a label to tell you what is ethical.

Heather Bray's salary is partly funded by an Australian Research Council Linkage Project (LP130100419) which includes contributions from industry partners Coles Group Ltd, Elders Limited, Richard Gunner's Fine Meats Pty Ltd, and the South Australian Research and Development Institute. She is currently undertaking consultancy work for Animal Health Australia. She received scholarships from the Pig Research and Development Corporation (now Australian Pork Limited) between 1991 and 1997. The University of Adelaide is a partner in the Animal Welfare Science Centre.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Research Council Linkage Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 3 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Gunner's Fine Meats Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSIRO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles Group Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Food Standards Australia New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Certified Organic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pig Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Animal Health Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swan Valley Free Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Animal Welfare Science Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanneroo Free Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Pork Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Humane Choice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snowdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LP130100419</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snowdale Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heather Bray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Organic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FSANZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
