<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404720635856064</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/new-perspective-helps-hawthorn-star-jarryd-roughead-appreciate-footy-more-20170801-gxmrfo.html</url>
  <title>New perspective helps Hawthorn star Jarryd Roughead appreciate footy more</title>
  <content>
Hawthorn captain Jarryd Roughead has a new appreciation for footy after overcoming his recent cancer scares.
The four-time premiership star will play his 250th match on Sunday when the Hawks face Richmond at the MCG.

Up Next

Nick Riewoldt announces retirement

01:42

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

But that milestone seemed a long way off last year when he was diagnosed with a recurrence of melanoma which had spread to his lungs.
Consequently, the utility had to sit out the entire 2016 season after also suffering a nasty knee injury earlier in the year.Photo: Paul Jeffers
In 2015, Roughead was first diagnosed with melanoma and needed a lesion removed from his lip but only missed two games.
Those experiences have taught Roughead that there is more to life than footy and as a result he now has a more relaxed approach to the game he loves.

"The injuries you understand happen with footy but with what happened last year, your perspective changes a fair bit and you understand that footy's not everything," Roughead said at Waverley Park on Tuesday.
"You think it is after you grow up, you move from home at 17 and move to here and you've been here for 12 years.Photo: AAP
"I've probably relaxed a little bit. A lot of people would know that you have a little bit of OCD and your routine's a little bit different but it's probably relaxed since I've come back which has been good."
Reaching the 250-game milestone wasn't a priority for Roughead as he was battling to resurrect his AFL career during a very difficult 2016; instead, simply playing footy again was the aim.
"At the start of the year when I was coming back I didn't think about this [milestone]," he said.
"When I got the all-clear to come back and play it was just about playing footy again because once something is taken away from you that you've known since you were 17 years old, you want to get back and try and play as quickly as you can."
The challenges didn't end when he made his momentous return to the playing field, with Hawthorn losing their first four matches this year by an average of 55 points as they sank to the bottom of the ladder.
Roughead admitted there were times where he questioned his own ability as a leader during that period.
"It's obviously not ideal," he said. "I heard [first-year Sydney captain] Josh Kennedy say last week that you kind of look at yourself and ask the question whether it's your fault and you do go through those moments but at the end of the day you understand it's a totally different side to what I've known in the past and what everyone else has.
"So when you get to these situations you've just got to try and get through as best as you can because you learn on the fly."
The seas have become a lot less choppier in recent times, with the Hawks undergoing an incredible form transformation, despite missing a host of key players, that has seen them match it with premiership contenders Adelaide, Sydney, Geelong and GWS.
Hawthorn are now six points outside the top eight and while finals might be a stretch this year, Roughead is confident that his club is back on the path towards its next premiership.
"To be able to play the footy that we have since the bye pretty much, that in itself is exciting for the group and the fans and it gives us a chance to go into the off-season knowing that we've played some good footy and build another pre-season into these boys," he said.
"If you look at the side, especially with the kids that are under 23, in the past they've probably come in and filled the gaps and played one or two games and they feel like they've got to do something really special to stay in the side whereas now they're the little group within the team that are driving the standards and they're going to be the future of the footy club.
"They've been given pretty important roles in the last few weeks and really feel like they're a part of AFL footy and the Hawthorn Football Club."
The rapid improvement of the Hawks' youngsters in the second half of the season might have shocked many, but not Roughead.
"They've almost done an apprenticeship at the VFL," he said. "To be able to have six or seven guys come through and play good footy, we've known that they can do it because down at Box Hill it's exactly the same game plan so it's just a matter of getting their chance."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waverley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
