<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404840894942365</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/leadership/better-health-became-core-purpose-for-medibanks-george-savvides-20170727-gxjtyg</url>
  <title>'Better health' became good business for Medibank's George Savvides</title>
  <content>
by
George Savvides

Former  chief -George Savvides led formerly government owned health insurer for 14 years, through a public listing in 2014, and stepped down in 2016. He describes why, before the float, his focus shifted from financial metrics to purpose.
After fixing the burning platform, the senior execs and I discovered that financial viability, although important, was not the key challenge in our assignment. I noticed that our people were still a bit flat and the financial turnaround was not enough to fuel the passion we needed to transform the business into providing what our customers really expected of us.
Whilst financial stability was important, our customers wanted us to provide assurance and peace of mind when navigating the health system. More than paying their health bills, ie health insurance, they wanted health assurance.
So it became clear that the leadership challenge was to connect more deeply with our purpose, ie to provide better health, rather than stay in the "business as usual" domain of paying bills. After presenting the concept of purpose to my executive team, we decided that the best way to achieve organisational transformation from health insurance to health assurance was to give our leaders and supervisors the time and space to dialogue and discover in their own work context the deep need our customers have for the provision of health assurance.

Glenn Hunt

Better health

As they became excited about the enhanced relevance and significance that such a change would bring to our customers and our jobs, we invited them to sign up for the purpose journey. The response was powerful and the organisation was energised for change from bill payer to health player, which was captured in the Purpose Statement "...we stand for better health."
This impacted product design, provider contracting, health system capability and recruitment. What have been, or are expected to be, the main benefits? Our ability to articulate our purpose at every level of the organisation meant that our staff became the Purpose Statement in word and attitude; it communicated to our customers and other stakeholders the reason we exist and the response was positive and respectful. Our ability to know why we exist acted as a filter for strategic decision making in services offered and in business acquired.
Purpose became the strategic filter that we used to drive organisational alignment and change. Operating in a tough competitive environment meant there were always everyday business challenges, like big seas on an ocean voyage and sometimes resistance like headwinds, but our clarity of purpose acted like a keel that kept us steady and held us together with teamwork alignment.
Our organisation-wide clarity of purpose, "for better health", gave us much greater confidence and conviction in our decision making including, for example, our decisions to acquire healthcare capabilities in other companies, or boldly asking our contracted hospitals to take accountability for improved clinical performance and safety, which meant they, the hospital, not the patient nor their health fund, would pay for their mistakes when they occurred outside pre-agreed tolerances.

Wayne Taylor

Purpose a flywheel

Our ability to articulate our purpose acted like a flywheel that gave us forward momentum and more resilient performance that was more durable than short-term results.
Looking in the rear-vision mirror, purpose has been far more transformational than I could have possibly imagined when we initially set out to discover it. What are your recommendations to others in relation to purpose? If you build your strategy on a clear understanding of your organisation's purpose it will be much more durable and more likely to give you a sustainable competitive advantage.
Purpose will take your organisation closer to what your customers or stakeholders desire you to be. Focusing your organisation on fulfilling its purpose reduces the distraction of executive individualism or ambition. Purpose keeps you invested in team alignment and customer needs; it's also a natural fuel for problem solving and innovation. Whilst purpose is intangible, it unlocks the tangible power of humanity by getting both head and heart engaged in work.

Purpose will give you great momentum, but purpose and the momentum it generates can easily dissipate if you don't continue to live and breathe purpose in an authentic way. Purpose will demand values and behaviours consistent with the goals of the mission. If they are not upheld, the engagement of the team will be discouraged and passion fail. In short, purpose transforms companies by transforming the motive and behaviour of leaders and their teams.
Edited extract from Why Purpose Matters by Nicholas Barnett & Rodney Howard (Major Street Publishing $34.95)

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Purpose Matters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major Street Publishing $34.95</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Savvides</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Purpose Statement</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medibank's George Savvides</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas Barnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
