<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404797945268768</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/new-zealand-labour-opposition-leader-andrew-little-quits-amid-poor-polls-20170801-gxmr26.html</url>
  <title>New Zealand Labour Opposition Leader Andrew Little quits amid poor polls</title>
  <content>
Wellington: New Zealand Opposition Leader Andrew Little has quit just two months before the country goes to the polls.
Little fell on his sword on Tuesday, saying the focus on this week's "very, very disappointing" poll results was distracting from the Labour Party's messages.Photo: Bloomberg
A cloud has persisted over his leadership since two disastrous poll results from One News Colmar Brunton and Newshub Reid Research that recorded support for the party at just 24 per cent.
A third, by Labour's own pollsters, UMR, put support at just 23 per cent, low enough to even leave Little's position as a list MP in doubt.Photo: New Zealand Labour Party
Little said, as leader, he had to take responsibility for the poll results and the narrative that was preventing Labour getting their message across.
No one has yet publicly declared their candidacy for leadership, although deputy Jacinda Ardern is expected to, possibly with Maori MP Kelvin Davis as her deputy.

Little said she would have his full support.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Labour MP Carmel Sepuloni stood alongside Little during his announcement.
"Politics is hard. Of course Andrew's done a great job for us and we admire the fact that he's made this decision to step aside," she said.
"You feel of two minds - there's a little bit of sadness but we've got to get on with the job and that's winning the election."
Little said his colleagues were as deeply disappointed as he was with the recent results and had been warm in their support of him and his decision.
The New Zealand general election will be held on Saturday, September 23.
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One News Colmar Brunton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand's Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Opposition Leader Andrew Little</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UMR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinda Ardern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maori MP Kelvin Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newshub Reid Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Labour Opposition Leader Andrew Little</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour MP Carmel Sepuloni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
