<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404849484877241</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/east/retro-gem-attracts-young-buyers-420000-gain-in-five-years/news-story/5421667d9ef0a7d55391534cd840982c</url>
  <title>Retro gem attracts young buyers, $420,000 gain in five years - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
sold for $901,000 at auction on July 29.

A HEATHMONT home has topped $900,000 at auction and its previous sale price by more than $400,000, just five years after it last changed hands.
Hocking Stuart Ringwood senior sales consultant Naiomi Bentley said the three-bedroom home at , built by project house builder Merchant Builders, had won young buyers over with its seventies style.
They led the charge at its July 29 auction, Ms Bentley said.
"We had an opening bid of $800,00, there were four bidders, and it sold under the hammer," she said.
"Two bidders were going strong from $870,000 onwards.
"It sold about $20,000 over the reserve."

Timber-lined ceilings with exposed beams feature throughout the interior.

CoreLogic records show the property last changed hands in April 2012 for $480,000, meaning its latest sale price is an improvement of $421,000, an almost 88 per cent rise.
Ms Bentley said the gain was indicative of recent strong price growth in the area.
"Particularly in the last 18 months or so," she said.
The vendors had painted the property's exterior and enclosed its carport, but no major renovations had been done since it last sold, she added.
Ms Bentley said a young couple from St Kilda won the keys to the home, ahead of two other young couples seeking their second homes, and a first-home buyer couple.
"They loved the style of the house and the natural feel of it, being a Merchant Builders home," she said.
"They had been looking for around seven or eight months."

Large windows with garden outlooks are another prominent feature of its design.

Ms Bentley said young buyers from closer to the city were frequently coming out to the area to find homes.
"Most are coming from the inner city," she said.
"It's price, and often a lot of them have grown up in the area as well."

No major renovations had been done since the property's last sale.

The home was built circa-1975, CoreLogic records show.
It features a single-level floorplan, a design that emphasises garden outlooks, and timber-lined ceilings with exposed beams.
Ms Bentley said homes like it had been appealing to a much larger, mostly younger, audience recently.
"Being a bit retro and with that style coming back in, especially in terms of interiors and furniture, I think that's why it appealed," she said.
SEE SUBURB PROFILE:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merchant Builders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naiomi Bentley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hocking Stuart Ringwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HEATHMONT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUBURB PROFILE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bentley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
