<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404845189909705</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/boss/karl-fender-architect-20170717-gxcnsq</url>
  <title>Why Architect Karl Fender shops as fast as possible</title>
  <content>
by
Katarina Kroslakova

Architect Karl Fender is a partner in , the firm that designed the Museum of Old and New Art in Tasmania, Melbourne's Eureka Tower and Canberra's new Hotel Hotel.
Why the traditional architect dress?
People are often amused about architects dressing in black, but the old wives' tale goes that black was a pragmatic choice as it didn't show the graphite stains. I like it because it offers no distraction. It gets rid of the mix and match issues, black is quite slimming and it messages design, doesn't it?
What's your daily uniform?

Josh Robenstone

I usually wear a suit because I never know what meetings are going to jump up at me. I'm always in meetings. This Girbaud suit is fantastic, it's made out of a stretchy material, it's laser cut, has the appropriate amount of stylishness and I feel good in it.

Do you enjoy clothes shopping?
No, it's something I try to do as fast as possible, that's why knowing your brands is good. I'm not in bloody countless stores looking for something good.
Made to measure or off-the-peg?
I couldn't bear having tailors clambering over me with their tapes. Also, I like the convenience and clarity of seeing something, liking it and having it adjusted that same day.

Does it take you long to get dressed?
I live in the Eureka Tower and my office is over the road. I can wake up and be sitting at my desk in 15 minutes.
What about your weekend wardrobe?
The bottom half does stay black, but the T-shirts get a bit of colour. I wear mostly my golf T-shirts, which I tend to buy in the pro shops when I'm travelling.

Are you partial to a nice watch?
I've got a few watches to suit the mood: a Porsche, a Cartier, a U-Boat, a Georg Jensen. I tend to wear them for a few weeks and then swap them. If I'm travelling, my Breitling is robust and luminous and easy to see at night.
Where are your spectacles from?
I was walking down one of the little laneways in Venice and saw this shop called Micromega, with outrageous spectacles; designs I've never seen before, like something performers would wear. I saw a few pairs I really liked, including these ones, which are incredibly light and give me three bands of vision. So many people have commented on them. They are brilliantly made. It's Italian craftsmanship at its best. Every time I go back to Venice for the Architecture Biennale every two years, I get more spectacles from that same shop. It's a family-owned company. Apparently Elton John and Madonna are customers there too.

Do you remember your first proper luxury purchase?
It was a Versace shirt, which I bought on impulse in Paris 25 years ago. At the time, it cost me $1500. It had just come off the runway shows, it was black, of course, made from an incredible material. It was very comfy, it worked casually and formally, and it got me through many occasions through many years. I couldn't afford it, but I had to have it. Now that I don't wear it, I'll probably frame it.
Like Leadership with the Financial Review on . Follow us on . Join the  conversation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Girbaud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georg Jensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venice</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Fender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Micromega</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katarina Kroslakova</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Versace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Robenstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breitling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hotel Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Museum of Old</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eureka Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Art</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madonna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cartier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porsche</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Eureka Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Architect Karl Fender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U-Boat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Architecture Biennale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elton John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
