<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404849484877201</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/ufc/opinion-ufc-214-opens-a-window-into-the-ufcs-future-with-remergence-of-jon-jones-cris-cyborg/news-story/991b4f1ac4fd887dff2b069ff2fd3bc0</url>
  <title>Opinion: UFC 214 opens a window into UFC's future with remergence of Jon Jones, Cris Cyborg</title>
  <content>
Jon Jones looks on prior to a fight against Daniel Cormier.

Michael Blaustein

Share

FOR the first time in what feels like eons, a huge UFC event went down without a hitch.
All the fighters at UFC 214 made weight despite strict new rules in California that could have been a disaster. There were entertaining fights up and down the card. And two of the sport's biggest hibernating giants reminded everyone that there is a future beyond Ronda Rousey and Conor McGregor.
Jon Jones (23-1-0) and Cristiane "Cyborg" Justino (17-1-0) got first and third billing respectively on Saturday night (Sunday AEST) in Anaheim and they both, in their way, proved that they are the stars the UFC has been searching for.

KO stamps Jones' return
1:43

UFC: Jon Jones has knocked out Daniel Cormier to claim the fight and the belt

July 30th 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/More Sports/

Jones' rise to stardom is really a re-rise, because he was the first UFC fighter who had true crossover appeal. Winning the light heavyweight title at just 23-years-old, Jones was the youngest belt holder in UFC history and quickly got marketed as the baby-faced king of the sport. Picking up unprecedented endorsement deals with Nike and Gatorade, the young champ racked up win after win in his simple black shorts adorned in golden swooshes and green Gs.
Eventually building up a 21-1 record - his only loss coming via a disqualification due to illegal strikes in a fight with Matt Hamill - Jones was already being talked about as the greatest fighter of all time heading into his first fight with Daniel Cormier (19-2), at UFC 182 in 2015. Cormier, a former heavyweight titleholder in Strikeforce and Olympic wrestler, was 15-0 as he stepped into the cage with Jones.The titanic bout failed to live up to the hype. Cormier couldn't keep up with the younger, more dynamic Jones, who pulled away in the later rounds to win a five-round decision.
That's when Jones' world fell apart. There were hints of trouble in the pre-fight build up as the trash talk got extremely personal and a press conference devolved into a full-on brawl that cost Jones his Nike deal. Then he got caught using cocaine, was involved in a hit-and-run that injured a pregnant woman, and failed an anti-doping test just hours before UFC 200, where he was set to face Cormier.

Jones' classy message to DC
0:45

UFC: Jon Jones shows class, thanking Daniel Cormier for their incredible rivalry after defeating the champion in UFC 214

July 30th 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/More Sports/

For two years, Jones drifted between legal troubles and suspensions, while Cormier fought the best-of-the-best in the light heavyweight division knowing full well that his title meant nothing because Jones had whooped him.
As the two big men faded, McGregor exploded into the space they left behind. Less than a year after Jones-Cormier I, he knocked out Jose Aldo - a rival to Jones on the pound-for-pound greatest list - in 13 seconds. Then he had his two classic wars with Nate Diaz before his crowning glory at UFC 205 in Madison Square Garden back in November, when he became the first man to hold two titles in two divisions at the same time. McGregor's freak show boxing match with Floyd Mayweather is now sucking up all the air in the fight world, yet nobody knows what the Irishman is going to do afterwards.
Jones showed at UFC 214 that he is ready to step into the breach. Displaying next to no ring rust, he obliterated Cormier with a perfectly placed third-round head kick reminiscent of Holly Holm's masterpiece against Rousey. The kick immediately vaulted Jones back into the pound-for-pound conversation alongside McGregor and Demetrious "Mighty Mouse" Johnson, the flyweight champion who is nearly unknown outside MMA circles.

Jon Jones celebrates after knocking out Daniel Cormier.Source:AFP
Before Jones' rebirth, Justino earned the UFC gold her glittering career has always deserved. Fighting a badly outclassed Tonya Evinger, the Invicta FC bantamweight champion, Justino patiently broke down her foe before going in for the kill in the third round.
It was a surprisingly mature performance for Justino, who is the stuff of nightmare. Shockingly strong, savagely violent and unchallenged in her dominance, Cyborg is, in many ways, what everyone thought Rousey was before the former face of women's MMA was exposed a one-trick pony.
Justino's exciting style, knockout power and new belt should be enough to make her the new queen of the UFC. The throne is currently vacant, because bantamweight champion Amanda Nunes has yet to catch on - even though she's gotten top billing on two of the UFC's biggest cards - and strawweight champion Joanna Jedrzejczyk is such a technically brilliant striker that her fights often seem boring to casual fans.
The only thing that can stop Cyborg is her size. The featherweight division was created just for her because she flirts with death getting down to 140 pounds, much less the 135-pounds needed to fight at bantamweight. The issue is that there just aren't that many women in the world who naturally fight at 145 pounds.
The inaugural UFC featherweight champion, Germaine de Randamie, is too afraid to fight Justino and is now moving back down to 135 pounds. That leaves Megan Anderson (8-2), the Invicta featherweight champion who was scheduled to fight Cyborg at UFC 214 before dropping out for personal reasons, and 135 pounders like Evinger who are looking for a big payday.
UFC president Dana White admitted as much in the post fight press conference on Saturday night, when he revealed that Holm might be in line for another featherweight title shot after her disastrous display against de Randamie.

Cris Cyborg of Brazil reacts to defeating Tonya Evinger.Source:AFP
If Cyborg's problems are big, Jones' potential problems are larger than life.
Displaying new-found humbleness in the Octagon after beating Cormier, Jones' was full of praise for the former champion, who he called both a great man and a great fighter. It was a beautiful scene - even if it was followed by a controversial in-ring interview with a still woozy Cormier - that was almost ruined when Jones got back on the mic.
"Brock Lesnar, if you want to know what it's like to get your ass kicked by a guy that weighs 40 pounds less than you, meet me in the octagon." Jones said, dropping the mic.
Lesnar responded moments later, telling the Associated Press, "Be careful what you wish for, young man."
It's actually not a half bad idea for a fight if it weren't for the not-so-tiny problem of Lesnar's penchant for PEDs. Lesnar failed an anti-doping test at UFC 200, just like Jones - they even tested positive for the same drugs. The only difference is that Jones acquiesced to his suspension right away, while Lesnar has six months left on his because he retired earlier this year. As a result, the earliest the two titans could fight would be some time in 2018, if Lesnar comes out of retirement and submits to USADA testing today.

Jon Jones calls out Lesnar
0:36

UFC: Light heavyweight champion Jon Jones calls out Heavyweight Brock Lesnar after downing Daniel Cormier at UFC214

July 30th 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/More Sports/

So that fight isn't going to happen any time soon. That doesn't mean it isn't a harbinger of things to come. With each passing day, the UFC becomes more and more like the WWE. Big, huge, money-making fights are what the promotion wants - sporting legitimacy be damned.
Even Cyborg wants in on the fun.
The WWE-ification of the UFC is why we have McGregor-Mayweather, Jones-Lesnar, and even Georges St-Pierre vs. Michael Bisping,  after being cancelled, according to White. The reason it's back is because the UFC's welterweight champion, Tyron Woodley, who also fought at UFC 214, has put on three boring fights in a row. Thus, White took GSP away from Woodley after promising him the fight 24 hours earlier.
That's the UFC nowadays - it's about hype, and not about the quality of the fights.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dana White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyron Woodley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cris Cyborg of Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evinger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Lesnar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cris Cyborg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USADA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor-Mayweather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anaheim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanna Jedrzejczyk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cormier</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invicta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Hamill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>20</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germaine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bisping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nate Diaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWE-ification of the UFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Aldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cristiane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Blaustein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rousey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justino</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonya Evinger.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irishman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Cormier</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madison Square Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georges St-Pierre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lesnar</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Holm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonya Evinger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demetrious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heavyweight Brock Lesnar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GSP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Nunes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones-Lesnar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC 182</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PEDs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones-Cormier I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Cormier.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gatorade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Jones</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randamie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC 214</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC 200</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC 205</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd Mayweather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronda Rousey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mighty Mouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invicta FC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
