<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404248189445461</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/opinion/peter-van-onselen-liberals-start-to-feel-the-heat-in-wa/news-story/3ef291d359f2c714f661db76ea3866a3</url>
  <title>Liberals start to feel the heat</title>
  <content>
THE Prime Minister and his Cabinet are in town today ahead of tomorrow's full Cabinet meeting. 
It's all part of the showmanship of modern politics - fly your Cabinet around the country to show that you're in touch with the people. We can all thank Kevin Rudd for this waste of taxpayer dollars.
Showmanship or not, Malcolm Turnbull needs to do everything he can to shore up the Liberal Party's vote in the west, because internal research confirms what the State election already revealed. WA is now a problem State for the Liberal Party.
The west has long been a stronghold for Liberals. Even after a bruising campaign last year the Liberals still held 11 of 16 seats in WA. When John Howard lost the 2007 election, he actually managed to pick up seats in the west.
But there are no less than five seats being targeted by the Labor Party at the next election, and four of the five are held by high-profile MPs the Liberals simply cannot afford to lose.
Labor has high hopes of winning Hasluck, Swan, Pearce, Stirling and Canning at the next election.
Interestingly, none of these seats are among the Government's 10 most marginal seats. All have margins of 2-7 per cent.
But as the State election showed, WA swings wildly when a move is on.
Seats with margins as high as 17 per cent were lost at the State election, and some were within the boundaries of the Federal seats in the line of fire.
If Labor wins four of the five seats it is targeting it will hold more seats than the Liberals in WA for the first time in decades.
Not since WA's own Kim Beazley led Labor has the party thrived in the west.
But the real damage will be in the loss of high-profile Liberals who are necessary for the quality of the party room, lest the party fall into disrepute.
Christian Porter holds his seat of Pearce by just over 3 per cent, and there are real fears the Social Services Minister could lose. Touted as a future party leader, Porter is a leading conservative and highly regarded. Labor is planning an all-out campaign to remove Porter from office, knowing the long-term benefit in doing so.
Another high-profile Conservative with strong support among conservative commentators is Andrew Hastie. His seat of Canning is the safest of those under attack, but as an outer metro seat it is known for big swings. Like Pearce, the State seats within Hastie's electorate went to Labor.

Ken Wyatt is the first indigenous minister in the Federal Parliament, and commands the respect of colleagues on both sides of the Parliament. But his seat of Hasluck is the most marginal in WA, held by just over 2 per cent. Unless the political environment changes, Wyatt is a goner.
Justice Minister Michael Keenan entered Parliament back in 2004, and is unlucky not to be in Cabinet. The successes in his national security portfolio have been well noticed, but his seat has always been on the marginal side of the ledger. It could fall if the Statewide swing is on.
Nationally, Queensland will be the State most political observers zero in on.
Half of the 10 most marginal seats the Government holds are in Queensland. But if the Government recovers on the east coast, there is no guarantee that will happen on the west coast, where swings don't always follow the national movements.
Election night could see the Eastern States waiting anxiously for the results in key WA seats before Turnbull learns his fate.
Even if the election is a landslide and Government is lost before the polls in the west close, it will still be an anxious time for Liberals as they wait to find out how many key MPs of the future are put to the sword.
- Peter van Onselen is The Sunday Times' political analyst and a professor at UWA.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Onselen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Porter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UWA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Minister Michael Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Beazley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hastie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Services Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hastie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasluck</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government's 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
