<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404462937814473</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/watch-man-rescues-kangaroo-trench/3207303/</url>
  <title>VIDEO: Amazing rescue of trapped kangaroo goes viral</title>
  <content>
THIS could be the most Aussie thing you see all week - a Darling Downs man rescuing a kangaroo stuck in a narrow trench.  

Goondiwindi man Fritz White came across a kangaroo lying face up in a trench yesterday while at work.

The footage, shot just south of Goondiwindi, shows him reaching down into the hole to grab the kangaroo's paws.

The kangaroo struggles as Mr White pulls him from the ground.

The rescue only took about one minute and the kangaroo can be seen happily hopping away afterwards.

The video was uploaded yesterday afternoon and it has already gone viral.

It has been viewed by 100,000 people and shared more than 850 times.

'Bar of a lifetime' opens today for breakfast, lunch
This is how early you need to be at the airport now.
Family face life in limbo
Noosa is mourning the loss of bright, bubbly mother Sharon Cuthbert
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The popular comedian brings her latest show to the Sunshine Coast
The Voice winner Judah Kelly announces national tour.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
A place for lovers of good food and wine to gather
WE were the first building to open in Sunshine Plaza.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fritz White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goondiwindi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judah Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
