<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404797945268722</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/health/2017-08-01/back-pain-exercises-to-manage-an-aching-back/8731652</url>
  <title>Exercises to manage an aching back</title>
  <content>
Almost four million Australians suffer from back pain at any one time.
The list of reasons you might experience it is long and includes injuries, genetics and diseases like osteoporosis, arthritis and cancer.
But your day-to-day behaviour can also have a big influence on how your back feels.
Most of us spend our lives sitting down with poor posture.
On top of that, people who are overweight or obese, which is 62 per cent of the population, are more at risk because of the added pressure on their spine.
It's not surprising that personal trainers and allied health professionals find back pain is one of the most common reasons people seek their help.
If it's the bane of your life, this gentle workout can help by strengthening key muscles that support good posture: your shoulders and glutes.
The spinal warm-up will decrease stiffness by mobilising your spine, plus help you to create a little more mind/body awareness.
Warm up: Cat cow

Spend 60 seconds or so slowly moving from cat to cow. Focus on how your spine works and try to articulate each vertebra in your spine.
Low-cable abductions and hip extensions

This exercise works the abductors - the muscles around your hip and glutes - which can sometimes be implicated in lower back pain.
The hip extension strengthens your glutes and helps you activate your midsection.
Perform three sets of 12-15 of each exercise before moving to the exercises below.
For example: do 12-15 reps of a low-cable abduction on each leg, then do 12-15 reps of the supine banded hip extension. Rest for 30 seconds, then repeat twice more.
Thoracic extensions and seated rows

The extension-to-reach movement helps you keep good posture - and thus prevent back pain.
And the seated row is great for strengthening the muscles in your back.
Perform three sets of 12-15 of each exercise. Rest for 30 seconds then perform twice more.
Cassie White is a Sydney-based personal trainer, yoga coach and health journalist.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cassie White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thoracic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
