<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404802240236090</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/state-government-to-purchase-hybrid-turbines-to-generate-276mw-of-electricity-which-will-be-delivered-and-installed-before-start-of-summer/news-story/1e4bdadb8545c59045d16395ac8cd77a</url>
  <title>Power plant to arrive before summer</title>
  <content>
A LONG-TERM back-up power plant will be installed at Holden's Elizabeth factory as well as the Adelaide Desalination Plant before the start of summer, the State Government has announced.
Nine General Electric generators will be bought and are expected to provide up to 276MW of electricity to the grid - more than the 250MW originally promised.
The turbines will run on diesel fuel over the next two summers before they are transported to a permanent location to run on gas as a state-owned power plant.
The station will be tested monthly but will only be turned on when required.
It has a lifespan of about 25 years.
Premier Jay Weatherill says rather than purchasing temporary generators before the start of summer, the new turbines will deliver a long-term solution.
"The absence of a coherent national energy policy has led to a crippling of investment in new energy generation, this has left us vulnerable to shortfalls - like the load shedding event in February," he said.
"This solution will deliver more generation capacity than originally planned, while emitting less carbon pollution than Torrens Island Power Station."
The costs of the plant will be met under the previously announced $550 million energy plan.
MORE TO COMETHE $550M PLAN TO SOLVE SA'S POWER CRISIS
The Government's six-point plan to provide energy security for SA involves:
BUILDING a State Government-owned, fast start gas-fired power station that can come on when the market does not provide enough energy to keep the lights on. It is expected to cost about $360 million. No site has yet been selected. It would be 250MW, enough to deliver close to 10 per cent of SA'S peak demand.
SUPPORTING construction of the biggest battery in Australia - and possibly the world - as part of a $150 million spend on a new renewable technology fund.
ENCOURAGING the construction of a new privately-owned power station using a Government bulk buy power contract.
INCENTIVISING the extraction of more gas for use in SA power stations, through a taxpayer-backed exploration fund.
GIVING the SA energy minister powers to override other regulators and force power stations to fire up in times of need.
CREATING an "energy security target", which requires retailers to buy 36 per cent of their power from baseload sources in SA.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long-term</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrens Island Power Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Desalination Plant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Electric</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COMETHE $550M PLAN TO SOLVE SA'S POWER CRISIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government-owned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden's Elizabeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
