<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404716340888744</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/west-beaches/major-castle-plaza-revamp-at-edwardstown-passes-first-hurdle/news-story/707eefcbba2dde181b9dcd300e263ad1</url>
  <title>Major shopping centre revamp a step closer</title>
  <content>
CASTLE Plaza's owners have passed their first major hurdle in their effort to revamp the centre, after threatening to walk away from the project.
Marion Council has signed off on a plan to rezone the area, paving the way for extra shops, restaurants and a revamped Raglan Ave.
Some councillors wanted major roadworks to happen before two supermarkets and new specialty shops opened on the former Hills Industries site, north of the centre.
The works included a new link road connecting Raglan Ave with Ackland St to its north, and an upgrade of the South Rd and Ackland St intersection.
But speaking at Marion Council's July 25 meeting, Don Smith - the development manager at Vicinity Centres, which owns Castle Plaza - warned his company could walk away from the project if it was forced to carry out all of the roadworks.
"If it was too hard, we'd sell it all tomorrow," Mr Smith told the meeting. "We'd just carve up the titles and sell it as industrial land.
"I'd hope we can get to a resolution that doesn't impose too many constraints upon us."
Vicinity Centres proposed an $80 million development of the Edwardstown centre about a decade ago, but has since scaled back its size by about half, citing a downturn in the economy and lack of demand for shop space.
The rezoning plan will make way for the new supermarkets - potentially an Aldi and Woolworths - several specialty shops and restaurants and an upgrade of Raglan Ave, including extra trees and wider footpaths for outdoor dining.
It will also allow for new homes, shops and offices on adjacent land.
Vicinity Centres would complete the shopping centre and sell surrounding former industrial land to make way for the housing and more shops.
Mr Smith said his company may be willing to compromise and build the link road to Ackland St, but not the rest of the roadworks.
"We've sat here for 10 years with a bit of dirt and there's no way we're sitting here for another 10 years," he said.
An earlier proposal to turn part of Raglan Ave into a mall had been shelved when the development was scaled back.
The rezoning needed to be signed off by Planning Minister John Rau before any work could begin.
What do you think of the plans? Leave your comment below.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marion Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raglan Ave</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Minister John Rau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ackland St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hills Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicinity Centres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marion Council's July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwardstown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CASTLE Plaza</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
