<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404020556175164</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/boost-payment-rush-pushes-up-new-home-sales/news-story/a06849a16a5ffb54fb7d7a165104219f</url>
  <title>New home sales get big boost</title>
  <content>
A LATE scramble to get the $5000 first home buyer boost grant before it expired last month helped increase new home sales by more than a 20 per cent,  new statistics show.
The Housing Industry Association said there was a 21.1 per cent increase in the people agreeing to build new homes in WA in June.
HIA senior economist Shane Garrett said the uptick was part of a bigger trend - with sales up 2.1 per cent on 12 months earlier - but he attributed some of the increase to the rush to take advantage of the boost payment.
The $5000 boost was available to eligible first home buyers who entered into a contract between January 1 and June 30 this year to purchase or construct a new home, and those who started laying foundations of their home in that time.
It has now dropped back to $10,000.
Prominent builder Dale Alcock said the market had returned to normal in July after the June rush, which saw his building group sign about 20 per cent more contracts.
Mr Alcock called on the government to maintain the grant for new homes, claiming the sector helped buoy jobs whereas established properties did not support employment.
Impressions sale manager Rhys Watters said sales with his group had dropped as much as 80 per cent in the first home buyer market in July, after a 20 - 25 per cent jump in June.
Mr Watters said some buyers made decisions over 48 hours in a bid to get the boost grant, well below the traditional three week decision period.
The rush had put pressure on the firm to create contracts within days - instead of weeks.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Industry Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Alcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Watters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Garrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Alcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhys Watters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
