<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404205239771897</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/scans-leave-english-ok-to-face-selection</url>
  <title>Scans leave English OK to face selection</title>
  <content>
Tim English has avoided a serious facial injury in the VFL

THE WESTERN Bulldogs are breathing a sigh of relief after scans revealed first-year ruckman Tim English avoided a serious facial injury in the VFL.

English didn't return after half-time of Footscray's loss to Williamstown on Saturday, following a sickening collision that required him to be helped from the ground by trainers.

Television footage of him sitting on the bench showed him with significant swelling and bruising around his right eye.

His likely availability for this week is great news for the premiers, with fellow ruckmen Tom Boyd (mental illness) and Tom Campbell (abdominal strain) sidelined.

Bulldogs head physiotherapist Chris Bell told westernbulldogs.com.au the 19-year-old should be fit for the trip to the Gabba to face the Brisbane Lions on Saturday.

"Scans yesterday confirmed that Tim avoided any serious or structural damage to his face," Bell said.

"[He] will join back into full training this week and is expected to be available this weekend."

Tough midfielder Mitch Honeychurch is also expected to be fit for selection after being a late withdrawal from the senior side on the weekend due to illness.

Dynamic forward Jake Stringer is at least a week away from returning from a hamstring injury sustained in the round 17 win over Carlton.

Coach Luke Beveridge was hopeful the All Australian would be available for the clash with the Lions, but Bell said Stringer would ramp up his training next week.

"Jake is making some fantastic progress in the recovery following his hamstring injury, and is expected to resume full training next week," Bell said.

In further good news, premiership midfielder Josh Dunkley is likely to resume in the VFL this weekend in his return from a shoulder injury that's seen him sidelined since round seven.

Draftees Patrick Lipinski (hamstring) and Fergus Greene (wrist) are also expected to be available for Footscray's clash with the Northern Blues on Saturday.

Q2 | 's Tim English cops a HUGE hit. He'll be done for the day. Play is stopped.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williamstown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dunkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stringer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Honeychurch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fergus Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footscray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Lipinski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Blues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim English</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Stringer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
