<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404157995130945</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/sophisticated-traveller/romancing-the-danube-aboard-crystal-mozart-20170713-gxaivp</url>
  <title>Onboard spa and your very own butler on this high-tech cruise</title>
  <content>
by
Louise Roberts

The first few bars of Johann Strauss' An der schonen blauen Donau (Blue Danube) waltz elicit gasps of delight as the setting sun breaks free from a wreath of cloud, illuminating the arched windows of the Upper Belvedere Palace's gilded and frescoed Marble Hall. Formal gardens bedecked with fountains stretch into the darkening distance below and beyond glitters Vienna, the grande dame of Europe.
We're on our feet to encore the Schloss Schonbrunn Palace Orchestra and Ballet Club Wiener Volksoper after an evening of Mozart and Strauss. It's a signature event that began with a champagne reception in the extravagantly stuccoed Sala Terrena, swept past four atlantes straining under the weight of the vaulted ceiling and up the grand staircase for a private viewing of Gustav Klimt's 1908 art nouveau masterpiece, The Kiss.
The gallery is housed in the baroque man-cave built by the diminutive Prince Eugene of Savoy, who grew up in the French court of Louis XIV and, having set his heart on a military career, turned to Austria after being rejected by the French army, allegedly on account of his lack of stature. He carved out a successful and lucrative career under the Habsburg dynasty, defeating the Ottomans several times in the late 1600s and early 1700s and amassing enough loot to finance the construction of the palaces (the lower one includes bedrooms) in the 1720s. It's the perfect finale for our 11-day Eastern Danube river cruise, Vienna to Vienna.
But let me go back to the beginning.

Ian Schemper

In July 2016,  became ocean line specialist Crystal Cruises' first river ship. (Four more are on order, two of which enter service this year.) She's also among the world's largest river cruisers and, at almost double the average width, is limited to cruising the roomy Danube. In a nod to the target market, her godmother is Elisabeth Gurtler, head of one of the world's most luxurious hotels - Vienna's .

I'm travelling with my mother on this 11-day trip, which takes in such jewels as Hungary's Budapest, Vukovar in Croatia, Serbia's Belgrade and Novi Sad, and Slovakia's capital of Bratislava, before steaming back to Austria. On boarding in Vienna one sunny evening in May, we're personally welcomed by Crystal Mozart hotel director Sonja Gruber before being shown below to our suite and introduced to our attendant, Kamila, and butler, Nicolae, who instantly proffers champagne.
Crystal Mozart has 77 suites that range in size from just over 20 to 82 square metres. More than half are located on deck one, with fixed picture windows just above the waterline, and the rest are on deck two with French balconies, including two suites with two bedrooms and 12 penthouses. All feature king-size beds, Nespresso coffee machines, wall-mounted 40-inch flat-screen televisions and butler service. Nicolae gives us a quick tour of the room's features. My immediate priorities satisfied - large, ultra-comfy bed and steaming power shower - I cast an appreciative eye over the marble-tiled bathroom and head for the coffee machine.
All mod cons

The room is super high-tech, including an in-suite iPad linked directly to Nicolae, so that we place our order and, voila, he appears with room service. With just a tap of said iPad we can change the room temperature, book an excursion, check on-board menus, or have our shoes cleaned and shirts pressed. There's also a telephone with speed dial if you prefer the old way. Having acquainted ourselves with the gadgetry we head out to explore, not forgetting to tap for turn-down service so there will be truffles on the pillows when we retire.

Ian Schemper

It being evening, entertainer Neal Fullerton is at the baby grand two levels up in The Cove, where the elegant pre-dinner crowd gathers for cocktails. Thereafter, said crowd morphs into an impromptu ensemble of finger-clicking backing vocalists. The Cove curves round into the capacious forward-facing Palm Court lounge, where floor-to-ceiling windows form a panoramic backdrop to a parquet dance floor. By day, it hosts events such as wine tastings with Eileen Crane of Domaine Carneros by Taittinger, (the most powerful woman in Napa Valley, according to Forbes); lectures on Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart and the history of the Austrian-Hungarian Empire; plus cocktail masterclasses presided over by the good-humoured Dragan, who introduces me to a dayglow-orange Aperol spritzer.
After-dinner games are compered by Fullerton, who's blessed with a quick wit. Classical concerts are held here too, while the  from Bratislava conjures up a variety of chirruping bird songs using traditional Slovakian wind instruments. After a standing ovation these virtuosos, who also play the violin, accordion and piano, launch into an energetic rendition of the cancan.
The following day, we begin to get acquainted with our host river for the next 10 days, the mighty Danube. It's the second-longest river in Europe, but the only major waterway flowing from west to east. The Danube starts in Germany's Black Forest mountains and flows for more than 2850 kilometres to the Black Sea, passing through 10 countries along the way. For centuries, various empires and religions have vied for control of the strategic and fertile Pannonian Plain, part of a large basin of the same name that stretches across much of Central Europe. The Romans, Magyars, Mongols, Ottomans and Holy Romans, followed by the players of both world wars and, most recently, the opposing sides involved in the violent break-up of Yugoslavia, have all fought over these lush riverbanks.
River tales

Ian Schemper

Like most great rivers, the Danube has facilitated the spread of trade and new ideas as much as war and bloodshed. It's not just the many castles and fortresses that provide a visual link and historical context as the river snakes through different countries. Take the many yellow buildings. Empress Maria Theresa, who reigned from 1740 to 1780, decreed that all new ones be painted her favourite hue. Thanks to this whim on the part of the Habsburgs' only female ruler, today's traveller still enjoys the ubiquitous yellow baroque buildings along the route.
Then there were the sacks of coffee left behind after the Ottoman rout following the Battle of Vienna in 1683. Austrian folklore has it that Holy Roman Emperor Leopold I converted Europeans to coffee after finding the beans the Ottomans left behind in their scramble to retreat. Given Leopold I was also king of Hungary, Croatia, Bohemia and Serbia, the craze for his new brew spread quickly throughout the empire as it was being rebuilt in the wake of the departing Turks.
For almost two weeks, we weave our way along this fascinating stretch of water, making one stop a day, occasionally two, to take in the ports. At larger destinations such as Vienna and Belgrade, a Crystal shuttle bus conveys us into town. Tours are on offer at every port, with at least one of these included in the price. "Guests can take full advantage of all the options, from complimentary tours to the 30 e-bikes on board for organised excursions or to go it alone, and the shuttle and coaches," Gruber says.
Among the most spectacular scenery is the Iron Gates gorge, which separates the foothills of the Carpathian Mountains in Romania, to the north, and the Balkan ranges in Serbia to the south, as the Danube snakes down towards the Black Sea past the medieval Golubac fortress and a Roman plaque from 105AD commemorating Trajan's Bridge, whose remaining pillars were submerged in the 1980s when the river was dammed.

Ian Schemper

We go as far east as the Iron Gates Hydroelectric Power Station, turn back, heading west towards Belgrade, where the recently returned Crown Prince of Serbia is known as "Prince Alex of Claridge's", having been born in exile at the London hotel.
There are too many highlights to choose a favourite from - beautiful Szentendre, where the cobbled streets and stepped alleyways are lined with galleries, Hungarian paprika sellers and tubs of red geraniums; Croatia, with its pastel-painted wooden houses perched on forested hillsides, meticulously mown lawns sloping down to bright boathouses strung out like pearls along the water's edge. Budapest, the aptly named Queen of the Danube with its stunning castle district and magnificent Parliament, and Bratislava's medieval old town complete with moat, took our breath away.
"When we get back to Vienna we're just going to stay on board and head on up the Danube in the opposite direction," enthuses John, a retired dentist from San Francisco.
Time to chill

Anna Zavileiskaia

So much visual splendour day after day can get a little overwhelming, however. That's when it's time to opt for a day off to relax on the sundeck, or take a trip to the day spa, which is where I head more than once to enjoy a couple of head-to-toe treatments, including a Swedish massage and a pedicure.
One of the nicest things about this spa is they don't sell anything. It is dedicated solely to pampering. Afterwards, you can relax in the ship's hot tub and adjacent blue-black mosaic swimming pool (the largest on the Danube, it has a wave machine). Or retreat to the ladies' change rooms, where a sauna, steam room and banks of fluffy white towels await.
There are plenty of dining options on board. Waterside restaurant serves sumptuous breakfast and lunch buffets, and there's the option to dress up for an evening of fine dining with sommelier service. The Vintage Room on deck three is the ship's most exclusive eatery, serving wine-themed dinners for up to 12 guests at €290 ($425) a person.
For a more casual feel, sample the tapas menu in Bistro Mozart, which also offers an all-day mini-buffet for late risers, as well as home-made ice-creams popular with guests returning from a morning's sight-seeing by bike. Alternatively, head aft to Blue grill for burgers, deli-style sandwiches and salads in a diner-style setting with great views.
For the weary of foot, a lift enables access to three levels and all the restaurants, although not to the sundeck on level four.
Tucked away midship is the Connoisseur's Club smoking lounge, replete with a selection of cigars, fine wines, liqueurs and spirits. For good coffee, light pastries and fruit, we head to a cosy nook space, The Pantry.
Really, sailing the Danube on Crystal Mozart is akin to one long Strauss waltz: triple time may leave you a little flushed but you'll have a ball from beginning to end.
The writer travelled as a guest of Crystal Cruises.

Amos Chapple

Diary on the Danube

Day 1 (May 2) We're met at Vienna airport and whisked off in a private car to board Crystal Mozart at 6pm and be handed a glass of champagne.
Day 2 Morning city tour of Vienna and walkabout in the historic centre, then off on our own to check out the Bruegels (as in Dutch and Flemish master Pieter Bruegel the Elder) at Vienna's  (Museum of Fine Arts). Shuttle back to the ship for a 4pm lecture on the Austro-Hungarian Empire before setting sail for Hungary at 6pm.
Day 3 Dock at Esztergom in northern Hungary (46 kilometres north-west of Budapest) and board the coach for a tour that includes bishops' bones in the reliquary of the domed Basilica, plus views of the Danube Bend from the medieval . The coach reunites with the ship at Bodor Major, about 40 kilometres by road, for lunch followed by an afternoon stroll around Szentendre, where we purchase paprika, before sailing at 4.30pm.
Day 4 Early 7am wake-up call for immigration at Mohacs before entering Croatia, then Team Trivia in the Palm Court and lunch at Blue. Dock at Vukovar in eastern Croatia at 3pm with time for a walking tour of the city, with its bombed-out water tower and a multimedia presentation on the Homeland War (1991-1998) at the Municipal Museum, followed by wine tasting at Eltz castle. Crystal Mozart sails at 7.30pm for the Iron Gates Gorge.
Day 5 Morning yoga, followed by a spicy fresh ginger and Cointreau Cosmopolitan in Dragan's mixology class, then it's all up on deck as Serbia's medieval Golubac fortress marks the entrance to the gorge. The ship passes Roman ruins, castles and Dracula-inspiring Transylvania on the Romanian side before we turn back at the Iron Gates hydroelectric dam. Dress for dinner, enjoy a game of Liar's Club and end up at the late-night disco in the Palm Court.
Day 6 We wake up in Belgrade, a city razed 44 times over the centuries. Today, however, a Bollywood production is holding up traffic on a morning tour of the Royal Palace, Tito's memorial and the massive, unfinished Church of Saint Sava (begun in 1935). It's raining at first but the sun comes out in time for a stroll around lovely Kalemegdan Park with its walled fortress. A lively evening concert by pianist Elda Laro and tenor Steffan Mullan in the ship's Palm Court lounge precedes our midnight departure.
Day 7 Dock at Serbia's second city, Novi Sad, at 9am for a walking tour of the  and the historic old centre, stopping by the street market to sample the best poppy seed strudel in Serbia (or so says our guide). Back on board there's an afternoon movie quiz and wine tasting with the Crystal Society Party in the Palm Court before dinner and an evening with Neal Fullerton in The Cove.

Day 8 We're back in Hungary, at Mohacs, by 6am. I skip the (not to be missed, I am later informed) Pecs and Szekszard wine region tour for a revitalising day spent in the Crystal Life Spa & Salon. The ship and I catch up with the wine tourists in the quaint town of Kalocsa at 4pm. I join the others for a quick Hungarian Folk Culture Tour before we depart at 7pm. A game of Not-so-Newlywed rounds off the day.
Day 9 Arrive in Budapest at 8am. A city tour takes in Pest's parks, baroque boulevards and neoclassical museums. We cross to Buda for the afternoon, to stroll around the Gothic Mattias Church and Gellert Hill, with its 360-degree panoramas and art nouveau baths. An afternoon walkabout to the cavernous city market via the most opulent McDonald's in the world (stuccoed ceiling and chandeliers), ending up at the  for our complimentary Michelin-star meal before setting sail at 9pm, passing the gilded Gothic riverside Parliament building.
Day 10 Pilates in the Palm Court is followed by a talk on Mozart before we dock at Slovakia's capital of Bratislava at 4pm for a panoramic city tour and walk through the historic old town. Then it's back on board for the Pressburger Duo before dinner.
Day 11 We're back in Vienna by 8am. It's our last full day, so we take the shuttle to Schwedenplatz and amble through the gardens; visit the Gaudi-like Hundertwasserhaus and sample sachertorte at Trotsky's and Freud's favourite, . We board by 4.30pm for an early buffet dinner before a champagne reception and concert at the Upper Belvedere Palace.
GO-TO GUIDE

Built in 1987 in Deggendorf, Germany, Crystal Mozart had a complete refit before entering service with Crystal in July 2016. The ship, which carries 154 guests and 92 crew, is just over 120 metres in length and has an exceptionally broad beam for a river cruiser of 22.85 metres.
HEALTH AND FITNESS
Indoor pool with wave machine and hot tub; expansive sundeck with loungers, shaded seating and pop-up bar; living roof with observation deck; fully equipped fitness centre, separate ladies' and gents' steam rooms and saunas.

WINE AND DINE
Restaurant, bistro, burger diner-style grill, private-hire Vintage Room for occasion fine dining, 24-hour room service.
WHAT TO PACK
This is Europe, so pretend you're going to Melbourne and pack for four seasons. Include a hat, sunnies, sunscreen, walking shoes, a warm wrap (it can get chilly on deck, especially in the evenings), and don't forget your swimmers if you fancy a wave-machine workout.
READ AND LISTEN
Black Lamb and Grey Falcon by Rebecca West (The Balkans); Agatha Christie's Murder on the Orient Express (Belgrade); The Third Man by Graham Greene (Vienna); Embers by Sandor Marai (Hungary); The Hare with Amber Eyes by Edmund de Waal (Vienna); The Tiger's Wife by Tea Obreht (Serbia); Fatelessness by Imre Kertesz (Budapest); Dracula by Bram Stoker (Romania).
Listen to anything by Mozart, Mahler or Strauss; the soundtrack to The Sound of Music; Vienna by Ultravox (obviously); Budapest by George Ezra; and (somewhat tenuously) the Red Hot Chili Peppers' Victorian Machinery ("Sing along just like they do in Budapest").
TAKE ME THERE

Crystal Mozart's 11-day Eastern Danube Discoveries Vienna round-trip cruise, October 13-24, 2017, is priced from $US6000 ($7889) a person for a lead-in suite with fixed window. This cruise also operates from April 29-May 10, 2018, offering a suite with fixed window for $US5815 a person; suite with French balcony from $US6970; penthouse from $US11,845. See website for inclusions.
Call Crystal's Sydney office (02) 8074 6500, 1300 059 260 (Australia) or 0800 600 108 (New Zealand) or visit:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carpathian Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Gates</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Habsburg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgrade</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Szentendre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohacs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sava</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holy Roman Emperor Leopold I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Embers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cove</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mongols</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bohemia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaudi-like Hundertwasserhaus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6000 ($7889</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dracula-inspiring Transylvania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Mozart</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schwedenplatz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connoisseur's Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battle of Vienna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palm Court</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelin-star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serbia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian Folk Culture Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amber Eyes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gellert Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballet Club Wiener Volksoper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6970</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pannonian Plain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pantry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marble Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal's Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Napa Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edmund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nespresso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gustav Klimt's 1908</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schloss Schonbrunn Palace Orchestra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiger's Wife</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary's Budapest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Danube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deggendorf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elda Laro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gothic Mattias Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sala Terrena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trajan's Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leopold I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary (46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yugoslavia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Ezra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ottoman</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pressburger Duo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agatha Christie's Murder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austrian-Hungarian Empire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sound of Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taittinger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US11,845</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Sea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalocsa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandor Marai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Museum of Fine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US5815</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strauss</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mozart</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dracula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Trivia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steffan Mullan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vukovar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golubac</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gruber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slovakia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Early 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Novi Sad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fullerton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey Falcon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basilica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danube Bend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Alex of Claridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDAPEST</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vienna</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swedish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cointreau Cosmopolitan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Empress Maria Theresa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bodor Major</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Cruises</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany's Black Forest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fatelessness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungary</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serbia's Belgrade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonja Gruber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amos Chapple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magyars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balkan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Szekszard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vintage Room</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prince of Serbia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louis XIV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bistro Mozart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Zavileiskaia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esztergom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Gates Gorge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen of the Danube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Danube Discoveries Vienna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pieter Bruegel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slovakian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Hot Chili Peppers' Victorian Machinery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imre Kertesz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Life Spa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holy Romans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johann Strauss' An</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalemegdan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Society Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruegel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Third Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Gates Hydroelectric Power Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aperol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HEALTH AND FITNESS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Danube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Greene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orient Express</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carneros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultravox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trotsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolae</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper Belvedere Palace</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danube</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neal Fullerton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elisabeth Gurtler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 29-May 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Municipal Museum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bram Stoker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tea Obreht</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Eugene of Savoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liar's Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kamila</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Croatia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austro-Hungarian Empire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Church of Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Schemper</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eileen Crane of Domaine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRATISLAVA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BUDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
