<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404587491868120</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/lifestyle/news-and-views/kim-kardashians-first-marriage-twitter-has-found-some-funny-things-longer-than-scaramuccis-term-20170731-gxmp19.html</url>
  <title>'Kim Kardashian's first marriage': Twitter has found some funny things longer than Scaramucci's term</title>
  <content>
Kim Kardashian's marriage to Kris Humphries, a stubborn zit: these are just some of the things that lasted longer than Anthony Scaramucci's White House gig.
The Wall Street big shot turned White House Communications Director had just ten days in his new role before his, and Twitter has not failed to see the funny side.Photo: Twitter/TheSecondCity
The social media network has quickly lit up with lists of things that lasted longer than Scaramucci's tenure, and the results are quite humorous.
Kim Kardashian's ill-fated - and unfortunately televised - second marriage was a commonly-used yard stick, with many remarking Scaramucci's stint makes the 72-day arrangement seem marathon-length by comparison.

When Kim Kardashian's marriage to Kris Humphries was longer than your WH career

I... I can't believe I'm saying this, but every Kim Kardashian marriage has lasted longer than Scaramucci's time as WH Comm Dir.

Kim Kardashian's marriage to Kris Humphries lasted SEVEN TIMES longer than Anthony  as White House communications director.

But, Kardashians aside, plenty of other comparisons were to be drawn. 
Scaramucci held his job for less time than some women have endured a period, or a particularly stubborn pimple.

I've literally had zits that last longer than Scaramucci did in the White House. Then again, that guy was a zit on common decency.

I've got stuff in the fridge that's been around longer than Scaramucci...

Things that last longer than Scaramucci did at the WH:
Advent calendars
Airbnb guests
Kardashian relationships
Usain Bolt races
Hiccups

Twitter users just could not stop having a laugh about 'The Mooch' who, as US Buzzfeed reporter will be "a great pub trivia answer in six years".

Scaramucci out just in time for Celebrity Big Brother.

Scaramooch (scaramooch) appears to be easy come, easy go

Every contestant in the apprentice made it longer than scaramucci

moot point (n.): a matter of no relevance
mooch point (n.): a matter so laughable it is dismissed almost immediately after it is brought up

Daily Life
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WH Comm Dir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Buzzfeed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEVEN TIMES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Kardashian</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kardashian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celebrity Big Brother</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Communications Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter/TheSecondCity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Humphries</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramooch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
