<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404935384224473</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/john-cena-the-living-embodiment-of-a-transformers-movie-has-joined-the-bumblebee-spinoff/</url>
  <title>John Cena, The Living Embodiment Of A Transformers Movie, Has Joined The Bumblebee Spinoff</title>
  <content>
Honestly, the only real reaction you can have to The Hollywood Reporter's announcement that John Cena - the wrestler turned meme turned actor - has joined a Transformers movie is: "Huh, he wasn't already in one?"

Image: John Cena at the 2017 Kids' Choice Awards,  /  

He's such an obvious choice that it almost seems self-aware to cast him. But we all know that, if there is one thing the Transformers movies are amazing at, it's not recognising when they have descended into self-parody. Remember that the Bumblebee spinoff is set in the '80s, and if the costume designer and makeup artist doesn't put Cena in a Miami Vice pastel suit and give him a Flock of Seagulls haircut, I will be bereft.

We don't actually know anything about Cena's role, and the synopsis from The Hollywood Reporter is lacking a description for who he could be:

Bumblebee also now has a US release date of 21 December 2018, the same as Aquaman. Someone - almost certainly Paramount and Transformers - is going to blink, which will deny us the Cena versus Jason Momoa match up we didn't even know we wanted. But for now, rest assured that Cena and a giant yellow robot are set to take on Momoa and all the power of the sea.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood Reporter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flock of Seagulls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miami Vice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aquaman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bumblebee Spinoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transformers Movie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kids' Choice Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Cena</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Living Embodiment Of A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cena</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Momoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Momoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
