<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404888139583481</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/nrl/mark-geyer-questions-laurie-daleys-origin-future/news-story/3adbfcecc3e8a3a80e14edcfbc17a8fa</url>
  <title>Mark Geyer questions Laurie Daley's Origin future</title>
  <content>
Laurie Daley speaks out
19:09

NRL: NRL: NSW coach Laurie Daley has joined NRL 360 for his first public interview since State of Origin

July 31st 2017
15 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/NRL News/

Laurie Daley speaks to the media after arriving at the domestic airport in Sydney.

Adam Santarossa

Share

FORMER New South Wales enforcer Mark Geyer wants change in the Blues ranks - and he's starting with coach Laurie Daley.
Daley's position appears to be under review after New South Wales stunning State of Origin capitulation this season, although good judges believe Daley has a standing offer on the table of a one-year deal, if the Blues boss wants to take it.
But Geyer feels New South Wales should look elsewhere, while explaining the incumbent leader's shortcomings.
"I think he's had five years to try and do what he can do," Geyer told the Triple M Grill Team Sydney. "I just don't think he's the man for the job. "
Geyer appeared to suggest the controversy surrounding Josh Dugan and Blake Ferguson's pre-Origin III drinking session was an example of Daley's failure to instil the right culture.
"(Daley should) try and coach a club side first and see how he goes with a club side," Geyer said.
"Queensland have an opportunity where they can do it with a Kevvie Walters and a Mal Meninga because their culture is so strong.
"Ours isn't, when players think they can go 80km and get on the drink four days before a game."

NRL great Mark Geyer.Source:News Corp Australia
Geyer says New South Wales must move to a coach with recent NRL experience who has the mettle to exist in the pressure cooker atmosphere that the Origin arena provides.

"We need to get a coach that has week to week coaching in the NRL," Geyer said.
"So he's resilient to the fact that it's a hard job. It's a very hard job for someone to do.
"Someone like a (Craig) Bellamy, Des Hasler, whose week in, week out grind is compatible with what Origin is.
"I don't think Loz is up to it, for the fact that he comes in for six weeks and all the pressure is straight on him. Not coaching a rugby league team week in the NRL, I think that affects him.
"Look what all these coaches cop on a weekly basis."
Daley revealed on NRL 360 he only learnt of the eight-hour drinking session of Blues' stars Dugan and Ferguson after the game.

Coach Laurie Daley looks on during a New South Wales Blues State of Origin training.Source:Getty Images
Geyer's Triple M Grill Team co-host Matthew Johns expects New South Wales to remain with Daley should he want to continue in the role.
"What I got out of (the NRL 360 interview) was that Laurie Daley is incredibly loyal to his players," Johns said.
"He does feel like they've let him down. He was pretty softly softly on it, he didn't throw them under the bus, that's what we learnt, he did feel let down and he was disappointed in what they did. My understanding firstly is that Laurie will get a year if he wants to take it.
"You can only see the toll, watching Laurie last night on the show, I feel really sorry for Laurie."

NSW coach Craig Bellamy with his players after a loss.Source:News Limited
But Johns agrees should the Blues turn to a new coaching staff, there is only one option they should look at.
"If Laurie decided its taken too much of a toll on me personally then for mine, it's got to be (Craig) Bellamy. It's got to be," Johns said.
"Bellamy had a crack once before and it's my understanding that Bellamy understands the mistakes he made the first time and he would coach different the second time around, that's good enough for me."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL360</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Daley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Santarossa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Des Hasler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Geyer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dugan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dugan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales Blues State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M Grill Team Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevvie Walters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geyer</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Daley's Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mal Meninga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Geyer.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geyer's Triple M Grill Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin III</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
