<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404888139583521</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/four-buyers-compete-in-sevenfigured-postauction-contest/news-story/f3cc256316cf83f980ed86adb179fefd</url>
  <title>Four buyers compete in seven-figured post-auction contest - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, sold after auction for $1.51 million on July 29.

AN ASPENDALE house sold for more than $1.5 million, a figure $135,000 above its reserve price on its auction day.
Despite failing to attract a single bid under the hammer.
The property at  initially passed in, but shortly after attracted competition from four different parties.
Hocking Stuart Mentone agent and auctioneer Garry Donovan said the property was just doors from the beach, but this wasn't enough to tempt a bid.
He said after a $1.35 million vendor bid, it was passed in.
And that's when the competition began.
"Four people came up after the auction, and we had an auction after the auction," Mr Donovan said.
He said after negotiation the home sold for $1.51 million, well beyond the $1.375 reserve price.
The fact there was no highest bidder to secure rights to negotiate had increased the competition for the home, Mr Donovan said.
"If someone had bid, they would have had the first right to come inside," he said.
The post-auction competition also scored a price $110,000 above an offer made for the property ahead of its auction day, Mr Donovan added.
"It was a great outcome," he said.
"It was a great price, and the vendor was ecstatic."
The result was good enough to mark it as the third-highest Aspendale sale price reported to CoreLogic so far this year.

The beach is just steps away from the home.

The four-bedroom house has multiple living areas, a bay view from its balcony, and is four doors along from the beach.
"You could see the view from the balcony upstairs so it still had that connection to the water, and it was only 100m or so from the beach," Mr Donovan said.

Water views are part of the package.

He said the property's sale had ended an almost year-long search for the buyers.
"They were out of town buyers, looking for a coastal change, and they had been looking for a really long time," he said.
A downsizer, another couple, and a young couple who'd missed out on several homes previously also competed for the home, he added.
Lengthy house hunts were often the case when it came to property this close to the beach, Mr Donovan said.
"I've had people looking for two years," he said.
"It's not your everyday real estate."
There was also a lack of available property for sale in the suburb, Mr Donovan said.
"Aspendale is one of the most tightly held parts of the area at the moment," he said.
SEE SUBURB PROFILE:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hocking Stuart Mentone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Donovan</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Donovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASPENDALE</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUBURB PROFILE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
