<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404892434550912</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/mediterranean-diet-only-good-for-rich/news-story/14d28bdbc85f348f3211882ebbd12854</url>
  <title>Mediterranean diet 'only good for rich'</title>
  <content>
Only rich and educated people reduce their risk of heart disease by adopting a Mediterranean diet, researchers claim.
Surprising results from the Italian study suggest that eating a healthy mix of fruits, vegetables, nuts, beans and fish while cutting down on red meat offers no benefit to the less advantaged.
This was true even when both groups, rich and less well off, showed comparable adherence to the diet.
"The cardiovascular benefits associated with the Mediterranean diet in a general population are well known. Yet, for the first time, our study has revealed that the socio-economic position is able to modulate the health advantages linked to Mediterranean diet," said Lead researcher Dr Marialaura Bonaccio, from the Mediterranean Neurological Institute in Pozzilli.
The study, reported in the International Journal of Epidemiology, involved more than 18,000 participants from the Molise region of Italy.
Detailed analysis indicated that people at the top of society were likely to consume healthier versions of the Mediterranean diet richer in antioxidants and polyphenol plant compounds. They also had access to a greater range of fruits and vegetables.
"These substantial differences in consuming products belonging to Mediterranean diet lead us to think that quality of foods may be as important for health as quantity and frequency of intake," said co-author Dr Licia Lacoviello.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Marialaura Bonaccio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pozzilli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Journal of Epidemiology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Licia Lacoviello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean Neurological Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
