<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404454347879669</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/wafl-rule-could-stifle-nic-naitanuis-progress-as-he-attempts-afl-comeback/news-story/458429cc09c53144fe107ccd81696569</url>
  <title>Rule could stifle Naitanui's progress</title>
  <content>
NIC Naitanui's hopes of returning from a knee reconstruction to play finals are likely to rest on the West Australian Football Commission reversing a precedent set during 2015.
The West Coast ruckman has increased his training in a bid to play again this year, but concedes he is unlikely to be available to play any football until round 23. He revealed yesterday that any AFL return would have to be through the WAFL.
East Perth play Subiaco that weekend, but that would be Naitanui's only game before the AFL finals begin unless East Perth qualify for the finals and the Eagles convince the WAFC to let him play in the Royals' first final.
Eagles players are banned from playing WAFL finals unless they have either been selected for five matches or West Coast are playing on the same weekend. The AFL bye between round 23 and the first week of finals will make Naitanui ineligible.
West Coast applied for Scott Selwood and Patrick McGinnity to play WAFL finals during their week off between the 2015 AFL qualifying and preliminary finals, but were rejected by the WAFC. The Eagles were upset by that ruling and neither Selwood nor McGinnity played again that season. West Coast refused to comment yesterday.
Fremantle have named Harley Balic and Harley Bennell in reserves teams in the past two seasons, despite them not playing, to help them to qualify. Only four games remain this season.
Naitanui said it would be too difficult to return to the AFL without a game.
"I'd be kidding myself if I think I can come straight back into the AFL side," he said.
"I probably do need a bit of match fitness because training couldn't offer that physicality that you probably would get in a game. Pre-season time you can do it, but this time of year, boys are pretty sore and not tackling or not jumping into each other as hard. If that did come the case, I'd definitely have to bide my time by going through the WAFL."
Naitanui injured his left knee against Hawthorn in round 22 last year and returned last week from a training camp in the US.
West Coast moved back into the top eight after thrashing Brisbane on Sunday.
While refusing to guarantee he will play this year, Naitanui said he would regret closing the door on a return if the Eagles made the grand final.
"The last thing I want to do is focus on my little rehab stuff and then we make it to a grand final and I'm not a chance or I've talked myself out of it because I haven't trained the way I want to do," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subiaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley Bennell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Naitanui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naitanui</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley Balic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick McGinnity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Football Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGinnity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pre-season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
