<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404892434550937</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/rebecca-judd-relives-that-horribly-awkward-nonkiss-from-tony-jones-a-year-on/news-story/9979cc3af48f6c5347cc1461483a48dc</url>
  <title>Bec Judd relives horribly awkward kiss</title>
  <content>
IT'S BEEN bang on one year since Rebecca Judd narrowly escaped an awkward on-air kiss from Channel Nine sports presenter Tony Jones.
But, , it seems that now-infamous moment has never left her.
Speaking to Katie 'Monty' Dimond on KIIS FM radio, the pair discussed the recent Hawthorn v Sydney Swans AFL match last Saturday .
"Someone coming in to kiss you is a real invasion of privacy if you're not ready for it or you don't want it to happen," Monty said, before bursting into fits of giggles.
"Funny you say that," the model and television presenter replied.
"As we know that you've had that in the workplace before as well with old mate Tony Jones," Monty added.
"Love Tony Jones, my buddy," Judd laughed.
It was just before Judd gave birth to her twins when the unwanted kiss occurred. Finishing up her final weather segment, Judd was joined at the desk by Jones who tried to give her a peck on the cheek. But she swiftly rejected his kiss and it made for one of the best, cringe-worthy TV moments.
"I reckon you are the most famous workplace kisser," Monty said of the uncomfortable farewell.
"It was a non-kiss, the kiss that never was."
As the pair discussed how AFL players could deal with unwanted on-field attention, Judd had this advice:
"I just think, where else in any workplace is it okay to annoy somebody in your workplace, so you kiss them?
"I think I need to run like a little course for AFL players. The Rebecca Judd how to avoid a kiss on live TV workshops," she added.
"It's all about the duck and move, so you duck and move away."

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S BEEN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monty' Dimond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Judd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bec Judd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Swans AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KIIS FM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JUDD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monty</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Jones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
