<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404196649837141</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/celebrity-selfies/paris-jackson-and-macaulay-culkin-get-matching-tattoos/news-story/cb0cb4f2e5041de7fb2ccf8fe62538c1</url>
  <title>Paris Jackson and Macaulay Culkin get matching tattoos</title>
  <content>
What are Paris Jackson and Godfather Macaulay Culkin's Matching Tattoos REALLY About?
1:39

Paris Jackson has added yet another work of art to her body - but this time she&#x2019;s sharing the love. The model and her godfather Macaulay Culkin now have matching tattoos. While neither the model or actor confirmed the meaning, some spectacle that spoons could represent their own struggles with chronic illness or low points in their lives, which of course has plagued them both. What do you think they're about? Let me know in the comments below.&#xD;

August 1st 2017
5 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Paris and Macaulay, inked for life.

Tyler McCarthyFox News

Share

PARIS Jackson just made her bond with her godfather a little stronger with the help of some matching ink.
The star posted on social media that she and Macaulay Culkin got matching tattoos.
The model posted an image to  story over the weekend showing off some new body art alongside her godfather. According to E! News, the design seems to be of an identical spoon that appears on both of their forearms. The 19-year-old model is the daughter of the late Michael Jackson, who Culkin met at the height of his Home Alone fame in 1990. They remained friends with Culkin spending time at Jackson's Neverland Ranch in California and starring in the video for Black or White at age 11. Today, he's the godfather of Paris.

Paris and Macaulay, inked for life.Source:Instagram
Jackson has previously said that she had over 50 tattoos on her body. However,, this appears to be the first on Culkin's arm. As a result, the spoon, whose meaning is still shrouded in mystery, has a distinguished place of honour on the 36-year-old's arm.

Godfather and goddaughter show off their matching tatts.Source:Instagram
This isn't the first time the duo have been seen hanging out together. Previously, she posted a photo of herself to Instagram painting Culkin's toenails. Her caption jokingly called him a "hipster." Culkin, on the other hand, recently made headlines for cleaning up his rock star look after being photographed on the streets looking clean-shaven and camera-ready.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson's Neverland Ranch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Culkin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Jackson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler McCarthyFox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godfather Macaulay Culkin's Matching Tattoos REALLY About</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macaulay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Alone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macaulay Culkin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
