<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404797945268725</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/01/10/48/venezuela-dictator-us-sanctions</url>
  <title>Venezuelan President Nicholas Maduro slams US sanctions and</title>
  <content>
Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro lashed out at the United States for slapping sanctions on him, saying the move smacked of American "imperialism."
"I will not obey imperial orders. I do not obey foreign governments. I'm a free president," he said after Washington froze his US assets and called him a "dictator".
The restrictions came after Maduro pushed through a vote for a powerful new assembly that will rewrite the country's constitution.
The sanctions froze any assets Maduro may have in US jurisdictions as well as barring Americans from doing business with him.
"Yesterday's illegitimate elections confirm that Maduro is a dictator who disregards the will of the Venezuelan people," US Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin told reporters.
Imposing sanctions on a head of state is rare however it follows through on a US threat of action last week against Maduro and his government if they went ahead with Sunday's election.
The US were not the only ones to oppose the election - with a wave of bloodshed sweeping Venezuelan streets on Sunday as troops cracked down on violent protests against the election.

Related Articles

Protesters attacked polling stations and barricaded streets around the country, drawing a bloody response from security forces, who opened fire with live ammunition in some cases. At least 10 people were killed including a soldier.
While the National Electoral Council has claimed more than 40 percent of Venezuela's 20 million voters had cast ballots on Sunday, the opposition says voter turnout was closer to 12 percent.
Surveys by polling firm Datanalisis showed more than 70 percent of Venezuelans opposed the new assembly.
America's Treasury Secretary Mr Mnuchin has warned of further US penalties against Maduro allies.
"Anyone who participates in this illegitimate (constituent assembly) could be exposed to future US sanctions for their role in undermining democratic processes and institutions in Venezuela," he said.
Colombia, Mexico, Peru and other nations joined the US in saying they did not recognize the results of Sunday's election.
Maduro's own attorney general, Luisa Ortega -- who broke with him months ago over his policies -- also said she would not acknowledge the body, calling it part of the president's "dictatorial ambition."
The European Union expressed "preoccupation for the fate of democracy in Venezuela" and said it, too, doubted it could accept the results.
And Britain's Foreign Minister Boris Johnson warned that Venezuela "stands on the brink of disaster."
"Nicolas Maduro's government must stop before it is too late," he said.
The European Union condemned the "excessive and disproportionate use of force" by Venezuelan police and troops on Sunday.
A spokeswoman for the European Commission said: "A Constituent Assembly, elected under doubtful and often violent circumstances, cannot be part of the solution."
However, old allies Bolivia, Cuba, Nicaragua and Russia stood by Maduro, who shrugged off mass protests and a previous round of US sanctions on some of his officials to see through the election.
Russia also threw its weight behind Maduro and the election, backing the government turnout figure.
The foreign ministry in Moscow said in a statement it hopes countries "who apparently want to increase economic pressure on Caracas will display restraint and abandon their destructive plans."
With AFP
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela's 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luisa Ortega</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's Foreign Minister Boris Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Datanalisis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Electoral Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constituent Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan President Nicholas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America's Treasury Secretary Mr Mnuchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicaragua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolivia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
