<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404982628865429</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Asia Pacific Defence Reporter</source>
  <url>http://www.asiapacificdefencereporter.com/articles/1222/Next-Gen-Military-Vehicles-Thousands-Of-Victorian-Jobs</url>
  <title>Next-Gen Military Vehicles, Thousands Of Victorian Jobs</title>
  <content>
Victoria is a step closer to securing a multi-billion dollar military vehicle contract that would create thousands of jobs in local manufacturing

1st Aug 2017

Victoria is a step closer to securing a multi-billion dollar military  vehicle contract that would create thousands of jobs in local  manufacturing and help keep our troops safe for the future.

Premier Daniel Andrews and Minister for Industry and Employment Wade  Noonan today visited the General Motors Holden site at Fishermans Bend  to announce that Victoria had been selected as the preferred state by  BAE Systems Australia to build 225 new Combat Reconnaissance Vehicles.

The Andrews Labor Government has signed a Heads of Agreement with BAE  Systems to build the state-of-the-art vehicles at the former Holden  site at Fishermans Bend, should it win the contract for the LAND 400  Phase Two project.

A final decision on which state is awarded the contract rests with the Turnbull Government.

Victoria has an outstanding track record in the design, development  and manufacture of military vehicles for Australian and international  customers. The world-class Bushmaster and Hawkei vehicles are already  manufactured at Thales in Bendigo.

Our research and development expertise, highly-skilled workforce and  supply chain makes Victoria the natural home of vehicle manufacturing.

The LAND 400 Phase Two project is worth around $5 billion and would  create more than 2,000 manufacturing and supply chain jobs in Victoria.

Victorian defence companies would get a large share of the work, with  BAE Systems agreeing to partner with Marand, MOOG Australia, Motec, AME  Systems, RUAG Australia, DVR Engineering and APV to build vehicle  components.

The new fleet of vehicles will replace the current Australian Light Armoured Vehicle fleet.

Victoria's defence sector is worth $8 billion to the local economy  every year, and is made up of about 20,000 people and 400 businesses.

Quotes attributable to Premier Daniel Andrews

"Victoria is the traditional home of vehicle manufacturing, and  this project would create thousands of jobs at a time when our  automotive sector is in transition."

"Our message to Malcolm Turnbull is simple - bring this work to  Victoria. We have the workforce, the track record and the supply chain  to get it done."

Quotes attributable to Minister for Industry and Employment Wade Noonan

"Victoria's automotive workers deserve certainty at a time when local car manufacturing is coming to an end."

"This project is the perfect opportunity to harness our  highly-skilled manufacturing workforce and build the next-generation of  combat vehicles that will help keep our troops safe."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thousands Of Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Motec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phase Two</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOOG Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAE Systems</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAE Systems Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heads of Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews Labor Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LAND 400 Phase Two</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUAG Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bendigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisherman's Bend</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bushmaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Employment Wade Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Land 400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Motors Holden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gen Military Vehicles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVR Engineering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AME</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Employment Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Combat Reconnaissance Vehicles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Light Armoured Vehicle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
