<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404286844151816</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/flippin-heck-cdc-rocker-brian-johnsons-own-highway-to-hell/news-story/cea6732e4e0b4c6b9d8fa43900a0483a</url>
  <title>AC/DC rocker's own highway to hell!</title>
  <content>
AC/DC rocker Brian Johnson has found out the hard way that it's a long way to the body shop if you want to roll your car.
The now-retired lead singer crashed his classic motor in dramatic fashion taking part in a charity fundraiser race on the weekend. Johnson must have felt he was on a highway to hell when his Austin A35 flipped and landed on its roof during a qualifying round in the English countryside.
But the experienced racing and car enthusiast kept a stiff upper lip and walked away unscathed from the bender.
The 69-year-old petrol head is renowned for his stable of cars, with reports his garage is a roll call of impressive vehicles including a Ferrari, Rolls Royce and Bentley.
He was putting his driving skills to the test at the Silverstone Classic in Northamptonshire - the world's biggest classic motor racing festival - when he crashed.
Johnson was zipping around the course as part of the Celebrity Challenge Trophy Race which raises money for prostate cancer research.
The race split the celebrities into teams by their professions and they were mentored by a racing professional.
The Screen Stars team, which was mentored by Formula 1 star Mark Blundell and included former Top Gear anchor Tiff Needell, was the winner.
Johnson, who has reportedly previously said "cars give me the same thrill as music", has fronted documentaries on classic cars and claims his hearing loss is more from his love of engines than rock'n'roll.
He stepped down from the AC/DC's world tour in March 2016 because of hearing problems.
In 2014 he opened up to US shock jock Howard Stern about it, saying: "I've got hearing loss in me left ear. I didn't get it from music.
"I got it from sitting in a race car too long without ear plugs. Music had nothing to do with it."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silverstone Classic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Formula 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiff Needell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Blundell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AC/DC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austin A35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top Gear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northamptonshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Stern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Screen Stars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celebrity Challenge Trophy Race</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
