<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404969743963271</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/pilot-lands-plane-blind-after-giant-hailstones-shatter-cockpit-windscreen/news-story/9ffbdc793087b28340b988f2d71b3720</url>
  <title>Pilot lands plane 'blind' after giant hailstones shatter cockpit windscreen</title>
  <content>
The Best of Bumpy Landings
0:57

While air travel is, statistically speaking, the safest method of transportation, a bit of turbulence can put even the most seasoned journeyman at the edge of their seat. Here's a collection of our favorite aviation clips. Credit: Various via Storyful

May 18th 2017
2 months ago
/video/video.news.com.au/Business/

Brave pilot lands plane "blind".

Sam WebbThe Sun

Share

A BRAVE pilot landed a passenger jet "blind" after giant hailstones smashed the cockpit's windscreen and almost tore off its nose cone.
These incredible pictures show the plane after the pilot's heroic emergency landing at Istanbul's Ataturk Airport with 127 passengers on board,  reports.
They show the severe external damage to the Airbus A320 from sudden unexpected hail during a thunder storm, and passengers crying and praying as the stricken plane comes in to a shaky landing.
A voice on the ground is heard saying: "He won't do it, he won't do it."

Brave pilot lands plane "blind"

Captain Alexander Akopov said he and other crew were celebrating as if it was a "second birthday" after his lifesaving heroics in coping with damage caused by hailstones the size of hen's eggs.
Incredibly, his autopilot was taken out in the damage.
"I have been flying for 30 years," he said.
"Well, did you see the plane landing? Was it okay? The passengers are alive. It is normal. This is our professional reliability.
"Our locator did not show this weather disaster, this is why it happened. It was hard, but the main thing is that people are alive."

Самолет турецкой компании "Atlasglobal", пилотируемый украинскими пилотами, попал в град.
Oleg Lungul
The catastrophe hit some 10 minutes after taking off on a Turkish airline Atlasglobal flight to Erkan in northern Cyprus.
Having climbed to 1300 metres, the hailstones cracked the cockpit windows - preventing the pilot from seeing his runway approach.
The captain was permitted to try and land at Ataturk airport even though it had been closed due to the atrocious weather.
Full-scale emergency protocol was in place with fire appliances and ambulances awaiting the plane.

A video shows a woman with red nails gripping a seat because of the plane's extreme shaking during the landing.
Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko called the captain to congratulate him and awarded him with the Ukrainian Order of Courage.
Aviation experts also praised the two Turkish cabin crew for their bravery.
Mass applause broke out at the airport when he landed the plane.
The pilots of other planes greeted the plane by flashing their lights and came aboard to shake the pilots' hands.
This article originally appeared on  and was reproduced with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam WebbThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbus A320</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Самолет</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Istanbul's Ataturk Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erkan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best of Bumpy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyprus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Akopov</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ataturk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oleg Lungul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukrainian Order of Courage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlasglobal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
