<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404939679191783</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:42</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/ratehacker-augusts-best-credit-card-savings-account-and-home-loan-deals-2/</url>
  <title>Ratehacker: August's Best Credit Card, Savings Account And Home Loan Deals</title>
  <content>
In our monthly Ratehacker round-up, Jeremy Cabral from comparison site  highlights the latest credit card deals, plus the best savings accounts and home loans.

Credit Cards

Feature: 0 percent balance transfer

: 0% per annum for 24 months on balance transfers With 24 months interest-free, this card is one of the longest-running balance transfer deals in the market right now. The annual fee for the card is $90. This offer is exclusively available through finder.com.au, and you have to apply before 31 August 2017.

Feature: Bonus reward points

: 100,000 bonus Membership Rewards points and $400 travel credit To qualify for the bonus points, you need to apply before 2 October 2017, be approved and spend $1,500 on the card within your first three months of membership. Note that the card has a relatively high $395 annual fee, so you'll want to actively take advantage of the bonus points and $400 travel credit.

Home Loans

Feature: Variable rate home loan

: Comparison rate of 3.66% per annum This loan is a frequent Ratehacker pick due to its minimal fees and low variable rate. To qualify for the bottom rate, you'll need to be an owner-occupier, and you'll need a 20% deposit saved.

Feature: Interest-only loans

: Comparison rate of 3.72% per annum Regulatory crackdowns have made it , but there are still options out there. This loan lets you go interest-only as an owner-occupier for up to 10 years.

Savings Accounts

Feature: High bonus saver interest rate

: 3.05% per annum bonus rate To earn the bonus interest rate, you need to link this account to an ME Everyday account and make a weekly purchase using Tap & Go on your debit Mastercard. If you don't do that, the interest rate is a less impressive 1.30% per annum. The interest is payable on balances up to $250,000, and there are no account-keeping fees.

Personal Loans

Feature: P2P car loan

: Comparison rate from 9.70% per annum Harmoney offers a customised interest rate based on your credit rating. You can borrow between $5,000 and $35,000, with 36 or 60-month loan terms.

Travel Insurance

Feature: Policy discount

: 10% off all premiums  Receive a discount on your travel insurance with this finder.com.au exclusive coupon.

Jeremy Cabral is the Global Head of Publishing for  which includes tools to compare credit cards, find savings accounts, energy deals, mobile & broadband plans, and a constantly updated database of discounts and coupon codes. Connect with Jeremy on ,  and .

WATCH MORE: Tech & Finance News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mastercard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Interest-only</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Cabral</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P2P</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August's Best Credit Card</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harmoney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savings Account And Home Loan Deals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Membership Rewards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Head of Publishing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ratehacker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
