<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404969743963302</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/sex-assault-shame-at-australian-universities/news-story/d94997d7a8f3f38ff019c2addc2309c3</url>
  <title>Sex assault shame at universities</title>
  <content>
DAMNING new research has exposed the prevalence of sexual assault and harassment at Australia's universities.
More than 30,000 students were surveyed by the Australian Human Rights Commission last year for the Change The Course report, the findings of which were declared "concerning".
Half of all students said they were sexually harassed on at least one occasion in 2016, and one in five experienced it in a university setting.
Seven per cent of students overall experienced a sexual assault while 1.6 per cent of these took place at a uni itself in 2015 or 2016.
Hundreds of deeply personal submissions were also received and many are included in the report, such as the story of a male student exposing his genitalia to a female in the middle of a lecture.
Sex discrimination commissioner Kate Jenkins also spoke of women being groped by men during class, a rape that took place after a college party and a female student who was repeatedly sexually harassed by a lecturer during their commute home on public transport.
"A woman told us she was raped by a senior student leader who was running (an orientation week camp)," Ms Jenkins said at the report's launch.
"She later heard that he had previously raped another student at one of these camps and no action was a result."
Sex assaults were likely to occur at university or residential college social events, within the college setting or on public transport, she said.
"We also heard about hazing and other college traditions ... these have been widely documented in the media," Ms Jenkins said.
"The fact these behaviours continue to exist and that they involve sexual assault and harassment is deeply concerning."
There was a perception among students that college staff were aware of such conduct but "did nothing to prevent it".
The vast majority of victims took no formal action, saying they didn't know where to go for help or weren't sure how serious the incident was.
Perhaps adding to the reluctance to report assaults or harassment was the finding that 45 per cent of victims knew the perpetrator.
Universities Australia calls for 'zero tolerance' on sexual assault
"It's confronting to learn that sexual assault and sexual harassment is an all-too-common part of (university) life," Ms Jenkins said.
Professor Margaret Gardner of Universities Australia, which commissioned the report, announced an initial 10-point plan to tackle the problem.
"We send a strong and clear message today that these behaviours are not acceptable. Not on our campuses -- and not in Australia society," Professor Gardner said.
They include the development of a "respectful relationships" program, more specialist training for counsellors to support victims, a 24-hour support line and broader first responder training for uni staff.
"The 10 major initiatives we announce today signal our resolve to ensure our students study and live in a safe and respectful culture, and to ensure that students who experience and report unacceptable behaviour receive the right response of compassion, care and support," Professor Gardner said.
In addition to these national initiatives, universities across Australia will respond to the recommendations by taking specific local action to build on initiatives already in place, she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Margaret Gardner of Universities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jenkins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Gardner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
