<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404978333898023</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/personal-finance/shares/amazon-impact-on-australian-retailers-overplayed-20170721-gxfrn4</url>
  <title>Amazon impact on Australian retailers overplayed</title>
  <content>
Fund managers Kate Howitt of Fidelity, Katie Hudson of Yarra Capital Management and Don Hamson of Plato Investment Management talk to Sally Patten about the outlook for the reporting season.
Which sectors and companies are likely to deliver top line growth as opposed to lifting profits through cost cutting?
Howitt: Top line growth has become more elusive as the broader tail winds of credit creation, housing investment and mining infrastructure have receded. This is particularly true for the large cap end, with the banks, supermarkets and Telstra operating in more subdued environments. However, classic pockets of growth, such as healthcare and software, still contain a range of names offering high single digit or double digit revenue growth.
And growth can still be found in other sectors, albeit more selectively. In the consumer sector, A2 Milk will benefit from its expansion in China, the US and the UK, while Corporate Travel will also expand in its overseas markets. Within financials, alternatives manager BlueSky will see revenue scale quickly up as it builds its assets under management. And perhaps surprisingly, we also expect decent revenue growth from the more "yield-focused" Sydney Airport.

Michele Mossop

Hudson: Top line growth remains elusive for Australian companies and highly prized by investors. With earnings growth for the S&P/ASX 200 likely to be around 4 per cent, there are few companies currently exhibiting strong revenue growth trends. This coming reporting season we expect companies such as Resmed, Seek and CarSales, which are beginning to see the benefit of recent investments in product innovation, to deliver earnings growth through revenue rather than via cost-out initiatives.

Hamson: Higher average commodity prices, particularly for iron ore, will likely lift revenues for mining stocks and we see potential for higher earnings and dividends in this area. Higher electricity and gas prices will lift the likes of AGL Energy, which will show improvements at both the top and bottom line, given its role in generation. With more price increases posted in June, this should boost earnings into fiscal 2018. Healthcare stocks such as CSL and insurers like IAG and Suncorp (benefiting from premium increases) should also start to see some top line growth. Rising equity markets should also lift the revenue of some fund managers.
The miners produced buoyant half-year earnings figures. Do you expect this trend to continue for the full year and into 2017-18?
Howitt: As quarterly reports have come through for the miners, we have seen continued strength as a result of elevated commodity prices during the first half of the year. Strong commodity pricing to date has been a function of unexpectedly strong demand, supply cuts in China and a restocking of inventories.
As we look to out to fiscal 2018, we would agree with futures markets, which are implying a softer commodities prices, led by iron ore. We expect the drivers of this to be waning steel demand from recently tightened credit conditions in China, the completion of supply side reform measures and higher inventories in iron ore which will provide a further source of lower cost supply if steel prices do roll over.

Arsineh Houspian

Hudson: The resources sector will deliver another solid set of results this half as they rebound off a weak prior year when commodity prices were at lower levels and, in the case of BHP, included major asset write-downs. More important is the likely direction of commodity prices.
For commodities such as iron ore we believe current prices are unsustainably high, with iron ore in oversupply relative to modest growth in demand from Chinese steel production and margins for iron ore producers close to historical peaks. These trends all suggest the future direction of the iron ore price is downwards. As a key commodity for BHP and Rio Tinto this is an important lead indicator for their future earnings.
Hamson: Profits will likely be moderately higher than the last half-year and given reduced investment, they should have improved cashflow. We have no expectation that prices will move too far from current levels given the supply-demand balance. Having said that, recent rises in the Australian dollar may provide a little headwind.
Will it be possible this August for the retailers to convince investors that they will be able to survive the expansion of Amazon and survive it well? In other words, will the retailers' figures be strong, and is anyone paying attention to them anyway?

Howitt: A lot of the concern over Amazon's impact comes from the experience in the US, but the US has a massive oversupply of retail space, making it a less reliable case study for other markets. Here at home, retailers have competed against online offerings for years, but the concern is that Amazon will raise the bar on customer experience and be happy to operate at a loss for many years.
Aside from Amazon, local retailers face other headwinds - the ongoing shift of spend towards services and experiences, the growing impact of Aldi and Costco, the potential loss of disposable income from higher utility prices and mortgage repayments and the tapering of the wealth effect from housing as house prices flatten. None of these will be resolved on a six-month view. But in this reporting season, we expect JB Hi-Fi and Harvey Norman to report solid numbers, bolstered by the exit of Dick Smith and the ongoing strength of the housing market in the first half of this year.
Hudson: Forecasting the direction of change is often easy but the rate of change and the final outcome is far more difficult. While the world of retail continues to shift we believe investors have recently over-reacted to Amazon's entry to Australia, the shape of which is not yet certain. It's often forgotten that despite its success, Amazon has been operating in the US for 20 years and today accounts for only 4 per cent of retail sales.
In Canada, a country with similar demographics and density to Australia, Amazon has roughly 1 per cent market share after launching its localised website in 2002. We don't believe Amazon's Australian launch heralds the destruction for all incumbents.

Indeed some proactive retailers such as Super Retail Group have been trading well. Retailers with low cost structures and strong brands like JB Hi-Fi have an important place in the Australian market, with upcoming results likely to be solid. Amazon will be a slow build and won't be winner takes all. The greatest vulnerability will be with weak retailers, such as the discount department stores, and shopping centres, where reduced foot traffic and rising shop vacancies over time will pressure rental income.
Hamson: The Amazon effect is all expectation at the moment, which means Amazon's impending expansion to Australia should not impact current results. I'm not sure we will really get any better understanding of the impact of Amazon from this results season. We expect retail results will be quite mixed. Department store sales are still quite poor, whilst other retailers are still doing well.
What do you expect Telstra will do with its dividend this year and in the subsequent two years?
Howitt: As interest rates on typical retail yield products such as term deposits have come down, investors have increasingly turned to shares for income as well as capital growth. Despite fears that this results in less investment by businesses and worse economic outcomes, academic research has shown that higher overall dividend yields in a stock market are aligned with higher not lower capital returns.

Companies should invest in projects with a high probability of delivering strong returns to shareholders and Telstra is no exception. If it can do this and maintain the dividend, then well and good. But with the NBN cashflows rolling off and significant levels of industry change, the most prudent and conservative course of action would be for Telstra to reduce its dividend at some point over the next couple of years, in order to maintain a strong balance sheet and the ability to compete against large disruptors. Sadly for yield-focused investors, it turns out that "bond proxy" stocks are still stocks after all.
Hudson: Telstra's core earnings have been in decline for some time. NBN payments are expected to peak with the rollout in the 2019 financial year and then decline. Without the NBN payments Telstra has a large earnings and cash flow hole which we believe makes it extremely difficult to sustain the current dividend. One option under consideration is the securitisation of the long-term NBN cash flows, which would bring forward future NBN payments.
While on some levels this might appear an attractive strategy, it would add complexity to the business and we don't believe management will pursue that option. With declining cash flows and the need to invest it is clear that the 34c dividend will have to be cut. Whether Telstra's board makes the hard call this year or in the subsequent year will depend on the sense of urgency to address these issues.
Hamson: The longer term trajectory of Telstra's dividend is much easier to forecast than shorter term changes, but the outlook is not positive. Our longer term expectation is that Telstra has to reduce its dividend over the next few years as the NBN rollout continues, NBN payments slow, and as competition increases. Some say Telstra should begin to cut dividends this year in order to invest for the future, but we are more inclined to think that Telstra will delay cutting dividends as long as possible. There are also rumours that Telstra may even securitise its future NBN revenues and use the cash generated to complete a share buy-back.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investment Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporate Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Hamson of Plato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Hi-Fi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howitt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hudson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Hudson of Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsineh Houspian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Patten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Howitt of Fidelity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CarSales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Retail Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resmed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MICHELE MOSSOP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlueSky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
