<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404982628865390</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:52</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/do-you-know-answer-roundabout-road-rules-teaser/3207395/</url>
  <title>Do you know the answer to this roundabout road rules teaser?</title>
  <content>
ROUNDABOUTS.

Let's face it, so many drivers don't know how to use them. Or maybe they do and they just disregard the rules, but that's another matter entirely.

Indicate around, straight or off - do you know when you should indicate while using a roundabout?

The Queensland Department of Transport and Main Roads has created this little brainteaser to test drivers' knowledge of roundabout road rules.

The driver of the orange car wants to continue straight through the roundabout. How many times do they need to indicate?

Comment with your answer below.

And for a hint, the Department of Transport and Main Roads offered this advice: 

"Here's another way of looking at a roundabout-think of it like a clock face.

Noosa is mourning the loss of bright, bubbly mother Sharon Cuthbert
About 1800 passengers dock for a day at Coast
"We're struggling, no use lying to people..."
Architect of a region stops briefly on his final journey.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Cuthbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Department of Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
