<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404325498858231</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/world/donald-trumps-general-john-kelly-strikes-anthony-scaramucci-20170731-gxmngl</url>
  <title>Trump's General is now in charge to fix the internal bedlam</title>
  <content>
Now that a disciplined military man is empowered to impose order in President Donald Trump's chaotic White House, the foul-mouthed "Mooch" from Wall Street has been told, "you're fired".
's Day 1 ouster of communications director Anthony Scaramucci sends a bold warning to West Wing advisers and the world that the General is in charge to fix the internal bedlam.
Yet unless General Kelly can exert order over a wild President, the  that have bedevilled the President's opening six months, is likely to persist.
As former Wall Street salesman Scaramucci suggested last week in his expletive-ridden , the fish rots from the head.

AP

His invective on-record The New Yorker teeing off at White House colleagues was the antithesis of the type of behaviour condoned by General Kelly, a four-decade marine and Iraq war veteran.

Less noticed was Scaramucci's take-down of , in vulgar terms best not repeated here.
Trump, reportedly, originally endorsed Scaramucci's tirade calling Priebus a "paranoid schizophrenic" and leaker. The White House now insists the President believes it was "inappropriate".
Trump insisted on Twitter there was no "chaos".
Scaramucci, just 10 days in the job, joins a growing list of departed White House staff. These include a chief of staff, deputy chief of staff, national security adviser, deputy national security adviser, two communications directors, a press secretary and a media adviser.

AP

Stealing the spotlight

The former hedge fund operator and Goldman Sachs financier boasted that he reported directly to the President, not the chief of staff.
General Kelly is setting the chain of command, swiftly and decisively.
Scaramucci had become centre of media attention in Trump's soap opera resembling an episode of The Apprentice or House of Cards.

Time Magazine

Trump  from him - just like when Bannon's image was splashed over the February front page of TIME magazine and depicted as the second most powerful man in the world and "great manipulator".
Bannon, shrewdly, has been inconspicuous since then.
Besides managing the unpredictable Trump, General Kelly will need to unite the warring White House factions, encompassing nationalists, establishment Republicans and family members, including daughter Ivanka and son-in-law Jared Kushner.
Controlling who strolls into the Oval Office and who has the President's ear will not be easy, given the free-wheeling former reality television star's unwieldy presidential style.

General Kelly must reset the culture from Trump down in the White House to end the unprecedented dysfunction.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Kelly</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Cards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
