<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651403938951795028</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/qa-recap-panel-tackles-trumps-dysfunction-just-as-the-mooch-falls-20170731-gxmo36.html</url>
  <title>Q&A recap: Panel tackles Trump's dysfunction, just as the Mooch falls</title>
  <content>
It seems fair to say that before the Trump era, very few Australians would have been aware of the existence - let alone the name - of the White House communications director. But as Q&A reminded us on Monday night, these are not normal times.
This is an age in which you can take the acronym WTAF, and assume the T stands for Trump, and that the F will be censored in the newspaper unless you happen to be reading an interview with the A - Anthony Scaramucci, the President of the United States' recently appointed and just fired comms boss, loyalty enforcer and tormentor of journalists who have spent the past week coming up with imaginative alternatives to "bleep", "effing" and "rooster".

Up Next

Life after Pitt: Jolie reveals

01:26

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Q&A: Could Trump destabilise US-Australia relationship?

Despite the historically strongA relationship, is it possible theA current US administration could change relationsA between Australia and the US?

On Monday's Q&A, the man they call the Mooch - who had a job when the program aired and was out of that job just a few hours later - was front and centre as the program spent roughly half its time pondering The Donald and related matters, a sign of how completely Trump dysfunction and related fears have come to dominate global discourse. The world is now mulling the Trump and the Mooch, and wondering how the latter's evocative description of a White House colleague "bleeping" his own "rooster" might affect them.
It's a world gone mad.Photo: ABC
Trump first reared his head half an hour in, at the end of a discussion about Labor's fresh push for an Australian republic which had panellist Greg Sheridan lamenting "the hideous complexity and grotesque, deformed nature of the things that people would put in place of the Queen" - a statement that prompted host Tony Jones to interject: "Like President Trump or something?"
On recent evidence from Washington, even staunch Australian republicans could only nod in agreement.

Then a questioner, referencing the Mooch, wanted to know: "From recent events in the US, including the President's criticism of his appointed Attorney-General, the replacements of his chief of staff and the communication director's vulgar comment on his former colleague, the Trump administration has proven to be dangerously unpredictable. Despite the historically strong relationship between the US and Australia, is it possible the volatile nature of the current US administration can change relations between Australia and the US?"
Sheridan, a conservative commentator in the Murdoch stable, took comfort in the notion that for the most part so far, Trump merely looks crazy - cold comfort, but these days you take comfort where you can get it.Photo: ABC
"I annoyed all my readers by saying I thought Trump was a completely unacceptable person to be president," Sheridan said. "He has abundantly fulfilled that analysis. But, nonetheless, the US alliance is of the most profound importance to Australia's national interest and indeed to global security. So, what is smart for Australia to do through this period is to try to preserve the alliance and to get what good we can out of Trump... He speaks like a madman but so far he hasn't done truly mad things."
Which brought us to the delicate matter of how the government of the day reacts to the Madness of King Donald. 
Coalition panellist Steve Ciobo picked his words carefully - or more specifically, he picked Greg Sheridan's words carefully, latching on to Sheridan's concluding point on the indispensability of the US alliance.
Ciobo: "I agree with Greg's final comments."
Jones: "What about his earlier comments?"
Ciobo dived for the cliche, a not unreasonable tactic when trying to navigate these waters.
"The PM summed it up when he said it was more like family than anything else. That's a good benchmark to have in a relationship. Families squabble but we're strong."
Well, yes - but as Jones noted in response: "We see quite a few members of the Turnbull family and not many of them are like Donald Trump."
Labor's Jim Chalmers, free of government responsibilities but conscious of the strength of the wild currents into which he was wading, offered that while the Mooch and his expletive-laden meanderings were indeed interesting, we had to take a broader view.
"Our responsibility, our obligation as Australians is to make the best of this situation that we can," Chalmers said, his reference to the President of the United States as "this situation" perhaps telling us everything we needed to know.
"We don't have a say in who the Americans elect as their President or who he hires as his communications director or who he fires or what his communications director says to journalists when he thinks he's off the record. Those things are all interesting. But at the end of the day our responsibility...  is to make the best of this situation. We want the Americans to be rational and stable and to the extent we can help them be that, that is what we should be looking to do, but establishing and maintaining our own relationships as well."
And so this is where we're at: wondering how best we can help Donald Trump be rational and stable. 
If you listen carefully, you can hear alarms going off. Call it the Mooch effect. The world has woken up. 
Cock-a-doodle-do.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TheA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jolie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>relationsA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ciobo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>strongA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheridan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chalmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday's Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Sheridan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Ciobo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madness of King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's Jim Chalmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
