<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404505887488093</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/patrick-dangerfield-likely-to-accept-one-game-ban/3207330/</url>
  <title>Patrick Dangerfield likely to accept one-game ban</title>
  <content>
GEELONG is unlikely to challenge Patrick Dangerfield's one-match suspension on Tuesday, with the Cats and the champion mindful of the risks of missing an extra game.
The Cats have until 11am on Tuesday to decide whether to challenge Dangerfield's suspension for a tackle that concussed Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer, but on Monday night the club and Dangerfield were leaning towards accepting the one-match ban.
Geelong and its champion midfielder were unlikely to challenge, despite misgivings about the contentious verdict, because they do not want to risk Dangerfield missing a second crucial clash - round 21's game against Richmond, also at Simonds Stadium.
Club officials were deliberating with a QC and examining avenues for appealing the verdict and taking it to the AFL tribunal. If, as seemed likely, Dangerfield took the one-match ban, he would miss Friday night's huge game against Sydney at Geelong.
The Brownlow Medal is not a consideration for either club or player, as Dangerfield himself made plain on Monday. Dangerfield had been vying for favouritism with Richmond's powerhouse midfielder Dustin Martin, who will be extremely short odds should Dangerfield confirm the suspension on Tuesday.
The AFL match review panel's verdict was based on video evidence of the incident in which Dangerfield tackled Kreuzer - in one motion - and took him to ground, where he struck his head, causing a concussion.
The fact that Kreuzer did not return to the field and that the subsequent medical report from Carlton said he had headaches and would miss training for three to four days meant that the tackle was graded as "medium impact" - incurring a ban.
Had the tackle been graded as low impact, Dangerfield would have escaped suspension.
The MRP did not speak to the relevant umpire who called play on in the incident, as the panel did not feel it necessary given the umpire had not seen the incident clearly.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
