<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404969743963295</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/10/46/brisbane-gateway-motorway-road-rage-death-tamate-heke</url>
  <title>Maori man 'dry retched after striking victim' in Brisbane road rage incident, court told</title>
  <content>
A labourer has described witnessing a Maori man throw a left handed punch at an older man on the side of a highway before hearing a "loud bang" when the victim fell in front of an oncoming truck, a court has been told.
Leon Wellman was travelling in the south bound lane of the Gateway Motorway on December 1 in 2015 at the precise moment Shane Merrigan fell in front of a garbage truck and was killed instantly.
New Zealand national Tamate Henry Heke, 38, is accused of throwing the punch in an apparent road rage incident that caused Merrigan, 50, to fall under the wheels of the travelling truck at Eight Mile Plains.
Heke has pleaded not guilty to manslaughter, and not guilty to the alternate charge of unlawful striking causing death in the Brisbane Supreme Court.
Labourer Leon Wellman told jurors in the court today he saw the two men, a Maori and an older looking man, standing within a metre of each other on the side of the Motorway. 
"Then the Maori left punched the older guy... he punched him with his left hand," Mr Wellman testified.
Mr Wellman said he saw the Maori man grab his head, pace up and down, and dry retch after the collision.
Under cross examination he agreed the victim looked aggressive.
"He was angry, yeah."
Crown prosecutor Clare Kelly on Monday said both men had been making their way home from work before pulling over to the left shoulder of the road and facing each other "for about 13 seconds".
Photographs showing the truck's blood-splattered undercarriage were viewed by jurors on the first day of the trial.
The jury also saw graphic footage from a motorway camera showing the two cars pulling onto the road's shoulder, the men getting out and the moment of fatal impact.
Defence barrister Anthony Kimmins said Heke told police he didn't intend to get into a fight when he pulled his Holden Astra over to the road's shoulder.

Related Articles

He said Mr Merrigan had been gesturing at Heke with his middle finger from behind the wheel, with the accused man allegedly telling investigators he thought the other man would "back off".
The trial continues before Justice Peter Applegarth.

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateway Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Merrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eight Mile Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamate Henry Heke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Astra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Kimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Wellman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Peter Applegarth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wellman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maori</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
