<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404583196900698</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/premier-very-optimistic-new-trains-will-be-ready-for-games-20170731-gxmp3z.html</url>
  <title>Premier 'very optimistic' new trains will be ready for Games</title>
  <content>
Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk says she is "very optimistic" the government's new trains will be ready in time for the Commonwealth Games.
It comes as a Labor backbencher warns there could be a "transport debacle" during the Commonwealth Games.Photo: AAP
Delivery of the New Generation Rollingstock trains from India was  while numerous issues were fixed, including disability access.
Asked if she could guarantee the NGR trains would be completely operable by the Commonwealth Games in April next year, Ms Palaszczuk said she was "optimistic".
"I am very optimistic that we will have the extra trains that are needed in time for the Commonwealth Games," Ms Palaszczuk told ABC radio Brisbane on Tuesday.
"There would be disability access, yes, on those trains."

Ms Palaszczuk pointed out the contract was signed by the former Liberal National Party government.
The Newman government ordered the 75 half-price trains in 2014, with the expectation all the trains would be delivered and in service by December 2018.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Ms Palaszczuk said until the faults were rectified, the government would not receive any more of the trains from India. 
"I've had regular briefings and I've had a recent briefing from the chair of Queensland Rail and the CEO ... and they are quietly confident that those issues are being rectified," she said.
During budget estimates, Deputy Premier Jackie Trad said the braking rate, sight lines, heating, ventilation and air-conditioning had been fixed, and the government was still working with the disability sector to address accessibility concerns.
Meanwhile, a Labor backbencher said there could be a "transport debacle" at the Commonwealth Games.
Member for Marlborough Bruce Saunders said "we're pulling out hair out at the moment", in relation to the NGR trains and the transport plan.
"I'm on the Commonwealth Games committee, inside the Labor party, and we're pulling our hair out," he told Triple M Fraser Coast.
"I'll be quite honest to people, these trains were supposed to be up and running for the Commonwealth Games.
"At this stage, we won't have, we may have one set up and running, at this stage we've got 15 other sets cannibalised to get one on the ground.
"We are going to have a transport debacle if we don't do, you know, we're working feverishly behind the scenes there to make sure we've got enough buses and we've got transport and trains, to get people to and from the arenas on the Gold Coast and of course at Boondall with the cycling."
Mr Saunders said "we're struggling at the moment".
"There's no use lying to people and saying 'oh yeah everything's good'. We are struggling that the people are really trying to get the transport up and running for the Commonwealth Games," he said.
There are 15 NGR trains in Queensland.
Of those, five have travelled thousands of kilometres for testing, but 10 trains - all those delivered from December 1, 2016 - have not moved.
Department of Transport director-general  before being put in service.
The Commonwealth Games has been identified as a , according to a review of the train timetable.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M Fraser Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlborough Bruce Saunders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boondall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Generation Rollingstock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Rail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Premier Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Saunders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
