<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405064233245361</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/brisbane-city-council-transport-boss-fears-bus-strikes-may-drag-on/news-story/8eea533af639224fa1032892d94b786c</url>
  <title>Bus strike deadlock worries council</title>
  <content>
BRISBANE'S public transport boss is "losing confidence" a deadlock that has resulted in rolling bus driver strikes will be resolved.
Deputy Mayor Adrian Schrinner told the public transport committee on Tuesday morning that council was hoping for the best but planning for the worst as negotiations with unions continue.
"As time has gone on, I'm losing confidence that they will come to an agreement, which is also an appropriate agreement for the ratepayers of Brisbane," Cr Schrinner said.
ouncil is due to meet with the Rail, Tram and Bus Union on Tuesday.
Cr Schrinner warned there were isolated instances of union drivers abusing employees who continued to work through the strike.
He said complaints had been made.
"There has been a few instances where drivers who have kept working have copped abuse by drivers who are striking," Cr Schrinner said.
"Obviously that's not on."
RTBU spokesman Tom Brown has previously said it was understandable casual bus drivers would take shifts during the strike action because they needed to put food on the table.
Cr Schrinner told the committee meeting that council had agreed to double its investment in security guards because the State Government had failed to step up to the plate with its bus driver safety review that was due to be finalised back in March this year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Mayor Adrian Schrinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Schrinner</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
