<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404969743963308</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-universities-pledge-action-to-tackle-sexual-assault-on-campus-20170801-gxmsur.html</url>
  <title>'One is too many': ANU and UC pledge action on sexual assault and harassment</title>
  <content>
Canberra's two biggest universities have pledged to take meaningful action to tackle sexual assault and harassment, after a landmark report revealed 6.9 per cent of students nationally faced attacks on campus.
The Human Rights Commission study found at least 116 Australian National University students were sexually assaulted in 2016, including 52 assaults on campus.Photo: Jay Cronan
More than 840 students reported that they had experienced sexual harassment with women overwhelmingly more likely to be targeted.
At ANU, 183 male students reported harassment, higher than the national average, with 59 per cent of the incidents involving someone known to the student.

At the University of Canberra, 1.1 per cent of respondents to the student reported that they experienced sexual assault in university settings, while 7.2 per cent said they had been subjected to sexual assault.
More than a quarter of UC students reported experiencing some form of sexual harassment in university settings during 2016.

Nationally, the survey of 31,000 Australian students found students were experiencing "unacceptable" rate of sexual assault on campus, including reports of being assaulted on the way to university, inside residential colleges and by the staff supervising them.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Released on Tuesday, , while more than half of all university students were sexually harassed in 2016, with 21 per cent of those in a university setting.
At ANU, 74 per cent of sexual harassment incidents included student perpetrators, while in five per cent of cases they were a lecturer or a tutor. The report found in 82 per cent of harassment reports men were involved as perpetrators.
At least 620 students witnessed sexual harassment at ANU last year, and 61 per cent of incidents of sexual harassment involved inappropriate staring or leering, sexually suggestive comments or jokes and intrusive questions about private life.
ANU vice-chancellor Brian Schmidt apologised to students for the assault and harassment.
"One incident is more than we should accept.
"Every member of our community has a right to expect they will be safe in their place of study, their place of work, or - as this campus is for many - their home," Professor Schmidt said.
"And that they will have the support of the university when they disclose. And that we will make every effort to make sure our community understands consent."
University of Canberra vice-chancellor Deep Saini said sexual and interpersonal violence had no place as part of campus life.
"Here at UC, we all have the right to a respectful and supportive environment where we can study, work and live safely. It's up to all of us to make sure we work together to keep our University and our community safe," Professor Saini said.
"The report shows that there is work to do and the results will help us inform how we can work harder to improve our education programs, our support services, policies and practices."
More to come.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Cronan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Saini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU, 183</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU, 74</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deep Saini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
