<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404110750490004</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/world/anthony-scaramucci-loses-white-house-role/news-story/1a24f531300a45016338e47b7775c8d3</url>
  <title>Scaramucci dumped from White House</title>
  <content>
US PRESIDENT Donald Trump has removed Anthony Scaramucci from his position as communications director, just 10 days after accepting the role.
The White House confirmed his resignation in a statement early this morning, saying the President felt comments by Scaramucci in a magazine interview were inappropriate. It involved a crude attack against other senior members of the president's senior staff.
"The president certainly felt that Anthony's comments were inappropriate for a person in that position and he didn't want to burden General Kelly," White House spokeswoman Sarah Sanders said at a briefing, referring to John Kelly, who was sworn in as a replacement White House chief of staff earlier Monday.
He's the 10th high-profile government official to fall foul of Trump's "your fired" management style since the administration took office in January.DISCIPLINE PUSH
The decision to remove Mr Scaramucci reportedly came at the request of Kelly, who accepted his new role just hours earlier. Mr Kelly was tapped by Mr Trump to bring some stability to the chaotic White House.
But Trump had insisted while swearing-in the retired Marine general that there was "no chaos" in his White House.
CNN reported White House sources saying that Mr Kelly did not believe Mr Scaramucci was disciplined enough for the role. His attack on then-White House chief of staff Reince Priebus and Trump's chief strategist Steve Bannon in profanity-laden terms had clearly backfired.
CNN said that Mr Scaramucci, known affectionately as "The Mooch" by friends and colleagues, was escorted off the property.'SCARAMUCCI, PACK YOUR STUFF AND GO..."
The "Mooch's" colourful character has evoked an equally colourful reaction to his firing from social media.
Actor Kate Hudson was one of many personalities to quickly mock the in-and-out communications director and the White House.
She joked Scaramucci and Trump could be the lead actors in a remake of "How to Lose a Guy in 10 Days" ... with appropriate digitally altered art.
Other social media posts ranged from adaptations of the lyrics for Queen's Bohemian Rhapsody, repurposed memes and re-contexed White House clips.FIRED BEFORE HE WAS HIRED
Mr Scaramucci's removal came just 10 days after he was brought on to the West Wing staff, although he wasn't expected to officially assume his role until mid-August.
His arrival led to the departures of Sean Spicer, the former press secretary, and Reince Priebus, the president's first chief of staff.
Mr Scaramucci targeted Mr Priebus as well as chief White House strategist Steve Bannon in an expletive-filled interview with The New Yorker last week, calling Mr Priebus a "f**king paranoid schizophrenic, a paranoiac​."
Referring to the interview at a press briefing on Monday White House spokesperson Sarah Huckabee-Sanders said that Mr Trump "felt that Anthony's comments were inappropriate for a person in that position."
Ms Huckabee-Sanders also said that the president did not want to "burden General Kelly with that line of succession."
She said there would be no other role for Mr Scaramucci within the administration.

Highest Stock Market EVER, best economic numbers in years, unemployment lowest in 17 years, wages raising, border secure, S.C.: No WH chaos! THUNDERBOLTS AND LIGHTNING
Earlier, Mr Trump had refused to criticise Mr Scaramucci following the interview. Close associates of Mr Trump told media that the president approved of Mr Scaramucci's aggressive style.
Newt Gingrich, the former Republican House Speaker and a surrogate of Mr Trump, said Mr Trump and Mr Scaramucci "sort of speak the same language."
"I think that Trump is probably very happy with him right now and I think that's good for Trump himself because part of the reason Trump gets so aggressive is he feels like nobody is defending him and he's gotta go out and do it all himself,"  John Catsimatidis on the Cats Roundtable radio show on 970 AM in an interview that aired on Sunday.'BUSINESS AS USUAL'
In a Twitter message early on Monday morning, just hours before the announcement about Mr Scaramucci, Mr Trump insisted that there has been "No WH chaos!"
Later in an Oval Office ceremony Mr Trump predicted Mr Kelly, who previously served as US Homeland Security chief, would do a "spectacular job."

Highest Stock Market EVER, best economic numbers in years, unemployment lowest in 17 years, wages raising, border secure, S.C.: No WH chaos!
The chief of staff is the highest ranking White House employee - a chief operating officer who organizes staff, manages the president's schedule and decides who gets access to him and when.
That is no small mission in Mr Trump's White House, where a rotating cast of family and staff with unclear roles and opaque job titles walk into the Oval Office seemingly at will.CAREER SUICIDE?
Many question whether anyone can rein in the mercurial, Twitter-happy Mr Trump, who has appeared to encourage the infighting among various factions vying for influence in his administration.
Among the casualtis so fare are:
Reince Priebus, former White House chief-of-staff.
Sean Spicer, former press secretary.
Michael Dubke, former communications director.
Walter M. Shaub Jr., former diretor of the Office of Government Ethics.
James Comey, former director of the FBI.
Michael Flynn, former National Security Advisor.
Sally Yates, former acting Attorney General.
Preet Bharara, former US attorney for the district of Manhattan and the 'Sheriff' of Wall St.
Katie Walsh, former White House deputy chief of staff.
Ms Huckabee-Sanders said all staff would now report to Mr Kelly first, even the president's daughter Ivanka and son-in-law Jared Kushner, both senior advisors to Mr Trump.
In the words of the White House announcement Mr Scaramucci was leaving because he "felt it was best to give new Chief of Staff John Kelly a clean slate and the ability to build his own team."
The two-sentence release concluded: "We wish him all the best."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THUNDERBOLTS AND LIGHTNING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WH</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cats Roundtable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preet Bharara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter-happy Mr Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Priebus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Dubke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Scaramucci</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter M. Shaub Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S.C</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIRED BEFORE HE WAS HIRED</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KATE HUDSON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Bohemian Rhapsody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stock Market EVER</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Security Advisor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Homeland Security</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Catsimatidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAREER SUICIDE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Trump's White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January.DISCIPLINE PUSH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican House Speaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Yates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STUFF AND GO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newt Gingrich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheriff' of Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday's White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
