<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405059938277956</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/west-beaches/marion-junior-swimming-star-wins-30-gold-medals-in-just-four-days-at-the-sa-short-course-championships/news-story/ecfca635e3940becc221d29ddb88cddd</url>
  <title>This SA kid just won 30 gold medals in four days</title>
  <content>
ADAM Holland had just won 22 gold medals over three days of competition and entered the final day of the SA Short Course Championships with eight events to go.
The 800m freestyle and 400m individual medley loomed large - both difficult races at any time for a 12-year-old, and especially so for Adam, given his triumphs in the days before.
But the Seacombe Heights swimmer pushed through and won both, along with his six other finals that day to take his tally for the championships to an astonishing 30 gold medals in his age group.
"I knew that I had the fastest qualifying time in all the events so I set myself a goal of winning gold in all of them," Adam, a Marion Swimming Club member, says.
Along with his Michael Phelps-like medal haul, Adam broke 10 individual state records and one relay state record.
He also took home the President's Trophy for best male performance for his 200m breaststroke record and the Peter Bowen Pain Trophy for the leading male swimmer of the meet.
Adam puts the success down to rigorous training.
"I train in the pool seven times a week and I have three strength training sessions plus one session of yoga per week," he says.
"I enjoy swimming any event but when your focus is competitive swimming you tend to prefer those which bring you the most success.
"For me that seems to be longer races, 200m and above, particularly the 400m individual medley."
Adam dreams of one day reaching the Olympics like some of his Marion role models.
"Being around Olympians like Kyle Chalmers, Sally Hunter and Travis Mahoney at the club every day helps you feel like it's achievable," he says.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President's Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADAM Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Short Course Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Phelps-like</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marion Swimming Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Bowen Pain Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seacombe Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Chalmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Mahoney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
