<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404291139119243</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>23:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>ABN Newswire</source>
  <url>http://www.abnnewswire.net/press/en/89397/FORUM-Explor-Resources-Inc-(CVE-EXS)-Drilling-Results-from-Timmins-Imminent-89397.html</url>
  <title>FORUM: Explor Resources Inc. (CVE:EXS) Drilling Results from Timmins Imminent</title>
  <content>
Rouyn-Noranda, Aug 1, 2017 AEST (ABN Newswire) - We're all excited gold appears to be getting stronger lately, holding in the US$1,265-70 range. Given some of the most recent geopolitical events, it's somewhat surprising that we haven't exceeded US$1,300 as yet.
Hopefully, that realm is close at hand? Word from my associates suggests we could be looking at the Timmins Porcupine West gold deposit drill results by the end of this week. If CEO Chris Dupont receives them Thursday or Friday, chances are he will hold off on a formal News Release until after the long August weekend, or Tuesday, the 8th. It's probable a new video interview with Dupont will highlight the drill results, and possibly offer an estimate into upgraded TPW numbers?
Obviously, any upward estimates, especially near surface, will strengthen the 'Open Pit' attractiveness to our prospective suitors. Speaking to those suitors, progress has been made on a number of fronts, with some positive feedback. Given its early days, when we will actually see proposals for the TPW is very difficult to estimate, although 2, or 3 may be forthcoming.
With Copper hitting two-year highs, revisiting the company's Chester Copper Deposit seems appropriate. Based on the current two-year high of US$2.82/lb, that suggests the value of the known deposit is approximately US$295 million. Apparently, some new interest has been expressed, and a prospective partner/buyer is taking a very hard look at the potential at the Deposit.
That is an exciting new development! The drill results released last fall were nothing short of spectacular, especially near surface, firming up a solid case for an 'Open Pit' scenario.
NOTE: This forum commentary was published from a third party source. It has not been verified by the company.
About Explor Resources Inc.

Explor Resources Inc. () () () is a Canadian-based natural resources company with mineral holdings in Ontario, Quebec, Saskatchewan and New Brunswick. Explor is currently focused on exploration in the Abitibi Greenstone Belt. The belt is found in both provinces of Ontario and Quebec with approximately 33% in Ontario and 67% in Quebec. The Belt has produced in excess of 180,000,000 ounces of gold and 450,000,000 tonnes of cu-zn ore over the last 100 years. The Corporation was continued under the laws of Alberta in 1986 and has had its main office in Quebec since 2006.

     

Related Companies
   

Social Media
Share this Article

ABN Newswire
This Page Viewed:  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1,300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 1, 2017 AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN Newswire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abitibi Greenstone Belt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TPW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Chris Dupont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEWS RELEASE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester Copper Deposit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Explor Resources Inc</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quebec</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Open Pit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Brunswick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Page Viewed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2.82</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DuPont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Explor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timmins Porcupine West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saskatchewan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ontario</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$295</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alberta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rouyn-Noranda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
