<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405064233245333</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/do-you-know-answer-roundabout-road-rules-teaser/3207395/</url>
  <title>Do you know the answer to this roundabout road rules teaser?</title>
  <content>
ROUNDABOUTS.

Let's face it, so many drivers don't know how to use them. Or maybe they do and they just disregard the rules, but that's another matter entirely.

Indicate around, straight or off - do you know when you should indicate while using a roundabout?

The Queensland Department of Transport and Main Roads has created this little brainteaser to test drivers' knowledge of roundabout road rules.

The driver of the orange car wants to continue straight through the roundabout. How many times do they need to indicate?
Department of Transport and Main Roads (Queensland) | Facebook

Comment with your answer below.

And for a hint, the Department of Transport and Main Roads offered this advice: 

"Here's another way of looking at a roundabout-think of it like a clock face.

Any turn that exits the roundabout before 12 o'clock can be considered a left turn, so you need to indicate left on approach.

Any turn that exits the roundabout after 12 o'clock can be considered a right turn, so you need to indicate right on approach.

Straight ahead at a roundabout is 12 o'clock, so you don't need to indicate on approach.

*Everyone* needs to indicate left to exit a roundabout."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Transport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Department of Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
