<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405051348342944</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/11/47/cyclist-oil-spill-melbourne-deliberate-dental-work-capital-city-trail</url>
  <title>Young cyclist chips front teeth in deliberate oil trap on Melbourne bike path</title>
  <content>
Police fear brazen oil traps on Melbourne bike paths may become more frequent after a young woman chipped her two front teeth on a deliberate oil spill on the Capital City Trail.
Brittany Slater, 21, underwent dental surgery at the Royal Melbourne Hospital after slipping on her bike on Dynon Road on Sunday night in West Melbourne.
"I rode through the oil, the bike slipped underneath me... I fell forwards on my nose and teeth," she told 9NEWS.
Ms Ward said there had been another oil slick pattern using diesel on the exact location three weeks prior.
"To do it a second time is just crazy. If they find out who it is, I'm willing to press charges," she said.
Australian Cycle Alliance President Edward Hore said it was clear the offender had no concern for the welfare of cyclists.
"It's another bizarre situation where a cyclist has been attacked on separated infrastructure away from cars," he said.
"It's like it's a targeted attack. We're demanding police involvement. There's plenty of CCTV in the area. We need this done because the path is used by up to 900 riders an hour (at peak hours)."
Victoria Police has been investigating similar oil spills on the Capital City Trail this month.
"The person who is perpetrating this could be facing serious charges including conduct endangering the person," Senior Constable Rueben Larson said.
"As for cameras, we'll be speaking to the local council. One of the issues we've had is a lot of reports have been anecdotal, that's why we're seeking actual witnesses or victims of people who have been involved."
Similar incidents were reported by cyclists in July, who were unhappy with the police response.
Cyclists were also furious after tacks were deliberately laid on Yarra Boulevard in 2015.
Anyone with information should call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cycle Alliance President Edward Hore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dynon Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constable Rueben Larson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brittany Slater, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Boulevard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital City Trail</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Melbourne Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
