<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405055643310325</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/trump-scaramucci-harvard-directory-said-he-was-dead/8762612</url>
  <title>Harvard lists Anthony Scaramucci as dead in alumni directory, apologises for error</title>
  <content>
Anthony Scaramucci is having a bad week.

Key points:

He was  - and listed as dead in Harvard Law School's alumni directory.
The Law School apologised today after the directory mailed to alumni this week had an asterisk next to Mr Scaramucci's name, indicating he had died since the previous edition was released in 2011.
"Regrettably, there is an error in the Harvard Law School alumni directory in the listing for Anthony Scaramucci," Harvard Law spokeswoman Michelle Deakin said in a statement.
"We offer our sincere apologies to Mr Scaramucci.
"The error will be corrected in subsequent editions."
The directory is published every five years and is available only to alumni of the Ivy League law school in Cambridge, Massachusetts.
Mr Scaramucci, who was fired from his White House post today after only 10 days on the job, is a 1989 graduate of the law school.
He also served as an "expert in residence" there in 2012, according to Harvard Law's website, offering finance and investment advice to students.
He founded the SkyBridge Capital investment fund in 2005 and later served as a senior official for the US Export-Import Bank before being named communications director for the White House on July 21.
Mr Scaramucci  with an expletive-laced interview that targeted then-chief of staff Reince Priebus and White House chief strategist Steve Bannon.
He later tweeted that he sometimes used "colourful language" and pledged to refrain.
But today, the White House announced his axing only hours after former General John Kelly was sworn in as Mr Trump's new chief of staff.
AP/Reuters

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Deakin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard Law School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Export-Import Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Scaramucci</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP/Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivy League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SkyBridge Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard Law</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massachusetts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
