<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404076390751161</docid>
  <date>31/07/2017</date>
  <time>22:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/teams/collingwood/how-specialist-defensive-coach-like-rohan-smith-could-fix-collingwoods-biggest-issue/news-story/781b1fd19f35616acab53d38e9b90c5b</url>
  <title>The coach that can fix Pies' biggest issue</title>
  <content>
DUAL premiership Kangaroo David King believes Collingwood needs a "specialist defensive coach" to address its shaky defensive structures under coach Nathan Buckley.
And he has suggested Rohan Smith, an assistant coach at the Western Bulldogs, as the man who could fix it.
AFL pundits, particularly Fox Footy's On The Couch panel, have been constantly critical of the Pies' defensive structures under Buckley - something that cost Collingwood dearly during its draw with Adelaide on Sunday, according to King.
The Pies led the Crows by 50 points at one stage, but it all fell apart on the scoreboard from there until the end of the game - despite the Pies' dominance in contested ball (+15) and clearances (+14) during the same timeframe.
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 19 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
Of the 50 points Adelaide made up across the second half, 67 came from Collingwood turnovers, with a whopping 44 (7.2) starting in the defensive half.
"(The Crows) were able to score at will out of the backline, despite the fact that they were losing contested ball and clearances," King told Fox Footy's On The Couch.
But should Buckley stay on, King said the acquisition of a "specialist defensive coach" at Collingwood would significantly help the club's fortunes on the field.
"I do think that if Nathan Buckley is to survive at the end of the year - and he's making a pretty good case, they've played some great football (in recent weeks) - they need to look at a specialist defensive coach," King said.
"Whether that's a Rohan Smith, who was at the Bulldogs last year and organised a 'lesser back six' ... because you've got to give Nathan chance.
"That brand we've seen over the past couple of years hasn't been able to influence enough games in Nathan's favour."
Pushed a little deeper by host Gerard Healy, King cheekily said: "Ed, go and get Rohan Smith now. Spend what you've got to spend."
Smith was the Bulldogs' defensive coach during the club's premiership year in 2016, but was moved into development for the 2016 season.
Earlier, Carlton great Robert Walls said there was still hope for Buckley, saying strong performances from Collingwood during the back-end of the 2017 season could help him keep his job for next season.
"It shouldn't because he's been there for six years, but in some ways I think (wins in the end of the year) might," Walls told Fox Sports News' AFL Tonight.
"In the last three games, they had a draw against the premiership favourites and before that they had two wins.
"If they can get three of the next four games with wins, you could mount an argument for Collingwood to go on with Nathan Buckley."
While Walls said it was still unlikely that Buckley would be coaching Collingwood next year, he said he hoped he was there.
"I think he's got the job against him, (but) Eddie (McGuire) would love to have him there. That's why the next month could sway it slightly in his favour," Walls said.
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo David King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Smith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News' AFL Tonight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 19 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's On</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Walls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Healy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
