<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405072823180241</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-east/victorians-first-policewoman-madge-connor-to-be-honoured-with-special-ceremony-at-boroondara-cemetery/news-story/65caf9111aa8f5d8718a01b347985f97</url>
  <title>Relentless mum who smashed glass ceiling</title>
  <content>
SPEND some time walking around Boroondara Cemetery in Kew and you'll ncome across some famous names among the more than 75,000 that adorn the plaques.
They include the 'father' of Australian football Henry Harrison, the proprietor of The Age newspaper David Syme, the memorial to "the beautiful young" Annie Springthorpe or the architect who drew up the layout for Hawthorn, Albert Purchas.
But deep within the 13ha grounds you will come across a simple grave for a woman with one of the most fascinating stories of all.
Madge Connor (one of eight names she was known to have used), who died in October 1952 was Victoria's first policewoman.
She was believed to be 70 when she died, but her true birth date is unknown.
This year the force is celebrating the 100th anniversary of policewomen in this state.
Among the celebrations and commemorations will be the unveiling of a plaque on Connor's grave on August 11 to recognise the role she played as a pioneer for women in the police force.
Historian and retired policewoman Colleen Woolley from Diamond Creek has researched the story of how an Irish immigrant became an important role model for women in this state.
"She had eight different names, and five different birth dates, no one knows quite sure which one is right," Woolley said.
"It's an incredible story, Madge was born in Ireland, moved to the United States, then to New Zealand, but then her family wanted her to marry someone inappropriate and so she eloped and ended up in Australia.
"She had two children and then her husband died when he was just 36."
From this point Ms Connor's story was forever linked to the force.
"I hypothesise, but the story goes and I believe it be true, that when the officers came to speak with her after her husband had died, they found her calm and composed and were impressed by the woman they had seen," Woolley said.
"Before long, because of the way she was able to handle certain situations, she was doing undercover work around Melbourne.
"Then eventually police bowed to public pressure to employ policewomen and because of her work she had previously undertaken, she was first in line."
But it wasn't all smooth sailing for Victoria's first policewoman.
"Connor was the first of two, selected in July 1917, on half the pay of a policeman, with no powers of arrest or rights to a pension," Woolley said.
"As early as 1920 Connor led deputations of female police and watch-house matrons to the chief secretary, arguing for an increase in their salaries.
"She described the often distasteful duties they had to undertake for 17 shillings and sixpence per week."
She was unrelenting in pursuit of equality and wrote several reports, insisting that a "stroke of the pen" would solve all problems; that all that was needed was to change the words his and he to his/hers and he/she.
"On November 12, 1924 the then four policewomen were finally sworn in, becoming the first women to obtain equal pay, nearly half a century ahead of women in other occupations in Australia," Woolley said.
It is not known why Connor retired from the force in 1929, but when she did, she discovered that her years of undercover work did not qualify her for a police pension and she was well short of the 15 year service threshold required, retiring with little more than 27 pounds in her pension fund.

An extremely abridged and vaguely accurate account of Melbourne's colourful history

A HISTORY OF MELBOURNE
She would briefly go on to work as a private detective, with her last known correspondence with the force coming in 1939 where she wrote to see if any jobs - including as a cleaner - were available.
Ms Connor's great granddaughter, Paula Roque from Prahran, said she knew little of her great grandmother until contacted by Woolley in 1996.
"I don't know how she managed to track me down, I had a different name, she must have done her own detective work," Ms Roque said.
"She asked me if I knew of anything and I didn't, but I looked around and I came across her diary, which was up in a cardboard box.
"Madge was left with two young children and no way support them, how she ever managed to convince the powers that be in 1917 to take her on as an agent is incredible.
"I understand she did a lot of undercover work during the Squizzy Taylor period and she also did a lot of work exposing shady clairvoyants which she wrote a lot about in her diary."
Ms Roque described Ms Woolley as now one of her dearest friends and part of her family.
"She is a lovely lady and very passionate about my great grandmother, but not just her, she is passionate about all the stories of the women in the force."
Past and Present Women Police Association of Victoria president Detective Inspector Monique Swain said she would not be where she was today without the "pioneering trailblazer" that was Madge Connor.
"We owe so much to those first policewomen," Inspector Swain said.
"It cannot be underestimated what they did for us to get recognition.
"When she started there were no powers of arrest, no pensions and in fact up until the 1970s, we weren't even allowed to carry handcuffs.
"It's always been a gradual thing but certainly in the last 30 years, so much has changed and now policewomen are regarded equally with men.
"Obviously we'd love to get to a point where police numbers reflect the population, as in 50-50.
"It's all about developing flexible, nurturing and welcoming environments, but we've seen women can raise right up the ranks to chief commissioner
"Certainly, I would not be where I am today without the pioneers like Madge Connor."
Colleen Woolley's book on the history of women in Victoria Police, Arresting Women is available from arrestingwomen.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Roque</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 12, 1924</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector Swain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HISTORY OF MELBOURNE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Woolley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1952</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colleen Woolley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prahran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paula Roque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boroondara Cemetery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Present Women Police Association of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Connor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madge Connor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Purchas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1917</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annie Springthorpe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Monique Swain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Squizzy Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Syme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
