<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405064233245396</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/news/synthetic-dna-trial-to-safeguard-whittlesea-valuables-from-theft/news-story/35c225d13bc0e835d8a7ba13b314750d</url>
  <title>DNA to crackdown on crime</title>
  <content>
SYNTHETIC DNA will be used to safeguard valuables from theft in a police trial to be rolled out in Whittlesea.
The municipality, along with Geelong, was chosen by Victoria Police to be among the first in Australia to take part in the six-month pilot program.
Would you use the DNA to mark your goods?
As part of the program, users will be provided with kits capable of applying up to 50 items, including jewellery and electronics, with a traceable synthetic DNA liquid.
If those items are stolen and recovered, police will be able to run them under UV light and identify the registered owner.
The program, named Protect|Prevent, is one step in Victoria Police and Whittlesea Council continuing to prevent residential burglaries, according to Mayor Ricky Kirkham.
"Community safety has always been a priority for council and this is just another step forward in helping us achieve that," he said.
"While we hope none of our residents have their valuables stolen, it's encouraging to know that with innovative technology they have a greater chance of having their property returned."
Police, along with Neighbourhood Watch, will deliver samples to 1000 people in both areas in early August.
The homes for the trial have already been decided and residents will be notified.
How it works:
Residents are supplied with a kit containing a clear liquid with its own unique DNA code.
The glue-like substance can then be applied to any item and it will dry clear.
If the item is stolen and recovered by police, a UV light will pick up the substance. Using the DNA code, police can track it back to its rightful owner.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Ricky Kirkham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neighbourhood Watch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
