<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651404754995595014</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/paddy-whacked-geelongs-patrick-dangerfield-accepts-ban-loses-brownlow-chance/news-story/be6bf9a0fb0cf85827de324b2fc4bc5d</url>
  <title>Paddy whacked: Dangerfield accepts ban</title>
  <content>
GEELONG superstar Patrick Dangerfield is ineligible for this year's Brownlow Medal after officially accepting a one-week suspension for rough conduct.
The Cats sought legal advice on the matter last night, but have this morning advised the AFL they would not appeal the match review panel's decision.
Dangerfield was banned over a tackle that left Carlton ruckman Matthew Kreuzer concussed during las Saturday's match at Etihad Stadium.
The midfielder pinned Kruezer's arms and drove him into the ground in an incident that was classified as careless conduct with medium impact to the head.
Dangerfield would have risked a two-week suspension if he had challenged.
He will miss the second-placed Cats'clash with in-form Sydney (sixth) at Simonds Stadium on Friday night.
The week off will help Dangerfield overcome ankle soreness, which has troubled him in recent weeks, for the build-up to the finals.
Adam Simpson speaks to Seven

Dangerfield won his first Brownlow Medal last year, but yesterday said the prospect of winning a second would have no bearing on the club's decision on an appeal.
"After seeking independent advice, the club has decided to accept the penalty handed down to Pat by the match review panel," Geelong's general manager of football, Steve Hocking, said.
"The club reviewed all possibilities around the case in coming to this decision. We respect the fact that the match review panel has a challenging and difficult role and has to operate under high scrutiny.
"While there has been a lot of debate around Pat's eligibility for the Brownlow Medal, Pat and the club have at all times remained focussed on what is best for the team as we head towards to last part of the season."
Match review panel member Jimmy Bartel this morning said Dangerfield's action was "careless".
Bartel, who won the Brownlow in 2007, was not one of the three members who sat in on the Dangerfield decision.
"That was probably the discussion the MRP had yesterday; was it a careless act and unreasonable?" Bartel told RSN927 this morning.
"As soon as they decided, well, maybe Danger had a duty of care and could have done a little bit better, then it comes onto the table.
"I think we all agreed, it wasn't intentional. It was a careless act."
The TAB installed Richmond star Dustin Martin as an almost unbackable $1.20 favourite on the back of Dangerfield's initial charge.
Hawthorn's Tom Mitchell ($5.50) is on the second line of betting, with Essendon's Zach Merrett ($13) rated the only other serious challenger.
Martin is walking a Brownlow tightrope.
He has had two fines for classifiable offences this season and faces an automatic one-match ban, ruling him ineligible for the medal, if he transgresses again during the final four rounds of the home-and-away season.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn's Tom Mitchell ($5.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAT</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kruezer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bartel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Bartel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSN927</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon's Zach Merrett ($13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
