<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405064233245336</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/lifestyle/beauty/the-rise-of-basic-make-up-proves-the-beauty-industry-is-allknowing-always-20170731-gxmj63.html</url>
  <title>The rise of 'basic' make up proves the beauty industry is all-knowing, always</title>
  <content>
The Beauty industry knows what you think of it. Or rather, it knows what you think of the current all-inclusive, OTT makeup trend. For proof, look no further than MAC's Australian release yesterday of an eyeshadow and highlighter palette called Basic Bitch. Hues include a light grey known as "Me Me Me" and purple, called Sly Girl. The Basic Bitch is one in a range of six such palettes, carrying would-be insults repurposed into personalities, including Prissy Princess, and Power Hungry.
Meanwhile, over at Los Angeles-based beauty company, Lorac, they've named an eyeshadow palette , (it's so popular it just sold out). Colours include Eggs Benny, Pancakes and Avocado Toast. Are you sensing a theme? Well hang on, because Jeffree Star Cosmetics does a lip scrub called  This re-appropriation by cosmetic companies of what it is to be a Starbucks-sipping, contour-loving, Taylor Swift-worshipping Basic, is, to borrow a phrase, so amaze, I can't even.Photo: Supplied
If, right now, you're wondering why cosmetic brands think it's ok to pander to what is essentially this generation's Valley Girl, please, take a seat. This is not new. Remember everyone thought it was deeply witty and ironic when a makeup brand called Urban Decay came out with nail polish names like Bruise, Mildew, and Roach when they launched in 1996? It's the same thing, only they were re-appropriating Grunge culture, AKA the go-to young, female identity of the time.
Then there were the early 2000s, when cosmetics brands, taking their cues from a boundary-pushing Britney Spears and a new, daring show called Sex and the City, went to Raunch Town. Enter Nars blush in Orgasm. A product so popular, in large part because of its name, it grew to become a range that included lipstick and illuminiser.  Nars also brought out colours called Deep Throat and Sex Machine, which, yeah, probably aren't to everyone's taste. But the early-to-mid 2000s weren't dubbed the  for nothing.

But in 2017 it's about the rise of "Basic" makeup, that is, makeup designed for fun, for play, for YouTube tutorials, for anything save subtlety. Anyone who has watched a perfectly sane looking man or woman apply tiger stripes up and down their face, blend them until they practically disappear, pop on more foundation, blend that, dust with highlighter (and this is before the false eyelashes even come out of the packet,) only to repeat the entire exercise until they no longer resemble a human but an artist's depiction of what a shining cartoon doll from space sent to tell us that makeup is the future, knows what I mean.
These makeup stars and influencers might be derided for their dependence on contouring but the truth is, 1. They have serious artistic flair and 2. They are making boatloads of money.  And, yes, where the trends are, the Beauty companies will follow.Photo: AP
Basic Bitch Eyeshadow Palette $99 available at

You will now receive updates from

Daily Life Newsletter

Daily Life Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

I Love Brunch Pro Palette $44 available

Pumpkin Spice Latte Lip Scrub available  for $US12
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pumpkin Spice Latte Lip Scrub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OTT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prissy Princess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Love Brunch Pro Palette $44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Life Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basic Bitch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAC's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deep Throat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley Girl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Power Hungry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raunch Town</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Starbucks-sipping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeffree Star Cosmetics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Swift-worshipping Basic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Decay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sly Girl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitch Eyeshadow Palette $99</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Machine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nars</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britney Spears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eggs Benny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avocado Toast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
