<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405223147037897</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/war-over-armoured-vehicle-contract-heats-up-20170801-gxms6j</url>
  <title>War over armoured vehicle contract heats up</title>
  <content>
The Turnbull government faces a choice between throwing a lifeline to Victoria's car sector or creating hundreds of jobs in marginal seat rich Queensland when it awards a lucrative $5 billion contract to manufacture armed combat vehicles for the army.
BAE Systems Australia on Tuesday stepped up its campaign to win the contract to supply 225 new Combat Reconnaissance Vehicles (CRV), or tanks, by pledging to establish a defence hub at Holden's former factory at Fishermans Bend in Melbourne.
The British-owned defence giant boasts the hub would be the biggest of its kind in the nation and bring together up to 1000 engineers and technicians to design, develop and maintain land, aerospace and naval defence platforms.
Urban renewal

The company claims more than 200 people will be employed to build the CRVs and the vehicles will be maintained and upgraded there during their 30-year life. Testing and training facilities will also be built there.

BAE said the hub would also be a centre of collaboration with Canberra for other military kit for the Australian Defence Force and possible future export customers.
﻿Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews signed a heads of agreement with BAE to establish the hub at Fishermans Bend, which will help underpin the massive urban renewal project planned for one of Melbourne's historic industrial heartlands. 
He said if BAE secured the contract, it would sustain 2000 jobs across the supply chain in Victoria, helping the automotive sector as it undergoes transition from as domestic car making winds down.
But BAE faces stiff competition from German company Rheinmetall  for the CRV contract. The company announced in mid July it would build and maintain the CRVs in Queensland, potentially creating up to 450 jobs.

Proximity a plus

Part of the company's pitch is that it makes sense to build vehicles close to where two-thirds of them will be based at Brisbane's Enoggera Barracks and Townsville's army base.
While the government has focused its efforts on South Australia and to a lesser extent Western Australia to spruik the benefits of the  awarding a rich contract to Queensland would boost the Coalition's chances in the Sunshine State, which is home to eight of the 20 most marginal seats in the country.
A year-long evaluation process by the army comparing the performance of the two vehicles finishes this month, with a decision on the successful bidder some time after that.

The CRV contract is part of the army's Land 400 project to replace its armoured vehicle fleet at a cost of up to $20 billion - the biggest acquisition in the army's history.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAE</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRVs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAE Systems Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British-owned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisherman's Bend</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rheinmetall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Land 400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Enoggera Barracks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Combat Reconnaissance Vehicles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRV</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
