<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405313341352384</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/banking-and-finance/banks-to-curb-sales-tactics-for-addon-insurance-20170801-gxmros.html</url>
  <title>Banks to curb sales tactics for add-on insurance</title>
  <content>
Bank tellers will stop selling add-on insurance to customers when they are applying for credit cards, in a bid to prevent people being pressured into taking out a product with "poor consumer outcomes".
The shift comes after the  to make sure local retail bank staff were not following in the footsteps of those at United States bank .

Up Next

World's longest suspension bridge opens

00:42

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Has Wells Fargo solved its culture problem?

Wells Fargo CEO Tim Sloan comments on the bank's efforts to contain the fallout from a fake-accounts scandal.

While the watchdog found no evidence of such wholesale misconduct here, it said consumer credit insurance was an area in need of improvement.
When a customer signs up for a mortgage, personal loan or credit card, banks often promote a "consumer credit insurance (CCI)", which claims to help cover repayments if they lose their job, get sick or die.

However, the Australian Securities and Investments Commission (ASIC) on Tuesday said the type of insurance had long been problematic.
Customers were often unaware they had bought the cover, many ended up being ineligible when they made a claim, and the amount paid out by banks was much smaller than what customers paid in premiums.

ASIC said the banks had agreed to introduce a "deferred sales" model for CCI sold with credit cards through branches or over the phone. That means banks will not sell the insurance until at least four days after the customer has applied for the card.
"This reduces the risk that a consumer will feel pressured to purchase the CCI product, or purchases a CCI product that does not meet their needs," ASIC said.Photo: Jessica Shapiro
The changes will not stop banks from selling CCI with credit cards online, or with other types of loans such as home loans or personal loans. A working group including consumer advocates and the banking industry would look at other "improvements" in the sale of CCI, ASIC said.
The move is the latest sign of heightened scrutiny of banks' cross-selling, where they try to sell customers multiple financial products, often in wealth management. 
Problems with cross-selling were highlighted in 2016 when staff at Wells Fargo were found to have created millions of fake bank accounts in order to meet aggressive sales targets.
ASIC late last year ordered eight banks to to make sure there was no similar misconduct occurring in Australia, and on Tuesday it said this had not revealed evidence of systemic misconduct.
The changes will not stop banks from selling CCI with credit cards online, or with other types of loans such as home loans or personal loans.

However, the audits said CCI was a "standout product for customer complaints," and there was a "heightened risk" consumers could be signed up for the insurance without giving informed consent.
"Consumers should be confident that when they sign up for consumer credit insurance, they know what it is and that it suits their needs," the deputy chair of ASIC, Peter Kell, said.
"We welcome industry's commitment to improve their sales practices and look forward to working with industry and consumer advocates on these initiatives."
Concerns about aggressive sales tactics are also prompting banks to overhaul the bonuses offered to frontline staff, with National Australia Bank this week saying it will  for branch managers, assistant branch managers, and sales team leaders.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wells Fargo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fargo CEO Tim Sloan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Kell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Shapiro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCI</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
