<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405141542657992</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/geelong-accepts-onematch-suspension-patrick-dangerfield-ineligible-for-brownlow-medal/news-story/996a24c3f21bc2000ea8ffad15c378d2</url>
  <title>Danger, Cats accept 'umpire's call'</title>
  <content>
PATRICK Dangerfield cannot win the 2017 Brownlow Medal after Geelong decided against rolling the dice on an appeal of his suspension for a dangerous tackle.
The superstar midfielder will miss the Cats' clash against Sydney on Friday night.
Under Brownlow rules he is now ineligible to win the game's top individual award,.
Speaking on Tuesday morning, Dangerfield said the Brownlow was not a consideration when it came to a possible tribunal challenge.
"It's not in my thinking," he said.
"People can speculate as much as they like but I think if you're involved in any sport you understand that the most important thing is being there on the final day and being triumphant."
Dangerfield was offered a one-match ban by the match review panel on Monday for rough conduct on Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer.
And the Cats revealed they took until 10am to decide whether or not to roll the dice at the tribunal.
"Oh look you weigh up a whole myriad things that come into your calculations but at the end of the day, it's a decision that's based on what's best for us as a group and as a club, and now really it's about moving forward and focusing on this week," Dangerfield said.
The Cats would have risked losing Dangerfield for a second game if they appealed the decision at the tribunal and failed. Football boss Steve Hocking said there was "little wriggle room" for the club, which would accept "the umpire's call".
When asked if it was "frustrating" to be outed for what many deemed a fair tackle, Dangerfield played a straight bat.
"I respect the AFL for what they're trying to do in trying to protect the head and concussion is certainly something that we take very seriously as an industry and as a club ... but it's the umpire's call and we'll deal with it and move forward. We've got a game to win this Friday night."
As the reigning medallist, he will have to present the award to this year's recipient. But that's not something he's spent any time thinking about.
"No, I'm hoping that we're preparing for a game the coming Saturday (in the AFL grand final), so there's obviously plenty of water to go under the bridge before we get to that stage, but that (having to award 2017 Brownlow Medal) hasn't entered my thinking," he said.
Dangerfield's tackle on Kreuzer left the Carlton ruckman concussed and was rated of medium impact to the head.
ROBBO:
JAY CLARK:
MRP member Jimmy Bartel said Dangerfield's conduct was careless. "That was probably the discussion the MRP had yesterday; was it a careless act and unreasonable?" Bartel told radio station RSN927 on Tuesday. "As soon as they decided, well, maybe Danger had a duty of care and could have done a little bit better, then it comes onto the table.
"I think we all agreed, it wasn't intentional. It was a careless act."

My understanding is Geeling won't appeal Patty Dangerfield's one week ban. Too much to lose. Rest helps heal his ankle, team over Charlie
The MRP's assessment has been hotly debated and Cats coach Chris Scott admitted his initial thought was to go in to bat for his superstar.
But he said the price of a two-match ban was a huge risk.
"That's our instinct but we do have a duty to the team," Scott said. "We've got big games coming up towards the end of the season ... we play two teams in contention for the top four."
Second-placed Geelong have two massive home games, against the resurgent Swans (sixth) and against Richmond (fourth) the week after.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patty Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geeling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBBO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bartel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Bartel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSN927</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
