<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405317636319839</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/malcolm-turnbull-struggling-to-hold-the-line-on-samesex-marriage-20170801-gxmrcf</url>
  <title>Turnbull struggling to hold the line on same-sex marriage</title>
  <content>
Malcolm Turnbull has urged rebel MPs threatening to force a vote on same-sex marriage to consider that while they were free to , they would be in breach of government policy. 
With the government on the brink of implosion and his leadership under increasing strain, Mr Turnbull stressed the policy remained that there be no vote in Parliament unless there was a plebiscite first.
"We went to the last election promising that the Australian people would have their direct say on this issue. The only reason that plebiscite or vote has not been held, the only reason every Australian has not been given the opportunity to vote on this is because of Bill Shorten's opposition," he said.
"We made a commitment to give every Australian a say on this issue and that is our policy. It has not changed.

"Our policy is very, very clear. We have established processes through our party room which everyone is very familiar with. We have committed that every Australian will have a vote."

Open dissent

But the Prime Minister appears increasingly  as rebel MPs are now openly vowing to cross the floor to force a debate on a private members' bill and then vote for it in the next few weeks. 
They claim the party has discharged its obligation toward a plebiscite and the issue needs to  be resolved to get it off the table and end the distraction.
The chief rebels are Liberal Senator Dean Smith and lower house MPs Trent Zimmerman, Trevor Evans, Warren Entsch and Tim Wilson.

The National Party has threatened to leave the Coalition if the issue is forced to a vote and Liberal conservatives are threatening all manner of retribution, ranging from a leadership spill to challenging the preselections of MPs who cross the floor.
"If they cross the floor, it will be precarious to say the least," said a senior conservative.
"There's not easy solution on the table.
'Membership will go nuts'

"The four won't hold, they'll cross the floor, they won't back off."
With Parliament to resume next week and a showdown planned for Tuesday morning's party room meeting, Mr Turnbull and his senior misters are trying to find a compromise.
"We're now exploring other ways to keep faith with the Australian people, to give them the opportunity to have a say on whether or not the definition of marriage should be changed," said Finance Minister Mathias Cormann.
Immigration Minister Peter Dutton is proposing a non-compulsory postal plebiscite as the only other option but neither side of the argument accepts this will be definitive.

Just over a month ago, Mr Turnbull proposed debating a policy change now but taking it to the next election first. This is consistent with the position of his predecessor Tony Abbott.
 "The next election is two years away and we will examine our policy in the lead up to the next election, but we made a commitment at the last election that we would have a plebiscite," he said.
But the senior conservative said that, too, would be tough.
"If we go for a free vote, the membership will go nuts."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance Minister Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
