<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405236031940045</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/hot-twins-muscle-up/3207422/</url>
  <title>Hot twins muscle-up</title>
  <content>
Extra mechanical and external bling has been added to the 2018 model Subaru WRX variants.
The starting price remains $39,240 plus on-roads, but both the base WRX and its high-spec STI stablemate gain some cool extra kit.
Both variants have a new nose and grille, a larger 5.9-inch colour entertainment screen with a higher resolution, steering responsive LED headlights, and revamped forged alloy wheels (19-inch on WRX STI and 18-inch on WRX) to deliver a racing car look.
Subaru's EyeSight Driver Assist functionality, which helps avoid accidents, is now standard on all WRXs with an automatic transmission. They also have an electric park brake and 'vehicle hold' - meaning the driver doesn't have to keep their foot on the brake pedal in situations such as traffic lights and road congestion.
Base models also get Jurid performance brake pads, red-painted front brake calipers, LED fog lamps and revised suspension. The STIs come with yellow Brembo six-pot front and two-pot rear brake callipers and red seatbelts, while the suspension has been altered for better control, stability and a flat ride.
There is also now a new range-topping model - the WRX STI spec.R has Recaro front seats, starting from $57,690.
Under the bonnet nothing has changed, with the 'Rex' still motivated by a 197kW/350Nm turbo four-cylinder boxer, while the STI gets a 221kW/407Nm 2.5-litre turbo boxer.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brembo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WRX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW/350Nm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Recaro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STIs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru's EyeSight Driver Assist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WRXs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WRX STI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru WRX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
