<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405274686646221</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/tassie-star-matt-bevilacqua-has-ironman-in-his-sights-after-conquering-hawaii-for-third-time/news-story/b7edda5638349b12c5e3fae6268b8771</url>
  <title>Ironman series in Bevilacqua's sights</title>
  <content>
WITH a third paddleboard world championships under his belt, Tasmanian Matt Bevilacqua believes he can become the ironman series champion.
Bevilacqua, 25, won his third straight Molokai 2 Oahu title off Hawaii on the weekend, beating his own world record time along the way by completing the 50km course in 4 hours 29 minutes 20 seconds.
It shows the former Clifton Beach lifesaver is primed for a crack at the ironman series.

"Absolutely, that is definitely on the cards this summer," Bevilacqua said.
"I've got that work ethic and I'll be putting it on the line even better than last year.
"I'm pretty confident and the Nutri Grain series is definitely in my reach."
Since moving to Queensland six years to chase his ironman dream, Bevilacqua has relied on his work ethic to make up ground on his contemporaries, which again came to the fore off Hawaii.
"This was no different, it was just insane," he said.
"The first half was lightning fast and I've probably never paddled that fast over 25km in my life and then the last 25km was an outgoing tide, massive swell clashing together, it was really slow and hard going.
"It was really tough but also amazing at the same time."
Winning the Molokai 2 Oahu for the third time has not taken any lustre off the event.

I've got that work ethic and I'll be putting it on the line even better than last year.
"Coming from Tassie I just had a love for the ocean and even when it was hard, that love got me there," he said.
"To come here is the centre of paddling and racing and I feel so at home here.
"Everyone is so amazing, it is almost like Tasmania actually.
"I just love the race, it is such an epic experience.
"Not even winning it, just crossing that channel and being out in that open blue water and racing and battling 10-foot swells.
"My dad [Tym] is on the boat next me, directing me to Oahu because I can't even see the land. It is a really amazing experience. I love coming here."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bevilacqua, 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Matt Bevilacqua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tym</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifton Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassie I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bevilacqua</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nutri Grain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OAHU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ironman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molokai 2 Oahu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
