<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405223147037921</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4822625/weston-burner-nears-approval/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Weston burner nears approval</title>
  <content>
Up in smoke: Weston Aluminium managing director Garbis Simonian.

Cannabis, amphetamines and pharmaceutical waste will continue to go up in flames at Weston Aluminium if a request to expand the facility's services is approved. 

A modification request which would allow the facility to destroy 5000 tonnes of illicit drugs and pharmaceutical waste a year is currently open for submissions from the public, ahead of a final decision by the Department of Planning and Environment. 

It comes as a two year trial, during which Weston Aluminium processed drugs and pharmaceutical waste from around the state, nears completion in October. 
- Weston Aluminium managing director Garbis Simonian
An environmental assessment by AECOM Australia, released in July and based on the trial so far, gave the proposal a tick of approval. 

Weston Aluminium managing director Garbis Simonian said he didn't foresee the facility reaching the proposed 5000 ton limit in the next several years, but said approval would "future proof" the facility for the next 10 or 20 years. 

"Over the years if the amount [of drugs and waste] increases, we have the capacity to handle it," he said.  
"If there's a product recall and a large amount of pharmaceuticals have to be destroyed, it's something we can cope with."  

Mr Simonian said pursuing the modification was a necessary action to broaden the range of services the business could perform. 

"It's diversification. With the aluminium and steel industries not expanding, we're looking for more work," he said. 

Before the trial Weston Aluminium would aid local police with the disposal of illicit drugs on a small-scale basis. 
It's not the only change afoot at the facility, with directors currently attempting to gain approval for a trial that would see up to 8000 tons of medical and hazardous waste incinerated there.

Submissions regarding the modification proposal are open until August 21. 
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Planning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garbis Simonian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weston Aluminium</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AECOM Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Simonian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
