<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405227442005269</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/golf/rory-mcilroy-ended-partnership-with-caddie-years-too-late-according-to-fellow-professionals/news-story/d8a146cd12e090910c24c98d0080016f</url>
  <title>Rory McIlroy ended partnership with caddie years too late according to fellow professionals</title>
  <content>
McIlroy sacks caddy
0:38

Golf: Rory McIlroy has sacked his caddy JP Fitzgerald who guided him to all four major victories.

August 1st 2017
3 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Golf news/

Northern Ireland's Rory McIlroy (R) has sacked his caddie JP Fitzgerald.

News Corp Australia Network

Share

Rory McIlroy has sacked his caddie JP Fitzgerald - just 11 days after crediting Fitzgerald with transforming his fortunes at The Open.
The partnership took the Irishman to four major titles and the top of the world rankings, but according to McIlroy's fellow professionals the move comes years too late.
Ahead of the Masters in April,  to ask who was likely to win and McIlroy's peers offered three reasons it would not be him donning green at Augusta that year.
Firstly injury, McIlroy was coming in to the tournament with a rib injury, a problem one professional put down to too much gym time. "There's a link between Rory and Tiger. I'm convinced Tiger's body broke down because he overdid it in the gym. He shortened his career by 10 years - at least. I've never seen any of the heavier guys injured. I'm not sure any of the gym rats will have great longevity."
Second, putting, "'Rory can't win there because he's a below-average putter. He has been his whole career, and not too many of them win at Augusta National. He's been streaky-good at times, but he's had one good putting week in the past two years. You can talk all you like about Rory winning the Masters, but that depends on him having his best putting week ever. And it has to happen at Augusta National. Really?'"

Northern Ireland's Rory McIlroy (R) has ended his partnership with caddie JP Fitzgerald.Source:AFP
And the third major concern was McIlroy's partnership with Fitzgerald.
"Rory is an in-and-out chipper, and his clubbing is suspect at times. How often do you see him and [caddie J.P. Fitzgerald] looking at each other in shock after his ball has finished 20 yards over the back?" ... "If you listen to them on the course, you often hear Rory asking, 'What happened there?' More than once I've heard J.P. saying something like, 'OK, hit a soft draw with a 6-iron off that tree.' And I've immediately thought, This ball is going over the green. And sure enough, it does. So you have to wonder. I see Rory up close only occasionally, and I know he's going to hit the ball over the green when his caddie clearly doesn't. It makes no sense." ... "Rory needs someone to tell him what he needs to hear, not what he wants to hear." ...
"Why he doesn't employ Billy Foster is a mystery. Rory would have 10 majors by now if he did. Of course, we know what Rory is like. He's as stubborn as anyone on tour. The more people tell him that J.P. is not the right caddie for him, the more he'll keep him on."
McIlroy, who won his last major at the 2014 US PGA Championship, employed Fitzgerald in 2008 shortly after turning professional.

The pair enjoyed a brilliantly successful partnership as McIlroy took over from Tiger Woods as the game's dominant force and became world number one. "He has taken me from 200 in the world to major champion," McIlroy said of Fitzgerald in 2011.
At the British Open at Royal Birkdale earlier this month, McIlroy again heaped praise on Fitzgerald, who delivered some blunt words to his boss after the Northern Irishman started the tournament with a string of bogeys. After fighting back to shoot one-over 71 in the first round, McIlroy told reporters that Fitzgerald had done a "great job".
Forbes estimated that Fitzgerald earned $US1.65 million ($A2.07 million) from his cut of McIlroy's prize money over the 12 months to June this year.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Birkdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McIlroy</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Ireland's Rory McIlroy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiger Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J.P. Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J.P</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US PGA Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUSTA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory McIlroy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Irishman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JP Fitzgerald.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irishman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JP Fitzgerald</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Augusta National</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.65</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
