<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405184492331592</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/sa-to-buy-new-power-generators/news-story/2629c53d695e75683cfd49fe14f66162</url>
  <title>SA to buy nine new power generators</title>
  <content>
South Australia will buy nine new generators to overcome any shortfalls in electricity during summer.
The government says the generators will be installed at two temporary locations for the next two summers before being moved to one permanent site.
They have the capacity to provide up to 276 megawatts but will only dispatch energy to the grid if there are shortfalls that could result in load shedding.
The nine new aeroderivative turbines, which work like jet engines to produce electricity, will be initially fuelled by diesel before being connected to a gas supply.
They replace the government's plan to build a new gas-fired power station and to put temporary diesel generators in key locations across the state.
Premier Jay Weatherill says the generators will be funded within the existing $550 million energy plan, with the bill to be lower than the previous options.
The plan also includes construction of the world's biggest battery in the state's mid-north by tech billionaire Elon Musk and was developed following the statewide blackout in September 2016 and major load shedding in February.
"Rather than purchasing temporary generators before building a new gas plant, this solution will deliver long-term, back-up generation for South Australia before this summer," the premier said on Tuesday.
"Importantly, this solution will deliver more generation capacity than originally planned while emitting less carbon pollution."
The temporary locations to be used will be alongside Adelaide's desalination plant in the city's south and on the soon-to-be-vacated Holden car assembly plant in the northern suburbs.
Energy Minister Tom Koutsantonis said the existing infrastructure at the two sites made them good strategic locations for connection to the energy grid.
He said work was continuing to select the permanent location.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Minister Tom Koutsantonis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
