<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405407830634255</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:31</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/six-million-dollar-upgrade-locked-in-for-coast-ven/3207448/</url>
  <title>Coast venue's massive $6m upgrade locked in</title>
  <content>
THE Sunshine Coast's fledgling arts scene has received a huge hand up thanks to a $6 million war chest to revamp The Events Centre at Caloundra.

A dollar-for-dollar partnership between the Sunshine Coast Council and the Federal Government means they'll stump up $3 million each to refurbish the region's major events venue.

The council's application under the Building Better Regions Fund was announced as being successful on the day the region celebrated its 50th anniversary.

The redevelopment project will include refurbs of the main entrance, a foyer upgrade, improvements to the box office, bar counters and function room and more.

Acoustic upgrades to theatre walls and the ceiling are also scheduled, while heating and air-conditioning and disability access will all be delivered.

Mayor Mark Jamieson said the announcement would enable the venue to continue to offer a "premium level of service".

"I thank the Federal Government for this commitment and commend the Federal Member for Fisher, Andrew Wallace, for his support of this important project for our community," he said.

"The Events Centre is one of the Sunshine Coast's largest venues and it welcomes national and international performing artists.

"The proposed redevelopment will enable The Events Centre to continue to attract top end entertainment and performances, whilst offering our residents access to an array of cultural opportunities and business events that are an incredibly important part of the economic and social fabric of our region."

Sunshine Coast Creative Alliance president Phil Smith said it was "excellent" news to hear investments would be made in the venue.

He said the announcement was significant in that it marked investment into arts infrastructure, something which had been lacking previously, which had held the industry back locally.

Mr Smith said it also had wider ramifications for the development of Caloundra as a cultural and artistic hub.

"It will bring better plays and more frequent productions," he said, adding it would help leverage a night life in Caloundra, helping create a vibrant, after-hours community.

Cr Jamieson said the upgrades would help to attract visitors for major business expos and conferences as well.

"In fact, the five national conferences held at The Events Centre last financial year injected almost $2 million to our regional economy," he said.

The Events Centre chairman and Deputy Mayor Tim Dwyer said it was a vital element of the new masterplan for the revitalisation of the CBD.

"A redeveloped Events Centre will also enhance Caloundra's cultural precinct, integrated as it is with the nearby Caloundra Art Gallery and Council library," Cr Dwyer siad.

The community supported the redevelopment, with $43,000 in pledges raised by local businesses and residents.

Cr Dwyer expected the centre's volunteer numbers to swell as a result of the upgrade.

Despite helping orphans in Africa, Sam Childers had to fight to get in
Do you know when you should indicate while using a roundabout?
UPDATE: It's rare for whales to swim to where the pair was beached.
Architect of a region stops briefly on his final journey.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Mayor Tim Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Art Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Member</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Building Better Regions Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Childers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Mark Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Creative Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Dwyer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Event Center</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
