<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405403535666928</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/student-performs-indecent-act-front-teacher/3207449/</url>
  <title>Student performs indecent act in front of teacher</title>
  <content>
A TEENAGE boy who allegedly performed an indecent act in front of a school staff member and indecently assaulted a woman at an ATM has been charged.

It is alleged the 16-year-old from Manoora went to a Manunda school on January 20, entered an office where a female staff member was working and committed the act in full view of the victim.

She yelled to another staff member in an adjoining office and the youth then fled on foot. He was unable to be located anywhere in the complex.

It will be further alleged that on January 28, the youth was at a Mt Sheridan shopping complex

when he approached a woman from behind and indecently assaulted her whilst she was

withdrawing funds from an ATM.

The woman screamed and the offender fled on foot.

Cairns Child Protection and Investigation Unit detectives spoke with the boy yesterday and he was charged with one count each of committing an indecent act intended to offend and indecent assault.

Neither of the female victims were physically injured as a result of the incidents, and the boy was not known to them.

Tuesday August 1, marks a very special day for the region
Despite helping orphans in Africa, Sam Childers had to fight to get in
Do you know when you should indicate while using a roundabout?
Architect of a region stops briefly on his final journey.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manoora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MANUNDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Sheridan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Childers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investigation Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Child Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
