<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405399240699509</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/world/donald-trumps-ability-to-achieve-swift-tax-reforms-questioned-20170801-gxmuiz</url>
  <title>Donald Trump's ability to achieve swift tax reforms questioned</title>
  <content>
by
Sam Fleming and Barney Jopson

The Trump administration's ability to push through tax changes this year is being questioned by congressional aides following the failure of healthcare reforms and the prospect of a fiscal quagmire.
President Donald Trump on Monday swore in John Kelly as his new chief of staff as he attempts to instil greater discipline in the White House. The president has told Republicans they need to remain focused on healthcare but focus in the Senate and House is switching to tax reform, as members seek a legislative victory before the 2018 midterm elections.
Republicans say they are optimistic about their ability to hammer out a tax package, with the momentum to be driven increasingly by two powerful congressional committees rather than the chaotic Trump administration.
However, the party must first tackle highly contentious budget negotiations, a potential debt ceiling impasse and a host of legislative hurdles before it can get into the meat of the debate.

"As far as getting [tax reforms] signed into law before the end of this year, that is pretty optimistic," said one Republican Senate aide.

"Early next year is possible. It depends on how well things progress through the process - there could be landmines that scuttle the whole effort."
Last week, party leaders ditched plans for an import tax in recognition that the measure was divisive in the business world and becoming a barrier to tax cuts.
A statement by top party lawmakers, together with Steven Mnuchin and Gary Cohn, respectively the Treasury secretary and National Economic Council director, said they expected tax legislation to move through congressional committees in the autumn.
In coming weeks the administration, lawmakers and advocacy groups will undertake a concerted campaign for tax reform.

Caroline Harris, chief tax policy counsel at the US Chamber of Commerce, said the unity now being displayed by the Republicans on tax was an important development.
She added, however: "We will not be satisfied until we see the implementation of comprehensive pro-growth tax reform."
To maximise their chances of getting tax changes through Congress without relying on Democratic support, lawmakers need to pass a budget resolution with so-called reconciliation instructions after their summer break.
They also face the need to avoid a government shutdown after the fiscal year ends on September 30, and they have to lift the $US19.8tn debt ceiling before the Treasury runs out of cash - which will probably happen in early to mid-October.

The administration and congressional Republicans see tax reform as a means of igniting economic growth, investment and consumption. With US multinationals complaining that a 35 per cent federal income tax rate hobbles them globally, the party wants to bring the rate below the OECD average of 25 per cent.
Mr Trump's ambitions for a 15 per cent corporate tax rate are seen as unrealistic.
The present system has been blamed by politicians from both parties for encouraging companies to flee the country via so-called inversion deals and other tax manoeuvres.
One of the hardest questions for policymakers is how to handle more than $US1tn of earnings that US companies have parked overseas.

Once the debate over the details of tax changes starts, rifts could re-emerge within the corporate world.
Among the potential flashpoints are plans to reduce businesses' ability to deduct interest payments from their tax bills, and the provisions behind a shift to a territorial system under which companies are only taxed on domestic earnings.
For individuals, Republicans want to lower tax rates across the board. But Democrats say all the recent proposals would deliver bigger benefits to the wealthy than anyone else.
Steve Rosenthal at the Tax Policy Center, a think-tank, predicted that different business factions would end up in a lobbying competition for the biggest giveaways.

"Tax reform is harder than healthcare, but tax cuts are easier," he said. 
"Right now I think we are seeing a publicity campaign that will label tax cuts as tax reform. We have not seen any reform measure with any viability."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barney Jopson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tax Policy Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Economic Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Rosenthal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Fleming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OECD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Cohn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Mnuchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US19.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
