<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405399240699581</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/accounting/findex-moved-clients-into-more-costly-investments-asic-20170801-gxmux8</url>
  <title>Findex moved clients into more costly investments: ASIC</title>
  <content>
Findex has admitted it moved clients on to more expensive in-house branded financial products without proper justification and has agreed to have an independent expert review the files of impacted customers.
The Australian Securities and Investments Commission said that the financial advisory and accounting group's Adviser Incentive Scheme was likely to "encourage representatives to switch clients from existing third party products to [Findex's] own branded product".
"The majority of clients whose files were reviewed by ASIC were moved from their existing third party product to a more expensive [Findex] branded product without adequate justification or explanation as to why the move was likely to leave the client in a better position," the ASIC statement, released on Tuesday, said.
The firm, which is part owned by private equity group KKR & Co, has had preliminary discussions with Findex management, prospective investors and a handful of potential advisers to offload .

Findex has acknowledged that ASIC's concerns were reasonable and has agreed, via an enforceable undertaking, to have an independent expert review client files and compensate clients where appropriate.

"ASIC identified a number of concerns in relation to [Findex's] financial advice business, including out-of-date policies and procedures, deficiencies in the file audit process, and insufficient information being provided to clients who were being moved into new products," the regulator said.
'Full disclosure'

This is the second time in less than a year that ASIC has pinged Findex over its method of selling and promoting financial products to clients.
In October,  to clients on its website when ASIC said the products on offer "were likely to have been affected by commissions or other benefits received from the issuer of recommended financial products".

Findex spokesman James Hutchinson said ASIC's concerns only related to a "small portion of our client base" and that the firm had already made contact with all impacted clients.
"The concerns outlined in the [enforceable undertaking] are confined to a small portion of our client base and are not a result of any client complaints," he said.
"At no stage have there been any concerns about the security of client funds, or the way they have been invested or supervised. ASIC's concerns predominately relate to the fullness of the advice documentation process."
The firm also denied that money was a motivator in moving clients on to more expensive house-branded products.

"Clients accepted full disclosure on fees and, as is always the case, our recommendations were supported by thorough research provided by external leading industry professionals with the aim of delivering quality outcomes for our clients; they are not dictated by price," he said.
"The performance of the funds has generally been consistently above benchmark over the entire period that the recommendations were made."
edmundtadros@afr.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KKR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adviser Incentive Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hutchinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Findex</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
