<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405442190372969</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/cricket/ashes-scout-the-holes-england-must-fill-before-coming-down-under/news-story/6573fd087b0d2687b42b3c6b31631a40</url>
  <title>Ashes Scout: The gaping hole England must fix</title>
  <content>
THE third Test against South Africa was the perfect example of the cricket England is capable of playing when its assortment of X-factors fires.
On Monday, Joe Root's side wrapped up a 239-run win over South Africa at the Oval, with a new seamer shining on debut after Ben Stokes battered another century. Moeen Ali then put the icing on the cake by finishing the match off with a hat-trick.
However, there remain gaping holes in England's XI. With the Ashes now only four Tests away, that should worry Trevor Bayliss and his selectors.
Welcome to the first edition of Ashes Scout. Less than five months out from the series' curtain raiser at the Gabba, we take a look at the major issues facing England.

Cricket: Moeen Ali strikes for England with hat-trick.

Moeen Ali strikes for England with hat-trick
LIVE stream Sri Lanka v India on FOX SPORTS. Get a free 2-week Foxtel Now trial & stream LIVE within minutes.
WHO BATS WITH COOK?
Alastair Cook has had 11 different opening partners since Andrew Strauss retired. The way things are going, he will need a 12th by the time the Ashes roll around. His current partner, Keaton Jennings, has had a tough time of it against the Proteas (92 runs at 15.33) and has looked particularly troubled against the new ball - never a good thing for an opener - and South Africa's quicks. That's worrying considering the frightening pace stocks Australia currently boasts. Graeme Smith went so far as to say Australia might be "quite a scary place" for Jennings.
This is a particularly tricky conundrum for selectors. Keep the faith, or give a new opener the chance to settle himself into the XI before the Ashes?
After picking up two ducks in the first five innings of the series and posting a top score of 33, Jennings complicated matters for selectors by scoring a second-innings 48 at the Oval. On paper, dropping him now after showing him so much faith would seem odd. At the same time, the 25-year-old's 48 was a blessed one - dropped on six, Jennings picked up boundaries with almost-impressive proficiency with the edges of his bat.
Helping Jennings is Haseeb Hameed's awful form. Hameed left selectors with no choice but to pick him during last year's Test series against India by dominating the county season (1200 at 49.91) for Lancashire. He didn't disappoint (219 runs at 43.80) and when he broke his hand in his third Test it was expected he'd slot straight back into the Test XI by the time he was fit. But by the time the current series against South Africa came around, Hameed was barely in the debate due to a shocking run of form in County cricket. His form hasn't really improved since then, with a top score of 47 and an average of 19.45 across 12 innings for Lancashire this season. He scored a century in a second XI match a fortnight ago but unless he can find form in first-class cricket soon, his hopes of playing in the Ashes look slim.
There are options for England though. Surrey pair Mark Stoneman (761 at 58.53, three centuries across 13 innings) and Rory Burns (732 runs at runs at 60.91, one century across 13 innings) are banging the door down for selection by dominating division one of the County championship. Australian-born Sam Robson is also pushing for a recall via weight of runs in County cricket (534 at 59.33, two centuries across nine innings), though he did himself no favours by registering a pair in his most recent first-class match.
There's also the possibility of new No.3 Tom Westley going up a spot in the order.
Meanwhile, relieved of the captaincy, Cook has been in good touch this series without dominating it, notching impressive half-centuries at the Oval (88) and Lord's (69). He will consider a tally of 212 runs at 35.33 disappointing but there are signs he's gearing up for a big Ashes campaign.

Cricket: We compare the recent 'willy-nilly' high five on England's Jonny Bairstow against the one back in 2013 between James Faulkner and Brad Haddin.

Return of willy-nilly high 5
THE FIRST DROP AND THE JOE ROOT CONUNDRUM
As captain of the side and as England's best batsman, Root is locked into the Test XI. Just where he plays is another question. England seemed to have settled on Root at first drop last year, with the then-captain-in-waiting playing all but two of his 14 innings at No.3. It didn't always work - he passed 50 eight times but only 100 twice - but when it did the pay-off was huge, with Root posting a career-high 254 against Pakistan in Manchester and 124 in Rajkot against an Indian attack at the height of its powers.
Now that he's skipper, Root has slid back down to No.4. Captaincy doesn't seem to have hurt Root as a batsman so far (360 runs at 60, one century in six innings) but his promotion/demotion has left England with a hole at first drop. It's a hole they had hoped to fill with Gary Ballance, who forced his way back into the XI via frightening County form (815 runs at 101.87, three centuries across 11 innings). Unfortunately for England, Ballance has not taken that form into the Test arena. Prior to breaking his left index finger in the second Test, he'd managed to get his eye in in three innings but failed to pass 50 once. Ballance's finger injury took the decision out of the selectors' hands but the noose was already starting to tighten.
He was replaced in the XI by Westley, who having excelled for division one side Essex this season (478 at 53.11, two centuries across 11 innings) did enough on his Test debut (25 and 59) on a seam-friendly track to suggest the call-up was not too soon. Ballance is not expected to be on the sidelines too long and should be back in the mix for selection shortly - especially if selectors decide they have run out of patience with Jennings.
THE BATTING DEPTH
Bowled out twice in less than 100 overs at Trent Bridge, England picked an extra batsman - Dawid Malan replaced Liam Dawson - at the Oval. That meant Moeen Ali, who has five Test tons to his name, batted all the way down at No.8.
It's never a bad thing to have a batsman of Moeen's quality at No.8. However, more often than not he's the team's No.7 with Root the last out-and-out batsman in the line-up at second drop. As good as wicketkeeper Jonny Bairstow has been with the bat over the last two years - he was 2016's highest scoring Test batsman - it remains a risky ploy to be so dependant on all-rounders.
The key to England finding consistent success with the current all-rounder heavy formula could be Stokes making the step-up from rocks and diamonds to diamonds and gold. Stokes clattered a 153-ball 112 at Trent Bridge then rocked South Africa's middle-order in a man-of-the-match performance. That's the firepower he brings to the XI. Conversely, in half of his innings this series he has failed to reach 20 - a worrying stat for a man who generally bats at No.5 or 6. Stokes is continually improving with the bat but his average sits at 36.36 over the past 12 months - he's capable of much better than that.

Cricket: Ben Stokes collects wickets in back-to-back balls against South Africa.

Stokes goes bang bang
AUSTRALIA MUST RESPECT MOEEN
Kagiso Rabada, James Anderson, Vernon Philander, Stuart Broad, Morne Morkel - there's no shortage of seam bowling talent in the current series between England and South Africa. But none of those men sit atop the wicket-takers' chart for the series. That honour belongs to the perennially underrated Moeen.
Having finished the series opener with 10 wickets to his name (4-50 and 6-53), the all-rounder took a match-sealing hat-trick at Trent Bridge and across the first three Tests he has taken 18 wickets at 14.72. His career bowling average still sits at a rather ugly 37.95, but against South Africa he has noticeably been bowling with more attacking intent, flighting the ball and experimenting with variations. The Australians can expect a different and hugely improved Moeen to the one they faced in 2015.
THE NEW QUICK ON THE BLOCK
We'll wrap up this rather lengthy Ashes Scout debut with the outstanding performance of another debutant.
Toby Roland-Jones will look back on his first Test fondly after snaring a five-for in South Africa's first innings (5-57) and adding three in the second (3-72). He wasn't half bad with the bat either, backing up a run-a-ball 25 with an unbeaten 23.
Roland-Jones, whose most potent weapons are accuracy and movement off the seam, will have a tough time holding onto his spot once Mark Wood and Chris Woakes return from injury but he looks a good enough prospect - if that's the right word for a 29-year-old - to push for Ashes selection.

Cricket: England Debutant Toby Roland-Jones has taken four wickets in his debut innings in Test cricket.

Debutant's dream day
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIRST DROP AND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XI</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kagiso Rabada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roland-Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennings</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haseeb Hameed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Woakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Stokes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Burns (732</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEW QUICK ON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Proteas (92</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England XI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England's Jonny Bairstow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonny Bairstow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Ballance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vernon Philander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stokes</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Test XI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Broad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawid Malan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOE ROOT CONUNDRUM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Stoneman (761</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballance</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord's (69</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Dawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Roland-Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval (88</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-born Sam Robson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moeen Ali</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hameed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Strauss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lancashire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moeen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Root</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Haddin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Westley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rajkot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashes Scout</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X Factor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England Debutant Toby Roland-Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BATTING DEPTH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRALIA MUST RESPECT MOEEN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lanka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morne Morkel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keaton Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Bridge</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BATS WITH COOK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Faulkner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alastair Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Bayliss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
