<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405356291026037</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826044/war-of-words-as-mp-retires/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Cootamundra MP Katrina Hodgkinson's retirement announcement draws mixed reaction on social media</title>
  <content>
Katrina at the Henty Machinery Field Days in 2012. Her shock resignation announcement has attracted mixed reaction on social media.

Cootamundra MP Katrina Hodgkinson's shock resignation announcement from parliament has drawn mixed comments from her constituents on social media. 
The state member released a statement on Monday afternoon saying 'she felt like it was time to move on to something new' and would stand down at the end of August. 
While some comments are supportive of Ms Hodgkinson's decision, others have welcomed her decision to retire.  
"No loss at all" Carl Erle commented on the Cowra Guardian, 
"Why is a politician doing their jobs considered achievement? Did little more than what would be expected. Was nowhere to be seen when the cannery was sinking. And thanks for the bi election." Marc McLeish wrote. 
"Bye,bye....you did nothing for harden," Karen Woodhead wrote on the Young Witness page. 
"The way she handled the Council amalgamation of Gundagai with Cootamundra was brutal and certainly not in the best interests of Gundagai. To be in favour of Greyhound racing bodes poorly in my eyes... so much suffering in the interests of greed... Goodbye Katrina and good riddance!" Colleen Donovan commented on the Young Witness Facebook Page. 
The cost of the by-election forced by Ms Hodgkinson's resignation just 18 months from the next state election in 2019 has also drawn concerned comment from residents, some calling for Ms Hodgkinson to foot the bill unless she has a good reason for standing down. 
"Why do people run for a term when there going to piss off before next election, they quit before end of term and get all the perks, we quit our jobs and fend for ourselves, wrong, unless they have to quit eg- health or family health issues fair enough but to seek another opportunity while still in term that's crap, of to another election we go," Adam Manwaring said on the Young Witness page. 
Ms Hodgkinson has stood in office for the past 18-and-a-half years, representing the electorates of Burrinjuck and Cootamundra and not everyone was happy with her decision. 

"Katrina has been a great member for Cootamundra,we will be sorry to lose her," Beverley Oliver told the Daily Advertiser. 

"I think she worked hard for our electorate it's not always easy to keep everyone happy and I think if anyone wants to be critical step up to the plate and have a swing yourself for our community plenty of us do." Stephen Howse commented on the Harden Murraumburrah Express Facebook page. 
"This is so sad. Just when we get a good person in there who looked after the people, not themselves like most do," Fran Houghton said on the Cowra Guardian page. 

Cowra Guardian
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Manwaring</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hodgkinson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burrinjuck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beverley Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cootamundra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katrina</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Witness</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colleen Donovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gundagai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carl Erle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fran Houghton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henty Machinery Field Days</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen Woodhead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc McLeish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Advertiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Howse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cootamundra MP Katrina Hodgkinson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harden Murraumburrah Express Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Witness Facebook Page</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowra Guardian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
