<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405399240699524</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/world-breastfeeding-week-event-at-eastland-attracts-100-mums-and-bubs/news-story/e1b269dd72cb7442c1cdf9e3dfdaed87</url>
  <title>Film fun for mums and bubs</title>
  <content>
SCORES of breastfeeding mums and their babies have gathered at a cinema in Eastland to celebrate World Breastfeeding Week.
An entire cinema at Hoyts was booked out for the special event today, which was sponsored by breastfeeding expert Pinky McKay.
Ms McKay organised the event for 100 women, to help them feel confident and comfortable breastfeeding in public.
"I meet so many mums who are anxious about breastfeeding in public because they're afraid they will receive negative feedback," Ms McKay said.
She said people should know breastfeeding could be done practically anywhere.
"Your breastfed baby is completely portable," she said.
"The more we see mothers breastfeeding, the more normal it becomes ... breastfeeding doesn't have to tie you down at all.
"If it's a problem for other people who see you breastfeeding in public - they can put a cover over their own heads."
Ms McKay is also spreading the campaign online through her Instagram account  and the hashtag #whereareyoufeedingtoday.
The viral trend is encouraging mums to share "brelfies", and the hashtag has generated more than 2000 photos of women breastfeeding in different situations, including one feeding her baby in a firetruck.
Ms McKay said the gathering at the Eastland cinema was a great way to involve women and remind the community breastfeeding was normal for mothers to do.
"It's a nice opportunity to have something in the suburbs for the mums and somewhere comfortable and safe for the mums to be with a baby," she said.
Ringwood policewoman and mother-of-two Olivia Lyon joined the event and said it was a fun way to increase public awareness.
"Reducing the stigma around breastfeeding and making it more common in our everyday life is important," Ms Lyon said.
"I'm confident breastfeeding in public, but I wasn't when I first started.
"I realised the most important thing is for my baby to be nourished and it shouldn't matter where or when."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoyt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivia Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Breastfeeding Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pinky McKay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McKay</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
