<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405450780307685</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/will-jack-be-back-tigers-left-waiting</url>
  <title>Will Jack be back? Tigers left waiting</title>
  <content>
Jack Riewoldt had surgery on his eye last week

RICHMOND does not expect to know if Jack Riewoldt will be available for Sunday's clash against Hawthorn at the MCG until Thursday morning as he recovers from eye surgery.

Riewoldt's fate will be left in the hands of doctors after a knock at training last week led to a cut in the cornea of his right eye, requiring several stitches. 

The star forward missed Saturday night's win against Gold Coast at Metricon Stadium and could be sidelined for a second week if he is not given the green light by doctors.  

Coach Damien Hardwick was confident Riewoldt would return to face the Hawks when asked about the vice-captain's fitness on Saturday night.

"We look forward to welcoming him back next week, it should only be a one-week injury. It'll be handy to get him back against the Hawks," the coach said.  

Riewoldt could be one of two key inclusions for the Tigers, with midfielder Dion Prestia expected to return after he was rested for one match because of knee and calf soreness.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dion Prestia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Hardwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metricon Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Riewoldt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
