<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405351996058697</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/chicago-cubs-gift-steve-bartman-infamous-fan-world-series-ring/8763398</url>
  <title>Chicago Cubs gift infamous fan Steve Bartman World Series ring 14 years after 2003 incident</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

The Chicago Cubs have publicly buried the hatchet with one of sport's most infamous fans, gifting Steve Bartman a championship ring.
Bartman was the most recent and unfortunate embodiment of , which was blamed for the Major League Baseball team's 108-year title drought .
The diehard Cubs fan famously attempted to catch a fly ball near the fence during the sixth game of Chicago's 2003 play-off series against the Florida Marlins.
The Cubs led the best-of-seven series 3-2 and the game 3-0, but Bartman's interference, which prevented Cubs outfielder Moises Alou from making a catch to remove Luis Castillo in the eighth inning, was blamed for costing the Cubs a title that year.

External Link:

Family Guy's retelling of the Steve Bartman incident
After Castillo received that lifeline, the Marlins scored a whopping eight runs in the game's penultimate inning and went on to win the game and the series.
Bartman suffered horrific abuse from fans at Chicago's Wrigley Field - ironically nicknamed "The Friendly Confines" - and people from all around the country, eventually going into hiding.
The subject of the 2011 ESPN documentary Catching Hell had to move house and did not speak publicly for 14 years - until today, when he said he was not worthy to receive the ring, but was "deeply moved and sincerely grateful".
"I am fully aware of the historical significance and appreciate the symbolism the ring represents on multiple levels," he said.
"My family and I will cherish it for generations."
Cubs hoping to end sorry chapter in franchise's history

The club's chairman, Tom Ricketts, reached out to Bartman, "signifying to me that I am welcomed back into the Cubs family".
Ricketts said the way Bartman was treated was "an unfortunate chapter" in the club's history, while general manager Jed Hoyer said any hatred he received "should never have been there in the first place".

"I think it's impossible not to look at him in an incredibly sympathetic way," Hoyer said.
"This is a guy who was in the wrong place at the wrong time and his life has been dramatically impacted indirectly by the Cubs organisation and this franchise for 14 years.
"Us winning the World Series should wipe that away."
Bartman said he hoped he and his family could now finally move on from the saga.
"I humbly receive the ring not only as a symbol of one of the most historic achievements in sports, but as an important reminder for how we should treat each other in today's society," he said.
"My hope is that we all can learn from my experience to view sports as entertainment and prevent harsh scapegoating, and to challenge the media and opportunistic profiteers to conduct business ethically by respecting personal privacy rights and not exploit any individual to advance their own self-interest or economic gain.
"Moreover, I am hopeful this ring gesture will be the start of an important healing and reconciliation process for all involved."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Ricketts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bartman</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friendly Confines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida Marlins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castillo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago's Wrigley Field</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bartman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bartman World Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago's 2003</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moises Alou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jed Hoyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catching Hell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major League Baseball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Castillo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago Cubs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
