<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405442190372976</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-woman-who-swore-threw-cup-in-court-gets-21-days-in-jail-for-contempt-20170801-gxmvxq.html</url>
  <title>Canberra woman who swore, threw cup at magistrate gets 21 days in jail for contempt</title>
  <content>
A woman who hurled a cup of water at a Canberra magistrate before yelling "F--- you, you hear me?" has been jailed for 21 days for contempt of court. 
, at Magistrate Peter Morrison before she was dragged back down to the cells after he refused her bail on drugs and property crime charges last month.Photo: Melissa Adams
The usual water jug and pile of plastic cups were missing from the defendant's side of the bar table when Organ again appeared before Mr Morrison in the ACT Magistrates Court on Tuesday.
She pleaded guilty to contempt, prompting Mr Morrison to jail Ms Organ for her "spectacular, defiant and very public conduct".
Ms Organ was charged after she had sworn as she stood up and pitched the plastic cup towards the magistrate before Corrections officers restrained her on July 17.
Three supporters in the public gallery who clashed with police and shouted at the magistrate were also removed from the court.
￼
Mr Morrison, whose head and robes dripped with water, had wiped his face and said he would give reasons for his decision to refuse bail in the woman's absence.
"That is why we replaced the glasses on the bar table with plastic cups," he had said. 
Defence lawyer Tim Sharman​ on Tuesday handed an a letter, penned by Organ, to the court and said she acknowledged her wrongdoing and had apologised for actions - which she "sincerely regrets".
He said the outburst had been her reaction to the court's decision to refuse bail and had not been premeditated.

Prosecutor Katie McCann agreed Organ's actions appeared to be reactive and said the letter showed genuine remorse. 
But she said the woman's antics were extremely offensive to the court and Mr Morrison.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Mr Morrison said he set aside any personal feelings of annoyance at being Organ's target, but her behaviour had interfered with the performance and dignity of the court.
He accepted her apology and remorse were genuine but noted there was a significant number of people in the courtroom at the time and said: "Your actions caused quite a spectacle."
Mr Morrison acknowledged Organ's anger at police and the court, and her concern for her children if she had been remanded in custody that day.
However, he said her "spectacular, defiant and very public conduct" warranted a term of imprisonment.
He convicted Organ, who was already in custody, and sentenced her to 21 days behind bars. She cannot apply for bail in that time.
Organ had been arrested after she struggled and yelled abuse at police during a raid at her Dalziel Street, Gowrie, home on July 16.
Documents previously tendered in court said officers seized a wallet with $2750 cash and clip seal bags that contained about 3.5 grams of cannabis.
As they searched the home, police saw Organ pick up a hairbrush that was next to her on the lounge and go to brush her hair with it.
They took the brush and removed the cap on the end of the handle to allegedly reveal three clipseal bags that contained about eight grams of a drug believed to be ice.
Organ pleaded guilty to cannabis possession and was fined $75. She will fight two stolen property charges.
The case returns to court later this month.
 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Peter Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Sharman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie McCann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrison</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gowrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Organ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalziel Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
