<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405059938277961</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/the-one-missing-element-that-would-drive-a-brisbane-property-price-boom/news-story/83acdd9cd54a9475e78454f93a151eef</url>
  <title>The one missing element that would drive a Brisbane property price boom - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
There's one key ingredient missing to fuel property price rises in Brisbane according to a CoreLogic analyst. Pic Darren England.

Apart from employment opportunities, Brisbane had all the right fundamentals to be Australia's next big property market, according to CoreLogic head of research, Cameron Kusher.
Mr Kusher said Brisbane's future gains were absolutely hinged to jobs growth.
"I think that's still the big drag on Brisbane," Me Kusher said.
"We've been thinking for a number of years that Brisbane is the next market to take off, and certainly other have as well, but I think the big missing ingredient ultimately has been that strength in the jobs market," he said.
CoreLogic released their Hedonic Home Value Index, July 2017 which revealed Brisbane's median house price of $490,000 was a drop of 0.7 per cent for the three months to the end of July.
The city had seen just 2.2 per cent price growth over the past 12 months.
In relation to investors, Mr Kusher said even the attraction of Brisbane housing's 4.1 per cent gross rental yield compared to Sydney's 2.7 per cent, hadn't been enough to bring buyers north.
"Investors still seem to have a focus on capital growth, so you'd need Sydney and Melbourne to slow more to attract investors to Brisbane," he said.
"The other challenge is investors tend to like units and I think everyone is pretty aware that there's some concerns in the unit market in Brisbane at the moment of a potential oversupply, so that might hold it back as well," Mr Kusher said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hedonic Home Value Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kusher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's 2.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kusher</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Kusher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
