<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405571039393484</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/bereaved-father-consoled-by-gift-of-life-to-others/news-story/c8afde5a3c57d146c9a5a26bfe9489fa</url>
  <title>Legacy of late son lives on</title>
  <content>
JIM Wilson lost his son Levi last year, but his bouts of sadness are softened by the thought his boy's loss has helped save the lives of others.
Early in 2016, the Sunbury man wrestled with the devastation of losing his son to suicide.
He had found Levi and administered CPR on the 22-year-old, restoring his pulse and breathing until the ambulance arrived.
All the family went to Sunshine hospital but there was worsening swelling on his brain and it was soon evident Levi wouldn't regain consciousness.

"He was declared dead on January 10, but the night before people from  came to see us and asked about donating his organs," he said.
"As a child my father had said organ donation was the right thing to do and in this moment I felt the same."
So the heart, liver, eyes, kidneys and other organs were taken and donated to those needing it, saving their lives in the process.
Body tissue was taken for research, a fact Mr Wilson thinks could multiply the impact of the donation.
"The possibilities for medical advances and breakthroughs astound me and I like to think that will be his legacy," he said.
While the act of donating is by its nature anonymous, Mr Wilson has been buoyed by recipients reaching out to him to explain the impact on their lives. A letter, prior to last Christmas, came from the family of an eight-year-old girl who had received his son's liver.
It explained how a condition had threatened the girl's life since she was 10 weeks old and described how post-operation "she is now running and jumping, the same as healthy kids".
"The letters confirmed in me with aces that we made the right decision and the recipients had been given a gift," he said.
"I still miss my son, if I could get him back I'd take all the organs back, but that's not going to happen.
"I'd love to meet everyone that has a part of Levi living on in them and I'd give them all a hug."
Mr Wilson attended a memorial -service last year organised by -DonateLife. He was struck by how one man had pondered whether any of those who had inherited his wife's organs had inherited one of her innocent vices - a love of chocolate.
For Mr Wilson, he wonders whether anyone has taken on the artistic streak of his son.
Mr Wilson now drives around in the Holden VH Commodore he was doing up with Levi at the time of his death. In the glove box is information about organ donation he shares with others. He also keeps letters from the those that live on for Levi's death.
Contact  on 13 11 14 if you need help.
to register to donate at DonateLife.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DonateLife</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levi</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden VH Commodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
