<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405399240699528</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/music/zara-larssons-complicated-relationship-with-hiphop-20170731-gxmpkk.html</url>
  <title>Zara Larsson's complicated relationship with hip-hop</title>
  <content>
Most celebrities have topics they refuse to talk about. But for Swedish pop sensation Zara Larsson, nothing is off limits. 
Whether it's criticising artists like Chris Brown, or discussing how she came to be heavily influenced by R&B despite Sweden not being the first country that springs to mind when thinking of that kind of music, the 19-year-old has a thoughtful - and measured - response for everything thrown her way. 

Up Next

The life and times of Sam Shepard

01:07

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Entertainment news highlights

Bitchiness on The Bachelor, Dr G Yunupingu's marvelous career, talk shows take on Trump's transgender ban, fans' anger at Australian Ninja Warrior and Ringo and Paul back together again.

"I'm still learning, everyday," the pop star told Fairfax Media during her short promotional visit to Australia.
"But when it comes to my music, I would never denigrate another woman - 'all these other bitches' or whatever people are talking about. When I close my eyes and picture my audience, it's definitely young women and girls."Photo: Supplied
Larsson said she likes her songs to be "positive and uplifting" to help counteract the sexism that can find its way into pop songs - especially lyrics. 
"Even though I love hip hop, it's pretty violent," she said. "It's especially degrading towards women. It might not be a big thing, because it's just a song, but it does make an impact on society. Especially if you have people looking up to you."  

The 19-year-old was in Australia - a country she "loves" and has visited twice before - to promote her latest single Don't Let Me Be Yours. The song was co-written by Ed Sheeran, who the Stockholm success story calls "the sweetest person". 
"I love those people that don't take themselves so seriously and allow other people to talk," she said. "I'm sure he's aware of the fact he's the Ed Sheeran, but he's also extremely humble. If I reached that level, that's how I'd want to be - a completely regular person." Photo: Helen Sloan
So what did Larsson think of the backlash Sheeran copped Game of Thrones ?
"He didn't deserve that!" she said. "He fit in perfectly, he just sat there singing. I liked it."Photo: Jerod Harris
Don't Let Me Be Yours is an emotional pop ballad similar to Larsson's smash hit Never Forget You. However, the 19-year-old said fans shouldn't jump to any conclusions about the song signalling a shift in tone or style. 
Larsson said she expects R&B to continue to feature heavily in her music. White artists are often criticised for incorporating R&B into their work, but she said she draws on hip hop and dance when collaborating with other artists because she wants them to actively contribute to the shape of a song.
"That's the beauty of collaborating with people," she said. "Not only with people on the track - other artists - but the writers and producers in the studio. If someone loves the pop genre, the R&B genre, I love to add a little touch of that."  
Over the next year, Larsson said she wants to do more live shows - including an Australian tour which is "99 per cent" locked in. Then, it'll be "straight back into the studio" for her second album. 
"I had an amazing year last year, but I mostly did TV performances," she said. "I'm in the studio writing songs because I want to be on stage - that's my favourite part of it all." 
Zara Larsson's latest single Don't Let Me Be Yours is out now through Sony Music.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Sheeran</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Shepard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerod Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr G. Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larsson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockholm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swedish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitchiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Sloan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Never Forget You</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheeran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Let Me Be Yours</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zara Larsson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
