<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405528089719907</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/beauty/cosmetic-surgery/the-human-ken-doll-celebrates-his-birthday-with-his-tenth-new-nose-and-an-operation-to-give-him-eyes-like-a-cat/news-story/f7ad62694d5b37224c9fb847c29c35e3</url>
  <title>The Human Ken doll celebrates his birthday with his tenth new nose ... and an operation to give him eyes like a cat</title>
  <content>
Rodrigo Alves has had more surgery. Picture: Rodrigo Alves/Instagram

Emma GrittThe Sun

Share

THE HUMAN Ken doll celebrated his birthday yesterday with the nose he's always dreamt of ... and an operation to give him eyes like a cat.
The Brazilian reality star - real name Rodrigo Alves - had his tenth rhinoplasty procedure last week, and has delightedly told it was a great success.

Rodrigo Alves has had more surgery. Picture: Rodrigo Alves/InstagramSource:Instagram
Rodrigo shared an update on his latest image overhaul from a Tehran hospital, where he is waiting for a new set of veneers to be fitted as well as a have his eyes sliced and stitched in to a more feline shape.
He said: "Last Thursday I had my nose done for a tenth time in an attempt to fix my breathing.
"Doctors used cartilage from the back of my ears and after three hours on the operating table, Dr. Farshid and Dr. Sadr were able to fix my nose with great success."

Rodrigo and one of his doctors flew to Tehran from Kish Island for his next lot of surgeries. Picture: Rodrigo Alves/InstagramSource:Instagram
Rodrigo added that the last time cartilage was needed to prop up his nose, it was taken from his ribs, leaving him with visible and unsightly scars.
He's also undergoing another radical procedure, a "cato eye lift" that will elongate his eye for an almost more feline appearance.

Rodrigo Alves has had more surgery. Picture: Rodrigo Alves/InstagramSource:Instagram
Another stark change will be his new smaller chin, after cruel trolls made him switch the shape of his chin implant.
He said: "People attack me online for having a huge head because my chin implant is too big.

"But now my chin has also been replaced by a smaller square shaped implant."

Rodrigo needed another nose job to help him breathe after a previous op left him with too-small nasal passages. Picture: Rodrigo Alves/InstagramSource:Instagram
Earlier this month, Rodrigo told The Sun Online that he was defying doctor's orders to have his tenth nose op during a holiday to Dubai, as well as a new triangular chin implant.
Making a bid for 'dolly nose', the popular socialite has chosen to ignore the doctors on Botched's warning that he was now at risk of losing his nose altogether if he kept meddling with it.

Rodrigo discusses his options with one of Persian Beauty's surgeons in Iran. Picture: Rodrigo Alves/InstagramSource:Instagram
Despite flying off to Dubai for his £35k ($58,000) bumper haul of surgery, Rodrigo actually went under the knife in neighbouring Iran.
Staying at a private hospital on Kish Island, Rodrigo's nerves were put at ease as doctors and locals treated him "like royalty".

Rodrigo Alves has made regular appearances on Botched TV. Picture: Rodrigo Alves/InstagramSource:Instagram
Photos from the modified man's surgery trip he has shared with The Sun Online show him being escorted through airport terminals, being presented with flowers and generally being waited on hand and foot.
And that wasn't the only highlight for the former air steward, who got a chance to admire the Arab nation from an unusual vantage point.

Rodrigo was presented with flowers during his £35k surgery holiday. Picture: Rodrigo Alves/InstagramSource:Instagram
He added: "On Saturday Dr Sadr and I flew to Tehran from Kish Island, and I was invited to sit on the flight deck mid-flight over Iran.
"Then yesterday to mark my birthday, Persian Beauty organised a surprise birthday party at the clinic."

The amazing birthday cake Rodrigo was presented with by the organisers of his surgery holiday. Picture: Rodrigo Alves/InstagramSource:Instagram
Sadly for Rodrigo, being presented with a cake of his own face couldn't have come at a worse time.
Speaking on Monday morning, he said: "Right now I'm toothless and waiting for my porcelain veneers to arrive.
"To kill time, I'm having the eye lift, and laser hair removal."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tehran</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. Farshid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday Dr Sadr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. Sadr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Ken</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodrigo Alves/InstagramSource</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodrigo Alves/Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodrigo Alves</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kish Island</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma GrittThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodrigo</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Last Thursday I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sun Online</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botched TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Persian Beauty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
