<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405184492331669</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/queensland-woman-donates-her-oversized-liver-to-medical-science/news-story/e0f2246f6596bb411e254118df57651c</url>
  <title>Losing that liver was a load off</title>
  <content>
A QUEENSLAND mother has to medical science.
For seven years Fiona Murray could barely bend as the herculean-sized organ grew and grew until it had invaded most of her small body.
A healthy human liver is typically 1.5kg or less while Mrs Murray's liver, which was ravaged by polycystic kidney disease, topped over 12 kilograms.
The Greenbank woman weighed under 60kg following its removal.
"It was frightening that this colossal thing was getting bigger and I didn't know where it would end. I was lucky enough to have a lifesaving kidney and liver transplant and now I'm living life to the full," she said.
Mrs Murray knew she could never become an organ donor due to her hereditary disease but offered her organ to be used by The University of Queensland for research.
The liver was donated to UQ's Integrated Pathology Learning Centre (IPLC), within the Faculty of Medicine.
The IPLC houses 2500 pathology specimens and uses the latest technology to create interactive learning resources to teach students about human diseases.
"My liver is the first living donor specimen to be donated. I am glad to be able to offer something back to medical science. The size of the liver definitely shocked the doctors," she said.
At 47, Mrs Murray is playing netball and riding her bike regularly and forever grateful to the donor's family for giving her new life.
"For seven years I looked like I was nine months pregnant. The liver was squashing all the other organs in my body. It was a scary situation.''
Mrs Murray encourages families to discuss organ and tissue donation during DonateLife Week this week.
"I think organ donation is an exceptionally unselfish gift that everybody in a time of grief makes. It's a decision that everybody should try to think of before anything happens."
Mrs Murray said she wanted to thank her donor family but due to strict privacy laws she was unable to meet them and instead wrote an anonymous letter of thanks.
In Australia only one in three people have joined the Australian Organ Donor Register and more than 1400 people are waiting for an organ transplant.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Organ Donor Register</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faculty of Medicine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DonateLife Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPLC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Murray</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UQ's Integrated Pathology Learning Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
