<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405094298017072</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/01/11/59/us-cocaine-kingpins-enforcer-sent-to-prison-for-role-in-violent-o-dog-organisation</url>
  <title>US cocaine kingpin's enforcer sent to prison for role in violent O-Dog organisation</title>
  <content>
The generous bouquet of flowers delivered to the door of a beautiful Hollywood actress wasn't meant to charm or woo her, far from it.

Inside a benign white envelope, tucked amongst the orchids and pink roses, a card addressed to Brazilian model Greice Santo read, "Best of luck with your endeavours - Junior."

Junior was in fact an alias of Owen Hanson, a 34-year-old Californian-based kingpin who was believed to be making a fortune trafficking large shipments of cocaine and other drugs to Australia.

Between the lines of his messy hand written note, Hanson was warning Santo he and powerful forces knew where the Jane the Virgin actress lived and that she could be got.

Hanson was leaning on Santo because her high-roller husband, R.J. Cipriani, owed him $2.5m from a 2011 ill-fated gambling session at Sydney's Star City casino.

Cipriani, a professional black jack player and Las Vegas VIP, had been used by Hanson to launder money inside Sydney's Star City from his lucrative Australian cocaine operation.

But the plan to bring clean casino cheques back to the US blew up when Cipriani went rogue, often punting $120,000 a hand and losing millions in several days.

Today Jack Rissell, an enforcer for Hanson who arranged that flower delivery and spent months intimidating Santo and Cipriani, was sentenced in a San Diego court to two years in prison on charges of extortion.

Rissell had been described in a court indictment as a specialist in "aggressive measures" who collected money and debts for Hanson "using intimidation, threats and violence".

Under orders from Hanson, Rissell regularly parked up in his van outside the couple's high-rise apartment, allegedly plotting to kidnap, hurt or kill the pair, Cipriani told nine.com.au.

The uber-prestigious 1221 Ocean building, which has been home to the likes of Britney Spears and Michelle Pfeiffer, is one of the most secure residences in Los Angeles.

Cipriani claimed Rissell, who was unable to penetrate tight security at 1221 Ocean, at one point offered a doorman $10,000 to deliver a box to his home.

"Now what the f--k was in that package for me? I could only think it was a bomb," Cipriani said.

"Thank God the doorman declined."

But deliveries, such as the flowers, made it through. So too did a large envelope addressed to Santo containing a DVD movie of a brutal beheading carried out by a Mexican drug cartel.

Coincidentally, Santo had been expecting a parcel from her mother in Brazil with childhood movies and other memories.

"When I put in the DVD it was two guys getting beheaded. I don't even want to remember it, one with a chainsaw and one with a knife," Santo told nine.com.au.

Hanson and his crew bombarded Santo with threatening texts and phone calls, telling her she was in grave danger because of Cipriani's $2.5m debt, she said.

They made it clear they knew all sorts of personal details about her.

"I still don't feel safe today," Santo said.

"I'm actually extremely paranoid after all this happened. I constantly look behind my back."

In the face of repeated and increasing levels of intimidation, Cipriani contacted the FBI and became a source, codenamed "Jackpot", for the crime-fighting agency.

He fed the FBI details on Hanson's drug-running operation, which was rumoured to be linked to connections in Mexico and Peru.

Cipriani also gave the FBI Jack Rissell's address, after he tracked down the hired heavy to a "little sh-thole place" in the San Fernando Valley.

"I banged on (Rissell's) door. Finally he opened it, and he looks at me. So imagine, this guy is looking to kidnap me and my wife - and now I'm at his front door. He sees me and I go, 'Now I know where the f--k you live motherf--ker.'"

Rissell simply slammed the door shut, Cipriani said.

In 2015, Hanson and 21 of his associates, including Rissell, were arrested following a joint FBI-NSW Police investigation into the gang known as O-Dog Enterprise.

Hanson pleaded guilty in January to racketeering conspiracy and conspiracy to distribute narcotics charges.

He faces a potential 20-year sentence when he next appears in court in September.

Last week Daniel Portley-Hanks, 71, a Los Angeles private detective hired by Hanson was sentenced 16 months for desecrating the grave of Cipriani's dead mother.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cipriani's $2.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O-Dog Enterprise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas VIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greice Santo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Now I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Rissell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R.J. Cipriani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owen Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O-Dog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rissell</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Pfeiffer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Portley-Hanks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI-NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cipriani</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santos</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britney Spears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Star City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI Jack Rissell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Fernando Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
