<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405321931287217</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/geyer-pans-daley-i-just-dont-think-hes-the-man-for/3207437/</url>
  <title>Geyer pans Daley: 'I don't think he's the man for the job'</title>
  <content>
FORMER New South Wales enforcer Mark Geyer wants change in the Blues ranks - and he's starting with coach Laurie Daley.

Daley's position appears to be under review after the Blues' stunning State of Origin capitulation this season, although good judges believe Daley has a standing offer on the table of a one-year deal, if the Blues boss wants to take it.

But Geyer feels NSW should look elsewhere.

"I think he's had five years to try and do what he can do," Geyer told the Triple M Grill Team Sydney yesterday.

"I just don't think he's the man for the job."

Geyer appeared to suggest the controversy surrounding Josh Dugan and Blake Ferguson's pre-Origin III drinking session was an example of Daley's failure to instil the right culture.

"(Daley should) try and coach a club side first and see how he goes with a club side," he said.

"Queensland have an opportunity where they can do it with a Kevvie Walters and a Mal Meninga because their culture is so strong.

NSW State of Origin coach Laurie Daley watches a training session in Sydney.PAUL MILLER

"Ours isn't, when players think they can go 80km and get on the drink four days before a game."

Geyer said NSW must move to a coach with recent NRL experience and who has the mettle to exist in the pressure cooker atmosphere that the Origin arena provides.

"We need to get a coach that has week-to-week coaching in the NRL, so he's resilient to the fact that it's a hard job," he said.

"It's a very hard job for someone to do.

"Someone like a (Craig) Bellamy, Des Hasler, whose week in, week out, grind is compatible with what Origin is.

"I don't think Loz is up to it, for the fact that he comes in for six weeks and all the pressure is straight on him. Not coaching a rugby league team in the NRL, I think that affects him.

"Look what all these coaches cop on a weekly basis."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney.PAUL MILLER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Daley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Des Hasler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Geyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dugan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M Grill Team Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevvie Walters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geyer</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mal Meninga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin III</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
