<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405523794752537</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/roebourne-child-abuse-cashless-welfare-card-would-punish-all/8762682</url>
  <title>Cashless welfare card resistance in Roebourne after town hit by child sex abuse cases</title>
  <content>
A prominent Aboriginal leader in a northern West Australian town grappling with unprecedented child sexual abuse allegations has rejected the state police commissioner's call for cashless welfare cards, saying the whole community should not be "punished" for the actions of a few.
Earlier this year police charged 36 people with child sex abuse offences from a town of 980 people, while the Commissioner says there are 124 possible suspects in total.
Commissioner Karl O'Callaghan says if the card was rolled out in Roebourne it would reduce the amount of cash available for criminal activities, and there was a link between welfare and child abuse.
"There's a pattern of an increase [in] offending activity when welfare payments are given and for some days afterwards," he told ABC Karratha.
"That's linked also to increases in the purchase of alcohol in the local stores, increases in the purchase of drugs, and of course payment for sex.
"It's not a panacea, but it would give us a circuit breaker to get government and non-government support in there to address some of the complex ongoing issues with families."
But Yinjibarndi Aboriginal Corporation chief executive Michael Woodley questioned the link.
"Why punish the community, after they've now done the investigation, found out who the perpetrators are," he said.
"No-one in the community saw the report, and can connect these things [are] a factor in it."
Mr Woodley said the move to cashless welfare would create more problems.
"The rights of any person is to be in a position to do what they want to do with their lives," he said.
"Basic human rights, in terms of getting the money and spending it the way that they want to.
"Being controlled under the welfare card I think is I don't think going to assist the community, it's going to make the community worse."
People 'need opportunities' to break welfare cycle

Ian Trust, the executive director of Wunan, an Aboriginal development organisation operating in the East Kimberley where the cards have been trialled, said the card had reduced ambulance callouts while hospital admissions for assaults had gone down.
But he said it had to be part of a wider strategy to create community change.
"I think any sort of action that reduces alcohol and drugs is a step in the right direction, in regards to reducing sexual abuse, or assaults, ... reducing the environment where those sorts of behaviours are prevalent is always a step in the right direction," he said.
But he cautioned it was not a silver bullet.
"You've got to provide opportunities where people who have been receiving welfare benefits in some cases for many generations, you've got to get people to exit from that through jobs, ... also housing is a key indicator ... so people can send their kids to school," Mr Trust said.
"It's something that each community has got to weigh up for themselves.
"To just carry on doing what they've always done is just madness, I think communities should consider where they want to go in the future."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Woodley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roebourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Woodley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Karratha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yinjibarndi Aboriginal Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Karl O'Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Kimberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wunan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
