<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405360585993421</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/people-and-pets-kickstart-their-weekends-with-fresh-air-and-exercise-with-chelsea-parkrunners/news-story/e9121b675076fa7f78345b18a9f5da5d</url>
  <title>Enthusiasts run thousands of kilometres in one year</title>
  <content>
CHELSEA Bicentennial parkrunners find it hard to remember how they spent their Saturday mornings before the weekly 5km walk/run came to town.
In the 12 months the event has been running, more than 2000 people of all ages have completed more than 46,000km and achieved 2420 personal bests along the way.
Event director Peta Wragg said these impressive statistics were made possible with the help of more than 200 volunteers.
And ahead of the Chelsea Bicentennial parkrun's first birthday, Ms Wragg encouraged others to get involved.
"We welcome runners fast and slow, walkers, parents pushing prams - and you can
also bring a dog on a lead for an invigorating outing," Ms Wragg said.
Parkrun is an international organisation that holds free, weekly 5km timed runs in parks
around the world.
Participants can register, print off a unique barcode and bring it along each week to wherever they choose to run, afterwards receiving a time and world ranking.
"It's the start of you competing against yourself to improve your health and fitness," Ms Wragg said.
Join the local parkrun team each Saturday before 8am, at the Chelsea Bicentennial Park rotunda near the skatepark.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Wragg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Bicentennial Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHELSEA Bicentennial</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peta Wragg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
