<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405528089719880</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/postie-delivers-the-goods-after-elderly-customer-robbed-of-precious-watch-from-late-wife/news-story/70dec6e27860855e207cb7604d0c2390</url>
  <title>Postman's timely gift</title>
  <content>
CALL him the poster child for modern posties - not to mention the much-maligned millennial generation.
Bundoora postie Dean Lesha, 22, has brought back old-school chats by the letterbox, often finishing up hours later than other posties after stopping for one chinwag after another.
Dean's regulars know when he rings the bell, as he pedals up the street, it's time to pop out for a chat.
For some of his elderly customers, Dean is the only person they talk to all day.
So when one regular, Angelo, was robbed and lost his prized jewellery collection last year, this young man stepped up in the most astounding way.
"There was one watch in particular from his late wife that he really loved, and the one day he wasn't wearing it and left it at home, he was out for a walk when he was robbed," Dean says.
"He's a beautiful man - one of the nicest people I've ever come across. So I bought him a watch and gave it to him and he was astonished. He was close to shedding a tear and made me shed a tear, too.
"He said he would never have thought such a young man especially nowadays would do such a kind gesture. It was a special day, really."
READ MORE:

Dean's mum, Donna Lesha, contacted us after our stories on Aussie Post staff who've gone above and beyond.
"My son comes home weekly with stories similar to this one," she says. "I'm one proud mum."
Know a postie who's gone above and beyond? Let us know.
Email:
Check out In Black & White in the Herald Sun newspaper Monday to Friday for more stories from our readers.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundoora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Lesha, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Lesha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
