<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405528089719861</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/crash-pilots-thought-each-other-in-charge/8763534</url>
  <title>Two Tasmanian pilots failed to plan flight, thought each other in charge, crash report finds</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A pilot and his co-pilot whose light plane crashed in Tasmania's north-east last year thought each other was in command, an investigation has found.
Last July, the two pilots left the Bridport Aerodrome in an amateur-built Europa Aircraft Classic on a flight to familiarise the new owner with the plane.
The pilots had to do a forced landing in a paddock after the engine stopped.
One man from Scottsdale was taken to hospital with spinal injuries while his co-pilot from Launceston walked away with only minor injuries.
At the time of the crash, police said the men were lucky to be alive.
The Australian Transport Safety Bureau (ATSB) said inadequate communication between the pilots resulted in the plane taking off with no defined flight plan, no pre-flight brief and each pilot believing the other was in command.

The ATSB also found low fuel levels onboard the two-seater plane had the potential to interrupt the fuel flow to the engine.
"The lack of a flight plan prevented the pilots from ensuring there was sufficient fuel and reserves available to ensure safe flight," the report said.
"In addition, in-flight fuel monitoring was not sufficient to identify low fuel quantity and ensure fuel supply to the engine was not interrupted.
"Good communication between the pilots, observing recommended operating procedures and effective flight planning will all help to reduce risk and enable safe flying."
The ATSB said the accident highlighted the importance of pre-flight planning.
"Pilots should ensure that every flight is appropriately planned for, utilising accurate flight times and fuel calculations."
"Once airborne, the continual monitoring of time and remaining fuel should be conducted."
The investigation found neither pilot understood the fuel system.
Examination of the wreckage identified no pre-existing mechanical defects that might have contributed to the engine shutdown.

External Link:

Bridport plane crash report

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europa Aircraft Classic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scottsdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATSB</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridport Aerodrome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Transport Safety Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
