<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405489435013792</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/first-new-tram-for-sydneys-21b-light-rail-line-finally-unwrapped-20170801-gxmryc.html</url>
  <title>First new tram for Sydney's $2.1b light rail line finally unwrapped </title>
  <content>
It feels more spacious inside and open to natural light than Sydney's existing trams. And, once coupled to another, the new tram sets for Sydney's $2.1 billion light rail will be twice the length of those running on the
After weeks  at Randwick, the first of 60 trams for Sydney's $2.1 billion light rail line from Circular Quay to Randwick and Kensington was unveiled on Tuesday.

Up Next

'Universities are a big part of the problem'

01:35

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Sydney light rail fails to connect dots

Differing track standards on Sydney's inner west light rail line and the south east line mean trams carrying passengers won't be able to switch between the two.

"It will have a very modern smooth feel [for passengers] but obviously longer than any other light rail vehicle they have seen before," Premier Gladys Berejiklian said.
Describing it as a "game changer", she said the new line would provide a better link for people travelling to the CBD or, in the other direction, to the University of NSW at Kensington and hospitals at Randwick.

"Once the line is up and running, we will find the need to put on additional services and, of course, we are geared up for that," she said.
Built in France and Spain by transport conglomerate Alstom, the 97-metre Citadis X05 tram sets will be among the longest trams in the world when they start operating in 2019.

That is and almost four times as long as one of Sydney's bendy buses.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In all, 30 of the trams sets will eventually be running on the 12-kilometre rail line from Circular Quay to the south east.Photo: Supplied
Capable of carrying of up to 450 passengers - the equivalent of nine buses - each coupled set will have 96 permanent seats and 24 flip seats.
Alstom Australia managing director Mark Coxon said passengers were most likely to notice the carriages' double doors, which would allow people to exit and enter more easily and quickly than standard trams.Photo: Supplied
So-called "balcony windows" also gave a more open feel to the interiors by allowing more natural light in, he said.
The interiors are 2.65 metres wide, about 10 per cent greater than the trams on the inner west light rail line.Photo:  Graphic: Remi Bianchi
"The wider it is, the easier it is to move around," Mr Coxon said.
The rest of the light rail vehicles will arrive over the coming months, and be housed at a new stabling yard under construction beside Randwick Racecourse. The trams will be tested along a section of new track later this year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Coxon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alstom Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alstom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citadis X05</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's $2.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's $2.1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick Racecourse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Coxon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Circular Quay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remi Bianchi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
