<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405485140046388</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/13/36/anu-warns-colleges-on-sexual-assault</url>
  <title>ANU warns colleges on sexual assault</title>
  <content>
One of the nation's most prestigious universities is taking a hardline stance against sexual assault and harassment, putting residential colleges on notice to lift their game.
Australian National University vice-chancellor Brian Schmidt says he won't rest until his institution has world-leading practices in dealing with sexual assault and harassment.
A Human Rights Commission survey of students found 57 per cent of those at ANU had experienced sexual harassment and nearly eight per cent experienced sexual assault last year - slightly higher than the national average.
"This level of sexual harassment and sexual assault is not acceptable in our universities, in our workplaces, in our city, or anywhere in our society," Professor Schmidt told reporters after the report's release on Tuesday.
"It is certainly my hope that it will be a game changer.
"I am sorry that we have had to wait for this, but if this report does not shake this university and the sector in general to change things, then I'm not sure what it will take."
ANU has commissioned an independent review of all its policies and procedures for dealing with sexual assault and harassment.

Related Articles

It will also review all residential colleges to see if cultures need to change or practices need particular adaptations.
Professor Schmidt warned the university will consider revoking the affiliation of any college that did not participate.
"What we have seen today is unacceptable for any college on this campus and we need to hold ourselves, every part of this university, up to external scrutiny so that we are better," he said.
"No one is immune from that."
He didn't want to pre-empt the review's findings, but said he would similarly expect colleges to act promptly on any recommendations.
Canberra Rape Crisis Centre counsellors now have a full-time presence on the ANU campus and the university is implementing consent training for all its students and educating staff on dealing with disclosures of harassment and assault.
National 24-hour support line for university students 1800 572 224, with access to Rape and Domestic Violence Services Australia counsellors.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Schmidt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domestic Violence Services Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Rape Crisis Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
