<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405656938740648</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/business/breaking-news/investors-demand-corporate-slavery-checks/news-story/91d4c6ac24e12a4ff347c5e77a29eb5a</url>
  <title>Investors demand corporate slavery checks</title>
  <content>
Australian companies should be legally bound to check and report on slavery risks across their operations and supply chains, a major superannuation investor group says.
The Australian Council of Superannuation Investors (ACSI) has called for new laws requiring Australian firms to report annually on how they are ensuring that their global supply chains are free of slavery risks such as forced labour and deceptive recruiting.
ACSI, which represents owners and institutional investors controlling more than $1.6 trillion in assets, has warned that, beyond its human impact, slavery is a real threat to corporate sustainability and value.
In submissions to be presented to a federal parliamentary inquiry into modern slavery on Tuesday, ACSI says the growth and complexity of global supply chains and Australia's reliance on imports from countries vulnerable to slavery means local companies are increasingly exposed to slavery risks.
There has also been a rise in reports of slavery in domestic operations in recent years, the council said.
The inquiry, which is holding a hearing in Melbourne on Tuesday, is examining whether Australia should adopt a Modern Slavery Act similar to one in the United Kingdom.
ACSI chief executive Louise Davidson said laws requiring companies to report yearly on slavery risks would make them more accountable and allow greater scrutiny from investors and the broader community.
"Self-monitoring and self-reporting have not driven adequate awareness of slavery risks and have allowed poor levels of transparency and accountability," Ms Davidson said in a statement.
"Although some companies are leading the way, devoting resources to map their exposure, this issue is too important to be left to a few responsible corporations."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACSI</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Council of Superannuation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Modern Slavery Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
