<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405231736972670</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/law-order/bourke-st-rampage-accused-dimitrious-gargasoulas-again-excused-from-court/news-story/31cdf08bc5f14406e1c3177e8c7d292b</url>
  <title>Gargasoulas not in court again</title>
  <content>
THE man accused of the Bourke Street rampage has again been excused from attending court, days after he was deemed mentally unfit to appear.
Dimitrious Gargasoulas, 27, is charged with six counts of murder and 28 of attempted murder over the January 20 incident in the city.
It's alleged he mowed down dozens of pedestrians in the busy retail strip, killing a baby boy, a schoolgirl and four other people as shoppers ran for cover.
He was due to face Melbourne Magistrates' Court today, but defence lawyer James Yianoulatos said Gargasoulas could not attend.
No reason was given and the magistrate did not question why.
Prosecutor Catherine Parkes updated the court on the case, saying police expect to complete a brief of evidence as planned.
"At this stage the informant is on track to comply by October 20," she said.
Gargasoulas was scheduled to face court last week over unrelated charges but another defence lawyer Tass Antos said he could not attend because of mental health issues.
"He has certain issues that are being explored in relation to his mental health and wellbeing," Mr Antos said last Thursday.
"It means that bringing him to court or having him appear would unfortunately not do his health any good."
Gargasoulas has not appeared in court in person since he was charged with deliberately striking pedestrians around Bourke and Queen streets as the area teemed with lunchtime and school holiday crowds.
He was arrested by police after being shot and wounded by officers.
Director of Public Prosecutions John Champion SC has told the Supreme Court previously that Gargasoulas' mental state could determine whether he stands trial over the rampage.
He is due to return to court on October 12.
Gargasoulas faces separate charges laid before the Bourke St incident, including assault, drug and driving offences.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tass Antos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Parkes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Prosecutions John Champion SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Yianoulatos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Antos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gargasoulas</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dimitrious Gargasoulas, 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
