<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405059938277885</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/01/tougher-english-test-prospective-citizens-highly-problematic-government-advisory</url>
  <title>Tougher English test for prospective citizens 'highly problematic': government advisory body</title>
  <content>
A bill being considered by a Senate inquiry that proposes tougher English language tests for prospective citizens has been slammed by a government advisory body.

By

Marese O'Sullivan

19 MINS AGO 

In a submission to the Senate, the Australian Multicultural Council expressed concern that introducing the English language test would "adopt a standard that is too high and above that needed to achieve the aim of integration."

While it said the ability to communicate in English was crucial for integration in Australia, it claimed the stricter requirements are "likely to prove highly problematic for vulnerable sections of the migrant and refugee populations", who may have had a "fragmented" educational experience.

Subject to the passage of that legislation, among the requirements to apply for Australian citizenship will be: candidates must be permanent residents in the country for at least four years prior to their application; prove they have integrated fully into the Australian community; and take an English language proficiency test before they sit the citizenship test, the latter of which will include new questions about Australian values.

The Minister for Immigration and Border Protection, Peter Dutton, said the changes would "implement the commitment" made by the Turnbull government to strengthen the test for Australian citizenship.

"Australian citizenship is an extraordinary privilege and is a common bond which unites us all, whether we were born here or choose to make Australia our home," he said.

"Australian citizenship involves a commitment to this country and its people. It is a privilege which should not be taken lightly."

According to a 2015 OECD report, 'Indicators of Immigrant Integration', over 80 per cent of eligible migrants take the opportunity to become Australian citizens. More than five million people have been granted citizenship since the process was introduced in 1949.

'Unconvinced of the merits'

The current citizenship test examines whether the applicant has a basic knowledge of the English language. It can be taken as a multiple-choice exam on the computer. Those with low levels of English literacy can take an alternative course-based test if they are referred by the Department of Immigration and Border Protection.

The Council said it was "unconvinced of the merits" of that citizenship test to analyse a person's commitment to shared values.

"A much truer test of a person's values lies in their actions, not in their ability to pass a multiple choice test, which can be compromised by inadequate English language skills," it declared.

The Council also noted that Level 6 standard of the International English Language Testing System, which is the level the government is considering implementing, is what is considered acceptable for undergraduate study of English at most universities.

"Newly arrived migrants are initially most concerned about employment, settlement, and education for their children as a priority, rather than English language proficiency for themselves," the Council stated.

Related Reading

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Border Protection</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigrant Integration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marese O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OECD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Level 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International English Language Testing System</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Immigration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Multicultural Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
