<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405613989067132</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/safety-concerns-halt-rollout-of-victoria-police-holsters-20170801-gxmvja.html</url>
  <title>Safety concerns halt rollout of Victoria Police holsters</title>
  <content>
The rollout of new semi-automatic gun holsters to Victoria Police officers has been suspended over safety concerns after the first 300 were issued.
Victoria Police ordered 18,000 new holsters from a US supplier after repeated issues with previous holsters, but problems have now been identified with the new ones.Photo: Paul Rovere
The holsters started being distributed last month as part of Operational Safety Tactics Training, Victoria Police said in a statement on Tuesday.
"Around 300 new gun holsters have been issued to frontline police officers," the statement reads.

"This rollout has now been delayed while the investigation takes place."
Victoria Police said the safety issue was "rarely occurring" but they declined to reveal what the problem is.

"Members who have been issued with new holsters have been asked to remain diligent to the issue identified," the statement says.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

A safety issue in "a small number of incidences" was found late last week, Superintendent Tony Langdon told 3AW on Tuesday.
"We don't believe it impacts frontline policing at this point in time. It's something our members need to be aware of and we don't believe it has any impact on the safety of the public," Superintendent Langdon said.
It is the fourth time Victoria Police has had issues with holsters and the new ones were ordered from a US company "in response to those other issues".
A previous five-year contract for holsters was valued at nearly $3 million when the tender was awarded in 2011.
On Tuesday morning Premier Daniel Andrews said the government would fix the problem although he had not yet been briefed. 
"If there's any deficiency then we'll remedy it with the investment the Victorian community would want," Mr Andrews said. 
A Police Association of Victoria spokesman said the union was working closely with Victoria Police "to see that the fault is remedied as quickly as possible".
AAP, with Benjamin Preiss
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Association of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Langdon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Preiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Rovere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operational Safety Tactics Training</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Tony Langdon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
