<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405699888414260</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/queanbeyans-former-mayor-tim-overall-to-run-in-nsw-council-election-20170801-gxmzfs.html</url>
  <title>Overall announces another run for council</title>
  <content>
Former Queanbeyan mayor and current administrator Tim Overall has announced that he will run in the .
It was also announced on Tuesday that former Queanbeyan councillors Trudy Taylor and Peter Bray, who served as deputy mayor, will run on Mr Overall's ticket.Photo: Jamila Toderas
Mr Overall, who has served as the council's administrator since last year's merger, said continuing the work that had been started during his time as mayor and then administrator was the motivation for running.
"I am very proud to have served as mayor from 2008 until 2016, followed by my appointment as administrator, and I'm committed to seeing the progress we've made continued and further extended to our now wider area," he said.
In his time as administrator Mr Overall has overseen the implementation of several projects that have drawn criticism from some in the community.
There has been vocal opposition to the Ellerton Drive extension and the proposed cemetery on Old Cooma Road. Many believed that such decisions should be left to an elected council rather than an appointed individual.

Mr Overall said his work as administrator fully complied with the expectations of the role.
"It was made very clear to all administrators on their appointment that their role was not only to work with the executive team and bring about the transition and transformation to the new council, but to deal with those matters that would have been dealt with by the council had it still been in place," he said.
"It was not about a caretaker period for those 18 months, not making decisions, it was quite the contrary.
"It is my view that those decisions that have been made on major projects would have reached the same result with an elected council."
In the 2012 election Mr Overall became mayor in a landslide victory receiving more than 54 per cent of first preference votes.
Residents will not elect the mayor in the upcoming election, rather will vote for 11 councillors who will then choose a mayor to serve a two year term.
Holding the position of administrator has kept Mr Overall in the public's eye, however he disagreed with the sentiment that this could equate to an unfair advantage.
"All potential candidates have had opportunities to be fully engaged with the community over the same period," Mr Overall said.
"My appointment as administrator came through a process of expressions of interest that all the former councillors were invited to do."
"As the administrator presiding over meetings of council I accepted the recommendations of the local representation committee. It was a collegiate administration."
Tuesday's announcement included the 10 candidates from across Queanbeyan-Palerang who will complete Mr Overall's ticket. In addition to Mr Bray and Ms Taylor there will be Anthony Zakaoski, Rena Spears , Vlado Cvetkoski and Michele Biscotti, Danny King and Ashley Meyer-Dilley.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan-Palerang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Bray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vlado Cvetkoski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Cooma Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rena Spears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trudy Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Overall</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Overall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Meyer-Dilley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Zakaoski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michele Biscotti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellerton Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
