<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405317636319807</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/i-know-what-you-did-key-white-house-officials-were-tricked-into-replying-to-a-british-email-prankster-2017-8</url>
  <title>'I KNOW WHAT YOU DID': Key White House officials were tricked into replying to a British email prankster</title>
  <content>
Freshly departed White House communications director Anthony Scaramucci replied to emails from a British prankster pretending to be fired chief of staff Reince Priebus warning that he "knew what he did" and "rest assured we were prepared".

, which included hoax emails pretending to be from members of president Donald Trump's family, including son-in-law and adviser Jared Kushner and son Donald Trump Jr. to Homeland Security adviser Tom Bossert, Eric Trump and Scaramucci.

Here's the exchange between the fake Priebus and the real Scaramucci, following the latter's resignation:

FAKE PRIEBUS: "I had promised myself I would leave my hands mud free, but after reading your tweet today which stated how; 'soon we will learn who in the media who has class, and who hasn't', has pushed me to this. That tweet was breathtakingly hypocritical, even for you. At no stage have you acted in a way that's even remotely classy, yet you believe that's the standard by which everyone should behave towards you? General Kelly will do a fine job. I'll even admit he will do a better job than me. But the way in which that transition has come about has been diabolical. And hurtful. I don't expect a reply."
REAL SCARAMUCCI: "You know what you did. We all do. Even today. But rest assured we were prepared. A Man would apologize."
FAKE PRIEBUS: "I can't believe you are questioning my ethics! The so called 'Mooch', who can't even manage his first week in the White House without leaving upset in his wake. I have nothing to apologize for."
REAL SCARAMUCCI: "Read Shakespeare. Particularly Othello. You are right there. My family is fine by the way and will thrive. I know what you did. No more replies from me."

The UK-based hoaxer, whose writing often contain spelling mistakes and other grammatical errors, has been identified by the Financial Times as a 39-year-old web designer from Manchester, in England's north.

He posts his exchanges on Twitter as @SINON_REBORN. Here's one:

Reince (me) giving  something to think about. He never replied haha
- EMAIL PRANKSTER (@SINON_REBORN)

He's previously targeted banking CEOs with astonishing success, including Goldman Sachs boss Lloyd Blankfein.

He also emailed Scaramucci on Friday using a Gmail account and pretending to be Trump's nominee for Ambassador to Russia, Jon Huntsman Jr, asking whose "head should roll first" and whether he could "help things along somewhat".

Scaramucci wrote back saying "Both of them", which is believed to refer to Priebus and adviser Steve Bannon, before asking Huntsman to "please visit" if he wasn't already in Moscow.

Bossert was fooled into handing over his personal email address by a fake Jared Kushner account inviting him to a "soiree towards the end of August".

"Thanks, Jared. With a promise like that, I can't refuse," he replied.

In turn, Huntsman was targeted by a fake Eric Trump, replying "Thanks for the thoughtful note", adding that "Russia will be a challenging but no doubt rewarding assignment".

I wished Jon Huntsman Jr all the best. He seems enthusiastic about his new role.
- EMAIL PRANKSTER (@SINON_REBORN)

The real Eric Trump also received an email pretending to be his older sibling, Donald Jr. but replied that he'd "sent this to law enforcement" when he realised it was fake.

White House press secretary Sarah Huckabee Sanders told CNN that they were aware of the incidents and were looking into them further.

You can .

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Huntsman Jr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeland Security</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KNOW WHAT YOU DID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gmail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINON_REBORN</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bossert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloyd Blankfein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntsman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Read Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Bossert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEOs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Othello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
