<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405699888414211</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/economy/monetary-policy/reserve-bank-holds-interest-rates-at-record-low-15pc-20170801-gxmy9x</url>
  <title>Reserve Bank holds interest rates at record low 1.5pc </title>
  <content>
The Reserve Bank of Australia has kept the cash rate unchanged at 1.5 per cent, as expected, maintaining its concerns around soft wages and consumer price inflation.
Board members left the overnight cash rate steady at 1.5 per cent for  on Tuesday.
The Reserve Bank inadvertently fuelled speculation of interest rate hikes when it revealed in the minutes of its July 4 meeting that the economy's neutral rate had fallen to 3 per cent.
But governor Philip Lowe firmly shut down talk of tightening in a speech last week, where he declared that the RBA would not be hurried by other central banks which are raising interest rates, because Australia's monetary policy response was not as extreme.

"Just as we did not move in lockstep with other central banks when the monetary stimulus was being delivered, we don't need to move in lockstep as some of this stimulus is removed," .

Ahead of Tuesday's meeting, traders were pricing in a 52 per cent chance of a hike for May 2018. The Australian dollar was fetching US80.2¢, rallying after another weak session for the out-of-favour US currency.
For now, the Reserve Bank remains firmly on hold as it awaits a pick up in inflation and fresh evidence that a regulatory crackdown on risky bank lending is curbing the build-up of debt. Most economists see the cash rate unchanged heading into 2018.
, the latest figures show, removing any impetus to cool the economy.
On Friday, the central bank will release its statement on monetary policy.

More to come.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
