<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405579629328204</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/facebookbased-neighbourhood-groups-spreading-positive-community-spirit-in-brunswick-and-coburg/news-story/3c57fc1a1f91fd80fd5432867dd3d4d3</url>
  <title>Putting the social in Moreland's neighbourhoods</title>
  <content>
GOOD karma is spreading through neighbourhoods in Coburg and Brunswick.
The groups, formed in January this year, are Facebook-based and have the aim of spreading positive community spirit.
The has more than 700 members and the  more than 630.
The Coburg's group administrator Nerina Papanastasiou decided to form the local network after her sister experienced .
"It's about community spirit and neighbourly connection. It's very fulfilling. I'm lucky to have a really good relationship with my neighbours on both sides, but not a lot of people know their neighbours. They may live alone or in share houses," Ms Papanastasiou said.
"The network provides the opportunity to offer assistance, knowledge and skills to those in need, with no expectation of anything in return. It's also a place to encourage community sharing, for example, swapping fruit and vegetables or unwanted household items."
Buoyed by its success, the network was about to set up a household appliances "library", she said.
"It won't be kept in one central place, but people will be able to borrow household items from each other, such as breadmakers, ice-cream makers, food processors - the sort of things some people have and use occasionally."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coburg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nerina Papanastasiou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Papanastasiou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
