<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405699888414304</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/world/scaramucci-was-tootrump-for-donald-trump-20170801-gxmuno.html</url>
  <title>Scaramucci was too-Trump for Donald Trump</title>
  <content>
Even by the standards of the Trump administration, an organisation in which time warps and telescopes like that of a fever dream, the Scaramucci era was brief to the point of abrupt.
Anthony Scaramucci, the New York financier with no political or communications experience was named White House Communications Director on July 21.

Up Next

Smelly water oozes into Niagara Falls

01:16

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Trump removes Scaramucci

US President Donald Trump's communications director, Anthony Scaramucci, is out after just ten days on the job, the White House said on Monday.

He unofficially assumed his duties on July 25, though his official start date was not to be until August 15. He was sacked on July 31, a fortnight before he began.
Like Sean Spicer, the White House spokesman who welcomed "The Mooch" by resigning, he marked his first day on the job by so thoroughly debasing himself before the White House press corps that he could never hope to gain even passing respect.

Where Spicer marked the occasion by transparently lying about the size of Trump's inauguration crowds, the Mooch turned up and declared his love the President in positively North Korean terms."I love the President and I'm very, very loyal to the President, and I love the mission that the President has," he told them.
"He is the most competitive person I have ever met," he went on. "I have seen this guy throw a dead spiral through a tire. I have seen him at Madison Square Garden with a topcoat on, he's standing in the key, and he's hitting foul shots and swishing the ball on them. He sinks three-foot putts."  (Someone in the White House was apparently unmoved by even this sycophancy. The official transcript of that briefing was altered to have Trump .)

Taking a leaf out of Trump's own playbook, Scaramucci decided to distract from this catastrophe by creating another. He called the New Yorker's  so obscene and paranoid, so revealing of ignorance about the standards and norms of Americans governance, that it even stood out in the Trump White House.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Despite the Mooch's obvious inadequacies for the role, there were those who thought he might survive, even some who applauded his appointment as just the sort of CEO-style cunning that only a man as brilliant as Trump could conceive of.Photo: AP
"For someone who's never worked in communications, @Scaramucci is a very impressive communicator. Great hire, @realDonaldTrump," tweeted the ever-loyal Piers Morgan.
To be fair there was as school of thought that the Mooch's similarities to Trump might save him. He is - was - rich and brash, vulgar and confident. He wears, as Matt Taibi in Rolling Stone  put it last week, the sort of suit the owner of a Lamborghini dealership might favour. He even owns a fancy mid-town Manhattan steakhouse.Photo: AP
Scaramucci's problem was that in the Trump administration the only person who can get away with behaving like Trump is Trump. If anyone else had been as erratic, noisy and destructive to the machine as the President, he would have been sacked long ago.  As it is, as many Americans today want to see Trump impeached as still support his presidency.
In truth Scaramucci was gone the moment Trump sacked his Chief of Staff Reince Priebus. Trump had hired Scaramucci to stop leaks from the White House and he installed Scaramucci with a direct line of report to the Oval Office to that end. No chief of staff should or could tolerate such a circumvention of his authority, so when Trump replaced Priebus with the retired four-star Marine General John Kelly to clean up the mess, Scaramucci had no chance.Photo: AP
The Mooch has had a tough month. He has won and lost one of the most high profile jobs on earth. He has had a baby. He would have more time to spend with his family, but his wife left him.
But pity John Kelly too. He has to try to end the chaos in the White House and he can't sack the chief instigator.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Niagara Falls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Taibi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine General John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Communications Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piers Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madison Square Garden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lamborghinis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rolling Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>realDonaldTrump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
