<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405699888414309</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/adelaides-property-market-has-recorded-strong-figures-throughout-july-with-more-good-news-predicted-in-the-months-ahead/news-story/5697a92c008ded8bea182a1bd2fd5b49</url>
  <title>Adelaide's property market has recorded strong figures throughout July with more good news predicted in the months ahead - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
24a East St, Magill was one of Adelaide's top sellers in July.

ADELAIDE homeowners have a reason to celebrate, as a new reports reveals South Australian property values grew over the past month.
According to the July CoreLogic RP Data Hedonic Home Value index, released this morning, Adelaide home dwelling values rose by 1.1 per cent for the month - up from the 1.7 per cent drop recorded in June.
The city ranked fourth, with Melbourne homes leading the charge and rising by 3.1 per cent for the period.
CoreLogic head of research Cameron Kusher said Adelaide was likely to see continued moderate growth in the coming months.

2B George St, Norwood is one of July's top sellers.

"Despite the city still struggling to attract many interstate buyers and international migrants, I predict Adelaide will continue to see a steady, moderate growth in value prices," Mr Kusher said.
"A bonus for Adelaide is that it's a lot more affordable than other capital cities which is what's driving the market.
"Also, like most other capital regions, Adelaide's housing market generally outperforms units with the exception of July where units recorded a 5.6 per cent growth, compared to only 0.7 per cent for houses.
"Generally speaking, Adelaide is not really a unit centric market."

24a East St, Magill sold for $1.99 million.

Among Adelaide's top sellers for July was which sold for $1.99 million - $230,000 more than the $1.76 million record set by a property in the same suburb.
It is in stark contrast to Magill's $645,500 median house price, according to CoreLogic data.
Impressive sales were also recorded in in early July when two million-dollar homes sold within days of hitting the market.
Strong marketing campaigns, including a combination of print and online advertising was credited to getting the sales across the line.
The auction of 2b George St, Norwood, was scheduled for July 22 and the 'best offer by' sales campaign for 10 Glenburnie Ave, Torrens Park was due to end on July 19, but both properties sold after less than a week on the market.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrens Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magill's $645,500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenburnie Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kusher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July CoreLogic RP Data Hedonic Home Value</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B George St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Kusher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NORWOOD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
