<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405266096711503</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:58</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/01/12/22/top-ten-tips-to-spot-the-northern-lights</url>
  <title>The best ways to make sure you don't miss the northern lights</title>
  <content>
The lure of the northern lights is enough to drive any intrepid traveller mad with excitement. The mystique. The magic. The way they dance through the sky.
But here's the catch: loads of Aussies travel all the way to the other side of the world to see the lights. They trek to the depths of the Arctic Circle, stand apprehensively in the middle of an icy field in -30C conditions with their camera at the ready - and what do they see? Nothing.
Locals don't call the northern lights "the tricky lady" for nothing, after all. The lights are unpredictable, moody, and seem to sit somewhere on the scale between fairy-tale and reality. That's what makes them all the more special to see with your own eyes.
Yes, there's a lot of luck involved, but there are some sure fire things you can do to infinitely increase your chances of catching the show.
1. Get your timing right
The lights can be seen anytime from late August to mid-April. If you rock up in the middle of the arctic summer, when many regions have near 24-hour daylight, the only light you'll see is the sun. Daylight makes the lights invisible to the human eye.
The more darkness there is, the more opportunities you'll have to see the lights. We travelled in the darkest month of the year, December, and saw the lights four nights out of six. That said, you may wish to avoid the extreme cold and 24-hour darkness of the polar winter, in which case September or March are also great choices.

Related Articles

2. Choose your destination wisely 
As a starting point, you're looking for any region within the "aurora oval".
Parts of Alaska, Canada, Greenland, Iceland, Scandinavia and Russia all qualify. But not all arctic regions are created equal. Some lack the tourism infrastructure and others may not suit your individual needs.
Scandinavia is a great choice because it has whole industries dedicated to hunting the lights. From there, narrow down your choices to a country that offers other activities you think you'll enjoy. For example, Finland boasts Rovaniemi, the "official hometown of Santa Claus", Norway offers boat cruises along its epic fjord lined coast, and Sweden lays claim to the Abisko National Park.
3. Wait it out
This is a numbers game. The more nights you spend in the aurora zone, the greater your chances of landing a sighting.
At least 5 nights above the arctic circle is a good guide. This is enough time for most weather systems to pass - so if the weather is rubbish when you land, it should improve by the time you leave.
4. Look for clear sky
You can't see the northern lights through clouds, so have a weather app ready to show you the local radar and satellite images. Then look for gaps in the cloud cover.
Here's the foolproof rule of thumb: if you can see the stars, you can see the lights.
5. Beware the igloos
Before too long, you'll start seeing advertisements for glass igloo accommodation. The idea is wonderful, in theory. You settle in for the night, pour a red wine and watch the aurora borealis from the warmth and privacy of your glass-top igloo. But it may not be all it's cracked up to be.
It's all well and good if the lights just happen to appear on the very night you've booked, in the precise patch of sky above your igloo. But if they don't, well you're looking up at a whole lot of nothing. Ditch the novelty accommodation and stay mobile.
One night we drove 4 hours from Norway to Finland chasing clear sky. It was worth it. We saw a brilliant display and met other lights chasers along the way. You can't do that if you're stuck in an igloo.
6. Go pro
Join a lights chase tour and let an expert do all the hard work. Specialised tour guides have all the gadgets and local knowledge. They'll do whatever it takes to get you a sighting.
Many groups even offer a second night's tour at half price if you don't see the lights on your first outing. But book early. The tours can sell out months in advance.
7. Be nimble
Take it from me - the lights will appear when you least expect it.
Perhaps you've just ordered a burger and are sitting down to eat. Or maybe you've just put your pyjamas on and hopped in to your warm bed. Have your camera and warm jacket on hand at all times so you're only ever a few seconds away from being ready to dash outside.
Some hotels and cruises offer a lights alarm that goes off when the lights come out so you don't sleep through the whole thing!
8. Rug up 
Temperatures in the arctic routinely fall below -40C. Waiting for the lights often involves standing in wide open spaces for long periods of time. Invest in good thermals, gloves, thick socks, beanies, neck warmers and scarves.I even took a balaclava for the skin on my face. I may have looked like a pro criminal out in the field but I was nice and toasty while other travellers were shivering in their boots.
Oh that reminds me... snow boots... get some of those too.
9. Ditch the big cities
Big cities and towns produce a lot of light pollution, so you might need to travel past the town borders to get a clearer view.
Having said that, if the lights are strong enough, you'll be able to see them from anywhere - and the city skylines can make a pretty backdrop for that perfect northern lights photo.
10. Remember, it's not all about the lights
The Arctic Circle is an incredible wonderland of sights, flavours and adventurous experiences. Don't pin all your hopes on seeing the lights. Know that some of the best times you'll have will be doing those once-in-a-lifetime things that you simply can't do in Australia.
We joined a sled dog expedition along a frozen river....
We raced snowmobiles full throttle through arctic wilderness....
We caught the Hurtigruten boat along the Norwegian coastline and experienced a white Christmas....
We enjoyed all of these activities just as much as seeing the lights.
Bonus tip: If you are lucky enough to see the northern lights, make sure you take some time to watch them with your actual eyes. So many people get carried away trying to take the perfect photo to post online later. Don't be that person. Anyone can look at a photo of the northern lights on a computer screen, but only you will ever experience that exact moment. Treasure your own personal encounter with the lights. Then maybe afterwards, give the lights a little wave to let them know you enjoyed the show.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C. Waiting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hurtigruten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norwegian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abisko National Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alaska</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iceland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Claus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scandinavia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arctic Circle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovaniemi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
