<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405699888414241</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826010/the-great-weight-debate-dividing-illawarra-rugby-codes/?cs=302</url>
  <title>The great weight debate dividing Illawarra rugby codes</title>
  <content>
Divided: Illawarra rugby codes have different policies for their junior competitions.

IT'S the great weight debate, which polarises parents, officials and sporting codes. 
Illawarra junior manager Steve Nielsen has declared rugby league has every confidence in the age-based system.
However, Illawarra junior rugby union chairman Len Blackmore said there could yet be a move to weight divisions in future.
The 15-man code already has a "weigh up, weigh down" policy, where players voluntarily move up or down age groups because of the physical stature.
It has been successful enough for the guidelines to be expanded to two age divisions.
"We've had the policy in place for three or four years now," Blackmore said. 
"But it is always at the players request, there's certainly no situation where they would be forced into moving.
"One area we've focussed on is coaching and refereeing techniques to play safely when there are much bigger and smaller players involved.
"An area of concern is where the ball is cleaned out (at the breakdown) and a bigger child falls over on to someone else.
"That's where injuries can occur."

There are ongoing trials of using junior weight divisions in Canberra's rugby union competitions, however, Illawarra is yet to receive any official feedback from the ARU.
Junior representative players were also measured and weighed at the state titles this year, as part of union's studies into the matter.
In contrast, Nielsen has backed the age divisions, saying rugby league has fewer issues over player size than in western Sydney.
The debate was raised again this week, when a Samoan boy in the Bankstown area under eights, was videoed forcing his way past several defenders to score a try.
"We certainly implement and abide by the safe play rules for the game," Nielsen said. 
"In the Illawarra, it hasn't becoming quite the issue it has been elsewhere.
"We want to make sure everyone is safe playing rugby league and enjoys the game."

Finals for both codes kick-off later this month.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bankstown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nielsen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Nielsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Len Blackmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
