<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405442190372992</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/ringwood-east-residents-action-group-launches-online-fundraiser/news-story/f845f47204a3bb8354f465318b71a1be</url>
  <title>Call for help to fight apartment plans</title>
  <content>
THE Ringwood East Residents' Action Group has launched an online fundraising campaign to help them fight plans for a four-storey apartment block.
The group to hire a planning expert to help make a submission against David Reid Homes' plans for 1 Laurence Grove.
The plans remain in limbo after a recent mediation hearing at the Victorian Civil and Administrative Tribunal last month failed to reach an agreement.
David Reid Homes took its case to the tribunal after Maroondah Council refused to grant a planning permit for the development.
On the action group's , member John Lawrence said the case would now be heard over three days from August 21.
Mr Lawrence told the Leader they were employing an expert "to help us come out with the legal reasons rather than just emotional arguments" against the plans.
"It will set a precedent if it gets through VCAT which we're fighting seriously... we have an issue that the area will be overdeveloped eventually," Mr Lawrence said.
David Reid Homes did not want to comment when contacted by the Leader.
It comes as Maroondah Council pushes on with its vision to protect the suburb from overdevelopment, despite an independent planning panel recommending it abandon its plans.
Through Amendments C96 and C97, the council wants to adopt the Ringwood East and Heathmont structure plans into its planning scheme, which would see some new zoning and overlays.
But the panel, which looked at submissions and considered the amendments against local and state planning policy contexts, said the plans did not seek "sufficient" growth and development and "placed too much emphasis on the protection of the existing character of the area".
At a recent council meeting, its report in response to the recommendations was presented.
The council has refused to accept the panel's recommendation to abandon the plans.
Instead, it will make some changes - including removing mandatory height limits in the commercial areas - before submitting the amendments to Planning Minister Richard Wynne for approval.
Mayor Tony Dib told the Leader it was important to maintain the character of Ringwood East.
"Ringwood East [is a] neighbourhood centre and plays an important role in providing a diversity of housing types across the municipality," Cr Dib said.
"Ringwood and Croydon are the focus for development within Maroondah."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Reid Homes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroondah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Croydon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood East Residents' Action Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lawrence</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood East</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Minister Richard Wynne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Dib</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HEATHMONT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroondah Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Lawrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amendments C96</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurence Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Tony Dib</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C97</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Civil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Administrative Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
