<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405321931287201</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/the-pros-and-cons-of-dating-someone-with-a-foot-fetish/</url>
  <title>The Pros And Cons Of Dating A Foot Fetishist</title>
  <content>
Feet are not my kink. I'm not about to shame anyone. Personally, if I'm taking the time to aesthetically appreciate a guy, it's generally from the waist up. However, my most recent serious relationship opened my eyes to the world of guys who can't think of anything sexier than having their face stepped on.

The Discovery

My first clue to the fact I was dating someone with feet on his mind was a few months into the relationship. My boyfriend at the time took a sudden invested interest in why I wasn't wearing socks around the house.

Just to clarify, weekend me doesn't bother with these niceties. Finding matching socks is an added complication my weekend brain isn't required to deal with. Until my boyfriend kept asking about it. Over time, I found I was slowly starting to develop a certain insecurity about how clean or unclean my feet were. I wasn't entirely sure where this niggling worry came from. So I started wearing socks.

I did wonder at one stage whether he was one of those fabled "feet guys" I had heard so much about. That theory was hard to confirm considering if my feet went anywhere near his face, he would get instantly angry and move them away. Little did I know at the time, it was because I was giving him a huge hard on and he didn't want to give away his fetish at that point in our relationship.

I don't even remember the point of realisation. All I know is that eventually I figured out that if I wanted him to get off (so I could go to sleep), all I had to do was put my feet on his face for instant results. Bless.

The 'Free' Massages

There is the common notion that if you're dating a foot fetishist, you're going to enjoy foot massages every night at a moment's notice. This is true, and was exciting for a few weeks, but what people fail to realise is that you're expected to put out almost instantly after the 'free' massage, under pain of being accused of leading them on and working them up.

The post-massage whining isn't nearly worth the massage, regardless of how good it is. And I personally found the masseuse moaning a bit, I want to say... unnerving? But I consider that a personal fault.

The Painted Toenails

Another point to consider. Being a foot fetishist doesn't instantly mean your boyfriend is going to be great at painting your toenails. In fact, the focus of the task is so distracting on a baser level I feel like the entire effort suffered for it. I found myself on more than one occasion going straight for the nail polish remover when he was out of sight to eradicate the giant globs of hideous red that had been shakily applied all over my toes.

The Shoes

On the one hand, you have a boyfriend who is keen for shoe shopping (which sadly for him, owning four pairs of shoes total, I was not). On the other, you can't try on more than two pairs of heels without him having to run to the bathroom. And socks become lingerie. OH THE SOCKS. Taking off socks is EVERYTHING. My boyfriend was pleased to inform me my socks/stockings never smelled. Thank you, she replied to her doting boyfriend, not really paying attention.

The Other Women('s Feet)

I do feel like I'm doing foot fetishists a slight injustice, everyone is going to be different. I'm not going to lie though, I felt mildly uncomfortable knowing he was judging all my friend's feet. And how do you warn your friends not to flash their feet around your boyfriend?! Occasionally there would be a boyfriend outburst of "SUCH-AND-SUCH has HIDEOUS feet!"

What makes feet hideous!? What makes feet attractive?! I still don't know. The best advice I can give on that level, is to not worry about it too much. I don't think there's a danger of him copping a feel of the friend's feet that he's been secretly wanking over. And it's not really affecting you.

The Footjobs

Now prepare yourself for TOO MUCH INFORMATION. The biggest learning curve for me was trying to learn how to give footjobs. It's really hard (HA).  Especially if you're both bored and confused simultaneously.  I watched different foot fetish porn to try to figure out the perfect technique but I'm fairly certain these women had more extensive training than I did. They were probably picked from birth for their perfectly manicured, smooth, flexible feet. I never quite passed on that front, although he appreciated the effort which was kind of him.

The Next Level Fetish

Then came the second fetish addition. Giantess fetish.

I can neither confirm nor deny whether feet fetishes and giantess fetishes go hand in hand but there's a surprising amount of porn on this front. The basic idea being the guy wants to be crushed by feet. Giant feet. Sexy feet.
It's... a niche.

I just watched TV while he pretended to be a tiny person getting crushed underfoot. There are worse things to be doing to satisfy your partner I guess?

The Aftermath

Like any relationship, sexual compatibility is important. If I was a more dominant sort of sexual deviant I might have enjoyed it. As it was, we were two subs trying to make things work, in an unconventional unromantic way.

Now that I'm single, after a day at work walking around in heels all day, I do sometimes wish there was a guy offering a foot massage with an optimistic glint in his eye. But these days I'm kind of happy settling with a solo bath.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Next Level Fetish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Painted Toenails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Free' Massages</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giantess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pros And Cons Of Dating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MUCH INFORMATION</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footjobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foot Fetishist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
