<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405785787761220</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/mornington-peninsula-shire-backs-12-million-project-to-upgrade-rye-pier/news-story/1331eddd2faec2940c980c2b1544c86f</url>
  <title>Boaties buoyant over upgrade news</title>
  <content>
AN  EXTRA boat ramp and second pier at Rye will slash queue times over summer and make the area safer for boaties, says one of the region's biggest charter -operators.
Mornington Peninsula Shire voted in favour of the $1.2 million project, which includes the upgrade of the three existing ramps and a reconfiguration of the lanes.
The work will be paid for with a $588,000 State Government Boating Safety and Facilities grant and $648,000 from the council's capital works program.
Savage Seas Adventures owner Charlie Micallef said the upgrade and extra ramp would make getting boats in and out of the water safer.
"At the moment it's pretty dangerous," Mr Micallef said.
"There's a lot of slime on the existing ramps. I have slipped and fell and slashed open my leg and I know of a lot of others who have had similar accidents."
Mr Micallef said demand over summer meant he often had to launch his boat in the middle of the night.
He said the problem was so bad that he had stopped taking charters in December and January.
"I haven't done it for the past five years and I estimate it has cost my business $180,000," Mr Micallef said.
Not everyone was pleased with the council's decision.
Rye Community Group Alliance chairwoman Mechelle Cheers said the Rye community had "strongly and consistently" opposed any expansion of the boat and jet ski facilities.
"The council just hasn't listened to the community," she said.
She said since the decision was made she had received 150 emails from residents upset that the plan had been approved.
Many were worried that the extra boat ramp would attract more jet skis and further endanger marine life, especially rare dolphins that frequent the area.
In a letter to the Leader Gail McMillan said the council had not taken into account the impact on the -environment.
"They don't seem to care that the road infrastructure cannot cope with the traffic congestion now, let alone how it will cope with the further influx of more vehicles with trailers, the further pollution of the bay, the safety of the swimmers, the stench of fumes emitted, the noise, the further congestion of the nearby streets with vehicles' parking," Ms McMillan wrote.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Gail McMillan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mechelle Cheers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Micallef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savage Seas Adventures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McMillan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government Boating Safety</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boaties</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula Shire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Micallef</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rye Community Group Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
