<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405227442005331</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/nsw-act/courts-law/lynette-daley-manslaughter-trial-i-didnt-know-a-fing-hug-can-kill-you/news-story/c613a521f6aa8f32c3f4602c2a115556</url>
  <title>Lynette Daley manslaughter trial: 'I didn't know a f***ing hug can kill you'</title>
  <content>
Lynette Daley died after a brutal sexual assault, prosecutors say.

AAP

Share

LYNETTE Daley lay drunk, naked and bleeding to death in the back of a car after "a wild sex session" with two men on a remote NSW beach, a jury has heard.
She was then dragged into the ocean where Adrian Attwater, 42, tried to wash the blood from her body before calling triple-zero on January 27, 2011, prosecutor Philip Strickland SC told the NSW Supreme Court at Coffs Harbour.
Attwater, who has pleaded not guilty to manslaughter and aggravated sexual assault, later said "I didn't know a f***ing hug can kill you," Mr Strickland said on Tuesday.
Ms Daley, 33, died from injuries sustained in the alleged sexual assault at Ten Mile Beach, the prosecutor has previously told the court.
Attwater's friend and co-accused, Paul Maris, 47, has pleaded not guilty to sexually assaulting the mother-of-seven and hindering the discovery of evidence.

Ms Daley's dead body was dragged from the car and washed before her attackers called triple-0, the court heard.Source:Supplied

Paul Maris allegedly took part in the sex act with Ms Daley. Picture: AAPSource:AAP
In his opening address yesterday, Mr Strickland SC said "all three of them drank a lot of alcohol on that day".
At dusk, they stopped halfway up the beach in Maris' troop carrier where Attwatter and Daley got on a mattress in the back.
Attwater "repeatedly and vigorously" sexually assaulted Ms Daley for a couple of minutes, Mr Strickland said.
Maris joined in with a sex act at Attwater's invitation, the barrister told the court.

Attwater only stopped the assault when he noticed blood on his hand and Maris later burnt her bra and the bloodstained mattress "because it stank," the Crown said.
Confronting photos shown in court showed injuries to Ms Daley that caused significant blood loss.

Adrian Attwater arrives at the Supreme Court in Coffs Harbour. Picture: AAPSource:AAP

Adrian Attwater told police at the time Ms Daley had been "off her face". Picture: Glebe Coroners Court.Source:Channel 9
The assault "substantially or significantly contributed to her death," Mr Strickland said.
Her autopsy also revealed a small amount of methylamphetamine and a blood alcohol concentration of 0.303 - meaning she was "grossly intoxicated". The prosecutor said Attwater told police "she was blind, she was off her f***ing face last night".
Attwater claimed Ms Daley had a fit or seizure in the ocean when she went for a swim while naked and he performed CPR after dragging her back to shore. When questioned about how the trio came to have group sex, Attwater said: "These things happen ... girls will be girls, boys will be boys." Both men told police they thought it was consensual.
Mr Strickland said Maris told police: "Well she didn't object when I jumped in the back, she'd moved over to give me oral."
The trial is expected to run for six weeks.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Daley, 33</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Attwater, 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Maris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mari</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Maris, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glebe Coroners Court.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attwater</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAPSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Daley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Strickland SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Mile Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Strickland SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attwatter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynette Daley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Attwater</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Strickland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
