<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405485140046400</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826209/illawarra-regional-airport-security-measures-outlined/?cs=12</url>
  <title>We need to be alert, but we don't need to be alarmed: Shellharbour Mayor Marianne Saliba</title>
  <content>
The passenger terminal at Illawarra Regional Airport. Picture: Robert Peet

Shellharbour's Mayor says "we need to be alert, but we don't need to be alarmed", as airport security measures have been heightened throughout the country. 
The state of Australia's airport security has been thrown into question after the arrest of an Islamist-inspired terror cell in Sydneyfollowing an alleged plot to bring down an aeroplane with a bomb or deadly gases. 

Regional airline JetGo will be running direct flights from the Illawarra to Brisbane and Melbourne from October. 
The airline newcomer was  as Shellharbour City Council's chosen carrier for its resurrected regular passenger service from Albion Park. 
Illawarra Regional Airport is owned and operated by Shellharbour City Council. 

Shellharbour Mayor Marianne Saliba said in the wake of recent events, airport security was "concerning for everybody... I don't think it's unique to Shellharbour".

"We have to follow the security measures that are put in (place) by national security; CASA are the people that would set the requirements. 
"Some of the things we do out there (include) our fences are checked four times a week, we make sure our gates are secure... When our new airline operations start we will have proper security equipment for the classification of airports that we will be, which I believe is a Class 5.
"We will have an X-ray machine for the luggage, we will have a metal detector that people will walk through, and we will have the machine that they use when they take swabs of shoes and bags.
"So we will have all the things that are needed to have by us. Should the regulations change then we would also have to change to meet those requirements."

Cr Saliba didn't believe recent events would deter passengers from utilising regional airports such as Albion Park. "We need to be alert, but we don't need to be alarmed," she said.
"We need to be vigilant and careful, but it shouldn't stop us from having the freedoms that we're entitled to.
"I don't think that Australians are the types of people to allow others to force them to do things that they don't want to do... I don't think it will stop people from travelling, but I do think it's something that we need to be mindful of."
Shellharbour City Council will go through the tender process for the installation of the X-ray machine and baggage screening equipment at Albion Park at an extraordinary meeting next week. 
"It will go out to tender, and we will be making sure that whoever it is that we buy this material from are reputable and provide the type of security required at other airports," Cr Saliba said. 
Meanwhile, tickets for flights from Albion Park to Melbourne and Brisbane went on-sale last month. 

READ MORE: 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Class 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rays</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour Mayor Marianne Saliba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamist-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBERT PEET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydneyfollowing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Regional Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour City Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CASA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JetGo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Saliba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour's Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
