<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405579629328296</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/braking-the-cycle-to-gain-employment/3207130/</url>
  <title>Braking the Cycle to gain employment</title>
  <content>
PCYC Ipswich and Ipswich City Council have partnered to bring a multi-award winning learner driver mentor program to Redbank Plains.

Braking the Cycle uses volunteer mentors and community sponsored vehicles to help disadvantaged young people gain the 100 hours of driving experience required to get their licence.

Young prospective drivers are supported through ongoing mentoring to overcome social barriers that can prevent them from getting work.

Braking the Cycle Redbank Plains will operate from the Redbank Plains Library for one day a week from September.

People interested in volunteering can attend from 9am and young people will be able to sign up to the program from 2pm.

PCYC Ipswich development officer Angela Watts said the aim was to get the program up and running with volunteer mentors to assist young drivers.

"This program helps disadvantaged and disengaged young people aged 16 to 25 to get their driver's licence which in turn assists them to gain employment," she said.

Division 9 Councillor Sheila Ireland said the program would provide a welcome boost for the local community.

"The program's success depends largely on the community and individuals getting behind this initiative and raising their hand to become a mentor to assist young people in getting their licence," Cr Ireland said.

To book a place or for more information, phone PCYC Ipswich on 3281 2547.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Watts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 9 Councillor Sheila Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCYC Ipswich</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redbank Plains Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redbank Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cycle Redbank Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
