<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405837327369753</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/north/ifly-looks-to-soar-into-westfield-chermside/news-story/cf7874450304822bcc328f3feab2e702</url>
  <title>Indoor skydive venue plan</title>
  <content>
THRILL seekers could soon be taking to the skies at Chermside - but not at 12,000 feet.
iFLY Australia has submitted a development application for an indoor skydiving centre at Westfield Chermside, between the cinemas and Gympie Rd.
The project would be a Brisbane-first and proposes a glass wind tunnel for skydiving alongside party rooms, a viewing area, preparation classrooms and amenities.
iFLY pitches an "exhilarating experience and a highly addictive sport" where there is "no parachute, no jumping, and nothing attaching you to planet Earth".
It's not the first time iFLY has sought to set up in Brisbane. It gained council approval for a site at Virginia in 2013, but an iFLY spokesman said Chermside was the preferred long-term option.
"From a business model perspective, Chermside is the number one shopping centre in Australia," the spokesman said.
"(An iFLY in Brisbane) has been four years in the making, but we took a long- term view."
The spokesman said iFLY had withdrawn from plans at Virginia.
The development requires 30 established carpark spaces to be removed.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chermside</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virginia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iFLY</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield Chermside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iFLY Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane-first</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
