<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405317636319827</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>ABN Newswire</source>
  <url>http://www.abnnewswire.net/press/en/89401/Greatcell-Solar-Limited-(ASX-GSL)-Share-Purchase-Plan-Offer-Document-89401.html</url>
  <title>Greatcell Solar Limited (ASX:GSL) Share Purchase Plan Offer Document</title>
  <content>
Canberra, Aug 1, 2017 AEST (ABN Newswire) - Greatcell Solar Limited (ASX:GSL) (OTCMKTS:DYSOY) ("Company") is pleased to present you the opportunity to increase your investment in the Company under the Company's Share Purchase Plan (SPP) - with no brokerage or commission costs and at an issue price of AUD 18 cents (A$0.18) per share.
The SPP Offer is proposed to raise A$5 million. The Board of Greatcell Solar has the discretion to accept subscriptions over the maximum of A$5 million that it has set to raise through this Offer.
The right to participate in this Offer is open to eligible shareholders only.
All eligible Directors have indicated their intention to participate in the SPP.
Eligibility
Participation in the SPP is exclusive, and strictly limited to shareholders who were registered as holders of fully paid ordinary shares in Greatcell Solar Ltd at 5:00 p.m. (WST) on the Record Date of 27 July 2017 and whose address in the Company's register is situated in Australia or New Zealand. The Record Date is determined by the ASX Listing Rules and is the day prior to the first announcement of the current SPP. The Offer is non-renounceable and non-transferable - the right to apply for shares cannot be sold or otherwise disposed of.
The Offer
Full details of the SPP are outlined in the attached Greatcell Solar Limited Share Purchase Plan, and I encourage you to read it in its entirety before you decide whether to participate. By law, the Offer under the SPP is limited to 30% of the ordinary shares already on issue. Shareholder approval is not required to issue shares under the SPP.
It is proposed to raise a total of A$5 million through the SPP Offer. In the event that oversubscriptions are received, Greatcell Solar may scale back the maximum number of shares issued to each shareholder at its absolute discretion. Greatcell Solar may take into consideration the size of an applicant's shareholding or application when determining the amount of any potential scale-back and therefore the extent of the scale-back may differ between applications. The Company also reserves the right to accept oversubscriptions. Shares issued under the SPP Offer will rank equally with shares on issue at the date of the SPP Offer.
Shareholders may make a maximum investment through the SPP of A$15,000.
Full details on the SPP and how to participate are contained in the documents attached (see the link below). To apply for a parcel of shares please read these documents carefully and follow the instructions on the enclosed personalised SPP Application Form.
To view the full Share Purchase Plan, please visit:

About Greatcell Solar Limited
Greatcell Solar Limited () () is a global leader in the development and commercialisation of Perovskite Solar Cell (PSC) technology - 3rd Generation photovoltaic technology that can be applied to glass, metal, polymers or cement. Greatcell Solar Limited manufactures and supplies high performance materials and is focussed on the successful commercialisation of PSC photovoltaics. It is a publicly listed company: Australian Securities Exchange ASX (GSL) and German Open Market (D5I). Learn more at our  and subscribe to our mailing list in English and German.

   

Related Companies
            

Social Media
Share this Article

ABN Newswire
This Page Viewed:  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>D5I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greatcell Solar Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Board of Greatcell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 1, 2017 AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN Newswire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPP Application Form</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities Exchange ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greatcell Solar Limited</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greatcell Solar Limited Share Purchase Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greatcell Solar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>German Open Market</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPP</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPP of A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX Listing Rules</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Record Date</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perovskite Solar Cell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Share Purchase Plan Offer Document</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Company's Share Purchase Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OTCMKTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Page Viewed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GSL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DYSOY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPP Offer</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Share Purchase Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
