<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405790082728625</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/beauty/face-body/drew-barrymore-praised-for-posting-refreshingly-real-selfie-on-instagram/news-story/e4f7ea82d90175a30bd40a6731352079</url>
  <title>Drew Barrymore praised for posting refreshingly real selfie on Instagram</title>
  <content>
Drew Barrymore shows off her Golden Globes makeup on Instagram.

Share

MANY of the photos you see on social media have been filtered and airbrushed within an inch of their life.
And celebs are often the biggest culprits. Not only do they have the photo editing apps available to all of us, but they have a professional team of makeup artists and stylists on their side as well.
That's why the photo that Drew Barrymore just posted on Instagram is so refreshing.

on

"OH MY GOD. How did I let it get this bad. Base and brows needed," the 42-year-old actor said in the caption, which accompanied the photo of her makeup-free face, complete with unkempt eyebrows and a sizeable amount of grey regrowth at her roots.
Since she posted it, the image has been liked over 80,000 times.
People seemed to love the fact that celebs, just like us, can be guilty of letting things slide a bit in the beauty stakes.

We're used to seeing Drew Barrymore on the red carpet, after spending hours with makeup artists and stylists. Picture: GettySource:Getty Images
"You never try to hide anything - you're the most honest and straight forward!" said one commenter.
"Thank you for this! More people need to understand that 'perfection' is an illusion and that true beauty is underneath. Have always loved you, love you more now," said another.
Website Hello Giggles also sang Barrymore's praises: "We can't even imagine what it must feel like to be under constant public scrutiny, and it takes a lot of courage to just put yourself out there as you truly are instead of attempting to create an illusion of perfection," .

Other commenters praised the fact that the actor's forehead appeared to be free of injectables.
Barrymore, who has her own makeup line called spoke to the  about her simple beauty routine.
"I would say 90 per cent of my life, I wear zero makeup," she said.
The actor posted the pic to promote the upcoming season of her Netflix series Santa Clarita Diet.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OH MY GOD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barrymore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Barrymore</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hello Giggles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GettySource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Globes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Clarita Diet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
