<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405227442005285</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/fashion/mecca-drops-200-products-under-45-but-how-do-they-compare-with-more-expensive-brands/news-story/5cb371fdb9a93f99f6212f2d8e92c1cb</url>
  <title>Cheap vs expensive make-up: Which is better?</title>
  <content>
IT'S EVERY make-up junkee's dream; when one of Australia's biggest cosmetic retailers drops hundreds of new, affordable products.
Today, Mecca, has launched their new beauty range, dubbed MECCA MAX.
Featuring 206 products with prices ranging from $5 - $45, it's designed for "experimentation, personalisation and play."
From foundation, concealer, brushes, powders, bronzers, mascaras, eyeshadows and contour palettes - the launch has been three years in the making, according to creative director Martia Burke.
The Australian beauty market is spoiled for choice when it comes to cosmetics and skincare. According to , some 6.3 million Australian women over the age of 14 buy make-up of some kind in an average six month period.
Beauty bloggers, you-tubers and social celebrity has changed the face of the industry. Once upon a time, a consumer was limited when searching for beauty information. But now, looks, hacks, ideas and product reviews are at arms reach.
But this new range hopes to break a niche in the market - the consumer who is obsessed with beauty, but doesn't have the bank account to feed their addiction.
We asked makeup artist to test five MECCA MAX staples, and compare them with cult classics, and see how the new affordable line compared with more expensive brands.
MECCA MAX LIFE PROOF FOUNDATION VS GIORGIO ARMANI LUMINOUS SILK:
is a self confessed Giorgio Armani Luminous Silk addict.
"I've used it for 12 years now both personally and professionally," she told news.com.au.
"So you're looking at a huge fan right here."

The new Mecca Max foundation claims to be oil free, waterproof and provide a matt finish on the skin while still being creamy and durable. Available in eight shades, and retailing for $32 - how does it compare with the $99 cult classic?
"The only main difference I can pin point is that the Mecca Max Life Proof foundation has a slightly more matte finish," Rachael said.
"Otherwise, the texture, coverage and wear is very similar and just as good as Luminous Silk.
"It's over $60 cheaper as well, so it's definitely worth trying."
MECCA MAX LIFE PROOF CREAM CONCEALER VS NARS CREAMY CONCEALER
A good concealer is a vital step in perfecting a flawless finish. For Rachael, the NARS creamy concealer has been a staple in her, especially for eliminating dark circles and other blemishes.
Retailing at $44, how does it compare to Mecca's new contender?
"The Mecca Max Life Proof concealer is a slightly thinner consistency to NARS, so the coverage offered is slightly less," Rachael explained.
"However, it blends well and the coverage can be built up by pushing the product into your skin with your fingers."

At half the price as its competitor - Mecca's new concealer claims to "remove redness, blur bumps, buff and blend pigmentation to erase darkness." But there is one flaw to the cheaper option.
"I would recommend using it for redness and under eye coverage rather than to cover blemishes," Rachael explained.
"After setting with powder, unfortunately the Life Proof concealer looks slightly dry, so I'd recommend skipping the powdering with this product."
MECCA MAX SUNLIT BRONZER VS NARS LAGUNA BRONZER:
Launched in 2001, the NARS Laguna bronzer quickly became the best selling bronzer in the world. Selling around 52 units each hour, it's a firm favourite because of its shade and sheer, buildable texture.

Retailing at $58, Laguna has been worn by celebrities around the world. So does it trump Mecca's version - which will set you back just $22?
"While Laguna is a very popular bronzer, it's actually very ashy, and deep in colour," Rachael said.
"So it's not always suitable for pale skins.
"The Sunlit skin Bronzer, however, comes in three different shades so pale skin tones have the option of choosing a lighter shade.
"This bronzer has a touch more warmth and shimmer than Laguna, so it's still appropriate for using under the cheekbones as a natural contour, as well as for bronzing.
"I also think it doubles as a nice eyeshadow too."
MECCA MAX EYE MAX MASCARA VS TOO FACED BETTER THAN SEX:
For Rachael, one of the most important factors when it comes to mascara is eyelash separation. Unfortunately, not all mascaras are created equal - but the Too Faced Better Than Sex quickly became a go-to for artists around the world for its curved brush, and ability to coat and curl each lash.
But at $33 for the wand, how does it compare to Mecca's dual stick - which will actually set you back $38?

"What I love about Mecca's new mascara is the dual end," Rachael said.
"The smaller wand can be used to separate and coat lashes before applying the fuller wand.
"The smaller wand is also perfect for bottom lashes. Usually, I'd have to use two mascaras to achieve this, but Eye Max has it all in one.
"The only downside is the product makes my lashes look slightly less fluffy compared to Better Than Sex."
MECCA MAX POUT LIPSTICK VS MAC CREAMY LIPSTICK:
If MAC cosmetics are known for one thing, it's their bold and creamy lipsticks. Oh, and for
With lipstick being the number one category at MAC, they reportedly produce one bullet per second globally.

Lipsticks are high risk for any wearer, especially when using bold colours. At $36 per unit for a Mac lipstick, how does it compare to Mecca's cheaper $20 option.
"I'm struggling to find a difference between the two," Rachael said.
"Pout pop has a luscious, creamy texture and a nice amount of pigment. The length of wear is the same as well, so I'm super impressed!"
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NARS Laguna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mac</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MECCA MAX LIFE PROOF FOUNDATION VS GIORGIO ARMANI LUMINOUS SILK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MECCA MAX SUNLIT BRONZER VS NARS LAGUNA BRONZER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faced Better Than Sex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martia Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MECCA MAX POUT LIPSTICK VS MAC CREAMY LIPSTICK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laguna</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Better Than Sex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giorgio Armani Luminous Silk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MECCA MAX EYE MAX MASCARA VS TOO FACED BETTER THAN SEX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Proof</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachael</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eye Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mecca Max Life Proof</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.75</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MECCA MAX</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S EVERY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mecca</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nars</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MECCA MAX LIFE PROOF CREAM CONCEALER VS NARS CREAMY CONCEALER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luminous Silk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
