<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405833032402401</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/preview-trainer-greg-hickman-changes-tack-to-bring-dream-folk-back-up-to-speed/news-story/ad2d40a7d6f5ad8b7cafffd8b908b75d</url>
  <title>Preview: Dream chance for an upset</title>
  <content>
GREG Hickman makes a compelling case for $51 shot Dream Folk to cast aside his lacklustre first-up record and cause a boilover in the TAB.com.au Handicap (1400m) at Warwick Farm on Wednesday.
Dream Folk turned eight-years old on Tuesday but looked half his age in a recent 806m trial at home at Warwick Farm, closing off from last to be beaten just 1 3/4 lengths.
"I was over the moon with the trial,'' Hickman said. "I have sort of trained him a little bit differently this time. He's only been working over 800m just to keep him a bit sharp going into this race and you see a happy horse coming off the track.''
Dream Folk has won from 1400m to 2400m but has registered only one placing from six first-up runs. "This is the first time I have trained him off an eight-week spell whereas before he'd only have a month in paddock," Hickman said.
"He's done a super job for us in the stable since coming from Guy Walter, I don't know exactly how much money he's won since he's been with us but it's plenty.''
Hickman saddles-up four runners on Wednesday, including last-start winner Centro Superior, who is one-for-one at the track and distance.
The son of 1994 Golden Slipper winner Danzero has only managed to win four times in 34 starts but is too often dictated to by tempo and luck in running.
"We're getting there with him,'' the trainer said. "Tommy (Berry) said, 'Let's take the ear muffs off him,' because he was getting too relaxed. He travelled on the bunny last time at Gosford and was more positive so obviously they (the ear muffs) were working too well. This is a nice race for him and he has done well since the other day when he won.
"I am a little bit worried that he's drawn barrier 11 but there is plenty of pace in the race so in that respect we should get a nice run. If Tommy rides him well again, he will be hard to beat.''
Hickman has called upon talented apprentice Courtney Van Der Werf to steer Phoebe's Lass in the ATC Schweppes Handicap (1200m).
Van Der Werf was having her first ride on the mare when a distant but closing second to Phuket in a very fast run 1000m race at Hawkesbury on July 16.
"I thought she would have done better first-up but she improved dramatically at her second run and has done very well through the week since,'' Hickman said. "She's been placed in town before and she'll just land where she is comfortable so she can hit the line.''
Meanwhile, Hickman's stayer Pyramid Prince is $61 to post what would be only his fourth career win at start 42 but has more to offer than his TAB Fixed Odds quote would suggest.
"He has no weight, his work has been up to the mark, where it should be, and I'm happy with him going into the race,'' he said. "If he gets a chance to be in a forward position and he hits the line, he will give it a big shake.''Newnham's big shot at Glory
MARK Newnham knows what makes supercharged gelding and Warwick Farm debutant Key To Glory tick. The trainer has had a close association with the Gooree-bred three-year-old's family for 20 years.
So it was an easy decision for the Gooree hierarchy to hand Key To Glory over to Newnham after the horse's previous trainer James Cummings took up the role as head trainer at Godolphin last month.
Newnham has a longstanding relationship with Gooree from his time at Tulloch Lodge as Gai Waterhouse's right-hand man. Key To Glory's dam Above Perfection and grand-dam Actress were housed in Bowral Street as was family patriarch, six-time Group 1 winner Desert War.
"It's nice to have the Gooree horses because I do know a lot about the families and you sort of know what you are dealing with from the time they come in,'' Newnham said. "They are good, tough, genuine horses - that's the description for Gooree-bred horses.
"They've got good bones and are well reared. They've got a really good system up there at Gooree that is proven over a long period of time so all I am doing is fitting in with that system and happy to be there.''
Key To Glory is a son of Gooree's own Group 1 winner Your Song and is a half to their stakes-placed sprinter Tactical Advantage. Like him, Key To Glory is possessed of incredible pace and speed, traits which propelled him to a 5 1/2 lengths win in a recent 1050m trial at Randwick, two weeks after a much narrower yet still highly impressive 740m heat win.
"His two trials have been excellent and he showed good improvement from one to the next,'' Newnham said. "I wouldn't say he is at his top yet, he's still got to clean up a little bit in the coat but I want him to be able to come out of his first run improving.
"Hopefully it's winning and improving. He's got natural pace and he ran home in pretty good sectionals the other day. He is ready to go to the races.''INSIDE MAIL
SHAYNE O'CASS analyses the meeting at Warwick FarmRACE 1 (12.40pm): PLUCK@VINERY HCP (1100m)
Gooree gelding 5. Key To Glory has won both trials at Royal Randwick before his debut, the last one by 5.3 lengths. He is a very fast horse and was strong through the line in that last 1050m heat. Great family, looks to have talent and $4.60 TAB Fixed is acceptable. 2. Cuba has always had a bit of a rap on him. He's run in a Listed and a G3 race at his only two starts last prep. Better after a run or two but has talent. 1. Al Mah Haha was the eye-catcher here behind a very good colt on debut.
BETTING STRATEGY: KEY TO GLORY to win.RACE 2 (1.20pm): THE EVEREST IS COMING HCP (1100m)
Astern and Mogador's half-sister 1. Alizee could end up being the best Godolphin-bred filly of the 2014 crop. She trials like a G1 horse and, while on paper her form appears muddling, she's had excuses. She was runner-up to Tulip in a Magic Night. If she runs ​up ​to that, and her recent trial, she will be winning. 8. Songlike is extraordinary value at $7.50. She was $1.80 against an absolute star 2YO named Marble at Hawkesbury and wasn't trounced. 4. Acqume has trialled well.
BETTING STRATEGY: ALIZEE to win; Exacta 1 to beat 8; Quinella 1,8.RACE 3 (2pm): SCHWEPPES HCP (1200m)
3. Mar​i​quita opened at $6 and quickly firmed to $4. Her two runs this prep have been at Rosehill in Saturday grade and both contained significant merit. She is ready to peak. 10. Luiza was $10 to $7 first-up here at the Saturday meeting on Jul​y​ 8 off a smashing trial but faded to finish last. Obviously better than that, expect a much improved outcome here. 8. Princess Command is tempo reliant but has a powerful finish. 2. Single And Free is fitter for the first-up run.
BETTING STRATEGY: MARIQUITA to win; Box trifecta 2,3,8,10.
RACE 4 (2.35pm): TAB HCP (2200m)
11. Don Pellegrino was $13 into $10 when runner-up to Roman Son in a similar race here on June 28. The Paul Perry-trained gelding was 11th of 12 here in another 2200m race after that, but only 5.4 lengths from the winner. Represents each-way value at $18. 7. Napoleon is always some sort of chance in these types of races, this is his trip. Wasn't beaten that far at the same track/distance on July 19. 4. Bastia is fourth-up, an on-pacer, blinkers off first time. Should place.
BETTING STRATEGY: DON PELLEGRINO each-way.RACE 5 (3.10pm): #THERACES HCP (1200m)
7. Charming Lad is a locally-trained gelding from the red-hot form stable of Jason Coyle. When his horses trial well, they almost always run well on raceday and no one could have missed Charming Lad's last 100m in his recent Warwick Farm heat. Plenty of speed on here, look for him to be charging home late. 5. Jonny Ge drew 12 of 12 at Grafton and was back near last at the bend but got within 2.8 lengths of the winner. Big run! He will be closer here, that's guaranteed. 6. Young Huit will be prominent from his good draw.
BETTING STRATEGY: Charming Lad each-way; Quinella 5,7.RACE 6 (3.45pm): BOWERMANS HCP (1600m)
6. Manhattan Son hit his best stride winning at Hawkesbury third-up off a forgive run at Kembla. This Clarry Conners-trained chestnut is a little trier and is over the odds at $15. Ditto 10. Trenchant at $18, he can only be better for the first-up run in a much deeper race. 15. Arigold was 12th of 14 at Kembla but was only 3.2 lengths from the winner and closing fast. Is 5s 1-2-0 at this distance, trained here and has a featherweight.
BETTING STRATEGY: Manhattan Son/Trenchant/Arigold each-way; Box quinella 6,10,15.RACE 7 (4.20pm): TAB.COM.AU HCP (1400m)
8. Dream Folk is the best roughie all day. He went up at $81, was $51 the next morning which is still probably double what he ought to be. Granted, he is a stayer and is 6s 0-1-0 fresh, but he looked anything but an 8YO stayer in his recent trial. Bet small, win big. ​1​4. Know How is a frustrating horse in that the talent is surely there but he doesn't get things to go his way. One day he will. 9. Fortensky is lightly-raced and has done nothing wrong.
BETTING STRATEGY: DREAM FOLK and KNOW HOW each-way.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kembla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>COM.AU HCP (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desert War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortensky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAB Fixed Odds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonny Ge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Farm</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tactical Advantage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INSIDE MAIL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinella 1,8.RACE 3 (2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosehill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newnham</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATC Schweppes Handicap (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOWERMANS HCP (1600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HCP (2200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick FarmRACE 1 (12.40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACE 7 (4.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centro Superior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy Walter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phuket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACE 5 (3.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exacta 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoebe's Lass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THERACES HCP (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godolphin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarry Conners-trained</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCHWEPPES HCP (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Key To Glory</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glory</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EVEREST IS COMING HCP (1100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Slipper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Perry-trained</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acqume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gooree</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Van Der Werf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KNOW HOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luiza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtney Van Der Werf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DON PELLEGRINO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Coyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godolphin-bred</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gooree-bred</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHAYNE O'CASS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Al Mah Haha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dream Folk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkesbury</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mogador</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyramid Prince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREG Hickman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinella 5,7.RACE 6 (3.45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pellegrino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danzero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAB Fixed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tulloch Lodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gai Waterhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alizee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Son</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G-3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G(1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Handicap (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan Son/Trenchant/Arigold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARK Newnham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan Son</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Night</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bastia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowral Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VINERY HCP (1100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arigold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hickman</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charming Lad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARIQUITA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tommy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Napoleon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACE 2 (1.20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ditto 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
