<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405790082728661</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-advice/flights/calls-renewed-for-airline-seat-size-regulation-over-safety-concerns/news-story/a3a4677412d1a98272351bca1a1bd0c5</url>
  <title>Calls renewed for airline seat size regulation over safety concerns</title>
  <content>
Seven Secrets To Getting the Most Comfortable Airline Seat
1:51

When it comes to airplane seats, you don't always have to pay more to get more. Here are 7 secrets for getting the most comfortable airline seats without breaking the bank. Photo: iStock/BraunS.

November 19th 2014
3 years ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Travel - News.com.au/

Calls renewed for airline seat size regulation over safety concerns.

Julia Corderoy with AP

Share

IF YOU swear flying economy is getting tighter and tighter, you're not wrong. But there could be some justice on the way.
In a significant win for the fight against profiteering airlines cramming as many seats on a plane as possible, a US appeals court panel has said that federal officials must reconsider their decision not to regulate the size of airline seats.
In a colourful ruling on Friday, one of the judges called it "the case of the incredible shrinking airline seat" and said that it represents a pretty serious safety issue.
Previously, the Federal Aviation Agency (FAA) had successfully argued not to regulate seat spacing because it was a matter of comfort, not safety.
But now, the three-judge panel for the federal appeals court in Washington have told the agency it needs to come up with a better-reasoned response to the safety concerns that cramped seating slows down emergency evacuations and raises the danger of travellers developing blood clots.
The concerns were raised by passenger advocacy group, Flyers Rights, who wanted to challenge the FAA in court after the agency rejected its request to write rules governing seat size and the distance between rows of seats.
In its ruling, the appeals court concluded that the FAA had relied on outdated or irrelevant tests and studies before deciding that seat spacing was a matter of comfort, not safety.
Judge Patricia Millett scolded the FAA for "vacuous" and "vaporous" evidence that diminishing leg room was not an issue for passenger safety.

In a colourful ruling on Friday, the US appeals court called it "the case of the incredible shrinking airline seat" and said that it represents a pretty serious safety issue.Source:istock
"We applaud the court's decision, and the path to larger seats has suddenly become a bit wider," said Kendall Creighton, a spokeswoman for Flyers Rights.

FAA spokesman Ian Gregor said the agency was considering the ruling and its next steps. But he stressed that the FAA does consider the spacing between seat rows when testing to make sure that airliners can be evacuated safely.
And while this comes as welcome news to passengers, it's safe to assume airlines won't be thrilled about the ruling. The airline industry has steadily reduced the space between rows to squeeze in extra seats and make more money.
This year, news leaked that American Airlines planned to order new Boeing 737 jets with just 74cm of leg room - or seat pitch - in the last three rows to make room for an extra row of premium-priced seats toward the front of the plane.
The airline did then back off after objections from customers, ensuring these rows will have 76cm of pitch - although still a tighter fit than the airline's current planes.
on six popular carriers flying in and out of Australia: Air New Zealand, Emirates, Etihad, Qantas, Singapore Airlines and United Airlines.
It found all airlines had seats with a minimum seat pitch of just under 79cm, except Singapore Airlines, where the smallest seat had around 81cm of leg room.
But it's not just leg room that matters. Flyers Rights said that the average seat has gotten narrower too - from 47cm a decade ago to 43cm.
According to Skyscanner's comparison, Emirates, Qantas and United offer the smallest option for Aussies flying out of the country, at 43cm. Singapore Airlines has the biggest economy seats (on some planes) at just over 48cm.
"This is the Case of the Incredible Shrinking Airline Seat," US Judge Patricia Millett wrote in her ruling.
"As many have no doubt noticed, aircraft seats and the spacing between them have been getting smaller and smaller, while American passengers have been growing in size."
The issue could wind up in Congress, where some politicians have already proposed legislation to regulate seat size.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Patricia Millett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing 737</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secrets To Getting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Case of the Incredible</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iStock/BraunS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendall Creighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singapore Airlines</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skyscanner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flyers Rights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Aviation Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Gregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Judge Patricia Millett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comfortable Airline Seat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FAA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shrinking Airline Seat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Corderoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
