<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405184492331660</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/this-time-next-year-ratings-karl-stefanovic-smashes-rivals-to-claim-no-1-spot-20170801-gxmtax.html</url>
  <title>Karl Stefanovic's new show finished at No. 1, smashing its rivals</title>
  <content>
Karl Stefanovic is now a prime time ratings champion. 
The Today co-host ranked No. 1 on Monday night with his new program, This Time Next Year. 

Up Next

Trailer: Romper Stomper

01:21

More Trailers Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

00:59
Trailer: This Time Next Year

Trailer: This Time Next Year

Everyday Aussies will tackle monumental personal goals during the most challenging year of their lives.

Up Next

Trailer: Romper Stomper

01:21

01:21
Trailer: Romper Stomper

Trailer: Romper Stomper

The original 1992 film that tells the story of the downfall of a neo-Nazi group in blue-collar suburban Melbourne.

Up Next

Trailer:
It

02:23

02:23
Trailer: It

Trailer:
It

The new adaptation of Stephen King's iconic work. In Derry, Maine, seven friends come face-to-face with a shape shifter, who takes the form of an evil clown who targets children.

Up Next

Trailer:
Kiki, Love to Love

01:52

01:52
Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Trailer:
Kiki, Love to Love

Director Paco LeA³nas vibrant new comedy follows a collection of lovers through a series of intertwined stories, delivering an outrageously provocative take on what can happen behind closed doors.

Up Next

Trailer:
Thor: Ragnarok

02:25

02:25
Trailer: Thor: Ragnarok

Trailer:
Thor: Ragnarok

Imprisoned, Thor must battle a former ally and race against time to prevent goddess of death Hela from destroying his home.

Up Next

Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

01:54

01:54
Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Set in Madrid, ordinary couples with real passion investigate their own sexuality through five intertwined stories.

Up Next

Trailer: A Monster Calls

02:26

02:26
Trailer: A Monster Calls

Trailer: A Monster Calls

A boy who is experiencing trauma from his single mother's terminal illness seeks the help of a tree monster.

Up Next

4 Corners: Pumped

00:30

Trailer: This Time Next Year

Everyday Aussies will tackle monumental personal goals during the most challenging year of their lives.

The reality transformation show averaged 1.28 million viewers in the five major cities. Once regional ratings are available, this figure will grow.
Monday's episode of The Block averaged 1.26 million city viewers - meaning Stefanovic increased Nine's audience, despite starting at 8.45pm. This is no mean feat. Top-rating non-news shows tend to occupy the plum 7.30pm slot, while those beginning close to 9pm draw few viewers.

Stefanovic also smashed his direct rivals, with an average audience more than twice the size of Ten's Have You Been Paying Attention? (620,000) and four times the viewership of The Bourne Ultimatum on Seven (315,000).
Based on a British series, This Time Next Year features ordinary Australians pledging to reach a goal within 12 months. 

Stephen is desperate to meet his biological mother. Emma intends to walk again. Liz - who has never heard her children speak - wants a cochlear implant.
For them, it's 365 days of gruelling work. For us, it's dizzying. Minutes after their initial interview, we skip ahead one year for the studio "reveal". Will Luke and Sequoiah, who've endured eight miscarriages, emerge with a baby? Is Paul, born with gender dysphoria, now living as a woman? Did Tracey, with terminal cancer, complete her "bucket list"? This Time Next YearPhoto: Channel 9
On Monday, we learned that Luke and Sequoiah had twins. Gay farmer Brad, however, is yet to find a boyfriend.
Stefanovic believes it's important to show that some participants don't fulfil their pledges. After all, that's life. A search for love has no guarantees. Intensive medical treatments might not work. Career goals remain elusive.Photo: Nine
"Sometimes, reality can bite," he says. "This is not your standard, stereotypical program. It's all there and it's genuine."
He remains deliberately ignorant of the results, ensuring his reaction is fresh. "I had no idea what was coming through the door. I had to prepare myself for what I might see - or might not see."
Sometimes, reality can bite.
Karl Stefanovic

"That was the trickiest part of the series," says Trent Chapman, Nine's production and development boss. "You don't want to sugarcoat everything; nor do you want seven fails in a row. But even when people don't achieve their pledge, they achieve big things along the way - or they have a success in another area."
In his search for participants, Chapman and his team contacted more than 7000 community groups and individuals. "They're not the kind of people you normally see [on reality TV]," he says. "They're not doing this for fame or infamy."Photo: Supplied
So why did they allow a camera crew to track them? "We all make New Year's resolutions, and most of us break them within a week," Stefanovic says. "Knowing you'll be on national TV is a huge motivator."
Not every pledge is heart-rending. Tim wants to join the circus, for instance, while Dustin vows to win a medieval sword contest. TodayPhoto: Louie Douvis
When Stefanovic does a 60 Minutes interview, he comes armed with research. On This Time Next Year, he's led by his gut. "I was probing and pushing, then pulling back. I have to be completely present."
Some commentators believed low ratings for his 2015 panel show, The Verdict, boded poorly for his new venture. "I was immensely proud of The Verdict," he says. "All I can control is what I do on air. I can't worry about what people say I'm doing."SurvivorPhoto: Nigel Wright
No deals have been inked, but he plans stay with Today in 2018. So far this year, Sunrise. "I think if we're honest with ourselves, we were so hellbent on winning last year that we may have lost focus on the most important thing: the viewers. But now we're back to winning the hearts and minds of viewers with great content, and I think we're doing that."
Long-running renovation show The Block topped the 7.30pm slot, followed by ABC's 7.30 (657,000), Ten's Survivor (656,000) and Seven's Billy Connolly & Me: A Celebration (589,000). 
On Sunday, Survivor's new season launched with 639,000 city viewers, finishing in eighth place. With , the network had high hopes for the lavishly-produced series - not least because . 
Ten's programming chief, Beverley McGarvey, says: "We are pleased with how Australian Survivor launched [on Sunday], given the heavy competition. It is a great show, with extraordinary contestants, drama and challenges. Australian Survivor dominated social media last night and we are confident viewers will engage with the show - across all platforms - as the new season unfolds."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven's Billy Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celebration (589,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourne Ultimatum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's 7.30 (657,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Stefanovic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thor</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten's Survivor (656,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monster Calls</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sequoiah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven (315,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Next YearPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIGEL WRIGHT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beverley McGarvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TodayPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paco LeA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Next Year</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ragnarok</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Chapman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chapman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten's Have You Been Paying Attention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trailers Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MADRID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stefanovic</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiki</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SurvivorPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
