<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405794377696015</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/paramedics-rush-crash-major-coast-road/3207509/</url>
  <title>Paramedics rush to crash on major Coast road</title>
  <content>
BREAKING: Paramedics are rushing to the scene of a crash on a major Sunshine Coast road.

The crash was reported to emergency services at 2.25pm from Caloundra Rd, near the Bruce Hwy. 

Initial reports suggest a vehicle has crashed into a barrier on the left-hand shoulder of the westbound lanes. 

One ambulance crew has just arrived at the scene.

More to come.

UPDATE: It's rare for whales to swim to where the pair was beached.
Released as part of a nation-wide campaign
Coast applauds decision to upgrade major venue
Architect of a region stops briefly on his final journey.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
