<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405790082728632</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/logan/children-united-with-iceaddicted-parents-at-cuttingedge-chambers-flat-units/news-story/03ea9a22327b1b5a6255b6805b22862e</url>
  <title>Ice units bring families together</title>
  <content>
LOGAN will play a crucial role in the state's crackdown on the drug ice when a series of live-in recovery units for families battling addiction open in Chambers Flat.
The groundbreaking project, the first of its kind in the state, will allow children to stay with their ice-addicted parents in a safe environment at the Logan House Recovery Centre, while their parents break their addiction.
Under the Lives Lived Well program, families can stay in the units for up to eight weeks while receiving targeted, tailored and family-focused rehabilitation.
The rehab program includes drug and alcohol treatment, as well as family therapy, positive parenting, trauma support, family development support and case management.
Child Safety Minister Shannon Fentiman said she believed the live-in recovery units would be a success and would help families stay together.
"Far too often we see behaviours stemming from ice misuse and dependence playing a role in family dysfunction, breakdown and conflict, leading to involvement with the Child Safety department," she said.
"For parents who are subject to a child protection order, the program will work towards reunification with their children."
The Chambers Flat units will be constructed using federal money and the Lives Lived Well program, which is part of a $7.4 million state commitment over three years to crackdown on ice.
Child Safety data released this week showed the use of the drug ice was an ongoing problem for Logan families.
The data, from the March quarterly Child Safety Report, showed the number of children in need of protection was on the rise because of ice use by their parents.
In the Logan, Beenleigh and Browns Plains, in the year to March, 82 children needed protection after one or both of their parents used methamphetamine. That was up from 63 children in the year to December.
The three areas were so notorious for drug abuse, this year's state budget included funding for an extra 13 child protection staff in Logan. A specialist "ice adviser" will also be employed as part of the budget's $7.4 million over three years for the state's Action On Ice.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beenleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Action On Ice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lives Lived Well</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Safety Minister Shannon Fentiman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Child Safety Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan House Recovery Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chambers Flat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Child Safety</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Browns Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
