<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405742838087721</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/ufc/ufc-tyron-woodleys-dana-white-threat-scorned-champion-hits-back-at-president-on-the-mma-hour/news-story/59701aeb42c48be4c185a0be0badb914</url>
  <title>UFC: Tyron Woodley's Dana White threat, scorned champion hits back at president on The MMA Hour</title>
  <content>
Tyron Woodley before UFC 214.

Staff writers

Share

UFC welterweight champion Tyron Woodley has threatened to "start leaking some s**t" unless he gets an apology from Dana White.
The UFC president slammed Woodley's performance in his title defence against Demian Maia at UFC 214 on Sunday (AEST), declaring it boring after fans booed during the American's unanimous decision win. Woodley fought a highly tactical fight against supreme submission specialist Maia, yet White was so unimpressed that he confirmed Woodley had been stripped of the chance to next face returning legend Georges St-Pierre, instead reviving GSP vs Michael Bisping for the middleweight title.
"You ask fans if they want to see Woodley fight again, I think that will be a flat out no," White said.
Woodley gave a startling retort on , while revealing that he suffered a serious shoulder injury (torn labrum) during the fight's first round.

Woodley retains belt
1:05

UFC: Tyron Woodley holds off Demian Maia for the welterweight belt.

July 30th 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/More Sports/

"I don't care so much about the fans but when your job title is promoter, promote your f***ing fighters," Woodley told MMA Fighting's Ariel Helwani.
"You're going to publicly scrutinise me, Dana White? You publicly need to apologise to me.
"I've done nothing but good stuff for the sport. I've done nothing but be a good model for the f***ing organisation. I go out there and I fight with integrity. I covered your sport from the FOX desk a week before my fight. I always uphold my responsibilities to the organisation. It's timeout for that.
"The word behind 'business' is 'man.' You need to be a man, you owe me a public apology. And if I don't get that, I'm going to start leaking some s**t that people don't want to be out in the wind. I'm not even kidding about that."

Tyron Woodley reacts after defeating Demian Maia during UFC 214.Source:AFP
Woodley didn't elaborate on what he may leak. The 170-pound champ also took a crack at White for playing favourites, especially with Conor McGregor.

"What happened to your golden boy Conor McGregor when he couldn't get Nate Diaz out and he was missing too many punches?" Woodley said.
"He folded and he quit. He laid on his stomach, and not even to a super-deep rear-naked choke, he quit. My shoulder popped out, not once, three times in that fight. I felt it the first time, I've had a labrum tear before, I'm like, 'Oh s**t, I think I tore my labrum.' And then I threw a couple more overhand rights, and each time it threw out. I threw a punch to the body and it came out, then I missed a punch and it felt like it slipped out.
"But what do I have to do? I said this dude is not taking my belt, he's not walking out of the Octagon with them saying 'and new,' he's not putting on that (champion's) jersey that I know they've got down there by ringside that they want to put on him so f***ing bad, he will not wear that today. And that's what I did.
"So that's why I'm upset, I'm upset because I don't get the simple courtesy of a human, the simple integrity that if you have a problem, come talk to me first.

Tyron Woodley's win over Demian Maia was heavy on takedown defence.Source:AFP
"The thing about it, be a straight shooter to me. That's how I operate. I can't speak for [fellow champions] Amanda Nunes and Demetrious Johnson.
"Those are my friends and you always want to see them maximised and getting what they deserve. But speaking for myself, the way I deal and operate, you come and talk to me. You feel like I had s**tty fight? Come pull me to the side before you get on the podium. If you feel like I didn't deliver or I didn't promote or I've done something negative, or you didn't like what I posted on social media or you had an issue with something I said on FOX, or whatever the situation is, I'm a communicator. Come to me. Talk to me about it.
"I don't want to hear about it afterward, because at that point I feel like you're not promoting me. You're demoting me. And then on that level, you can't selectively promote. You can't selectively promote and excessively promote certain individuals, and then the champions, the people who are out there fighting in the toughest divisions in the world, don't get the equal and the same promotion.
"I just can't see that. I can't see how our sport, if you recognise the people who talk the most stuff, who drop the most profane tongue, who actually throw the water bottles, who really actually are the most unprofessional, those are the highly promoted and those are the most paid athletes. Is this still a sport?"

UFC president Dana White puts a title belt on Jon Jones at UFC 214.Source:AP
Woodley insisted he was not on poor terms with White, though also said he had never expected the GSP match-up, despite the UFC president's assurances.
"Me and Dana don't even have a bad relationship," Woodley said. "I'm not even really that mad at Dana, he just owes me an apology. Once he gives me an apology, we good. The thing is, I know what to expect. I know what to expect out of people. I don't expect more out of a person than what they've shown me in the past. So with that, I never expected the Georges St-Pierre fight."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dana White</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyron Woodley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC 214.Source</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bisping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nate Diaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA Fighting's Ariel Helwani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA Hour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyron Woodley's Dana White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodley</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georges St-Pierre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demian Maia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GSP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Nunes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demetrious Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC 214</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
