<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405485140046395</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4826089/man-dies-woman-injured-in-single-vehicle-highway-crash/?cs=303</url>
  <title>Man dies, woman injured in single-vehicle highway crash</title>
  <content>
TRAGIC: Emergency services on the scene of the crash about 12.30pm. A man aged in his 20's died in the single vehicle rollover on the Pacific Highway.

Port Stephens police will investigate a crash that claimed the life of a man on Tuesday morning.
Emergency services were called to the Pacific Highway, north of Raymond Terrace, shortly before 11am on reports a Toyota Echo left the road and hit a tree.

The rollover happened along the highway between Rangers Road and Six Mile Road.
The driver of the vehicle, a man believed to be aged in his 20s, died at the scene.
His passenger, a 19-year-old woman, was treated at the scene by NSW Ambulance paramedics before she was taken to John Hunter Hospital with non-life threatening injuries.
A NSW Ambulance media spokeswoman said the teenager was trapped in the car for a short time before being assessed by paramedics.

She was transported to hospital in an ambulance.

The Westpac Rescue Helicopter also attended.
Port Stephens police attended the crash and established a crime scene.
Port Stephens SES unit and crews from NSW RFS Lower Hunter also attended.
An investigation is underway to determine the circumstances surrounding the crash.

Anyone that witnessed the crash has information is urged to contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
The highway is open near the crash scene, however traffic is heavy and moving slowly.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Six Mile Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac Rescue Helicopter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW RFS Lower Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hunter Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raymond Terrace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Highway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota Echo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Ambulance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rangers Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Stephens SES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
