<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405785787761218</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/nt-supreme-court-hears-shayne-pendlebury-45-allegedly-indecently-dealt-with-girl-at-baseball-clubs-anniversary-function/news-story/c49e9977742b1109c683a430c96c4168</url>
  <title>Girl allegedly touched inside bathers</title>
  <content>
A PALMERSTON baseball club member allegedly used a club function to start indecently touching a young girl inside her bathers, before continuing to touch her at a sleepover, the Supreme Court has heard.
Shayne Pendlebury, 45, has pleaded not guilty to four counts of indecent dealing with a child under 16.
Crown Prosecutor Mary Chalmers told jurors on the opening day of Pendlebury's trial yesterday they would hear evidence Pendlebury committed his first indecent act on a 12-year-old girl at the Palmerston and Rural Reds Baseball Club sixtieth anniversary function at the Free Spirit Resort on October 29 last year.
The indecent touching allegedly took place in the resort swimming pool as Pendlebury was playing a game of piggy in the middle, and "horsing around" with kids, but paying special attention to the girl, Ms Chalmers said.
The girl's mother - who was not there on the night - told the court her daughter later told her she tried to swim away from Pendlebury, only for Pendlebury to grab her by the leg and pull her back towards him.
"I could see that there was something troubling her, she was a bit uncomfortable telling me," the mother said. The Crown case is that a further three counts of indecent dealing took place later that night at Pendlebury's Lyons home, including one in which Pendlebury grabbed the girls hand and put it on his penis.
The girl's mother said her daughter told her the next day her hand was forced on to something "sticky and hairy".
"She was uncomfortable telling me about something like that," the girl's mother said. "She said she was very scared at that point." In a police interview to be played to the jury, Pendlebury outright denied the alleged offending, which Ms Chalmers said was a lie.
The girl's pre-recorded evidence was played in closed court late yesterday. The trial, expected to last for five days, continues before Justice Stephen Southwood and a jury.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Mary Chalmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Stephen Southwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pendlebury's Lyons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Chalmers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shayne Pendlebury, 45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmerston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Free Spirit Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rural Reds Baseball Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pendlebury</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
