<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405828737434965</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/queensland/news/gold-coast-spit-casino-and-resort-rejected-by-queensland-government/news-story/5370e99a7d840f1d57a04337ea3612d5</url>
  <title>Gold Coast Spit casino and resort rejected by Queensland Government</title>
  <content>
State Government terminates ASF plan for casino on Gold Coast
20:50

The State Government has torpedoed a $3 billion casino resort earmarked for the Gold Coast's Southport Spit. Vision: 9 News Gold Coast

August 1st 2017
3 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Gold Coast Bulletin/Gold Coast News and Galleries/

ASF's Gold Coast Integrated Resort has been scuttled.

Greg Stolz, Jeremy Pierce, Anthony TempletonThe Courier-Mail

Share

A multibillion-dollar integrated resort and casino in southeast Queensland has been rejected by the State Government, saying the area where it was proposed must be protected.
Chinese-backed company ASF had planned a five-tower integrated resort, including a casino, on Crown land on the Spit at Southport, on the Gold Coast.
ASF had been named as the preferred proponent for the resort and a second Coast casino.

An image of ASF consortium's proposed Gold Coast integrated resort with casino.Source:Supplied
Announcing the shock decision, Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk today said The Spit needed to be protected.
"This part of the GC is unique to qlders and unique to the world," she said.
She said Cabinet made the "very important decision" yesterday.
"The first decision we made was to terminate the ASF proposal for the spit."

What the development would've looked like.Source:Supplied
Ms Palaszczuk said another decision made by Cabinet was to have a masterplan for The Spit.
"I used to come here as a young girl, I still come here," she said.

"This area is probably equivalent to what Central Park is to New York."
Ms Palaszczuk said a three-storey height limit for development would apply on The Spit.
She said the casino licence would remain on the Gold Coast but no integrated resort would be allowed on The Spit.

ASF Consortium director Louis Chien had been in talks with global casino resort giant Caesars Entertainment in relation to the proposed $3 billion resort development on the Spit. Picture Glenn HampsonSource:Gold Coast Bulletin
She said the traffic congestion from the ASF proposal would result in locals paying more in rates and an "eyesore" in terms of new road development.
The project would have been a major job creator but was unpopular with many locals. Opposers, led by former Beattie government minister Judy Spence, had railed against the ASF proposal.
Ms Palaszczuk said The Spit would be able to be enjoyed by families for generations.
"I want that to be a significant legacy of my Government," she said.
Planning Minister Jackie Trad said the future of The Spit needed to be determined by the people of the Gold Coast.
"The master planning process will involve extensive community consultation ... to make sure we get the balance right between development that's appropriate on the southern end of The Spit but also making sure we preserve what is special about the parklands," she said.
"We want to make sure that Queenslanders continue to come here for decades and decades to come because we know how precious and beautiful this part of the world is."
Ms Palaszczuk said she did not agree the decision would cost jobs on the Gold Coast.
"It's not killing a job-creating project because there will be opportunities for other investment here on the Coast," she said.
"We will need people to be employed once the master plan is completed."
Ms Palaszczuk could not say how much compensation would be paid to ASF as a result of the decision.
Mayor Tom Tate's plans for a cruise ship terminal on the Spit are not expected to be impacted by the Government's decision.

PROPOSED GOLD COAST CRUISE SHIP TERMINAL
0:35

An artists impression video of the oceanside Gold Coast cruise ship terminal.

May 30th 2017
2 months ago
/video/video.news.com.au/News/

It comes a month after ASF Consortium director  he was in talks with Caesars Entertainment regarding the proposal. The global giant is behind famed Caesars Palace in Las Vegas.
"ASF Consortium has been in ongoing discussions with a number of world-class operators," he said in July.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Spit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn HampsonSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caesars Entertainment</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASF's Gold Coast Integrated Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Stolz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Pierce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GOLD COAST CRUISE SHIP TERMINAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony TempletonThe Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASF Consortium</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beattie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louis Chien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caesars Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast's Southport Spit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Gold Coast Bulletin/Gold Coast News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese-backed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Tom Tate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASF</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
