<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405833032402404</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-opinion/human-rights-commission-sexual-assault-report-universities-fail-in-their-core-mission-20170801-gxmyaa.html</url>
  <title>Sexual assault disgrace: Universities fail in their core mission</title>
  <content>
At the risk of proffering a reductio ad absurdum, universities have only one function: to turn out students deepened in knowledge but broadened in mind - people equipped with formal qualifications but also the confidence, curiosity, and optimism, required to go forth and contribute.
So, like a hospital that makes patients sick with infection, findings of the Human Rights Commission that 6.9 per cent of the university students surveyed had been sexually assaulted in the past two years, and that more than half reported being sexually harassed last year alone - many on campus - show these trusted institutions are failing.

Up Next

'Universities are a big part of the problem'

01:35

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Universities brace for sexual assault report

A landmark survey of 31,000 students by the Australian Human Rights Commission is likely to raise further allegations of sexual assault on campus.

The Human Rights Commission has branded that "unacceptable". Of course, it is worse than unacceptable, being a complete reversal of the university concept, and a betrayal of each institution's clear responsibility - or duty of care - to the individual student.
And as with adverse outcomes in the hospital system, it is the first response of universities to complaints of harassment or assault that is critical. Here the institutions have struggled.

In the aftermath of hospital acquired injuries, the official reaction is critical. Studies show that sensitive, immediate, validation turns out to be pivotal in reducing the psychological harm that compounds any physical insult, and generally outlasts it.
"The evidence is clear that universities need to do more to prevent such abuse from occurring and to build a culture that responds appropriately to these incidents by supporting victims and sanctioning perpetrators," noted Sex Discrimination Commissioner, Kate Jenkins.

Obviously the injury to students subject to sexually motivated ill-treatment, be it bullying, innuendo, discrimination, or assault, prevents them from enjoying their university experience, and from gaining the best from themselves and their education.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Universities can no more prevent all incidents, than they can ensure that vexatious, or malicious complaints will never be made. So care is needed. But the evidence suggests a real dysfunction here which is systemic and cultural.Photo: Josh Robenstone
The tertiary sector has been put on notice to upgrade its systems - particularly around residential colleges, to update its culture, and to dramatically improve its handling of such complaints.
Traditions and customs within venerable organisations are fine. But the data call for urgent change. If institutions geared to the acquisition of knowledge, cutting-edge research, and the liberal virtues of higher education, cannot adapt to these entirely reasonable standards, they will fail students, and see their reputations wane.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Discrimination Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Robenstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
