<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405828737435020</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/report-commissioned-by-local-government-association-of-sa-finds-capping-council-rates-would-lead-to-other-increased-costs-for-ratepayers/news-story/2e02ef1435a519b74d0106fa2fbe7ddb</url>
  <title>LGA: Council rate capping bad for ratepayers</title>
  <content>
CAPPING rates charged by local councils would lead to more debt, bigger infrastructure backlogs and higher fees passed on to ratepayers, a report funded by the Local Government Association warns.
University of New England Professor Brian Dollery, who authored the report, is in South Australia this week to deliver his findings after comparing outcomes for councils here and NSW, where rate capping has been in force since 1977.
Local government rates are shaping as a key point of difference between the major parties at the March state election - prompting the LGA to launch a campaign against the change which may include targetting marginal seats.
The State Opposition is pushing for rate capping while the Government is opposed.
Professor Dollery's report, funded by the Local Government Research and Development Scheme, found that rate capping in NSW had a particularly negative effect on smaller councils.
"Councils with capped rates have higher levels of debt and larger infrastructure backlogs than those without rate capping and also have higher fees and charges that they pass on to their communities," Professor Dollery said in a statement ahead of his visit to SA.
"In fact, rate capping leads to a decline in the financial sustainability of councils."
The Opposition argues that NSW has "the lowest council rates in the nation" as a result of rate capping.
Its policy would empower an independent regulator to set the rate increases that councils could apply - which would be based on the cost of services they provide.
Local Government Minister Geoff Brock has argued that residents would not "necessarily be better off under rate capping" and said there was evidence interstate that the policy "can restrict the level of services councils can provide".
LGA SA president Lorraine Rosenberg said rate capping had "failed" in NSW and was starting to affect council services in Victoria, where the policy was introduced more than a year ago.
"Before making up their minds on this policy, we're asking people to imagine what their community would be like without their local library, recreation and sporting facilities, food inspections, hard waste collection, jetties, parks, events, street trees or public toilets," she said.
"Rate capping would squeeze council budgets to the point where all services that are not mandatory under legislation would be at risk."
The first such service to be affected could be the maintenance of jetties in coastal council areas, which the LGA will highlight in Facebook posts from Tuesday.
There are about 110 jetties across SA.
More than 70 are owned by the State Government but under the care of councils through lease arrangements.
The LGA says councils have spent more than $6.6 million on both state and council owned jetties over the past decade despite not being required to by law.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGA SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorraine Rosenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England Professor Brian Dollery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Dollery</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Minister Geoff Brock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
