<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405961881423336</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/south/zak-vows-his-beloved-pizza-shop-will-rise-from-the-ashes-as-community-rallies-to-support-the-small-business/news-story/d98e053bddf0a476a0eb75e7ee77de39</url>
  <title>Zak vows his pizza shop will rise from the ashes</title>
  <content>
ZAK Kartabani rubs his eyes as he struggles to take in the charred remains of his Port Noarlunga pizza restaurant.
It is the first time he has stepped over blackened rubble to enter the dining room since it was devastated by fire on Sunday, July 23, about 3am.
"It still feels surreal," Zak says.
"I opened the business here 12 months ago and it had finally got to the stage where things were flowing right."
The alarm was sounded just hours after Zak's partner, Hanna Parades, had covered the leftover lemon pie and stacked the dining chairs - now welded into a chaotic mess with broken glass and charcoal - in preparation for the breakfast shift at Zak's Pizza and Grill.
Last Friday, when the Southern Times Messenger visited Zak, a tight-knit team of family and staff were covering their faces against the acrid stench of ash and garbage while disposing of everything - from scorched wine glasses still hanging on the rack to a blackened cylindrical container that squirts bright yellow mustard when Hanna picks it up.
One staff member, mother-of-two Lani Waziri, says she is "devastated" by the remnants which give just a hint of what once was a thriving restaurant.
"I got ready at 6am to come and do the breakfast shift that morning but then I found out about the fire and raced down here to support Zak," the born-and-bred Noarlunga local says.
"Zak has been so brilliant in working around my family.
"When I told him I could no longer work nights, he gave me mornings and two extra shifts a week prepping food on days when the place isn't even open - who does that?"
With Lani's livelihood gone, four local businesses have called her in the past week to offer additional shifts.
They include Beach Road Wines, which also offered shifts to other staff members.
At the site of the inferno, Hanna - her face hidden behind an industrial respirator mask - is comforting a distraught Zak.
He has just discovered what is left of a large port barrel that sits below a melted biblical statue.
Following a building inspector's survey, Zak reckons there is around $400,000 worth of damage - mainly to the dining area and also the takeaway store,
Zak estimates he is personally at least $200,000 out-of-pocket.
"Earlier this week I would've been tempted to just give up and walk away," Zak says.
"But the community here won't let you - even if you want to.
"It's been overwhelming, the level of support I have received from so many businesses."
Just then, the owner of a neighbouring chicken shop yells out from the building's only accessible entrance - the rear fire exit.
He's offering free lunch.
"That's an example of how supportive the community is being - I've had offers from all over Adelaide, tradespeople offering their services and 40 litres of paint left on our doorstep from a Dulux representative," Zak says. "With all the energy I've got left, I will rebuild this place."
Zak, who believes the fire was started by an electrical fault, hopes to relaunch the takeaway section of the business by the end of August.
The dining area will take at least six months to repair.
A SAPOL spokeswoman said the cause of the fire was not suspicious.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beach Road Wines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanna Parades</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak's Pizza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Times Messenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAPOL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lani Waziri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dulux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Noarlunga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noarlunga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ZAK Kartabani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
