<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405742838087769</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/14/35/abc-aap-commercial</url>
  <title>ABC and SBS chasing commercial revenue</title>
  <content>
The ABC could be chasing commercial revenue in an effort to replace money the public broadcaster lost after government funding was cut, the boss of Australian Associated Press has acknowledged.
Speaking to Nine.com.au, Bruce Davidson, CEO of Australian Associated Press, said the advent of digital players has allowed the likes of the ABC, and other players, to push into digital areas, potentially taking revenue and audiences from the traditional commercial players.
"The ABC has a very important role in the Australian media and has a remit to provide news and information services particularly in areas that are not commercially viable for some of the other players," Davidson said.
"The advent of digital platforms and the ease for which new entrants and other players, like the ABC, can push into digital areas that are starting to push up against the mainstream publishers.
"We've seen the likes of News and Fairfax and the TV broadcasters making some noise around how they see that impacting their business and their ability to be sustainable in some of those areas if the ABC, which is publicly funded, starts to knock up against them in competitive ways that perhaps they haven't in the past."
His comments follow on from that of .
Davidson said it "could be a legitimate argument by the ABC" that the public broadcaster has had to chase revenue elsewhere after it had its funding cut by government.

Related Articles

"If you look at SBS, the government gave SBS permission to take advertising - though I understand it is tightly controlled. But the moment you take advertising on a broadcast service, the advertisers are looking for value and in order to get value they need audiences so in order to sustain your advertising revenue, you need to grow your audience. Naturally I would assume the SBS wants to do that to ensure their advertising business is viable.
"It's a bit of a catch-22. If you give those organisations the opportunity to commercialise, of course they are going to do that. It is perhaps a philosophical conundrum the government needs to address."
Davidson says the AAP has itself felt the pain of the ABC shifting gears in its search for new revenue.
He explained AAP had worked for a number of years with outdoor advertising company Ooh Media, developing a software solution to provide content that could appear on Ooh Media's digital billboards within corporate offices and retail areas.
 "The ABC, I understood, offered that service to Ooh Media and my understanding is through price they won that contract. I'm not privy to the exact amount but we understand they did undercut us significantly and Ooh Media took they view if they could take that service at a cheaper rate, they would," Davidson said.
The ABC declined to comment. SBS and the Minister for Communications have been approached for comment.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ooh Media</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davidson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
