<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405957586455922</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/brisbane-council-approves-suburban-highrise-despite-noncompliance-with-plan-20170801-gxn0ln.html</url>
  <title>Council approves suburban high-rise, despite non-compliance with plan</title>
  <content>
A development that does not comply with planning requirements, but may relieve traffic congestion at one of Brisbane's most popular shopping centres, has been given the green light.
Brisbane City Council's planning committee discussed the development application for two residential towers, a commercial tenancy and an egress ramp next to Indooroopilly Shopping Centre, on Tuesday.Photo: Ruth McCosker
The council received the development application from Eureka Funds Management on May 20 last year, with one of the residential towers reaching 20 storeys on the 2427 square metre block.
The Indooroopilly Centre Neighbourhood Plan states that, for a site area less than 2500 square metres, the acceptable building height is 12 storeys.Photo: Bradley Kanaris
After the council provided feedback to the applicant on its proposal, the building height was reduced to 16 storeys, still four storeys over the acceptable building height.
Labor opposition planning spokeswoman Shayne Sutton said the extent to which people were allowed to argue for the next step of density had changed.

"This is the way planning has changed in this city from when I was first elected to now," Cr Sutton said.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"People used to have to argue really really hard to get approvals under performance outcomes and they had to really show a clear public benefitPhoto: Ruth McCosker
"To me it seems the extent of public benefit they need to prove is grossly deteriorated and the extend to which we allow those arguments...it's still 63 square metres under
"Even if you give them that 63 square metres and say, ok you can go to 15 storeys, they're actually going to 16 storeys
"It's kind of like they get the concession to go to 15 storeys and they still push it another level."
Eureka Funds Management has been approached for comment.
City Planning chairman Julian Simmonds said the applicant had been able to prove the additional height had no additional burden on existing residents or infrastructure.
Greens councillor Jonathan Sri (The Gabba) said while the acceptable outcome was 12 storeys, it seemed the development had been allowed to go higher because it included a green wall and some storeys would be used as a car park ramp.
"My concern is that we're effectively allowing them to build up to 16 storeys on a site that's clearly zoned for a maximum of 12," Cr Sri said.
"How does allowing them to build that much higher serve the public interest if all we're getting out of it is a green wall."
In the assessment report submitted by Urbis on behalf of Eureka Funds Management said the proposal would improve traffic at the shopping centre as well as providing a residential development.
"The provision of a new egress ramp for the shopping centre provides the opportunity to improve traffic circulation within and around the centre, which will provide additional benefits for centre users," the report said.
"The egress connects to the shopping centre to the west of the site and exits to Grosvenor Road. 
"The proposed residential development wraps around the northern and eastern facades of the ramp structure, as well as allowing for residential development above the egress ramp."
The application, following revisions by the developer, proposed a two-stage development with the northern tower reaching 10 storeys and the southern tower at 16 storeys.
There would be 98 units, 128 car spaces and 114 bicycle parking spaces.
The committee of six voted on the proposal with four LNP councillors in favour, Cr Sri against and Cr Sutton abstaining.
This report will be discussed again at next Tuesday's full council meeting. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Sri</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indooroopilly Centre Neighbourhood Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Planning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shayne Sutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grosvenor Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Sri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Sutton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>benefitPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Simmonds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urbis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indooroopilly Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley Kanaris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth McCosker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eureka Funds Management</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
