<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405966176390803</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/finally-how-to-use-noosas-roundabouts/3207534/</url>
  <title>Finally: How to use Noosa's roundabouts</title>
  <content>
VISITORS to Noosa either love them or hate them but there is little chance of avoiding the more than 100 roundabouts which dot the tourist destination's road network.
While how you use the things may be prescribed by law they are a constant source of confusion for some motorists who often find themselves veering off to unintended destinations.
That they give Noosa a different feel to other locations with their forests of traffic lights is without doubt.
And a new handy guide that's been introduced by Noosa Council may just make life easier for everyone.
It's new How to Use a Roundabout campaign includes a pamphlet, instructional video and information pop-ups to be held at Noosa's libraries.
 Project Officer Joanna Ferris said roundabouts were often a source of confusion for visitors not familiar with Noosa's roads, as well as newcomers to the shire.
"Even those who are comfortable using roundabouts may still benefit from brushing up on the rules," she said.
 Council staff will be on hand at Noosaville Library on Thursday, August 3, from 10am to 12noon, to show drivers the video, explain the rules and hand out copies of the brochure.
 Staff will be at Cooroy Library on Thursday, August 10, from 2pm-4pm.
"With more than 100 roundabouts across the local road network, including many multi-lane examples, roundabouts are a Noosa-specific road safety issue," Ms Ferris says.
"Drivers unfamiliar with the area can be daunted by the number of roundabouts, and cyclists can find it challenging to make their way safely through the roundabouts."
 Council has distributed How to Use a Roundabout brochures at all Council facilities, visitor information centres and caravan parks.
 Residents can view the video and download the pamphlet online at www.noosa.qld.gov.au/roundabouts.
 The initiative is funded through a Department of Transport and Main Roads Community Road Safety Grant.
Winter on hold as Coast bathes in sunshine
UPDATE: It's rare for whales to swim to where the pair was beached.
Released as part of a nation-wide campaign
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Roads Community Road Safety Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officer Joanna Ferris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooroy Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa-specific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ferris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
