<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405875982076064</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/west-beaches/dog-attacks-lead-to-a-suburban-council-to-build-a-protective-fence-at-childrens-playground/news-story/ac8c46bd4c238d111ab493eaac920c0e</url>
  <title>Fence to be installed at playground to halt dog attacks</title>
  <content>
DOG attacks near a children's playground have sparked Holdfast Bay Council to erect a protective fence at Dover Square Reserve.
Two attacks have been reported to the council in the past year, with a number of other unreported incidents also believed to have occurred at the South Brighton park.
The fence, which will separate the playground from a lawn area commonly used by dog owners, is being manufactured by the council and will soon be installed.
Holdfast Bay Mayor Stephen Patterson said the incidents and the proximity of the park to the Dover Kindergarten across the road led to the decision to install the fence.
"Two dog attacks have been reported to the council in the past 12 months in this location," he said.
"Anecdotally, we are aware that other incidents have occurred but, as these weren't reported to us at the time we have been unable to follow up.
"Our community safety officers have also increased the number of patrols in this park, and continue to promote responsible dog ownership and educate dog owners to keep their dogs under effective control."
A petition calling for the fence - signed by local residents and dog owners who use the park - was presented to the council earlier this month.
However, the 76-signature petition was not formally accepted because it was non-conforming. The petitioners' contact details were not included on each page as required under council policy.
Additionally, just 39 of the signatories lived in the Holdfast Bay district and only 13 within 500m of the reserve.
A Holdfast Bay spokeswoman said the council had already investigated installing a fence at Dover Square prior to the petition, because of the reported dog attacks.
Mayor Patterson said the council encourages residents to report any incidents as quickly as possible on 8229 9999 or to send details to mail@holdfast.sa.gov.au
Dog owners can find information, including free online 'responsible dog owner' training and details about walking dogs on and off leash at Holdfast Bay reserves and beaches, at
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dover Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dover Kindergarten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dover Square Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Patterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holdfast Bay Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holdfast Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holdfast Bay Mayor Stephen Patterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
