<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405055643310417</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/world-travel/asia/thousands-jostle-for-space-at-chinas-packed-water-parks-and-beaches/news-story/c19017e93cbeff1702f145955b74f630</url>
  <title>Thousands jostle for space at China's packed water parks and beaches</title>
  <content>
TRAVELLING IN CHINA IS WEIRD
0:49

Travelling in china is weird. From toilets that restrict how much paper you get to random street dancing, China is amazing and confusing all at once.

July 24th 2017
8 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Travel - News.com.au/

People play with inflatable rings and toys at a water park to avoid heat on July 30, 2017 in Fushun, Liaoning Province of China. Picture: VCG/VCG via Getty Images

Sam WebbThe Sun

Share

A HEATWAVE has driven Chinese tourists to seek sanctuary at a packed water park - and these extraordinary pictures show just how many people had the same idea.
Thousands of holiday-makers with rubber rings and inflatable whales packed into the pool to cool off in a heatwave, which hit 32C on Monday,  reported.
Weeks of searing heat have driven sweltering city dwellers to the coast or to water parks, some that feature wave machines.

People cool down in a pool at a water park in Fushun, Liaoning Province, as the mercury soars to 32C. Picture: VCG/VCG via Getty ImagesSource:Getty Images
Hundreds of swimmers bobbing in colourful rubber rings compete for space in chaotic scenes at a pool in Fushun, Liaoning Province.
Photos show thousands packed together, standing elbow to elbow amid a sea of people and bright-coloured inflatables.

Inflatable rings and whales are clearly all the rage in China this summer. Picture: VCG/VCG via Getty ImagesSource:Getty Images
The Sun revealed  in Qingdao where women in bizarre "facekini" costumes jostled for space in the sea.
The unusual garment - a fashion craze in recent years - is meant to protect women's faces from sunlight and jellyfish stings.

You can barely see the pool water for the people in it. Picture: VCG/VCG via Getty ImagesSource:Getty Images
The country is in the grip of a record heatwave with huge swathes of north, eastern and central China baking in temperatures in the high 30s or above.
Shanghai sweltered under a new record high of 40.9C two weeks ago, and authorities issued a weather alert.

The wave pool was one of the most popular spots. Picture: VCG/VCG via Getty ImagesSource:Getty Images
The baking temperatures come as southern China still reels from devastating floods that killed at least 50 people and forced 1.6 million to flee their homes.
This article originally appeared on  and was reproduced with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liaoning Province of China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam WebbThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHINA IS WEIRD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C. Picture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qingdao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fushun</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCG/VCG</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty ImagesSource</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liaoning Province</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
