<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405957586455952</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/dear-daniel-craig-if-playing-james-bond-is-too-hard-its-time-to-quit-20170730-gxlyoo.html</url>
  <title>Dear Daniel Craig, if playing James Bond is too hard, it's time to quit</title>
  <content>
When Daniel Craig took over as 007 in the 2006 Bond film Casino Royale, he brought some exciting new attributes to the role. First among them was his bruiser quality: he looked more likely to scramble out of a bare-knuckle boxing ring than tux up for pre-dinner cocktails.
This was a palpably different Bond from any we had seen - one with less of a debonair eyebrow game and more of an edge of menace. He meant business, and the business was mean.Photo: Supplied
Whether he still means it is a whole other question. Last week, a report from The New York Times suggested that his return for Bond 25 was a "done deal" - despite his previous much-quoted statement, since recanted, that he'd rather "slash his own wrists" than step back into the role. But would the Bond films be better off without him?
His age isn't a problem - Roger Moore was 57 when his last hurrah as Bond in A View to a Kill, with its hilarious over-reliance on stunt doubles, came out; Craig isn't even quite 50. But all the least interesting aspects of Craig's Bond have lately curdled his persona, turning him into a stiff, Madame Tussauds version of himself. It's time for a change.Photo: Supplied
For a start, he's hopeless at being funny. Say what you like about Moore, but he got on the wavelength of those cheesy wisecracks, making even the lamest ones strangely endearing. When Craig attempts one - "Got into some deep water" in Skyfall springs to mind - the level of cringe goes through the roof. He just can't do it. It's partly the writers' fault, for neither appreciating this limitation nor giving Craig better jokes to work with. But his company, like that of any prickly and humourless party guest, is becoming awfully hard work.
As for giving Bond sex appeal? Most would point to Sean Connery as the all-round winner in this area, but those famously bulging swimming trunks in Casino Royale could well bag Craig a silver medal. He had a brutish animal magnetism when he took over - so where has it gone?

Some said after Craig's casting that the attitude he gave off was a welcome throwback to the "true" Bond of Ian Fleming's vision: not a suave operator but a ruthless one, with little time for the after-hours innuendo.
Still, this down-and-dirty machismo has been a less enduring boon than we might have hoped. Contrast Timothy Dalton - the most underrated Bond - who managed to act the part better than anyone, save perhaps Connery on a good day. This will be controversial, but I don't think any of Craig's Bond pictures beats the grit and romance of The Living Daylights (1987), as technically tatty around the edges as it may look these days.Photo: Supplied
Dalton, balancing Bond's angst and professionalism with a skill we took for granted, deserved better than two Bond films - certainly in a franchise that is about to hand Craig a fifth, maybe a sixth. Alas, the paltry box office sealed Dalton's fate.
For all their pros and cons, every one of the candidates who have been dangled to succeed Craig - Tom Hardy, Tom Hiddleston, Idris Elba, Michael Fassbender -has a massive advantage over him: novelty. The formula is getting stale.
Playing Bond must be unbelievably hard work - long days, arduous location shoots, daunting pressure to live up to the brief. But it shouldn't look like such hard work, or an audience is likely to get depressed.
Craig, at this point, emits such grudging enthusiasm for the job that throwing in the towel would only be good for him - and us.
Telegraph, London
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dear Daniel Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hiddleston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Dalton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casino Royale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Bond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig's Bond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DANIEL CRAIG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Idris Elba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bond of Ian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Fassbender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fleming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Connery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madame Tussauds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bond 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Living Daylights (1987</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skyfall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
