<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405927521684449</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65446/bentley-goes-bonkers-with-special-edition-models</url>
  <title>Bentley Goes Bonkers With Special Edition Models</title>
  <content>
has been busy of late prepping a range of special edition packages for its existing range.
Over the last few weeks the British luxury carmaker's Mulliner customisation division has turned out three different different editions, each taking a unique inspiration.

The first out the door is Flying Spur Design Series with a run of 100 units of the sedan available across the V8, W12, V8 S, and W12 S model lines.
Described as a more extreme interpretation of Bentley's sedan, the Design Series claims to draw inspiration from details like "the flash of colour on a suit lining, or the vibrant stitching on a leather saddle."

That translates to an interior and exterior treatment highlighted by one of five accent colour splits: Pillar Box Red, Mandarin, Azure Purple, White, or Kingfisher used on the lower fineline (the trim in the lower bumper and lower doors) outside and through the door uppers and top roll of the dash, creating a three-tone interior.
The Design Series also incorporates quilted seat bolsters and door inserts, a 12 o'clock marker for the steering wheel, and a piano black centre console.
If the Flying Spur Design Series is too brash, perhaps the Continental GT Galene Edition is more to your taste? The ultimate edition of the Continental GT convertible takes its direction from the world of luxury yachts.

Rarer than the Design Series, with just a production run limited to 30 vehicles, the Galene is named in honour of the Greek goddess of calm seas.
This time Mulliner worked with British yacht experts, Princess Yachts, to create a design theme with a nautical slant, including Glacier White paint, Sequin Blue lower brightwork in place of traditional chrome matched to 21-inch 'Propeller' polished alloy wheels and a dark blue fabric roof.

Inside, the Continental GT Galene Edition continues the high-end yachting theme with an interior crafted from Linen, Portland, and Camel coloured hides creating a colour palette that would look right at home against the coastline of Santorini.
The highlight though has to be a new open pore Pinstripe Walnut timber veneer that adorns the centre dash facia and boot floor, along with the Glacier White dash plates that can be adorned with a hand painted superyacht image by Spanish artist Jaume Vilardell.

Power for the Continental GT Galene is provided by the Continental's 373kW/660Nm 4.0-litre twin turbo V8.
If you'd rather indulge your dark side, Bentley also has the Flying Spur V8 S Black Edition, which brings a swathe of more sinister details to the already sport-skewed sedan.
The Black Edition retains the regular  running gear including a 388kW/680Nm 4.0-litre twin turbo V8 and rear-biased all wheel drive system.

From the outside, the Black edition (rather sensibly) adds a roll call of black details including darkened headlamp housings, gloss black on the grille door handles, windscreen washer caps, and window surrounds, and 21-inch 'Elegant' black alloy wheels with either black or red brake calipers.
On the inside, the Black edition features a single tone interior with a bold contrasting stripe set through the seats and headlining roof bow, while piano black veneer continues the black theme and a three-spoke Sport Plus steering wheel comes accented with contrasting stitching to match the seat panels.

Upgrade to the  and the Flying Spur V8 S Black Edition adds diamond quilted leather for the doors and seats framed with contrasting stitching, plus a choice of 21-inch five spoke wheels finished in gloss black or dark chrome.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sport Plus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glacier White</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Continental GT Galene Edition</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingfisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Azure Purple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Continental GT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W12 S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V8 S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V8</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentley Goes Bonkers With Special Edition Models</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W. 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flying Spur Design Series</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flying Spur V8 S Black Edition</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulliner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Edition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santorini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pillar Box Red</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Continental GT Galene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Design Series</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Yachts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaume Vilardell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pinstripe Walnut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandarin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sequin Blue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
