<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405742838087756</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/basketball/joe-ingles-says-nba-teams-set-to-throw-full-arsenal-at-nbl-opponents-during-october-us-visit/news-story/ee5509d406783658ebb30a8cd9be50d0</url>
  <title>'For us, it's a serious game': Ingles</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN basketball star Joe Ingles says the NBL teams slated for historic NBA pre-season games in October will not be taken lightly.
Sydney Kings will open the bold venture against Utah Jazz, featuring Ingles and Dante Exum, on October 3, with Melbourne United taking on Oklahoma City Thunder (October 9) and Brisbane Bullets playing Phoenix Suns (October 14).
THUNDER UP:
The NBA has shortened its pre-season, limiting franchises to about 5-7 turn-up games before the regular season begins on October 17.
"I know our coach (Quin Snyder) will be prepping (us) knowing how hard those (Kings) guys will come in, and again, for us it's a serious game," Ingles said.
"Our preseason is cut in half, I think we play four or five games instead of nine or ten, so we got to take it as serious as we will game 82 as will these guys as it's a part of their preparation as well.
"It won't be taken lightly if anyone knows our coach it definitely won't be taken lightly so it will be a great experience for those guys that are playing, for the NBL, obviously being a part of it but for the fans."
NBL bosses have spent several years brokering the historic deal, which the league hopes will be the launching pad for future fixtures and, ultimately, an NBA game on Australian soil.
NBL owner Larry Kestelman welcomed the opportunity to showcase Australian talent in the US.
"For the NBL to be able to play some of the biggest teams in the world shows how far our league has come," Kestelman said.
"For our teams to be chosen to come and play in the NBA preseason is a great endorsement of the NBL and Australian basketball."
Melbourne United star Chris Goulding said his side would be in it to win it.
"It's really exciting, we've got nothing to lose, we're going to go over there and try and shock a few people," Goulding said.
"We're not going over the to try and lose - we're going over there to try and win and I think that's a really fun prospect to be a part of.
"The whole group will be super excited. They know what a fantastic opportunity this is and we can't wait, we want it to be October already."
Goulding had an idea for how United would cope with NBA MVP Russell Westbrook, who broke the single-season record fro triple doubles last season.
"It's a great test, obviously we are piecing together our team at Melbourne as we speak (and) I think we'll be looking for a 6'6" athletic point guard to combat Westbrook," he said.

NBL: Utah Jazz star Joe Ingles says he is excited to be playing against NBL opposition.

Ingles excited by 'huge' news
Ingles, who won an NBL title with the now defunct South Dragons in 2009, says he hopes to one day finish his career back in Australia.
"I've always said I would love to," he said.
"Starting in the NBL at 17 and playing three years... (it was my) first professional experience.
"I'd love to be able to finish here one day. I might be a bit older and slower."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dante Exum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Goulding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA MVP Russell Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma City Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quin Snyder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulding</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THUNDER UP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
