<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405661233708037</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/rendezview/fashion-needs-to-find-a-happy-medium-for-body-shape/news-story/772df2a08d8aa4964c196b310531d447</url>
  <title>Fashion needs to find a happy medium</title>
  <content>
I'VE got a message to people who agree with Sports Illustrated's : It's irresponsible.
Before you call me out for "fat shaming", I am not at all suggesting that to be a model you can only be a size 6 to 8. The Sports Illustrated parade included some beautiful size 12 to 18 models demonstrating that every woman, regardless of shape, deserves lovely swimwear.
But it seems to me the women who appeared to be approaching the sizes 20-26 on the catwalk are less representative of the average woman but are representative of a big underlying societal problem.
My argument here cuts both ways. If the fashion industry decides to stop using models who appear to have starved themselves to skin and bones - as they should - they shouldn't then choose to promote an equally unhealthy body shape.
According to figures collected from the Australian Bureau of Statistics, the average woman weighs 71.1kg and is 161.8cm tall.
This is a far cry from representation of women on the Sports Illustrated catwalk, which caught the attention of various media outlets including breakfast show Sunrise this morning.
Editor of Sports Illustrated's swimsuit issue MJ Day spoke out on national TV today about the move - much to the applause of hosts Samantha Armytage and stand-in Matt Doran.
"We've made a very positive statement that beauty is not one size fits all and now we're carrying through with that in our new line," Ms Day said on air.
"It's just further confirmation that this is what people want to see and this is what we should be doing.
"This is what our responsibility should be, you know, as people in the media we shouldn't create this little box in what's acceptable and what's considered beautiful.
"As a woman, yes I hope this continues."
Ms Armytage congratulated Ms Day for including "real women" on the runway.
"Watching those women's faces, the models, they're so happy and so proud good on you," she said.

Statistics show that in 1995 the number of obese people was 56.3 per cent. Fast forward to 2015 and that number has changed dramatically.
A staggering 63.4 per cent of Australians are now overweight or obese.
We've worked our society up to have heightened sense of sensitivity around overweight issues where the word "fat" is now frowned upon.
In turn it has created a taboo "look away" culture in fear of offending someone - even if the intention is to urge them to seek help.
I'm guilty of turning a blind eye when a friends says, "I'm so fat". I just stand there denying that they are but maybe a bit of truth can lead some people on the right track of weight loss. Too many people are risking their lives with weight-related problems.
Parading and glorifying size 20-somethings on any runway promotes an underlying and irresponsible message that doing nothing about your weight is OK.
But if you believe everyone deserves the best possible chance at a long and healthy life surely it's not OK.
Obesity increases your chance of heart disease and stroke, diabetes and high blood pressure, to name just a few. People classified as obese live an average of eight years less than those who are not.
It is absolutely right that we have developed as a society to the point where we recognise that bullying and joking about people who struggle with their weight is not OK.
People who want to make a change in their lives to lose weight deserve all the support we can give them.
But putting very overweight people on the catwalk feels more like giving in - the message seems to be, don't bother to strive to lose weight and improve your health and wellbeing.
Soraiya Fuda is the Sydney Confidential homepage editor.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports Illustrated</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Doran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MJ Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Armytage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Armytage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Confidential</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Day</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soraiya Fuda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
