<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405914636782272</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/jail-for-woman-who-swore-and-threw-water-in-court/8763930</url>
  <title>Woman jailed for hurling water, swearing at Canberra magistrate in court outburst</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A woman who swore and hurled a plastic cup of water at a Canberra magistrate has been jailed for contempt of court.
Tracey Organ, 38, became angry during a court appearance last month, lashing out when she was refused bail on drug charges.
She shouted "f*** you" and threw the cup at Magistrate Peter Morrison as she was dragged out of the court.
Three people in the public gallery were also advised to leave when they too began shouting at the magistrate.
After Organ left the courtroom Mr Morrison quipped: "That is why we replaced the glasses on the bar table with plastic cups."
Today, Organ pleaded guilty to a contempt of court charge and apologised for her actions in a letter.
Mr Morrison said the incident had created something of a spectacle in the court.
But he told Organ: "I accept your conduct was spur of the moment and not premeditated."
He said he accepted the letter of apology and that Organ had been angry with police, the court and herself, and was concerned about her children.
Organ is currently behind bars on remand for other charges.
Today's sentence of 21 days in jail means she will have to serve the time as a regular prisoner, and will not be eligible for any further bail applications until that expires.
Organ also pleaded guilty to a cannabis possession charge and fined $75.
But Organ said she would fight two other drug-related charges.
A hearing has been set down for October.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Peter Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey Organ, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrison</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
