<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405961881423400</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/vic-opposition-to-target-fuel-drive-offs/news-story/c4eba96b15aba57d92a0b90282afc5ec</url>
  <title>Vic opposition to target fuel drive offs</title>
  <content>
People who refuel and drive off without paying in Victoria will be the focus of a crackdown by a possible future Liberal state government.
Opposition Leader Matthew Guy said, if elected, his government would legislate petrol "drive offs" as a stand alone criminal offence, rather than a simple theft.
"A crime is a crime and petrol station theft, fuel theft, is becoming an enormous crime; more than 20 million dollars worth to the industry here in Victoria," Mr Guy told reporters.
A "clearing house" for stolen number plates between Victoria Police and VicRoads would see petrol stations able to identify offending cars quickly, he said.
Fuel theft has not been classed as a separate crime in Victoria since 2013 after recommendations from the police commissioner at the time, Mr Guy says.
Instead, an industry led approach was preferred which included the introduction of pre-paid petrol bowsers and more CCTV cameras.
Penalties for petrol drive offs would be classed as a theft under the Crimes Act and would be determined by the courts, opposition police spokesman Edward O'Donohue said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Guy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward O'Donohue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crimes Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Matthew Guy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
