<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405914636782296</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/thai-activist-abducted-in-laos-as-tensions-rise-in-thailand-20170801-gxn171.html</url>
  <title>Thai activist abducted in Laos as tensions rise in Thailand</title>
  <content>
Bangkok: A Thai activist has been abducted by armed men in Laos where he operated a community radio network affiliated with Thailand's opposition "red shirt" movement.
Witnesses said Wuthipong Kachathamakul, also known as Ko Tee, and his wife and a friend were confronted at his house in Vientiane by ten men wearing black hoods, hit with stun guns and had their wrists tied with plastic handcuffs and their mouths gagged.Photo: AP
Mr Wuthipong was then driven away in a vehicle and has not been since the incident on July 29.
His wife and the friend, who were left at the house, said the men were speaking Thai.

Thailand's military government has declined to confirm that Mr Wuthipong is being held in Laos where another exiled Thai activist disappeared in June 2016.
Thai authorities have accused Mr Wuthipong of using his radio program to stoke dissent in Thailand.   He has also been named as a suspect in a lese majeste case.

Thai generals toppled a democratically elected government in a 2014 coup, after months of political upheaval in Bangkok.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Brad Adams, Asia director at Human Rights Watch, described the apparent kidnapping as a "shocking abduction" and called for an investigation.Photo: AP
"It should not be treated with silence and swept under the rug," he said, adding the Lao government has a responsibility to find out what happened and identify those responsible. 
Human rights groups say Laos has failed to make progress on at least ten cases of suspected forced disappearances, including prominent Lao civil society activist Sombath Somphone, who was grabbed at a police check-point in Vientiane in December 2012.
Political tensions are rising again in Thailand ahead of a verdict on August 25 in the trial of former prime minister Yingluck Shinawatra on charges relating to a failed government rice subsidy scheme. She faces a possible 10-year jail sentence if convicted.
More than 1000 supporters ignored requests by Thai authorities to stay away from Ms Yingluck's trial as she gave her closing statement on Tuesday.
Thailand's government has moved quickly to crush any sign of dissent since taking office and has yet to name a date for long-promised elections to allow a return to democracy.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laos</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lao</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thai</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yingluck Shinawatra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ko Tee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wuthipong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Watch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sombath Somphone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangkok</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vientiane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wuthipong Kachathamakul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Yingluck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
