<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405875982076040</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/superracing-catches-up-with-former-melbourne-cup-winner-subzero-on-his-29th-birthday/news-story/ec6e835dda2229ef5608cebf4689399d</url>
  <title>Q+A: We catch up with Subzero</title>
  <content>
AUGUST 1 marks the horse's birthday, and with the countdown on to the Melbourne Spring Carnival, we caught up with 29-year-old Subzero to see what life's like for the former Melbourne Cup winner.
SuperRacing: Subbie thanks for joining us, and happy 29th birthday.
Subzero: No problems. Did you say happy birthday?
SuperRacing: Yes, it's your birthday today. 29.
Subzero: My goodness, I had no idea. And that is such a coincidence! I know a few other horses whose birthday is today as well.
SuperRacing: ... right. OK. Well, 29 today, and almost 25 years since you won the Melbourne Cup. Does it seem like yesterday?
Subzero: Seriously, I know like, at least 10 other horses whose birthday is today. That's uncanny.
SuperRacing: Yep. Now, your Cup win ...
Subzero: Oh yeah, what a day. Unbelievable. Highlight of my career. Can still remember it so vividly. The noise of the crowd, the thrill of crossing the line, that bloke sitting on my back whacking me with a whip.
SuperRacing: Talk us through the win.
Subzero: I was confident going in. It had rained a lot of the day and the going was a bit rough. 'Group 1' Glen Hall was saying as we went out that we'd be right in the finish.
SuperRacing: Greg Hall.
Subzero: Greg, is it? I always called him Glen. Anyway he was confident heading into the race. Lee (Freedman) had me trained to the minute, and then the conditions really fell my way.
SuperRacing: When did you know you had it?
Subzero: Probably about the 300m mark. Sir Winston had got out to a couple of lengths but I was really warmed up after running almost three ks. Once I saw the finish I just went for it. Ranged up to Sir Winston and went for home. I think Glen might've thought we went for home a bit too soon but I was always confident.
SuperRacing: It was a magnificent win.
Subzero: It was.

SuperRacing: And there were some quality horses in that Cup. Better Loosen Up and Super Impose to name a couple.
Subzero: Yeah, both gone now sadly, but a couple of greats there.
SuperRacing: Yes, terribly sad. Does the fact a lot of those horses have now left us make you think about your own mortality?
Subzero: Oh maybe a bit. But I'm still loving life.
SuperRacing: How do you spend your days?
Subzero: Oh I'm terribly busy, especially over the next couple of months when racing really cranks up here in Melbourne. As you may know I'm still with Graham (Salisbury) and have done quite a bit of work as a clerk of the course at Flemington. I do a few visits with the Cup to schools. I love working with kids. Even today Graham has me off at some gala event in Geelong.
SuperRacing: Yes, your work after racing has been quite extraordinary. You've raised millions for charity, met all kinds of celebrities from PMs to Kylie Minogue. You have your own . Heck, you . More than most of us achieve.
Subzero: Yes, good memories. That Kylie's a sweet kid. Would make a bloody good PM, actually. You know people often ask me what I'm more proud of - winning the Cup or my work after racing.
SuperRacing: And what do you say?
Subzero: Winning the Cup, of course. I'm not an idiot. The adulation I received - and still receive - for that was something else. I still like to put the old video in the player and watch a replay from time to time.
SuperRacing: Understandable. Well it's been terrific to catch up. On behalf of the kids you've met and inspired to take an interest in racing, and all the racing fans out there, thank you.
Subzero: Thanks for taking an interest in an old fella.
SuperRacing: Enjoy the rest of your birthday and we'll catch you over the Spring.
Subzero: Birthday? Huh?
* Subzero may not have actually spoken to Superracing for this interview.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Minogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glen Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salisbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GLEN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loosen Up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Impose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Winston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Spring Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuperRacing</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
