<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405966176390746</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/politics/state-government-kicks-in-186m-for-cooee-to-wynyard-cycleway/news-story/cb858d7807aea775a11fb1a0eb2fa52e</url>
  <title>Coast within Cooee of new cycling route</title>
  <content>
TASMANIA'S booming bike tourism industry has received another leg up, with a disused rail corridor to spring back to life as another link in a $25 million, 110km coastal cycleway from Port Sorell and Wynyard.
The State Government today committed $1.86 million to fund the Cooee to Wynyard link of the cycleway.
The Burnie and Waratah-Wynyard councils have funded the rest of the $3.7 million section, which will follow the coast past fairy penguin colonies and offer views of Table Cape and, in the not-too-distant future, its luxury resort.
Almost 40,000 tourists to Tasmania already enjoy cycling while visiting and the new link will provide them with stunning coastal scenery on a safe path.
Cycling advocate Keith Price expects hundreds of locals to also use the link to get to work, school or just for pleasure.
When the route is fully realised, the Government says it will inject $17.6 million into the region's economy and help support 100 full-time jobs by capitalising on Tasmania's booming cycle tourism industry.

"There is no better place to get off the beaten track and onto a bike than along what is one of the most majestic coastlines in the world," Premier Will Hodgman said on a visit to the site.
"This is just one part of an infrastructure project that will deliver great benefits."
Braddon MHA Roger Jaensch said the flat coastal cycleway would allow students from outlying areas to be able to ride bikes into the new UTAS campus at West Park.
It also being billed as a drawcard for cruise ship passengers, with Burnie welcoming 33 ships last season.
Waratah-Wynyard Mayor Robbie Walsh said the bicycle connection would lead to bigger and better things as his municipality looked forward to the development of the $90 million Table Cape resort overlooking Bass Strait.

Burnie Mayor Anita Dow said the cycleway was a sign of the future as her council and its neighbour collaborated for the first time to get tourism infrastructure in place.
"The council have been lobbying the State Government for many years regarding this section," she said.
"While some headway had been made in relation to access to the rail corridor, the funding news is what we have been waiting for."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Table Cape</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bass Strait</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratah-Wynyard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnie Mayor Anita Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Sorell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wynyard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braddon MHA Roger Jaensch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Will Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratah-Wynyard Mayor Robbie Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
