<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405923226717044</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/surf-lifesaving-athlete-of-year-labelled-a-potenti/3207527/</url>
  <title>Surf lifesaving athlete of year labelled a potential Olympian</title>
  <content>
SURF LIFESAVING: Newly-crowned Sunshine Coast surf lifesaving athlete-of-the-year Nick Sloman has the potential to be an Olympian, says his club's president Craig Law.
The 19-year-old claimed the region's annual award at Maroochydore on Saturday after a sterling season, which included a brace of victories at the Australian championships on the Gold Coast in April.
The Sunshine Beach competitor triumphed in the elite male open swim and in the under-19 surf race.
He was also in the winning Queensland team at the inter-state championships and also won national pool rescue medals.
"Nick is probably the most successful athlete we've had come through our club over the years," Law said.
"He's not a big fellow in stature but he's got a massive ticker. He's very focused on what he does."
While he's strong on the board, it's Sloman's swimming prowess which is particularly impressive.
He looms as a threat for the national open men's surf title at next year's Aussies and Law - who is also a regional representative team manager - said the young gun could become a force on the open water swimming scene.
He believed Sloman could potentially forge his way to the Tokyo 2020 Olympics.
"With his talent and with his focus and with the ticker he's got, he's the kind of kid who could reach those levels if he puts his mind to it," he said. "I think he's got the world at his feet and has that ability to reach those heights."
Sunshine Beach's Abbie Tolano was recognised as junior athlete of the season after winning the inter-state under-13 ironwoman crown while Maroochydore's Tiarnee Massie was adjudged the youth athlete of the year after winning the state under-17 ironwoman and surf events. She also won national relay titles, before a cancellation of The Aussies due to poor water quality.
Alexandra Headland's Lani Pallister missed out on an athlete of the year gong despite winning the Australian under-15 ironwoman and surf events.
Winter on hold as Coast bathes in sunshine
UPDATE: It's rare for whales to swim to where the pair was beached.
Released as part of a nation-wide campaign
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Sloman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Beach's Abbie Tolano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newly-crowned Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore's Tiarnee Massie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland's Lani Pallister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SURF LIFESAVING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sloman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo 2020 Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
