<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405875982076049</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4825654/how-uow-measures-up-on-sexual-assault-and-harassment/?cs=12</url>
  <title>How UOW measures up on sexual assault and harassment</title>
  <content>
The Australian Human Rights Commission has released a national report into the prevalence of sexual assault and sexual harassment at Australian universities. Picture: Adam McLean

One in 11 female University of Wollongong students surveyed say they were sexually assaulted in the past two years, while just under half of all students were sexually harassed at some point in 2016.
These are some of the damning findings of a new Australian Human Rights Commission report, released Tuesday, which surveyed 31,000 students from all Australian universities.

The commission said its findings show sexual assault and harassment were "far too prevalent", and also noted there was significant under reporting of these incidents to universities. 
UOW's results, released by the university, are on par with the national reporting, which found more than a fifth of Australian students (21 per cent) were harassed on campus, and 1.6 in every 100 university students experienced sexual assault while at university in 2016.
According to the data released, 740 UOW students were surveyed for the commission's report.
Of those sexually harassed at university, the most common types of incidents included leering, intrusive questions about private lives or physical appearance, sexually suggestive comments and unwelcome touching.
This was most likely to occur on public transport travelling to the university, on the university grounds, and at social spaces on campus like bars.
Four per cent (higher than the national three per cent) of the sexual harassment incidences occurred at university accommodation, and another four per cent occurred during university work placements.
Also higher than the average: one third of UOW students said they witnessed sexual harassment at the university (compared to one quarter nationwide).
As across the nation, women attending UOW experienced sexual harassment and sexual assault at disproportionately higher rates than men.
Nearly twice as many women (63 per cent) than men (32 per cent) were sexually harassed in 2016.

Most shockingly, female students were ten times more likely to have been sexually assaulted in the past two years: 9.2 per cent of UOW women were sexually assaulted compared to 0.9 per cent of men.

For 2.3 per cent of women surveyed, sexual assault occurred while they were somewhere on campus.

Conversely, men were overwhelmingly the perpetrators. The results released by UOW indicate men were the perpetrators of harassment against women 89 per cent of the time and overall, men were involved in 83 per cent of the cases.
Those surveyed said 67 per cent of harassment perpetrators were other UOW students and six per cent were UOW tutors or lecturers. The university did not release data on the perpetrators of sexual assault.
Despite the prevalence of harassment and assault, more than 60 per cent of students has little or no knowledge about where they could go to make a complaint.
Seven per cent of those who were harassed made a formal complaint.
Definitions:

Sexual harassment can take many forms, both physical and non-physical. Sexual harassment may include:

staring or leering 
unnecessary familiarity, such as deliberately brushing up against you or unwelcome touching 
suggestive comments or jokes
insults or taunts of a sexual nature
intrusive questions or statements about someone's private life
displaying posters, magazines or screen savers of a sexual nature 
sending sexually explicit emails or text messages 
inappropriate advances on social networking sites
accessing sexually explicit internet sites
requests for sex or repeated unwanted requests to go out on dates, and
behaviour that may also be considered to be an offence under criminal law, such as physical assault, indecent exposure, sexual assault, stalking or obscene communications.
Sexual assault
In the community, the terms 'sexual assault', 'sexual abuse' and 'rape' are often used interchangeably.

The NSW Department of Justice has defined the following terms commonly used to describe sexual assault in the community:

'Rape is a term used in the community which describes the forced penetration of the vagina or anus of any person with any part of the body of another person, or any object, against their will or consent. It also includes oral sex'.
'Indecent assault is unwanted touching of a person's body by another person. For example it can include kissing or inappropriate touching of a person's breasts, bottom or genitals'.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
