<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405120067821213</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:24</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/5-things-you-need-to-know-in-australian-tech-today-2017-8</url>
  <title>5 things you need to know in Australian tech today</title>
  <content>
Welcome to Tuesday:

1. The government has ordered ACMA to find out who's actually responsible for all the NBN complaints. With complaints rising about underperformance and disconnections, the ACMA will use its statutory powers to grill 21 industry players - from wholesaler NBN down to retailers that are actually selling broadband to Australians.

2. A Melbourne startup is putting people onto private jets for cheap. Airly has started a service where people can take a ride on jets that would otherwise be empty because they're flying somewhere for a traditional charter booking. Read .

3. A former Australian lawyer is now a tech entrepreneur that just raised $9 million. Ryan Kroonenburg didn't know anything about tech 7 years ago when the GFC hit - and after an attempted career change, and getting rejected for a job by Amazon, he hit on an idea that led to establishing A Cloud Guru with his brother Sam. Read

4. Perth Internet of Things startup Spectur has floated on the ASX after raising $4.5 million in an IPO. The company, which already has customers like Rio Tinto and Lend Lease, will use the cash to expand into Melbourne and Sydney, and potentially overseas. Read

5. Alibaba is coming for Australian startups. A local heat of the global  Cloud startup competition will be held at Haymarket HQ in Sydney next month, with the winner getting $50,000 of cloud computing credits and a trip to Shanghai for the finals.

Have a great day! Please  your story tips or .

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACMA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Kroonenburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alibaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Internet of Things</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lend Lease</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloud Guru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spectur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haymarket HQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
