<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406004831097084</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/15/45/queensland-students-bringing-guns-knives-and-tasers-into-schools</url>
  <title>Queensland  students bringing guns, knives and tasers into schools</title>
  <content>
Queensland students are bringing guns, knives, machetes and tasers to school each month, new police data has revealed.
According to the information released under Right to Information laws and published in the Courier Mail, students are being charged with weapon offences at an "alarming rate", with more than five incidents occurring every month.
In one incident, a student was holed up with a knife in a classroom and threatened to stab everyone.
In another, a student was reported to have a handgun in his bag.
The report also revealed a student brought a nunchaku to school for show and tell.
Police have not named the schools where the students were charged.
"School and homes should be the safest places possible," Parents and Citizens Queensland chief executive Kevan Goodworth said.

Related Articles

"There must be zero tolerance towards this sort of behaviour. When parents send their children to school they need to know that they're going to be safe."
Last year, a north Brisbane school student stabbed a classmate with scissors and in 2015 a 12-year-old girl slashed a student at a north Brisbane school.
In that year, there were three stabbings by children on the Gold Coast.
"Last year we introduced behaviour coaches into every region supporting behaviour management in every school," Education Minister Kate Jones said.
"Since we were elected we have seen a 20 percent reduction in the number of students bringing weapons to schools."
The Education Department has maintained Queensland schools are safe places.
"In 2016, there were fewer incidents classified as involving a 'weapon' in Queensland StateSchools that resulted in a School Disciplinary Absence than in 2015," a statement read.
President of the Teachers' Union, Kevin Bates, said the mental health of students was a growing issue in Queensland schools, but did not believe teachers felt unsafe at work.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>School Disciplinary Absence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevan Goodworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the Teachers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Kate Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Bates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland StateSchools</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citizens Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
