<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405914636782310</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/curious-sea-lion-hits-the-streets-in-south-australian-coastal-town-of-port-macdonnell/news-story/cc4ce4d8ff4d033e254ee585c6a2d164</url>
  <title>Curious sea lion hits the streets of Port MacDonnell</title>
  <content>
A WAYWARD sea lion caused a kerfuffle in a South East coastal town this morning after the confused animal found itself at a resident's doorstep.
The sea lion had managed overnight to make its way from the beach at Port MacDonnell into the small town of 600 residents, settling in the driveway of Kirby Carrison's house.
Mrs Carrison said their dogs alerted them to their uninvited house guest at 10pm last night, much to their surprise.
"My husband went to check what was going on and he came back saying 'bring your camera you're not going to believe this'," Mrs Carrison said.
"I heard this noise in the driveway and there was a massive sea lion, we were in shock, we just couldn't believe it."
Mrs Carrison said a council worker came this morning to help navigate the animal back to the water, but by then word had got out.
"Port MacDonnell is a small town so word got around pretty quickly and a lot of people came to have a look.
"It's certainly got the town talking and it was a bit of excitement for a Tuesday morning."
Periwinkles Cafe owner Paul Mullen said about 40 people congregated on the street to watch the animal being coached back into the water.
"I think the dog catcher was called to entice him back to the water," Mr Mullen said.
"He was given a nice little prod and the sea lion reacted by coming after him, which worked.
"It probably took about 1.5 hours to get him back in the sea, because they had to stop a few times to let him catch his break."
Mr Mullen believed the rare occurrence may have been the result of a whale washing up on the foreshore last month.
"I don't know whether the sea lion might of got scared because there's been a few sharks around, so it came into shore," he said.
"It seems to be happy it was back in the water though."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port MacDonnell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mullen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Mullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Carrison</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirby Carrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
