<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406000536129689</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/food/drink/daily-juice-company-starts-using-imported-oranges-due-to-shortage-caused-by-chinese-export-demand/news-story/ec76dccbefb618d73a0105ec1c61b15c</url>
  <title>Daily Juice Company starts using imported oranges due to shortage caused by Chinese export demand</title>
  <content>
Daily Juice Company has started using imported oranges in its juice, due to a shortage caused by a thriving export market.

Share

AUSTRALIAN juice companies are being forced to use imported oranges in their products due to a shortage caused by a huge demand for our oranges in China.
The Daily Juice Company has changed the labels on its 2L and 300mL bottles of orange juice, informing customers of the change.
"Due to a national shortage, our orange juice is currently 100 per cent imported yet still 100 per cent tasty," the label says.

"Due to a seasonal shortage, our orange juice is currently 100 per cent imported," the label reads.Source:Facebook
A spokeswoman for Lion, which owns the Daily Juice Company, said the shortage should only last for a few more weeks.
"There is currently a national shortage of oranges for juicing in Australia and as a result we have moved to using 100 per cent imported juice to ensure we can continue to manufacture Daily Juice and have it available for consumers on the shelves," the spokeswoman said.
"This includes a majority of imported orange juice from Spain, which is known for its high quality juicing oranges," she said.
"We expect to use large volumes of imported orange juice until around mid-August. This is a short-term solution until the new local navel season is available."

Picture: Daily Juice CompanySource:News Limited
China is one of Australia's biggest export destin-ations. This year, 40,000 tonnes of -oranges worth $70 million, about one-quarter of all orange -exports, will be shipped to China, according to .
China's growing middle class love Australian products - they've already caused infant milk formula and beef shortages - and now that's spread to fresh fruit.

Citrus Australia chief executive Judith Damieni that Australia won't need to start importing oranges from overseas.
Ms Damieni said the current shortage was partly fuelled by the record 2016 citrus export season, which saw demand from overseas markets absorb the vast majority of Valencia supplies before Christmas.
Normally, Valencias are in plentiful supply for Australian juice companies until at least March.
"It will impact the availability or pricing of fresh Australian juice," Ms Damieni said.
"Until the next wave of crop comes in, in June, it may impact on the supply of that product.
"I don't think we'll see empty shelves, because there will always be a supply, but it will just depend on the demand.
"But with this summer having been warmer for longer, that demand has gone up."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ML</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Damieni</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Juice CompanySource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Juice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Juice Company</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valencia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judith Damieni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
