<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405970471358149</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/joe-ingles-urges-nbl-players-to-seize-the-opportunity-against-nba-teams/news-story/3e491807bd2c9c4a19405ac06e513aef</url>
  <title>Ingles: This could make careers</title>
  <content>
ON Tuesday, Joe Ingles was overlooking Sydney Harbour, in town as an ambassador for the NBA.
Australia's NBL had just agreed to , with the opening fixture a matchup between the Sydney Kings and Ingles' Utah Jazz.
It was a stunning announcement for a league that has made tremendous strides since Ingles was in his first year in the NBL; winning the 2007 Rookie of the Year award.
Ten years on, and even he can't believe the beautiful circularity his career has been guided through.
"No," Ingles told foxsports.com.au, bluntly, when asked if he could've imagine he'd be the face of the NBA during the NBL's landmark announcement.

NBL: Utah Jazz star Joe Ingles says he is excited to be playing against NBL opposition.

Ingles excited by 'huge' news
The 29-year-old was in his typical playful spirits, cracking jokes throughout the day, and even throwing two basketballs into the harbour. It seemed like Ingles had an implicit goal to brand the event as a fun, somewhat happy-go-lucky affair; and hopes that can carry over to the games, themselves.
"It's just such an exciting day for everybody involved," Ingles said.
"The teams, obviously our team, Larry (Kestelman), and what his team's done to get this alive and happening. But, mostly, for fans, kids, grandparents, that have followed NBL teams.
"Brisbane fans that have followed the Brisbane Bullets since they won it, and now to be able to watch their favourite NBL players play against Westbrook and Bledsoe and Joe Ingles.
"It's just an awesome day."
The excitement of the day, and adrenaline from the announcement, will almost undoubtedly be outmatched by the October fixtures, which have been in the works - vigorously - since Kestelman became a part of the league in 2012.
The announcement of the pre-season games was the first major step of Kestelman's masterplan to bring basketball to the forefront of Australian sports, and one word that was prevalent throughout the day was 'opportunity'.
The NBL has the opportunity to grow its brand; the stock of Australian basketball would inherently rise with that. The NBA has the opportunity to interact with, and expand, its already-booming Australian market. Fans have the opportunity to see their favourite NBL team go up against teas in the best league in the world.
Ingles, on the other hand, thought of the players, and how they could potentially follow in his footsteps.
"I wish I had gotten the opportunity when I was playing in the NBL, to do this as an 18-year-old," he said.
"These guys have got a huge opportunity to play this game, and you just never know what a good game for them can do. If (Chris) Goulding goes out and has 30 (points), you don't know what that could mean for his career.

NBL: League Owner Larry Kestelman has announced three matches for Sydney, Melbourne and Brisbane to be played against NBA teams.

NBL goes global
"So, it's really exciting, and I'm proud to be an ambassador or face of this event. Hopefully it keeps growing. Hopefully we can get every NBL team to get an chance to play in this event over the next few years. it would just be huge."
Ingles began his career in the NBL, before playing in Europe and Israel, which led to his first shot at the NBA in 2014. The Adelaide-native just signed a four-year, $52 million deal with the Jazz, with his unique success story seemingly just getting started.
Part of the NBL's growth strategy is to brand itself as a legitimate pathway toward the NBA, and it's consistently pointing to the likes of Terrance Ferguson - the former Adelaide 36er, and 21st pick in the 2017 NBA Draft - and Torrey Craig, the former Brisbane Bullet who just signed a two-way deal with the Denver Nuggets.
It's a trend that every player currently signed in the NBL hopes to be a part of, and these NBA pre-season games are an important step in that direction.
However, despite the recent NBA success of a small handful of NBL athletes, the true model of the NBL-to-NBA pathway was in Sydney on Tuesday; with a big smile on his face, throwing balls into the harbour.
Olgun Uluc covers basketball for Fox Sports Australia. Twitter:

Basketball: The NBL is set to announce exhibition games for the Sydney Kings and Brisbane Bullets to be played against the Utah Jazz and Oklahoma City.

NBL set for NBA action
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's NBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide-native</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rookie of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrey Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL-to-NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olgun Uluc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles' Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OKLAHOMA CITY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledsoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrance Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide 36</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kestelman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League Owner Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver Nuggets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
