<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405059938277987</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/this-diy-recipe-for-that-mcdonalds-szechuan-sauce-from-rick-and-morty-is-pretty-damn-good/</url>
  <title>This DIY Recipe For That McDonald's Szechuan Sauce From 'Rick And Morty' Is Pretty Damn Good</title>
  <content>
Rick and Morty  and, thanks to the teaser premier that aired back in April, so is an incredible amount of enthusiasm for "Szechuan Sauce", a limited edition nugget sauce that was released by McDonald's to help promote the 1998 Disney film Mulan.

Photos by Claire Lower.

Sadly, according to the McDonald's Twitter account, the last three remaining gallons of the stuff have been given away.

Congrats to ,  &  who are lucky enough to get the last of our  left in the universe!
- McDonald's (@McDonalds)

That's OK though, because  - well, near copycat - recipe with his father many moons ago, and it's good. Here's the full recipe in all of its (unedited) glory.

Mince 6 cloves of Garlic and sweat (heat them up in a skillet)

add 4 tablespoons Balsamic Vinegar

add soy sauce to taste (DO NOT USE LOW SODIUM SAUCE)

add 2 tablespoon Plum Sake (Drink additional 3oz Plum Sake)

Reduce sauce slightly (Drink additional 1.5oz Plum Sake)

3 1/2 tablespoons cock sauce (Sriracha)

add 2 tablespoon brown sugar

Red pepper flakes to taste

Minced Ginger to taste

Consume remaining Plum Sake

Simmer that shit for a solid 5 minutes, stirring pretty much constantly. The brown sugar helps it keep the proper consistency, so it's important to use. Play around with the recipe to your taste. Might want more or less balsamic vinegar. Might want more or more Plum Sake. I'd definitely recommend you make it several times to figure out your own flavour.

Tasting is believing, so I ordered myself 10 pieces of Chicken McNuggets and got to saucing. "To taste" is kind of vague, but I added two tablespoons of soy sauce, two healthy pinches of red pepper flakes, and a 2.5cm-long knob of ginger.

Once the sauce had simmered down into a syrupy-looking, deliciously dark liquid, I poured it into a little bowl and took a taste. It was very good. It was sweet, salty and tangy, with a good bit of heat. It did not, however, seem like a sauce McDonald's would have put out, as it tasted too much like food.

To be very clear: I love McDonald's, but they produce unique items with unique flavours that do not occur anywhere outside of their franchises, and this sauce simply does not belong in that universe. So though I love the sauce created by Xeropoint and his father, I didn't feel that it quite "matched" the McNugget aesthetic. Taking a cue from , I mixed in a tub each of McDonald's two most iconic nugget sauces: Sweet & Sour and BBQ. (I also added a little more soy and sriracha).

Now I had a sauce that tasted like it belonged under the golden arches. It was still sweet, sour, salty and spicy, but everything had been muted a bit by all the corn syrup, which made it a much better mate for the bland meat product that is the McNugget.

So that's how you make a Szechuan sauce that will make your McNuggets sing. If, however, you are eating chicken that is not in the form of a nugget, I recommend Xeropoint's original recipe. It's freaking delicious.

If you're looking forward to the next season of Rick and Morty, you're not the only one. But if you'd like to find a way to watch the series legally, then we've got your back.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xeropoint</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Szechuan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonalds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald's Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Congrats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plum Sake</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Szechuan Sauce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Lower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicken McNuggets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DIY Recipe For That McDonald's Szechuan Sauce From</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USE LOW SODIUM SAUCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sriracha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balsamic Vinegar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McNuggets</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morty' Is Pretty Damn Good</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
