<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406000536129680</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/weather-records-broken-in-northern-territory-after-hot-july/news-story/51bde87e74c07916fd52e7465d411ac9</url>
  <title>NT weather records tumble after hot month</title>
  <content>
DARWIN, Alice Springs, and a number of locations across the Territory have just experienced their hottest July on record, says Bureau of Meteorology senior climate liaison officer Greg Browning.
"It seems like the whole country has seen warm temperatures during July," he said.
"We're likely to see above average temperatures right across Australia for the next few months at least."
Mr Browning said the overall mean temperature for the Territory this July was above 30C.
"It's a full 0.6C higher than the previous record," he said.
"It's an extraordinarily warm month, there's no doubt about that.
"In Darwin we've equalled our mean daily maximum temperature for July - we didn't quite break our record for warmest minimum or overnight temperatures but we did see a distinct lack of those cool nights.
"We consider a cool night to be a minimum below 20C - typically in July we'll see about 18 to 19 in Darwin. However, this month we've only seen six so its been well, well below average."
Mr Browning said locations were recording warm temperatures across the globe.
"We do seem to be seeing a warmer planet," he said.
Territorians are likely to see above average temperatures in the next few months.
"Unfortunately we could be looking at a pretty warm start to the build up," Mr Browning said.
"It is a concern, obviously, but we are just living in a warmer world these days."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Browning</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territorians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Browning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
