<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405704183381653</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nbl-owner-says-joint-series-is-a-big-step-towards-australia-hosting-an-nba-game-in-future/news-story/e7f99984fa99991aabc3f69f9bbcd707</url>
  <title>NBA game in Australia moves closer</title>
  <content>
NBL owner Larry Kestelman is a man with a track record of getting things done.
And he is certain an NBA match will eventually be played in Australia.
Kestelman was front and centre in Sydney yesterday when the NBL formally announced a series of matches between Australian clubs and NBA teams in the US in October.
The Brisbane Bullets will take on the Phoenix Suns on October 13 (October 14 Australian time) after Melbourne United has played Oklahoma City Thunder on October 9 (AEST), with a clash between the Sydney Kings and Utah Jazz on October 3 (AEST) launching the groundbreaking series.
Kestelman said the historic matches were an important step towards hosting two teams from the world's best basketball competition because it represented Australia being respected and recognised on the global stage.
"As far as the NBA coming to Australia, I have no doubt that it will happen," Kestelman told The Courier-Mail.
"The NBA is very supportive of the NBL and it's just a matter of time and scheduling. They are a busy organisation and scheduling games for them is difficult and they do it well in advance.
"I'm very confident we will get a game here.
"In some ways for me personally, this is actually bigger than the NBA coming here ... this has never been done before. Our teams, three teams, flying over to the US to play theirs.
"This is a huge thing for the fans and a huge thing for the sport in this country.''
Kestelman said the three matches were part of a one-year deal with the NBA and he hoped it would continue for years to come.
"We obviously recognise the standard of the NBA is higher than any other competition but now it's more about how we conduct ourselves as an organisation, as a business, as professionals,'' he said.
"Hopefully both parties enjoy the experience. Then we can start talking about next year.''
Bullets sharpshooter Daniel Kickert said the trip would be priceless for the club on a number of fronts.
Eighteen months ago, the Bullets did not have a side, now they will be playing against the Suns in the 18,400-capacity Talking Stick Resort Arena in Phoenix.
"It's huge for the NBL brand and for the Bullets brand as well. It's an awesome opportunity,'' he said.
"It will be great for team building too. To get away as a group and go through that experience and put it all out there on court will help us down the track.
"It's worth the extra travel and disruption to our season. It's bigger than us.
"It's a big carrot dangling right there in front of us now in the pre-season. The boys will go even harder at training knowing what's just around the corner.''
The Bullets started pre-season training yesterday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14 Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma City Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kestelman</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Kickert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talking Stick Resort Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
