<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406009126064392</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/brisbane-school-rocked-by-sex-abuse-claim/news-story/846dffcfa631fe81f8e721cf74d05789</url>
  <title>Brisbane school rocked by sex abuse claim</title>
  <content>
A Catholic girls school in Brisbane is the latest institution to be rocked by allegations of historical child sexual abuse.
Mount St Michael's College in Ashgrove principal, Sharon Volp, sent an email to current and former students on Monday confirming it had received a "formal complaint" about a former staff member between 1976-1978.
Ms Volp says she found "the abuse of children distressing and abhorrent" and the matter had been referred to police.
She reassured the school community the "most stringent protocols" were in place to protect students.
Ms Volp urged anyone with concerns or issues about similar "inappropriate behaviour" by someone who currently or previously worked at the school to contact her and police.
Operated by Mary Aikenhead Ministries, the school provides education for girls from grade seven to 12.
A spokesman for the school confirmed it had received the formal complaint.
"As is appropriate, we have reported the matter to the Queensland police and other relevant authorities and communicated transparently to our school community about the alleged incident," he said in a statement on Tuesday.
"Now that the matter is before the police, the school will not be making any further comment."
AAP is seeking comment from Queensland police.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashgrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Volp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Aikenhead Ministries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount St Michael's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Volp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
