<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406047780770696</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/business/breaking-news/kiwi-down-vs-aussie-no-reaction-to-ardern/news-story/b25f5871eddee9997ccddcb728d1608c</url>
  <title>Kiwi down vs Aussie, no reaction to Ardern</title>
  <content>
The New Zealand dollar lost ground against the Australian dollar on Tuesday when the Reserve Bank of Australia kept rates on hold at 1.5 per cent.
The RBA said its forecasts for the Australian economy was largely unchanged despite weaker-than-expected inflation in the second quarter.
The kiwi was trading at A93.48c at 5pm from A93.86c at 8am and from 94.06c Monday. The kiwi was little changed at US75.04c from 75.06c, having reached a two-year high of 75.58c last week.
The RBA said recent inflation data - which showed consumer prices were close to flat in the second quarter and core inflation was well below the central bank's target band - was broadly as expected.
It did note that the Aussie dollar had gained strength recently - largely because of US dollar weakness and "an appreciating exchange rate would be expected to result in a slower pickup in economic activity and inflation than currently forecast".
Tim Kelleher, head of institutional foreign exchange sales at ASB Bank, said markets overlooked news that Jacinda Ardern has replaced Andrew Little as the new leader of the opposition Labour Party. "There was no reaction to that at all," said Mr Kelleher.
He said Wednesday's domestic jobs data will be watched for direction. ASB is forecasting an unemployment rate of 4.8 per cent while the median in a Bloomberg poll is for 4.9 per cent.
The overnight GlobalDairyTrade auction could also have an impact on the kiwi, with whole milk powder prices tipped to rise between 4 per cent and 6 per cent, he said.
The kiwi continued to struggle against the euro, trading at 63.43 versus 63.95 cents late Monday.
The kiwi traded at 82.69 yen from 82.96 yen and declined to 56.77 British pence from 57.16 pence. It traded at 5.0409 yuan from 5.0495 yuan.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ardern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Little</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASB Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinda Ardern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US75.04</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kelleher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GlobalDairyTrade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Kelleher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
