<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405931816651801</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:33</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65448/2017-peugeot-3008-price-and-features-for-australia</url>
  <title>2017 Peugeot 3008 - Price And features For Australia</title>
  <content>
A resurgent  has announced the details of its new-generation 3008, with the new model ditching its previous minivan form and becoming a fully-fledged member of the medium SUV set.
The 3008 range will go on sale later this month with a four-variant model structure and entry level pricing starting from $39,990 drive-away.
At that price buyers will have access to the entry-level 3008 Active (with regular pricing of $36,990 plus on-road costs), but can step up through the range to the the Allure from $39,490, GT Line from $43,490 and range-topping GT at $49,490 (all plus on-road costs).

Power for the Active, Allure and GT Line variants comes from a turbocharged 1.6-litre four-cylinder petrol engine that produces 121kW of power and 240Nm of torque. The GT builds on those figures thanks to a 1.6-litre four-cylinder turbo diesel that produces 133kW and a more substantial 400Nm.
Both engines are mated to a six-speed automatic transmission and all models will be front-wheel drive only.
Standard features across the range include Peugeot's 12.3-inch digital dashboard, 8.0-inch infotainment touchscreen, front and rear parking sensors, dual-zone climate control, Apple CarPlay and Android Auto connectivity. Bluetooth, DAB+ digital radio, and satellite navigation.

The Active includes 17-inch alloy wheels, a rear view camera, cruise control with speed limiter, halogen headlights, LED fog lights, and a leather wrapped steering wheel.
The Allure adds a surround view parking camera and semi-autonomous park assist, keyless entry and start, rear privacy glass, electric folding mirrors, fabric dash and door inserts, and 18-inch alloy wheels.
The GT Line brings sporty style with a black headlining, extended interior ambient lighting, black mirrors and roof, sports bumpers, and stainless steel scuff plates.

3008 GT Line

At the top of the range the GT steps up to 19-inch alloy wheels, wheel arch extensions, Alcantara interior inserts, chrome mirror caps, a powered driver's seat with massage function, and front seat heating.
Safety systems across the range include six airbags, speed limit recognition, driver fatigue detection, lane departure warning, and a distance alert system. GT Line and GT also come standard with an Advanced Safety Pack that adds active lane keeping assistance, adaptive cruise control autonomous emergency braking, and active blind spot detection. Allure Buyers are also able to option the Advanced Safety pack.

3008 GT

The new 3008 is the first Peugeot model to launch follow the brand's Australian distribution handover with Inchcape, also responsible for Subaru Australia, now handling Peugeot and  in Australia.
Pricing

3008 Active - $36,990 plus ORC or $39,990 driveaway
3008 Allure - $39,490 plus IRC
3008 GT Line - $43,490 plus ORC
3008 GT - $49,490 plus ORC
Overseas model shown.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Price And</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peugeot 3008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ORC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peugeot</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IRC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT Line - $43,490</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Active - $36,990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advanced Safety</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple CarPlay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT Line</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inchcape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alcantara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allure - $39,490</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bluetooth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android Auto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Advanced Safety Pack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT - $49,490</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
