<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406009126064420</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/latest-news/staying-safe-at-uni-what-not-to-do/news-story/4758fa4cdd39d9d54560b804c73e0c47</url>
  <title>Staying safe at uni: what not to do</title>
  <content>
Students who want to avoid sex attacks and harassment should steer clear of boozy university and college parties, shun uni accommodation and watch out on public transport.
A landmark survey of more than 30,000 Australian university students has shone a light on the dark issue of predatory sexual behaviour at 39 of the nation's tertiary institutions.
The survey exposes sex attacks at booze-fuelled uni and college parties, and a binge-drinking sex culture at university-owned or affiliated accommodation.
It's also revealed the gauntlet students run when they catch public transport to and from class.
A Human Rights Commission report on the survey shows 1.6 per cent of students have been sexually assaulted in a university setting.
Just over one in five were assaulted at uni or college residence parties and social gatherings - the scene for 21 per cent of reported sex attacks in 2015 and 2016.
It paints a grim picture of a binge-drinking culture at university-linked accommodation, such as colleges, halls and dorms, where students are more likely to fall victim to sexual assault and harassment.
Student residents have told of excessive alcohol consumption being a major feature of college life and of it being accepted practice to have sex with heavily intoxicated partners.
One ad for a college party promised: "Beer $2, bitches free."
Another student blamed the lad culture of his college for helping to "cultivate scenarios where taking advantage of intoxicated people was accepted and commonplace".
Just seven per cent of students surveyed were living in uni-linked accommodation but of all the students who reported sex assaults in university settings, 34 per cent were living in that type of accommodation.
The disproportionate result suggests student residents are at greater risk of both assault and harassment.
The survey also identified public transport as a less obvious danger zone for students.
It was the most commonly reported location for sexual harassment (22 per cent) and the second most common for sexual assault (15 per cent).
Most of those who did the harassing were also university students, but those perpetrating sexual assaults on travelling students were mostly strangers.
What we know about where and how sexual assault and harassment happens to university students:
SEXUAL ASSAULT:
* Uni or college residence parties: 21 per cent
* On public transport to or from uni: 15 per cent
* In university grounds: 10 per cent
* At a university residence or college: 10 per cent
SEXUAL HARASSMENT:
* On public transport to or from uni: 22 per cent
* On university grounds: 14 per cent
* In a university teaching space 13 per cent
* Online: via social networking sites, chatrooms, email and text: 22 per cent
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
