<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406000536129649</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826212/bruadars-young-at-heart/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Bruadar's young at heart</title>
  <content>
YOUNG AT HEART: Veteran Kembla horse Bruadar has been retired. Picture: MICHELLE RITCHIE

Patricia Sweeney jokes that Bruadar is a bit like her very own version of a Disney star. 
"He is like Peter Pan because he has never grown up," she laughs.

Fittingly, he has brought his long-time owner his fair share of magic moments too throughout a career that wrapped up last month after a mammoth 99 starts.

Sweeney and current trainer Michelle Ritchie opted to call time on the veteran son of Covetous's career just weeks before he turned the ripe old age of 13. 
Sweeney insists if Bruadar had things his only way, he would probably have liked to continue racing. 
But the Dapto resident knew the time had come for her much-loved gelding to finally enjoy retirement. 
"I'm glad we have come to the end of his racing career on a happy note," she said.
"He has given us all a lot of joy and is going to a wonderful home with Michelle.
"His attitude to racing was just amazing. He loved to race and loved Kembla Grange.
"He had a personality that seemed to appeal to people and while he didn't win any huge races, he was just so consistent.
"He had a little fan club and brought a lot of joy to people."
Somewhat of a cult hero later in his career on the South Coast, Bruadar finished with a record of 12 wins and 20 placings.

However, for Sweeney it's never been about winning. 
"It's been exciting having him in life because I looked forward to his races and I never felt dejected if he didn't win. I felt he won every race that he came back in," Sweeney said.
Bruadar enjoyed stints with five different Kembla stables.

First with Kerry Parker, Bruadar spent time with Robert Price, Paul Murray, Donna Grisedale before eventually winding up with Ritchie. Given his old age in racing terms, Sweeney had to get clearance from NSW Stewards for Bruadar to race with Ritchie
"When I asked the stewards if we could have another year with him they had him screened very intensely by the vets and he passed the medical so then they checked to see if he had enthusiasm for racing and he did," Sweeney said.
Bruadar will now spend his days at Ritchie's farm at Berry. 

HAPPY OWNER: Patricia Sweeney. Picture: ADAM McLEAN

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Veteran Kembla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kembla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerry Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ritchie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Sweeney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweeney</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Stewards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MICHELLE RITCHIE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donna Grisedale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruadar</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kembla Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
