<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406000536129684</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/rendezview/ladies-want-equality-in-the-music-industry-heres-some-advice/news-story/8195c900fb6326135c8a277d8bc29107</url>
  <title>Ladies, want equality in this industry? Step up</title>
  <content>
THE recent report into had me reflecting on my own experiences of being a woman in​ the music industry for more than 20 ​years. ​
I've been ​a receptionist, a promotions co-ordinator, a promotions manager, a marketing manager, a talent acquisition manager and finally found my strength as a publicist and now director of my own PR company.
I worked for EMI Music, Virgin Records, Island Records in the UK and Warner Music in both the UK and Australia before setting up my own business. I'm often asked who I've worked with and after so many years there are too many to mention but I've been lucky enough to work with some of the biggest superstars in the music industry world as well as some of the newest most exciting baby bands.
It was when I stepped away from Warner Music (along with my company car and my company credit card) to set my own company up, that I really honed my craft. For the first year, I focused entirely on unsigned Australian artists and I worked hard. As a publicist, working with international superstars is easy - everyone wants them. Securing exposure for unsigned artists or artists in "different" genres is blood, sweat and hundreds of individual emails.
My father taught me that if you aren't going to give 150 per cent to a job, no matter how big or small, then don't bother to do it at all. Something else he taught me was to ask questions. Ask a lot of questions ​and never ever be afraid to have a voice. Stand up for what you believe in and who you are no matter how difficult ​it may seem at the time. ​
I've been called every derogatory name under the sun. Do I care? No! Respect and being really good at my job was always far more important to me than being liked.
I work in music because I love music. I don't much care for the industry around it and let's face it, it seems to attract some people with very questionable ethics. But when it comes to the question of "Can you have equality in this industry" - yes you can. But ladies, if you want more you need to step up.
Does inequality exist? Yes it does. Has it ever impacted me? No.
I know how to negotiate strongly on a salary or fee because I know my worth and in many cases have earned more than my male counterparts. Have I ever compromised myself, my values or belief in how this industry should work? No. And I never will, no matter the cost to my career.
I think there is much women in the music industry could learn about self confidence, knowing their worth, learning how to negotiate the salary or fees they want, what's professional conduct and what's not, how to manage conflict and difficult situations. That's where our efforts need to go. When any woman in this industry walks into a boardroom or a meeting, she should know how to command it.
Don't take time off for rubbish sick days, don't stand around gossiping at work, don't get shit-faced at company events (do it privately or with those closest and most trusted), don't screw your crew and for god's sake keep your tears and bitching out of the office.
Know your business. Know it inside out and know all the trends, not just your specialty. Learn how to offer valuable input. Don't base your decision making process on emotions, it devalues you as an employee.
They tell you you're lucky to have a job in this industry? Remind them how lucky they are to have you. You're there to do a job, making friends is a bonus. Keep it professional at all times and you'll soon see how to equal or better your male counterparts.
I once told a new employee: "If something stinks, call it. They can't fire you for having a voice." Women in music need to remember that.
Whining about the inequality just perpetuates the problem. Let's teach women who feel undervalued how to value themselves first because when you put a price on yourself, trust me, they'll find the money.
Victoria Ciesiolka is the director of Alpha Entertainment.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner Music</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alpha Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMI Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Records</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Island Records</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Ciesiolka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
