<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405450780307672</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/revealed-usc-sexual-assault-harassment-figures/3207455/</url>
  <title>REVEALED: USC sexual assault, harassment figures</title>
  <content>
A STAGGERING 54% of students attending University of the Sunshine Coast experienced some form of sexual harassment during 2016 including 62% who were female.

The findings of an Australian Human Rights Commission survey released today found that of those 21% had experienced the harassment at the university with 10% identifying a tutor or lecturer as the perpetrator.

A further 72% were students of the university and 7% were people the victim had considered an acquaintance or friend.

Most of the harassment involved behaviour students surveyed considered to be intrusive or intimidatory with only 5% reporting unwelcome toughing, hugs, cornering or kissing and only 1% (male) complaining of inapproriate physical contact.

The report was report was conducted at the request of Universities Australia as part of a sector-wide 'Respect. Now. Always.' campaign and is now available at the Commission's website at www.humanrights.gov.au

USC is one of 39 members of Universities Australia who have each received their own institutional report.

The Sunshine Coast university's report may be accessed at www.usc.edu.au/respect.

USC Vice-Chancellor Professor Greg Hill said the university was committed to adopting the commission's recommendations. 

"This survey was designed to provide universities with robust data to help them improve policies, programs and services to prevent sexual assault and harassment and support those who have experienced such behaviours," he said.

Professor Hill said USC had organised extra counselling services in anticipation of an increase in requests for assistance this week and would facilitate student forums in coming months.

"Students who participated in the survey have been assured that the results will be used by universities to guide further improvements in how to better prevent and respond to sexual assault and harassment," he said.

Professor Hill said actions taken by USC since the 'Respect. Now. Always.' campaign started locally in mid-2016 included email and poster campaigns on campus advising support and help was available for anyone who has experienced or witnessed sexual assault or sexual harassment.

Students were encouraged to take part in the Australian Human Rights Commission survey and the university has also screened the American film, Hunting Ground, which highlights the problems of sexual assault and sexual harassment in university settings in the USA;

The university has also partnered with local specialist sexual assault services to provide extra training to staff in responding appropriately to disclosures of sexual assault and harassment and in recognising and responding to students in distress.

It has also partnered with the Student Representative Council in training a number of students as 'Consent is Sexy' ambassadors, to help raise the visibility of conversations around consent, respect and healthy relationships at University events.

The university would also undertake a broad review of its existing policies, practices and service provision related to matters of student sexual harassment and assault, and ratifying a new Sexual Harassment Prevention Policy. 

Tuesday August 1, marks a very special day for the region
Despite helping orphans in Africa, Sam Childers had to fight to get in
Do you know when you should indicate while using a roundabout?
Architect of a region stops briefly on his final journey.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Student Representative Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STAGGERING 54</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexual Harassment Prevention Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Childers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC Vice-Chancellor Professor Greg Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
