<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405227442005305</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/newborn-twins-and-sister-left-orphaned-after-mum-dies-the-day-of-their-fathers-funeral/news-story/e6a93d3674f5be8620158661eaefe33a</url>
  <title>Newborn twins 'instantly orphaned'</title>
  <content>
NEWBORN twins and their two-year-old sister have been left orphans after their mother died on the same day as their gunned down father's funeral.
As family and friends mourn the tragic Florida couple, they say they are now thinking about the futures of the three children.
Reports said Jevaughn Suckoo, 26, was found shot and dead in an apartment in West Palm Beach where he lived with his two-year-old daughter and his girlfriend, Stephanie Caceres, who was heavily pregnant.
Three days later Ms Caceres give birth to twins Jevaughn Jr and Lailah - only to die as a result of an infection after she underwent a C-section.
She died as relatives of Mr Suckoo held his funeral service.
This week, friends and relatives gathered outside the hospital where Ms Caceres had worked for four years to speak about the family tragedy.
"We're just trying to figure out how to move forward from here," said Mr Suckoo's aunt Joni Saunders.
Office Manager Lina Niemczyk said they were seeking to come together to make sure the children, including two-year-old Kailanie, were cared for.
"Our goal is to secure their future," Ms Niemczyk said. "It's a promise to their mum and dad."
A day after Ms Caceres gave birth to the twins, she wrote on Facebook to talk about what had happened.
"I just don't understand how someone can have the heart to leave three kids without a father especially two that never got the chance to even meet him," she said.
"They didn't deserve this! I'm trying I really am to stay strong but this has to be the toughest battle I've ever had to fight."
A GoFundMe page has been established to help the youngsters.
"We are all devastated, heartbroken and at a loss for words for all 3 of these children who will grow up never having gotten to truly know their parents," says a posting on the page.
"In an effort to provide health, education, maintenance and support to these three little ones, a  has been established in the children's name.
"Thankfully Stephanie and Jevaughn were raised by a beautiful family that have accepted the challenge set forth by God. The grandparents are going to start over, now raising their grandchildren."
At the time of publication, the GoFundMe page had raised $97,335 of the $100k goal.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kailanie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Caceres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jevaughn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Suckoo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C-section</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jevaughn Suckoo, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lailah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Caceres</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joni Saunders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Niemczyk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Palm Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jevaughn Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office Manager Lina Niemczyk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
