<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406004831097037</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/afl/history-haunts-carey-on-talking-footy/news-story/4a75c14dc2f326c625d9bae2b633673f</url>
  <title>History haunts Carey on Talking Footy</title>
  <content>
Wayne Carey.

Adam Santarossa

Share

YOU could cut the tension with a knife when Roving Brian met Roving Carey.
Channel Seven commentator Brian Taylor landed a sharp jab on the chin of fellow Channel Seven analyst Wayne Carey on Monday night's episode of Talking Footy - and no one knew what to say or where to look.
It occurred as part of Talking Footy's "The Blowtorch" segment. Carey was talking about former teammates, and took aim at his former North Melbourne colleague, now Fox Footy analyst, David King. Carey called out King for his crticisim of West Coast's Mark LeCras.
"I'm going to have a go at a former teammate of mine, a guy who was very quick to retire, (Mark) LeCras," Carey said on Seven. King slammed the Eagles' man for his tackling effort in recent weeks, prompting Carey to dig out some tackling numbers of King to hit back.
"So I had a look at his stats and 'Kingy' laid 42 tackles in two years," Carey said.
"That's not even a tackle a week, so 'Kingy' let's not forget how hard this game can be at times and not be so critical."

Former North Melbourne trio Wayne Carey, Coach Denis Pagan and David King.Source:News Corp Australia
Reading the body language, it was clear that perhaps Carey and King aren't the best of friends, something Talking Footy panellist Brian Taylor clearly picked up on.
Taking his "Roaming Brian" talents to new heights, where Taylor walks around AFL dressing rooms with no script and a live microphone, he decided to question Carey on the "relationships" back in the day at North Melbourne.
Taylor was clearly alluding to Carey's affair with the wife of North teammate Ashley Stevens.

Carey was famously traded to Adelaide following the incident, as the North Melbourne side refused to play with him after the trecheary.

Carey was clearly uncomfortable, and it made for great TV.
TAYLOR: "It wasn't all that it seemed down there at North was it?
CAREY: "Oh, it was fantastic. Premierships, preliminary finals
TAYLOR: Relationships?
CAREY: ... of course
Talking Footy host Luke Darcy tried to interject but struggled to remain composed amid fits of laughter across the panel, that included Essendon legend Tim Watson, journalist Sam McClure.
DARCY: "Time for a break ... what are you on about (looking at Taylor)
TAYLOR: "They didn't like each other (North Melbourne players). Did you like each other as teammates?
CAREY: We were a very close group ...
TAYLOR: Not everyone ...
CAREY: Not everyone in a footy club gets along ...
TAYLOR: A lot of forced relationships in a footy club ...
DARCY: (Again, attempting to interject) Time for a break, time to wrap up Talking Footy ...
Luckily it happened in the final segment of the show, otherwise it would have made for an uncomfortable hour long program.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David King.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Santarossa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam McClure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roving Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LeCras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denis Pagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast's Mark LeCras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Carey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talking Footy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carey</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roving Brian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Taylor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Darcy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roaming Brian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
