<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405970471358140</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/breaking-news/acic-boss-to-be-new-wa-police-commissioner/news-story/5561b9adc8edbd9f42b9f76538be8ccf</url>
  <title>ACIC boss to be new WA police commissioner</title>
  <content>
Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission boss Chris Dawson has been named WA's new police commissioner and is expected to focus on tackling methamphetamine and domestic violence.
Chris Dawson has more than 30 years of law enforcement experience and previously spent 10 years serving as a WA police deputy commissioner, overseeing the organised crime and counter terrorism portfolios.
The Australian Police Medal for distinguished service recipient has been with ACIC in Canberra for three-and-a-half years.
Mr Dawson headed the biggest security operation in WA Police history - the 2011 Commonwealth Heads of Government Meeting.
"We must be relentless in protecting the vulnerable and we must exercise our powers with fairness in serving the community and bringing justice to all," Mr Dawson told reporters on Tuesday.
"We live in a rapidly changing world. Keeping Western Australia safe means our police officers must have the right capabilities to do their job.
"Police alone cannot prevent all crime and harm, so jointly building and maintaining trust with the community and alliances with our partner agencies will be central to my approach as commissioner of police."
WA Premier Mark McGowan says he expects methamphetamine and domestic violence to be Mr Dawson's priorities.
"Chris has the experience, he has the depth, he has the knowledge, he has the drive to take our police forward into the future," he said.
Police Minister Michelle Roberts thanked outgoing Police Commissioner Karl O'Callaghan for his 13 years in the role, saying he served with distinction.
She also revealed there were four candidates shortlisted by the selection panel and she recommended Mr Dawson to cabinet.
The process was shrouded in controversy at one stage when former Australian Federal Police commissioner Mick Keelty withdrew from the selection committee, citing unavailability for interviews due to overseas travel.
There were also claims of political interference, which the Labor government denied.
WA Police Union president George Tilbury thanked Mr O'Callaghan and wished Mr Dawson success, saying there were some outstanding issues he hoped to "effectively resolve for the betterment of policing".
The union has been locked in an industrial dispute, but Mr McGowan has repeatedly said they will not the get the pay rise they want.
Mr Dawson will begin his five-year term on August 16.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dawson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACIC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Tilbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Heads of Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Police Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Commissioner Karl O'Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Dawson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Police Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Criminal Intelligence Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Michelle Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Keelty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
