<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405313341352416</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/sirius-college-students-turn-lens-on-ability-at-film-festival/news-story/32a301297ac4dce56b6ff0507e660331</url>
  <title>Students turn lens on ability</title>
  <content>
AS FAR as successful film messaging goes, a college at Broadmeadows is right on cue.
A group of Sirius College Meadow Fair Campus students have made the finals in the Focus On Ability Short Film Festival.
The awards are designed to encourage budding filmmakers to focus on the ability of people who have a disability.
The six Year 8 drama class students made a short film, Spectrum Disorder, that focuses on a student who is being bullied because he has autism. His torment ends when other students in his class stick up for him.
Years 7 and 8 co-ordinator Adrian Verga said he was proud of what the students had accomplished.
Mr Verga said the film explored topics such as bullying, bystanding and per-ceived disabilities.
"The message of the film is to accept everyone and that everyone has good qualities regardless of their perceived shortcomings," he said.
This year's competition received a record 209 nominations, including 101 school entries and 53 international films from 19 countries.
Sirius College is in the running for the Judges' Choice - Best School Short Film and School with Most Online Votes.
Voting closes on August 7.  to vote for the school.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Online Votes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Verga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best School Short Film</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirius College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Verga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judges' Choice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirius College Meadow Fair Campus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Focus On Ability Short Film Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
