<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406047780770768</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/breaking-news/wa-mining-forum-restores-welcome-ceremony/news-story/ed3508ed6832134e3365f37191e86e76</url>
  <title>WA mining forum restores welcome ceremony</title>
  <content>
Organisers of WA's Diggers and Dealers mining conference have caved in to pressure to reinstate a traditional Welcome to Country ceremony.
The welcome was recently axed, with organisers blaming a tight schedule, but the decision has now been reversed amid a significant backlash.
Aboriginal elder Trevor Donaldson has been hired to open the conference after organisers approached him on Tuesday, Diggers and Dealer director John Langford told AAP.
"It's shorter, between five to 10 minutes, and he has assured us he will not be using it as a platform for making any political statements," Mr Langford said.
One Nation upper house MP Robin Scott, who had been calling for the ceremony's return, said it was wonderful the Diggers and Dealers organisers had "come to their senses".
"We have to show respect and the situation in Kalgoorlie at the moment, unfortunately, is rather tense," Mr Scott said.
"We need to have this reconciliation and this healing period, and the decision not to have a welcome to country ceremony was not a good decision."
It is a sensitive time in Kalgoorlie after a 56-year-old man who ran down and killed 14-year-old Aboriginal boy Elijah Doughty was acquitted of manslaughter in the WA Supreme Court and was instead jailed for three years for dangerous driving causing death.
Mr Donaldson was sought for comment.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Donaldson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Langford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Langford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Donaldson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA's Diggers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Robin Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elijah Doughty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
