<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406052075738184</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/scorned-cubs-fan-receives-world-series-ring/3207536/</url>
  <title>Scorned Cubs fan receives World Series ring</title>
  <content>
BASEBALL: For 13 years Steve Bartman felt the wrath of Chicago Cubs fans blaming him for continuing the "curse" of not winning a World Series.
Now, after the Cubs won the World Series for the first time since 1908 last year by defeating the Cleveland Indians, Bartman has received his own championship ring.
Bartman was the target of Cubs fans' hatred after his botched attempt to grab a foul ball while in a front-row seat at Wrigley Field foiled outfielder Moises Alou's attempt to get to it in the eighth inning of the sixth game of the 2003 National League Championship Series.
The Cubs had led the game 3-0 and the best-of-seven series 3-2 but went on to surrender eight runs in the inning and lost the game to Florida 8-3 and dropped the series to the Marlins in seven games.
The drought-btreaking win over the Indians provided the chance for the Cubs to repay Bartman in some measure for the suffering he underwent for his actions in the playoff game 14 years ago.
"I am relieved and hopeful that the saga of the 2003 foul ball incident surrounding my family and me is finally over," Bartman said in a statement.
"Although I do not consider myself worthy of such an honour, I am deeply moved and sincerely grateful to receive an official Chicago Cubs 2016 World Series championship ring.
"I am fully aware of the historical significance and appreciate the symbolism the ring represents on multiple levels. My family and I will cherish it for generations.
"I humbly receive the ring not only as a symbol of one of the most historic achievements in sports, but as an important reminder for how we should treat each other in today's society."
Bartman was presented with the ring in the offices of Cubs owner Tom Ricketts.
"We hope this provides closure on an unfortunate chapter of the story that has perpetuated throughout our quest to win a long-awaited World Series," Ricketts said.
Bartman also received a tour of Wrigley Field, where his seat has become a mini tourist attraction as his saga is recalled.
Bartman rose to try and catch a foul ball hit by Luis Castillo, not realising Alou was racing over to make a leaping attempt to grab the ball for what would have been a crucial out.
After Bartman deflected the ball from Alou's glove, the frustrated left-fielder took off his glove and hurled it to the ground, yelling at several fans.
As the game continued and the Cubs collapse came, Bartman had to be escorted by security out of the ballpark, one fan dumping a beer on him in anger.
Police guarded his home and he changed his phone number while rejecting appearance requests.
Why Noosa Council has had to launch its own road safety campaign
Vehicle smashed into guardrail in westbound lanes
Winter on hold as Coast bathes in sunshine
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Ricketts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bartman</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland Indians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alou</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bartman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wrigley Field</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Series</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moises Alou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago Cubs 2016 World Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National League Championship Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Castillo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago Cubs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
