<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406086435476976</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4826370/positions-vacant-with-big-chains/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Positions vacant with big chains</title>
  <content>
Speculation continues to mount about what businesses will occupy the now vacant Masters hardware store in Rutherford.
Camping, adventure and sporting superstore Anaconda is advertising on Seek for a store manager for its new Rutherford store and Toys R Us is also has a position vacant for a store associate at Rutherford.
Fairfax Media attempted to contact both organisations to confirm their new store locations and staff numbers but did not hear back from them at Press time yesterday.
Fairfax Media reported last week how Maitland City Council has recently approved a change of use for the New England Highway/Anambah Road property which became vacant after Woolworths announced it would close the hardware chain.
Council confirmed the change of use of the Rutherford store to bulky goods, creating six empty tenancies.

There were rumours that either Amart Sports or Super Amart furniture would be taking up residence in the building.
Super Amart denied the rumours, however a spokesperson for Amart Sports, which has merged with Rebel, could neither confirm or deny rumours.
Last week's report prompted many comments on social media about what stores readers would like to see operating from the complex.
There were calls for Ikea, Costco and Dan Murphy's.

Master's Rutherford store opened with great fanfare in May 2012 and closed its doors for trade late last year.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master's Rutherford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anaconda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IKEA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rutherford</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Amart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toys R Us</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New England Highway/Anambah Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amart Sports</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
