<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405141542658043</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/11/29/men-arrested-over-plot-to-bring-down-etihad-flight-have-links-to-aviation-industry</url>
  <title>Men arrested over 'plot to bring down Etihad flight' have links to aviation industry</title>
  <content>
Four men arrested over an alleged conspiracy to bring down an Etihad flight out of Sydney allegedly studied aviation management and had links with a network of pilots and airline staff.
The Sydney Morning Herald made the claim after unnamed sources revealed the Sydney cell behind the alleged plot were in communication with foreign fighters in Syria.
It has since been discovered intelligence agencies in Britain tipped off Australian authorities about the alleged plan after intercepting the communications.
The men who were arrested on Saturday include Sydney man Khaled Khayat, remain in police custody. However, no charges have been laid.
It is believed Mr Khayat's brother is a senior fighter with ISIS in Syria. His son Mahmoud Kayat is also being held by police.
Fairfax Media reports another of Khayat's sons studied aviation management at UNSW. This son has not been arrested and is not facing charges.
The ABC reports the other two men are related to Ahmed Merhi, who travelled to Syria in 2014 to fight with ISIS. Law enforcement officials told the ABC the detained men may have already made a previous attempt to smuggle their bomb onto an international flight.

Related Articles

A magistrate approved a move for the men to be held in custody for seven days without charge under anti-terror laws.

Australian authorities reportedly wanted to wait to gather more information before arresting the men, but the British government threatened to issue a public security alert for travel to Australia if raids did not begin, the ABC's 7.30 reported.
Counter terrorism expert Greg Barton said Government Communications Headquarters - the British security agency that monitors signal intelligence - would have picked up something suspicious.
"It comes out of communications with people in Syria... they would have picked something up, passed it onto their domestic agency who is looking for communication with Brits... and would've told us," he told the TODAY Show this morning.
"They've got the gear on the ground. They work closely with us... It shows the system works."
Mr Barton said it appeared as though the men were extremely cautious about what they said outside their close family circles.

"I think it reminds us that this outer circle of people - who aren't on police radar and we haven't looked at so much because of lack of resources - we need to go back and look at these people, relatives of people who have been to Syria, frankly," he said.
"This is another encouragement to speak up if you see something that concerns you."
He added tougher security measures at Australian airports were the result of an "abundance of caution", but behind the scenes intelligence was where most of the work was being done.
Travellers at major airports around the country are due for another day of possible delays after Prime Minister Malcom Turnbull yesterday highlighted the government's commitment to "upgrading and improving our security services".
More thorough security measures were put in place after Saturday's arrests in Sydney.
Intelligent Risks Group chief executive Neil Fergus said Australian Federal Police have been pursuing mandatory photo identification for all flights for years.
"The argument was it's not the person that's going on the flight, but it's what they're carrying. The reality is, is it such a hassle for people to show their ID and for you to have some idea of who is getting on and off flights?" Mr Fergus told the TODAY Show this morning.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Fergus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Kayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Today Show</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's 7.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fergus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Morning Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcom Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Communications Headquarters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Risk Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
