<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405961881423396</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/south/have-your-say-on-christie-downs-railway-station-upgrade/news-story/55c239d55def584c2ed78130b6a4a376</url>
  <title>Run-down train station in line for upgrade</title>
  <content>
TRAIN commuters have the chance - at a public meeting this weekend - to stamp their opinion on an upgrade of Christie Downs railway station.
It comes almost a year after residents and Onkaparinga Council representatives gathered at the station to discuss the project with Reynell state Labor MP Katrine Hildyard and Transport Department chief executive Michael Deegan.
The $500,000 upgrade would include levelling the ramp so it's not as steep and uneven, installing new lighting and a bike cage, and painting artworks to deter graffiti.
Mrs Hildyard, who is hosting Saturday's meeting, said the announcement was a major win for the community.
"We want to make sure that (commuters) feel safe and welcome there," Mrs Hildyard said.
"We know that public places are safer when there's lots of people around."
She also wanted to establish a rail care group made up of residents and commuters dedicated to keeping a close eye on the station and report any damage.
"We're really hoping to brighten up the station," Mrs Hildyard said.
"For that to work well, we need to hear people's views. What we want to do is make sure that everybody is aware ... and able to have a say in how some of these things might happen."
She said the upgrade was expected to be completed in stages, with all work likely to finish by the end of the year.
The meeting will be held at Christie Downs Community House from noon to 2pm.
Register your interest at the Facebook event 'Christie Downs Railway Station Community Day'.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Deegan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christie Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christie Downs Community House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MP Katrine Hildyard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reynell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hildyard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christie Downs Railway Station Community Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Onkaparinga Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
