<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406086435477016</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/dan-murphys-dead-in-darwin-as-liquor-retailer-pulls-legal-action-against-gunner-government/news-story/afa15c19a019b2043198ebb2b5918ff4</url>
  <title>Dan Murphy's pulls NT Govt lawsuit</title>
  <content>
DAN Murphy's is essentially dead in Darwin after the company officially pulled their lawsuit against the Gunner Government Tuesday afternoon.
The company said in a release that they had lodged a notice of discontinuance, but would reassess the situation after the completion of the Government's Liquor Act Review.
"We feel we have let down the people of Darwin who overwhelmingly wanted us to proceed and win this case, but the pragmatic decision is to await the Government response to recommendations from the Liquor Act Review before considering our options," said Shane Tremble, Endeavour Drinks Group's general manager.
The Gunner Government had outlawed the liquor retailer from operating in the Territory after first passing a regulation to limit the floor size of takeaway liquor outlets to 400 sqm. They then rushed through legislation to enshrine the restriction into law in May, before their liquor review was finalised.
It was alleged that representatives of the Gunner Government reached a backroom deal with the Australia Hotels Association NT in the lead up to last August's election to enact the new floor space restriction and leave Dan Murphy's out. Dan's was planning on building a nearly 1500 sqm location near the airport.
The Government has stated continually that legislating the floor restriction was "providing certainty" for its policies, many of which are currently part of the liquor review.
The legislation was announced the day after the Government learned that Dan Murphy's was seeking discovery orders against the Government and the AHA.
Mr Tremble said the Government should have waited until after their review to determine size restrictions before moving ahead with no evidence.
But the legal case my be pursued again, he added.
"A totally new and different legal case would need to be mounted to challenge the making of the legislation, which would then be subject to further uncertainty while we awaited the outcome of the Liquor Act review and the Government's response," Mr Tremble said.
"On behalf of the many Territorians who have voiced support for our campaign to bring Dan's to Darwin, we are extremely disappointed not to have been afforded the opportunity to contest the validity of the regulation due to these actions by the Gunner Government.
"We would still hope to be able to bring a Dan's to Darwin and have genuine concerns about the validity of the legislation. We will consider our options, including potential further legal avenues, after the Government provides its response to Justice Riley's Liquor Act review."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Hotels Association NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liquor Act Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gunner Government Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gunner Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Endeavour Drinks Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Murphy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Govt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Tremble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territorians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government's Liquor Act Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tremble</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AHA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liquor Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Riley's Liquor Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
