<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406086435477005</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/north-america/youre-fired-who-has-been-sacked-and-left-in-trumps-193-days-as-president/news-story/52ea86918381bfaf5fe7fe926161c0cc</url>
  <title>'You're fired': Who has been sacked and left in Trump's 193 days as President</title>
  <content>
Trump felt Scaramucci comments in interview inappropriate -White House
0:40

White House spokeswoman Sarah Sanders says U.S. President Donald Trump felt comments by his now former communications director Anthony Scaramucci in a magazine interview were inappropriate.

August 1st 2017
7 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Donald Trump on the Set of The Apprentice in 2004. Picture: Supplied

Share

HIS catchcry on The Apprentice was "You're fired", and President Donald Trump has let go his share of employees since moving in to the White House.
But despite removing 10 key staff since he became President, Trump says all is well.
"No WH chaos. It's a great day at the White House," President Trump said across two tweets today amid the incredulity that his latest key recruit had been dumped just 10 days into the job.
It may well be, but for many working under Trump, days appear to be the measure by which they can count their tenure.
The brings to at least 10 the number of staff who have left Trump's administration since his inauguration on January 20.
Trump has been president for 193 days. On average, that means at least every 20 days, there's an exit - forced or voluntary - under his Presidency.
A great day at the White House!

n this 2015 file photo, Donald Trump, then-host of the reality television series "The Celebrity Apprentice," poses for photographers showing off his signature "you're fired" move. Picture: Chris Pizzello/Invision/APSource:AP
Scaramucci's departure was so head-spinningly swift that those writers at Saturday Night Live, who have famously parodied the President since January, didn't even get a chance to get a Scaramucci comedy character to air.
Kudos to the much-maligned and much parodied Sean Spicer - of those who have departed Trump's team, the embattled press secretary was one of the longest lasting, serving 183 days before resigning.
Here are the key figures who have left the former The Apprentice host's team since January:

ANTHONY SCARAMUCCI
"The Mooch" .
Hired as the White House Communications Director, Anthony Scaramucci limped into double figures. In an appointment lasting less than a fortnight, his wife divorced him, he deleted tweets supporting Hillary Clinton, prompted the exit of Spicer, embarked on an expletive-ridden tirade about leaders on the phone to a journalist, missed the birth of his son, and warred publicly and forced out former Chief of Staff Reince Priebus.
Ironically, Priebus' replacement claimed his scalp. He was cut loose at the urging of new White House Chief of Staff John Kelly.

Anthony Scaramucci lasted 11 days. Picture: AP Photo/Pablo Martinez MonsivaisSource:AP
REINCE PRIEBUS
Priebus resigned six months into his tenure after a public feud with Scaramucci.
He stayed loyal publicly to the end, but Trump announced General John F. Kelly, the former Homeland Security secretary, would take over for Priebus in a tweet on July 28.
He lasted 189 days, resigning less than a week after Spicer. His card was probably marked from the time he privately told Trump he should quit the presidential race over the "Pussygate" scandal last year. Blocking Scaramucci's appointment didn't help.
SEAN SPICER
Spicer resigned after a , telling Trump he vehemently disagreed with Scaramucci's appointment. His service began with him insisting Trump's inflated take on crowd numbers at his inauguration were true. He famously mangled names, calling Australian PM Malcolm Turnbull "Prime Minister Trumble", insisted Trump knew exactly what he meant when he late-night tweeted the word  and mysteriously briefed reporters among bushes in the White House grounds when FBI director James Comey was fired, after going missing for a while.

Sean Spicer resigned in protest at Sacramucci's appointment. Picture: AFP/Mandel NganSource:AFP

YouTube screen grab of the comedy spoof sketch with actor Melissa McCarthy playing White House Press Secretary Sean Spicer. Picture: SuppliedSource:YouTube
MICHAEL DUBKE
Michael Dubke, Trump's first White House communications director, resigned in May, quitting citing personal reasons. He lasted 86 days after being brought in to help lighten the load on Spicer.
WALTER SHAUB
The former director of the Office of Government Ethics, resigned in early July after 181 days, calling Trump's administration a "laughing-stock". He'd clashed with the White House over Trump's complicated financial holdings and was a vocal critic of Trump's seeming disregard for possible conflicts of interest between his presidency and his business.
JAMES COMEY
Trump fired James Comey as FBI director, 110 days into his presidency, in May.
Comey was handling the investigation into the Trump campaign's possible collusion with Russia during the 2016 election at the time of his ouster, creating a firestorm of controversy for Trump's administration.
Trump said he fired Comey for his handling of the investigation of Hillary Clinton's emails. But he told NBC the firing was tied to "this Russia thing".
Comey testified that he believes he was fired to "change the way the Russia investigation was being conducted." A letter was sent to his office, but Comey says he heard about his sacking on the news.
continues.

Former FBI Director James Comey testifies before the Senate Intelligence Committee where he testified President Trump pressured him to drop the FBI's investigation into former National Security Advisor Michael Flynn and demanded Comey's loyalty during the one-on-one meetings with Trump. Picture: GettyImagesSource:AFP
MICHAEL FLYNN
Former National Security Advisor Flynn resigned in February after just 23 days. Flynn misled Vice President Mike Pence and other administration officials about the contents of his phone conversations with Sergey Kislyak, Russia's ambassador to the US.
SALLY YATES
Yates was the President's first casualty. The acting Attorney-General and an appointee of former President Barack Obama, was given her marching orders after just ten days when she refused to uphold Trump's controversial travel ban and sent a memo to Justice Department employees asking them not to defend it.
PREET BHARARA
Trump fired Preet Bharara, the former US Attorney for the Southern District of Manhattan and 'Sheriff' of Wall Street, in March after Bharara refused to submit a resignation letter to Attorney-General Jeff Sessions. Bharara, an Obama appointee, was fired along with a number of Obama-era US attorneys.

Sally Yates was sacked for not defending Trump's travel ban. Picture: AFP/Jim WatsonSource:AFP
KATE WALSH
Walsh, the former deputy chief of staff and close ally to chief of staff Reince Priebus, left the White House, a pro-Trump group outside of the government.
AND SOME HE'S THREATENED TO FIRE:
Addressing a recent Boy Scout jamboree, Trump joked if Health and Human Services Secretary Tom Price didn't get the votes to win on the healthcare bill, he would be out of a job. "Hopefully he is going to get the votes tomorrow ... He better get them. He better get them. Otherwise I'll say 'Tom, you're fired," Trump said.
Trump told New York Times reporters that if Special Prosecutor Robert S. Mueller began investigating his businesses it would cross a red line. But he did not answer the reporters' questions as to whether he would fire Mueller because he didn't think that line would be crossed.
Trump put his sons Donald Trump Jr. and Eric Trump in charge of the family business, and says they'll be out of a job if they don't run it well while he's President. We think he was joking, but then there's that not-so-small matter of  during the 2016 campaign after receiving an email promising damaging information about Hillary Clinton as part of a Russian government effort to help his father's campaign.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump's 193</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday Night Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuppliedSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeland Security</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergey Kislyak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP/Mandel NganSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Pizzello/Invision/APSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preet Bharara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Services Secretary Tom Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sacramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spicer</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Security Advisor Michael Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Attorney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General John F. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern District of Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S THREATENED TO FIRE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Trumble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy Scout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pussygate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comey</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Security Advisor Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Dubke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Communications Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Press Secretary Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Set of The Apprentice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bharara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>28</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Shaub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Special Prosecutor Robert S. Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Comey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian PM Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney General Jeff Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Yates</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama-era US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GettyImagesSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI Director James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP/Jim WatsonSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Intelligence Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheriff' of Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP Photo/Pablo Martinez MonsivaisSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S. President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celebrity Apprentice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
