<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406086435476982</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/nrl/cowboys/shaun-fensom-returns-to-tighten-cowboys-middle-against-storm/news-story/a26b3b823202c5e850a3141e099957cd</url>
  <title>Fensom returns to tighten NQ's middle</title>
  <content>
NORTH Queensland tackling machine Shaun Fensom is set to make a timely return from injury as the Cowboys host the Melbourne Storm in a blockbuster clash at 1300SMILES Stadium on Friday night.
Fensom has been playing through the pain of a rib cartilage injury, but he was a late withdrawal from last weekend's 22-16 loss to the Roosters in Sydney, with young prop Braden Uele handed his NRL debut.
The Cowboys have been the league's best defensive team the past two months, but they sorely missed Fensom's tireless work ethic through the middle against the Roosters as they blew a 16-6 halftime lead.
Fensom trained with the team yesterday, but coach Paul Green said the workhorse forward would still have to get through some contact tomorrow before taking his place against the Storm.
"Having the week off, he hasn't done a lot of contact so we really need to test that out before we put him into a game, especially against Melbourne," Green said.
"Defensively he tightens us up through the middle so that's important. The Storm are very good through the middle there. He'll be a welcome addition for us."
The Cowboys are on a four-game losing streak against the Storm, who justified their tag as premiership favourites to thump Manly 40-6 in Melbourne last weekend.
Storm captain Cameron Smith has been particularly brilliant, having a hand in four tries against the Sea Eagles in his 350th NRL appearance.
Green had high praise for Smith, but he urged his players to match the wily veteran's intensity or risk seeing their hopes of a top-four finish slip away.
"He's probably been in career-best form and I think they're the team to beat at this stage so we'll need to go up a level," Green said.
"(Smith) has been playing consistently well and he really took hold of that third Origin game and has done the same at club level ever since.
"Whether or not they need to go up another level, I'm not sure. They're playing pretty good footy, but it's a big game for us and we're looking forward to it."
Star fullback Billy Slater (concussion) is expected to return for Melbourne, but questions remain over the fitness of in-form five-eighth Cameron Munster who is battling an ankle injury.
Green admitted it would make his job easier if Munster was ruled out for Friday night's clash, but he said the Cowboys needed to keep the focus on themselves.
"It would be good, but you can't worry too much about whether or not those guys are out," Green said.
"It doesn't change too much about how we play. I know it won't change how they play. We've just got to focus on what we control and that's our prep."
NRL Cowboys squad: 1 Lachlan Coote, Kyle Feldt, 3 Justin O'Neill, 4 Kane Linnett, 5 Antonio Winterstein, 6 Te Maire Martin, 7 Michael Morgan, 8 John Asiata, 9 Jake Granville, 10 Scott Bolton, 11 Gavin Cooper (c) 12 Ethan Lowe 13 Jason Taumalolo 14 Ben Hampton 15 Coen Hess 16 Shaun Fensom, 17 Corey Jensen 18 Braden Uele 19 Kalyn Ponga 20 Sam Hoare 21 Javid Bowen.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMILES Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Fensom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL Cowboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fensom</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ethan Lowe 13 Jason Taumalolo 14 Ben Hampton 15 Coen Hess 16 Shaun Fensom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Jensen 18 Braden Uele 19 Kalyn Ponga 20 Sam Hoare 21 Javid Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Feldt, 3 Justin O'Neill, 4 Kane Linnett, 5 Antonio Winterstein, 6 Te Maire Martin, 7 Michael Morgan, 8 John Asiata, 9 Jake Granville, 10 Scott Bolton, 11 Gavin Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braden Uele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Coote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
