<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406099320379165</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/on-the-departing-ofx-cfos-other-achievements-20170801-gxmtvw</url>
  <title>On the departing OFX CFO's other achievements</title>
  <content>
With the announcement of OFX's new CFO Selena Verth this morning, we guess things must be drawing to a close for her long-serving predecessor Mark Ledsham.
So we thought we'd use this opportunity to bid farewell to Ledsham, one of the handsomest men in corporate Australia. Which isn't something one often says about a CFO. And it's not just our opinion - when Ledsham was 20 and studying business in Manchester, the dreamy accountant was the 1999 winner of Mr Gay UK (This newspaper also crowned him one of our , but frankly that's nowhere near as fun).
The annual beauty contest has tended to catapult its winners into some level of prominence, and Ledsham's year wasn't an exception - he went on to have a bit part in two episodes of cult classic Queer as Folk the next year, where his character  as "Handsome Man". "I'd hate people to think that just because I'm this year's Mr Gay UK I'm an airhead. I'm not a genius, but I'm not thick either," the multi-talented then-business student was quoted saying in 1999.
The Macquarie/Deloitte alum doesn't list the achievement on his LinkedIn profile, though the Mr Gay UK profile is still up on the organisation's website. From more recent photos he still looks like he's in very good shape - we bet his abs  Jack Lowenstein's.

Ledsham's handled the former OFX's accounts since 2008 (when it was OzForex), but resigned with six months notice last April, causing the share price to slide by as much as 7.9 per cent. Clearly we're not his only fans.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OFX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFO Selena Verth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gay UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Ledsham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie/Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Lowenstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OzForex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Handsome Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OFX CFO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gay UK I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LinkedIn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledsham</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
