<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405699888414248</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/new-hungry-jacks-approved-for-hampstead-rd-in-lightsview-despite-opposition-from-local-residents/news-story/d3cea5c8d5bd548e373eddd413baca49</url>
  <title>Whopper restaurant for Hampstead Rd</title>
  <content>
A NEW 24-hour Hungry Jacks is on the way to Lightsview despite opposition from local residents.
The Development Assessment Commission last week decided the $1.3 million fast food restaurant on Hampstead Rd met Port Adelaide Enfield Council development criteria and approved it.
In coming to its decison, the commission heard objections from councillors Mark Basham, Matt Osborn and Anne-Marie Hubycz, who represented three nearby residents opposed to its construction.
"I'm pleased that our concerns about noise, traffic and rubbish have been taken on board," Cr Osborn said.
He said he felt a mixed tenancy building would have been better suited to the location.
"I can imagine a few buildings with offices and cafes on the ground floor, and affordable apartments on the first floor," he said.
"In my opinion, a plan along those lines would have been a better option than a drive-through fast food establishment."
One Hampstead Rd resident, Judy Walker, expressed her fears in a letter to the Development Assessment Commission in May.
"Despite living on such a main road, I am concerned about noise emanating from the site 24 hours a day," she wrote.
"I am also concerned at the smells from the facility wafting across the road here."
In her letter, Mrs Walker also pointed to increased use of a pedestrian crossing, leading to the proposed fast food outlet, outside her home.
At the DAC meeting it was decided approval of the development would be subject to the relocation of that crossing, but a new location has not been identified yet.
She wrote that she was angry the development was again being considered after the proposal was withdrawn earlier in the year.
"I am also very angry that the Government and Lightsview are supporting this development, especially after having withdrawn it once after all the trouble they knew they would cause local residents, and future residents."
Port Adelaide Enfield Council chief executive Mark Withers said their main concerns were with noise and management of local traffic.
"(The) council raised a couple of concerns with the Development Assessment Commission regarding the proposed development," he said.
"These were based on possible issues including noise related to the 24 hour operation of the business and also local area traffic management.
"We have provided these comments in an effort to achieve the best outcome for the community."
A nearby building occupant who wished to remain anonymous said he didn't mind the development for its convenience.
"I can understand why residents would be a bit peeved, especially those who have built new properties (but) it doesn't worry me particularly," he said.
Three kilometres away McDonald's is planning a new outlet on the corner of Grand Junction and Briens roads - just down the road from Roma Mitchell Secondary School.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roma Mitchell Secondary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development Assessment Commission</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide Enfield Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hampstead Rd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Withers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lightsview</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Junction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungry Jacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne-Marie Hubycz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Basham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Osborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Osborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Briens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
