<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405699888414254</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/cancelled-tigerair-flight-leaves-darwin-resident-unable-to-get-to-splendour-in-the-grass/news-story/25dd5ee4d939ef612d6c601d85ea5caf</url>
  <title>Tigerair flight nightmare</title>
  <content>
A CANCELLED Tigerair flight almost cost a woman more than $600 after she was left stranded in Darwin with a ticket to Splendour in the Grass in Brisbane.
Harmony Dixon had plans to fly to Brisbane on Tuesday morning a fortnight ago but she received an email from Tigerair on the Sunday.
"They told me that my flight was cancelled and there would be no available flight for 48 hours," she said.
Confused about how to rebook, the Rapid Creek local phoned the airline but was unable to get through to anyone.
"I ended up going to the airport around the same time as my flight was meant to be but there was no one there," Ms Dixon said.
It wasn't until later during the day that she was able to get through to Tigerair's customer service over the phone.
"There was a flight on the Wednesday night and I tried to get onto that, but they said it was already full," Ms Dixon said. "They told me I wouldn't be able to fly until the flight on Saturday morning."
The frustrated traveller was meant to be visiting her sister on the East Coast and had tied in the trip with the Splendour in the Grass music festival Saturday week ago.
"I'm just really lucky that the people at Splendour gave me a full refund after I showed them the emails about the cancelled flight," Ms Dixon said.
"Otherwise that was a $400 ticket I couldn't resell. I hadn't planned to go to Splendour, that was just a lucky coincidence. It was the icing on the cake that I didn't get to eat."
Ms Dixon eventually accepted Tigerair's offer to refund her tickets and rebooked on another airline at an additional cost.
"I'm not going with Tiger ever again," she said.
"Imagine if you were flying in for a funeral or if your child was sick. You'd have no other option than to get on a $700-$800 flight (at the last minute)."
A Tigerair spokeswoman said the cancellation was due to operational reasons and that the airline "exhausted all options to provide alternative flights for the majority of affected customers".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CANCELLED Tigerair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Dixon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rapid Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigerair</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harmony Dixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
