<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406052075738128</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/nsw-defends-cash-for-cans-scheme/news-story/2253c5061250b37822578ec7b7d20730</url>
  <title>NSW defends cash for cans scheme</title>
  <content>
The NSW government has defended its decision to have Coca-Cola Amatil and other beverage companies oversee the state's container deposit scheme after critics labelled the move "utterly stupid".
The "return and earn" scheme aims to halve the number of cans and bottles thrown away by paying people 10 cents for every container handed in at designated sites.
But the appointment of a joint venture comprising major beverage companies - dubbed Exchange for Change - to co-ordinate the scheme has been savaged by the NSW Greens.
Greens MP Mehreen Faruqi says it amounts to "putting the fox in charge of the henhouse".
"The beverage industry furiously lobbied against the scheme for decades and now they will run it," she said in a statement this week.
The Greens MP said the appointment was a "scandal waiting to happen".
But Environment Minister Gabrielle Upton says the joint venture - which comprises Carlton and United Breweries, Asahi, Coopers, Lion and Coca-Cola - was chosen after a competitive tender process and would have to meet "strict performance requirements".
"Exchange for Change will have defined and limited responsibilities and will not set the scheme price or service level," she told AAP in a statement on Tuesday.
"The NSW Environment Protection Authority is responsible for regulating the scheme's operation - not the scheme co-ordinator."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Breweries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asahi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coca Cola Amatil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Minister Gabrielle Upton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coopers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Greens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens MP Mehreen Faruqi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Environment Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coca-Cola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
