<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406095025411839</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/streaming-service-amazon-music-is-coming-to-australia-2017-8</url>
  <title>Streaming service Amazon Music is coming to Australia</title>
  <content>
Amazon appears to be building up its Australian arm to something close to full service, with its streaming music service also planned for local release.

Amazon's cloud computing and Prime Video entertainment services are already running in Australia, and in April, the company .

Last week, the , while the company was even  to help make a localised version of its Echo home voice assistant device.

Now  the tech giants is seeking a new team to run an Australian version of its streaming service, Amazon Music, to compete against the likes of Spotify, Google Play Music and Apple Music.

The job posting for an Australia head of digital music seeks an executive with "proven experience in establishing and launching media businesses outside the United States to lead our Australia business".

"You will hire and develop a team to drive the roll-out of Amazon Music. You will work with the Amazon Music team and local in-region Amazon teams to develop a world-class and locally relevant digital music customer experience, and ensure that Amazon is well positioned versus other offerings," the ad reads.

Business Insider has contacted Amazon for comment.

There are also ads for other Amazon Music vacancies, all based in Sydney, including marketing managers, music curators and a senior label relations manager, who "will collaborate with Amazon major label partners to provide the best music experience for Amazon customers".

"Label Relations support the existing music relationships, drive collaborative efforts internally and externally around content launches, events, and promotions," the job post reads.

Amazon claimed in April that its Australian operations would bring many jobs and much economic activity to the country.

"We are excited to bring thousands of new jobs to Australia, millions of dollars in additional investment, and to empower small Australian businesses through Amazon Marketplace," the company said.

"We are optimistic that by focusing on the things we believe customers value most - low prices, vast selection, and fast delivery - over time we'll earn the business of Australian customers."

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Play Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotify</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple Music</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Music</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Video</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
