<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406056370705505</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/not-heading-hoff-veteran-westhoff-triggers-new-deal</url>
  <title>Not heading Hoff: Veteran triggers new deal</title>
  <content>
Justin Westhoff will remain a Port Adelaide player in 2018

PORT Adelaide swingman Justin Westhoff has activated a trigger in his contract to remain at the Power next year.

The 30-year-old has played every game for the Power this season and is likely to finish his career as a one-club player.

"I love the club and had no interest in exploring free agency, this is my home and I'm very happy here," Westhoff told portadelaidefc.com.au.

"The chance to keep playing my role as part of what we're trying to build here at Port Adelaide is exciting.

"To have the trigger activated now leaves me free to focus on doing my job as part of the team for the rest of the season."

Westhoff - who has played 221 games since making his debut in 2007 - has played most of this season on the wing, but has also spent time in attack and defence.

The Power's head of football Chris Davies said Westhoff's versatility was extremely valuable to the club.

"He's performed roles for us in every line this season," Davies said.

"His versatility and durability are an absolute strength and we're pleased Justin will be with us again for at least another year."

Westhoff is the latest Power player to re-sign this year, following Brad Ebert, Jack Hombsch, Sam Powell-Pepper, Dan Houston, Billy Frampton, Dougal Howard and Riley Bonner.

Free agents Jackson Trengove and Jasper Pittard remain unsigned next year, as do Karl Amon, Aaron Young, Matthew White and Angus Monfries.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Powell-Pepper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jasper Pittard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson Trengove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westhoff</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Frampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley Bonner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Ebert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Houston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angus Monfries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Amon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dougal Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Hombsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Westhoff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
