<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406052075738080</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/entertainment/television/game-of-thrones-recap-season-seven-episode-three/news-story/44f0d1f524a0b1bdf0b31123f7e36768</url>
  <title>Fan favourite's brutal last words</title>
  <content>
SPOILER ALERT: This is a recap. That means we'll be discussing the events of Game of Thrones' third episode.
If you haven't seen the episode yet and don't want to know what happens, this is your cue to leave.
Seriously, do a Theon and dive overboard now.
Otherwise, jump into  for some extra analysis of the moments you missed, along with some strained attempts at humour.
LISTEN TO OUR GAME OF THRONES RECAP
"A Lannister always pays ... attention to the news.com.au Game of Thrones podcast." - Tyrion
OLDTOWN
Sam could have been killed. Or worse, expelled.
His fantasy of being a wizard and living at Hogwarts is finally fully realised when Professor Slughorn figures out he cured Jorah's greyscale.
"Tarly, I'd like to speak with you in my study this evening," Slughorn says in a very Dumbledorey way. Once there, he gives Sam a very Dumbledorey lecture.
"You broke all the rules and you could have infected the entire S**tadel with a terminal disease but hey, everything turned out OK in the end, so 10 points to Gryffindor," Slughorn says.
Sam's only punishment is to copy a bunch of ageing scrolls, and if I know my Harry Potter, one of them will miraculously turn out to have the exact information he needs to win the Triwizard Tournament.
Meanwhile Jorah, ever the Hufflepuff, departs to once again serve loyally as Daenerys's awkward third wheel.
WINTERFELL
You know that cliche where the hero has a devil on one shoulder and an angel on the other? Sansa is living through it right now, except the devil is Littlefinger and the closest thing she has to an angel is some snobby fat man.
Littlefinger is certainly keen to whisper in her ear. Well, not whisper so much as squeeze strained sounds through his windpipe like a man whose testes are stuck in a vice, but that's just what passes for his voice these days.
"Everyone is your enemy. Everyone is your friend. Every possible series of events is happening all at once," he tells her. Either Littlefinger is a big believer in the , or his obsession with paranoid plotting has finally got out of hand.
Sansa is saved from her lecture by the arrival of Bran, perhaps the one person still alive who is even creepier than Littlefinger. He appears to be spaced out on shrooms.
The pair sit together in the godswood, and Sansa tells Bran he's technically the Lord of Winterfell now. He tells Sansa she looked really pretty when she was raped on her wedding night.
Bran needs to work on his social skills.
KING'S LANDING
Euron has returned with two important prisoners: Ellaria Sand, who murdered Cersei's daughter Myrcella, and Ellaria's daughter, the last remaining Sand Snake, whose name escapes me. You know the Sand Snake who kept going on about her "bad poosy"? All I know is she's not that one.
"I give you what no other man could give. Justice for your murdered daughter," Euron tells Cersei, continuing his systematic emasculation of Jaime.
Cersei promises to marry Euron "when the war is won", which in Westeros is code for "you will give me your ships and then die at a convenient moment either before or during the wedding". Ever the optimist, Euron proceeds to ask Jaime for sex tips.
In the dungeons, Cersei delivers some evil but admittedly poetic justice to Ellaria by forcing her to watch her daughter die, using the same poison Ellaria herself killed Myrcella with. It could have been much worse.
Don't believe me? Here's an actual quote, from the actual Queen of the not quite Seven Kingdoms: "I thought of this lovely face cracking open like a duck egg." With an imagination like that, no wonder she doesn't sleep at night.
Her gruesome task done, Cersei returns to her brother eager for sexy times, and on that note, I have good news for Euron. Much like him, Cersei clearly becomes sexually aroused when she murders people. It's a niche fetish, to be sure, but as long as they're happy, who are we to judge?
Good news for pervy viewers too - the bum cheek per episode ratio has risen considerably these past two weeks.
DRAGONSTONE
Jon must have travelled by motorboat, because he has already arrived at Dragonstone. He's greeted by Tyrion, master diplomat, who immediately brings up sex and Sansa in the same sentence for some reason.
Jon, meanwhile, really wants the viewers to know he's a secret Targaryen.
"Stark men don't fare well when they travel south," Tyrion says. "True. But I'm not a Stark," Jon replies, just as a dragon screeches overhead. So cryptic. What does it mean?
Waiting for them in the throne room is Daenerys, who I'm starting to think has a split personality. There are two versions of her: the humble liberator who listens to her advisers, doesn't want to hurt innocent people and has a passable sense of humour; and the arrogant, self-absorbed tyrant who enjoys threatening people.
Naturally, the bad Daenerys shows up for her meeting with Jon. She gets Missandei to read out all her fancy titles: The Unburnt, Mother of Dragons, Queen of the blah blah, yada yada yada.
"This is Jon Snow. Uhh. He's King in the North," Davos responds. Davos doesn't have time for pompousness.
Bad Dany is palpably angry when Jon doesn't immediately pledge fealty to her.
"He's refused to call me queen, he's refused to bow and now he's calling me a child," she says, channelling a whiny Trump tweet.
Jon, meanwhile, just can't understand why Daenerys is sceptical of his story about sentient genocidal ice zombies. If you look closely at his eyes, you can see into the depths of his soul, where he is wondering why he didn't bring Lyanna Mormont along to argue his case. She would have made Daenerys bend the knee.
It eventually falls to Tyrion to break through Jon's broodiness and Daenerys's stubbornness to broker a deal, in which she will give Jon access to dragonglass, and he will give her ... nothing, as far as I can tell.
Like I said. Master. Diplomat.
HIGHGARDEN
The Unsullied take the Lannisters' ancestral home, Casterly Rock, with minimal fuss, thanks to Tyrion's intimate knowledge of the fortress's sewage system. He used to sneak women through it, you see. Very romantic.
It's a pyrrhic victory. As Euron's fleet of teleporting ships traps Daenerys's forces on the wrong side of the continent, Jaime takes the bulk of the Lannister army to capture somewhere far more strategically important - Highgarden.
This is crucial for three reasons: Highgarden is the magic money tree of Westeros, which means Cersei will now gain the support of Mycroft Holmes and the Iron Bank; it takes out the Tyrells, perhaps Daenerys's most important ally; and most of all, it gives the sharp-tongued Olenna Tyrell a glorious death in which she gets to reveal her orchestration of Joffrey's murder.
"Will there be pain?" Olenna asks, examining the poison Jaime has brought her.
"No. I made sure of that," he responds.
"That's good," she says, downing the whole glass. "I'd hate to die like your son."
Savage until the very end.
The next Game of Thrones episode will air next Monday on Showcase at 11am and 8:30pm. Keep an eye out for news.com.au's recap and podcast analysing the episode.
In the meantime you can subscribe to our podcast, , on iTunes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarlys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euron</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mycroft Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casterly Rock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bran</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gryffindor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna Tyrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Kingdoms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uhh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord of Winterfell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Slughorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highgarden</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winterfell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jorah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellaria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Targaryen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joffrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missandei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyanna Mormont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sand Snake</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myrcella</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragonstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iTunes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mother of Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Littlefinger</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dumbledorey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hogwarts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triwizard Tournament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unburnt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sansa</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oldtown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hufflepuff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olenna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellaria Sand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slughorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPOILER ALERT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Landing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unsullied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
