<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405579629328269</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/new-developments-helping-to-rebuild-community-spirit/news-story/16a5a9173c9db08cbc1d4c39250c431b</url>
  <title>New developments helping to rebuild community spirit - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Garden Hill apartment complex in Doncaster will include an off-leash dog park.

NEW apartments are helping rebuild our flagging community spirit, a leading urban development industry group says.
The Urban Development Institute of Australia's Victorian chief executive, Danni Addison, said traditional neighbourhood interaction was dying out in the age of social media and digital technology.
RELATED:
RELATED:
"There is no doubt that our community spirit is changing and has even diminished in today's modern era," Ms Addison said.
"I know people who have never spoken to their neighbours, and others who go as far as to avoid eye contact with them.
"Once upon a time, people got to know each other because they lived close; they formed friendships and they looked out for each other. Now, that's not the case.
Ms Addison said community spirit was important for personal wellbeing and residential developers were looking for new and innovative ways to bring neighbours together again.
"Creating cohesive communities is more important for our personal wellbeing now than it ever was before and is highly valued by the residential development industry as we look at where and how we are building homes of the future," Ms Addison said.
"We are creating strong communities by promoting and enabling people to have more quality interactions with each other and the physical environments they occupy.

Urban Development Institute of Australia Victorian chief executive Danni Addison.

"These actions will improve the health and wellbeing of Victorians and encourage a sense of belonging."
Ms Addison said a new sense of community would need to be built by developers, policy makers and society.
"A future sense of community is not going to be the same as it was in the past," she said. "With the many changes to the way we live our everyday lives - social media, digital technology in our built environments - we need to craft a new sense of community that is unique to us."
Ms Addison said new apartments were a good example of how the changing nature of housing in Melbourne could rebuild our sense of community.
"Communal dog parks in apartment complexes and shared vegetable gardens - these are just two examples of innovations that will reconnect us with those who live around us," she said.
She said she expected more innovative urban projects to emerge as the residential property industry continued to grow and adapt to consumer wants and needs.
"The challenge now is for us all - the development industry, policy makers and the public - to work together to create the strong communities we live in," she said.
"For the development industry, that means finding ways to deliver unique features and lifestyle offerings focused on what is important to the lives of the communities we are building.
"For policy makers, it means working with the development industry to ensure the planning system enables innovation in a way that doesn't unnecessarily increase house prices. And for the public, it's as simple as introducing yourself to your neighbour."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danni Addison</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urban Development Institute of Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Addison</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doncaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garden Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
