<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406133680118227</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/paramedic-allegedly-told-of-wild-sex-before-mum-bled-to-death-on-a-beach/news-story/c71f01e0a469f0aad530a7c578ddc4b2</url>
  <title>Mum bled to death after alleged rape</title>
  <content>
A MAN on trial for manslaughter after a sex act caused his partner's death said they had previously engaged in the violent sexual activity and she had never been injured.
Lynette Daley, 33, bled to death on an isolated beach in northern NSW after having what her partner Adrian Attwater described as a "wild sex session" which involved a second man Paul Maris.
Attwater, 42, has pleaded not guilty to the rape and manslaughter of the mother of seven who was found dead by paramedics on Ten Mile Beach, near Iluka, on January 27, 2011.
Maris, 47, has pleaded not guilty to aggravated sexual assault in company and hindering the discovery of evidence by burning a bloodied foam mattress.
The Crown case is that Ms Daley was too drunk to consent to sex with the two men and that the sex act Attwater performed on her would have caused her extreme pain.
The Crown also claimed that Attwater would have known he had seriously injured Ms Daley because of her massive blood loss following the sex and that he failed to seek medical attention in time to save her life.
Defence barrister for Attwater, Nathan Steel opened his case to the jury by saying Attwater admitted to causing the injury but did not know how seriously she had been hurt until she collapsed while swimming the next morning.
"His position in this trial is the sexual intercourse was consensual. His position is that it wasn't until Ms Daley collapsed in the ocean that he realised that she had a serious injury that needed medical attention.
"From that point on when she collapsed in the ocean he did everything he could to save her life," Mr Steel said
The jury had previously been told that Maris called Triple Zero but when paramedics arrived in the isolated spot 50 minutes later she was dead.
IN OTHER NEWS:
When paramedics asked Attwater what had happened he said they had been having a, "wild sex session."
Mr Steel said the jury would have to decide whether Attwater should or could have reasonably assumed that the sexual activity they engaged in could have caused her serious injury.
"They had engaged in a similar sexual activity previously...she had never been injured and never had to go to hospital before."
The trial continues.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Maris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Steel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attwater</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Daley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maris, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 27, 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple Zero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Mile Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Attwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attwater, 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iluka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Steel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynette Daley, 33</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4.7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
