<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405360585993407</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/freelancers-revenue-growth-has-stalled-and-the-stock-is-tanking-2017-8</url>
  <title>Freelancer's revenue growth has stalled, and the stock is tanking</title>
  <content>
Freelancer, the pioneering freelancing and crowdsourcing marketplace, has been hit by a downturn in its escrow business in China.

Shares in Freelancer fell hard after reporting flat revenue for the half year to June.

A short time ago, they were down almost 23% to $0.505.

The company generated net revenue of $26.3 million for its latest six month period, roughly equal to the same half last year. The net loss improved to $711,000 from $778,000 in the same six months of 2016.

This is a marked contrast from the calendar year to December, when revenue rose 37% to $52.75 million.

Gross profit for the half-year was $22.5 million, also flat on the same period in 2016.

The gross margin was 85%, slightly down due to a higher cost of sales.

Operating cash flow was a positive $1.5 million.

Gross payments fell 18% to $291 million. Freelancer's share of that was $82 million, up 1%.

However, Escrow.com was down 24% to $209 million, mainly due to a fall in the China business as regulatory moves start to dampen property purchases.

This chart shows the drop off in business in China:

"We're confident that we've bottomed out here," CEO Matt Barrie told an analyst briefing.

Freelancer bought the the Californian-based site Escrow.com, which provides online escrow services including transaction management, in 2015.

Freelancer says its overall user base is still growing, adding 1.4 million in the six months to a total of nearly 25 million.

The half year results in detail:

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Matt Barrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
