<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406185219726642</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:32</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/burger-bun-anza-new-coast-burger-joint-sells-out/3207585/</url>
  <title>Burger bun-anza: New Coast burger joint sells out</title>
  <content>
IT'S almost eight months after opening his new cafe in Buderim and Shalom Persal is struggling to keep up with demand.
A bold transition from coffee and cakes to burgers has paid dividends, with hungry customers flocking to the shop which is part of the popular Middy's complex on Main St.
"It's taken off really fast, quicker than we thought," Spicy Butter owner Mr Persal said.
He was busy preparing for the lunch rush when we caught up with him.
He said the move had been made about two weeks ago and the business was still in the final stages of the transition, but it hadn't stopped punters piling in for a taste.
"We just sort of wanted to change it a bit and bring something else a bit different to Buderim," Mr Persal said.
Now open for lunch and dinner from Tuesday-Saturday, burger meals and ready-made meals are the mainstays of the menu.
Coffees are still available until about 5pm and for those with a sweet tooth, rest easy in the knowledge that home-made cakes and muffins aren't lost.
"We will get the cakes coming back soon," Mr Persal said.
Mr Persal was urgently conducting interviews and trials with new staff, having run the business alone with the help of family and friends.
His partner was assisting yesterday, but was juggling looking after their young kids at the same time.
The demand for his burgers has been such that it not only requires extra hands, but extra stock too.
"We ran out of everything on Friday," he said.
A couple of bread rolls and a few tomatoes were all that was left, forcing Mr Persal to close on Saturday.
"That won't happen again," he said with a laugh.
After eight months he said things were "looking a bit better now".
Opening from 11am-9pm, the menu was "simple" with four burgers and a lamb kebab on offer, as well as two kinds of fries and snacks for kids.
Mr Persal said the lamb kebab had proven most popular so far, with plenty of people grabbing a kebab containing 14-hour, slow-cooked lamb, tzatziki, tabouli, lettuce, tomato and onion.
"Everyone seems to be getting that," he said.
Gofundme set up for better mobility equipment and ongoing costs
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Persal</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spicy Butter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesdays-Saturdays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shalom Persal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
