<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406185219726685</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/changing-of-the-guard-at-scorchers-after-key-playe/3207583/</url>
  <title>Changing of the guard at Scorchers after key players leave</title>
  <content>
CRICKET: The Sunshine Coast has been dealt some significant off-season blows with the departures of several key players but coach Ashley Holznagel is optimistic their replacements can make the most of summer.
The Queensland Premier Grade side has lost all-rounder James Bazley, opening batsman Nick Selman and mainstay bowlers Ashley Renouf and Steven Heise, along with Kaden Dickfos and Jacob Dennien.
"It hurts the club but at the end of the day every club has player turnover. That's life and it's just a good opportunity for some of the younger ones," the coach said.
"We've got to try and get the best out of the players that we can...and as long as everyone playing buys into the team first mentality we'll be a competitive team."
But the loss of so many pivotal players leaves the Scorchers in a self-described "rebuilding" phase for 2017/2018.
"This year, because we're a young squad, there is going to be ups and downs but...in the next two to three years we'll definitely reap the benefits of that," Holznagel said.
"The biggest thing we've got to concentrate hard on this season is worrying about the process to get wins and not really put a huge emphasis on results."
The departure of Queensland Bulls-contracted local product Bazley to rival outfit Redlands is a tough one to take but that club is closer the young all-rounder's home and his state squad's training.
But perhaps the biggest hole to fill will be at the top of the order with Selmanset to play in Sydney, according to Holznagel.
The 21-year-old, who forged his skills on the Sunshine Coast, has shown some startling first-class form in England county cricket of late.
His century guided Glamorgan to a last-over win over Durham in June.
Meanwhile, seasoned wicket takers Renouf and Heise will play cricket at a suburban level, with the former taking on a captain/coach role at Nambour and the latter lacing-up at Glasshouse.
Holznagel is eager to build a side which is capable of supporting new skipper Alecz Day, who has taken over from Sam Gardiner.
"He's a dominant player. He's a very aggressive cricketer and that was shown last season when he finished third in the Peter Burge Medal (competition's best player standings)."
"He's a quality cricketer but we've just got to make sure we keep developing the blokes around him," he said.
The Scorchers boasts some shining prospects with state and national youth representatives Angus Lovell, Dean Elliott and Jarrod Sippel in the ranks.
"We'll be pretty young. It will be exciting," Holznagel said.
The coach hopes to see good things from top order batsmen Brandon Mahaffey and John Pechey and new ball bowlers Michael Goodluck and Tom Freshwater, many of who played for the club's minor premiership-winning team in second grade last season.
More established players like Wade Johnston, Kobi Griggs, Blake Maher and Gardiner will "have to take responsibility" in a squad which has a strong local flavour.
Gofundme set up for better mobility equipment and ongoing costs
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
Coast applauds decision to upgrade major venue
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
And so BYTE - the Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence - was born.
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Premier Grade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Bazley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaden Dickfos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angus Lovell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Sippel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Heise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alecz Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glasshouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Dennien</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glamorgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Selman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Holznagel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Durham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Pechey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Renouf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bazley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selmanset</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Burge Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Freshwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gardiner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wade Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Goodluck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Maher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kobi Griggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brandon Mahaffey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Gardiner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renouf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Bulls-contracted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holznagel</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
