<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406133680118165</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/victorian-universities-sexual-assault-statistics/8762822</url>
  <title>Universities accused of failing to help sexual assault victims as Victorian data released</title>
  <content>
Emma Hunt went along to a Monash University club event in the first weeks of semester, looking to make new friends - but says she woke up to find she was being raped by a fellow student.

Key points:

National survey shows half of university students nationwide say they have been sexually harassed
Of Victorian universities, La Trobe and Swinburne have the highest proportion of students who say they have been sexually harassed
2.3 per cent of Deakin students and 2.1 per cent of RMIT students say they have been assaulted at university, compared with the national average of 1.6 per cent

Members of the student committee did not take her to hospital, she said, instead putting her to bed, and when she woke up the next day it was as if nothing had happened.
"They didn't know what to do, so they did nothing," she said.
She later reported the alleged rape to the university and police, who are still investigating.
Ms Hunt was told she could switch classes to avoid her alleged rapist, but there was nothing the university could do to protect her from him in common areas on campus.
"I was worried about running into him anywhere, I was completely terrified of him," she said.
"I knew every single day that I came into campus there was a change that could happen, so my entire three-year degree, I was hyper vigilant about it.

External Link:

Tweet from EROCAustralia: If you've been affected by sexual violence in a uni community you can call 1800 572 224
"I know that is a reason why so many victims of sexual assault drop out of their universities, because universities across the country don't have anything in place to help survivors in that way so they feel they have no other choice than to drop out of uni."
While Ms Hunt is not alone in experiencing harassment and assault at university, although she is in the minority of victims who report it.
A survey by the Australian Human Rights Commission found half of student respondents nationwide said they had been sexually harassed, and about a quarter of them experienced harassment in a university setting.
In Victoria, 30 per cent of respondents from La Trobe University said they had been sexually harassed at university.
At Monash University, that figure was 28 per cent, and at RMIT, it was and 27 per cent.
Fifty-six per cent of survey respondents at La Trobe and Swinburne said they had been sexually harassed in the past year, but only 17 per cent of Swinburne students said it happened at university.

External Link:

Students harassed (%) in 2016
The survey also revealed the extent of sexual assaults experienced by university students. Nationally, 6.9 per cent of respondents said they had been sexually assaulted in the past two years.
Almost 9 per cent of La Trobe and Deakin students said they had been assaulted, and 2.3 per cent of Deakin students said the assault happened at the university.
RMIT students also experienced higher rates of sexual assault at university than the national average, at 2.1 per cent.

External Link:

Students assaulted (%) in 2015/16
However, the majority of harassment did not take place at university, but on public transport when students were travelling to and from campus.
Nationally, a little less than a quarter of students said they were sexually harassed on public transport.
In Victoria, that figure was much higher with nearly a third of students at RMIT, the University of Melbourne, and Swinburne stating they had been harassed on public transport.
At Victoria University, 40 per cent of students said they had been harassed.
University attendedSexually harassed on public transport to or from university
Victoria University40pc
University of Melbourne32pc
RMIT University32pc
Swinburne University32pc
Monash University27pc
La Trobe University25pc
Deakin University13pc
National average22pc
The report also found the vast majority of students who experienced sexual harassment and assault did not make a formal report, or seek any support services from their university.

Sexual assault support services:

National university support line: 1800 572 224 (until November 30, 2017)
1800 RESPECT: 1800 737 732
Lifeline: 131 114
Beyond Blue: 1300 224 636

Many said they did not believe it was serious enough to report.
Since being allegedly attacked, Ms Hunt has become an advocate for student safety, calling on universities to do more to prevent sexual assault and harassment.
She said victims did not know where to go, did not feel supported by universities, and 21-year-old student committee members were ill-equipped to deal with harassment and assault at off-campus events.
When she began speaking about her experience, Ms Hunt said she was met with disbelief, and a perception that university assault was a problem limited to colleges in the United States.
"Australian universities are fantastic at keeping their public reputation spick-and-span, and they don't let any of these things become public," she said.
"They shove it under the rug and they deal with it internally and very quietly."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hunt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RESPECT: 1800 737 732</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Trobe University25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria University, 40</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin University13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifty-six</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Trobe University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swinburne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University attendedSexually</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 30, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Trobe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue: 1300 224 636</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swinburne University32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EROCAustralia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT University32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
