<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406180924759196</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/south/women-in-drivers-seat-for-first-time-at-royal-adelaide-shows-v8-ute-challenge/news-story/04be04832831da3f608ba267199fcf59</url>
  <title>Women to compete for first time in show's V8 Ute Challenge</title>
  <content>
LISA Walker rarely has time to contemplate her status as South Australia's only female sprint racer.
She is far too busy taking on her male peers.
Next month the speedway champion will hit another milestone when she joins drift racer Kelly Wong in becoming the first women to ever compete in the Royal Adelaide Show's V8 Ute Challenge.
Walker was introduced to the world of motorsport at just nine years old by her father Darren, who watched on as the youngster climbed the ranks of go karting and, later, speedway racing.
"I grew up surrounded by guys in racing and I think because I started so young I didn't know any different," the Morphett Vale resident says.
"It has never bothered me too much but there does seem to be more girls coming into motor sports these days, which is great."
Professional drifter Wong put off buying her first street racing car because she was worried about entering a male-dominated sport.
"I held off for a long time because I was embarrassed but it turned out I was a natural," Wong, of Para Hills, says.
"The guys (drifters) are very supportive and it's more the male spectators on the sideline that might say, 'What's she doing here?' but that's because they're jealous it's not them doing it!"
Wong, who owns a car performance parts business in Para Hills West, is looking forward to returning to motorsports since welcoming son Kobe, 8 months, with husband, David.
"I can't wait to teach Kobe - I just bought him a little electric ride-on to put away until he's big enough," she says. "For me (the sport) is all about having fun.
"I'm really excited for the V8 Ute Challenge; it's kind of an honour to be asked."
And what do the women recommend to young girls looking to take up motorsports?
"Just give it a crack, have the confidence and don't let people discourage you," Walker says.
The Royal Adelaide Show runs from September 1-10.
Don't miss your copy of the official Royal Adelaide Show Guide in your Messenger on August 16.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kobe, 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KOBE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wong, of Para</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Show's V8 Ute Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V8 Ute Challenge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Para Hills West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LISA Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphett Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Show Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messengers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
