<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406103615346621</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/kkrs-ed-bostock-goes-west-20170801-gxn2z5</url>
  <title>Wesfarmers appoints KKR's Ed Bostock to plum role</title>
  <content>
Wesfarmers has appointed KKR's Ed Bostock as its new head of business development, a move that many will interpret as a sign that the Perth-based conglomerate is ready to do some deals.
Wesfarmers staff were informed of the appointment on Tuesday, and it's seen as the latest shake-up ahead of incoming chief executive Rob Scott, w, taking the reins from Richard Goyder in November.
Bostock joined KKR in 2007 and represented KKR on the board of credit cards and personal loans company Latitude Financial Services (formally known as GE Money in Australia and New Zealand) and forestry management business, Santanol. 
He previously looked after KKR's investment in Seven West Media and cancer care provider GenesisCare. 

For those in Perth that like to keep an eye on board links, there's some that question how much of a hand chairman Michael Chaney, who is considered to be relatively close to Kerry Stokes, had in the appointment of one of KKR's former representative in the Seven West deal. 

Internally, Bostock's appointment is being interpreted as significant in that it shows the business development role is being taken seriously.
Wesfarmers' decision to recruit a private equity operative comes weeks after its former chief financial officer
Street Talk has contacted representatives from KKR and Wesfarmers.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>KKR's Ed Bostock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Chaney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GenesisCare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Goyder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerry Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KKR</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santanol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bostock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latitude Financial Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven West Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesfarmers</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GE Money</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
