<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406180924759240</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/smokers-in-oakleighs-eaton-mall-being-forced-to-butt-out-after-tough-new-laws-introduced/news-story/ab02d5737f8baf04426c09478d79ae70</url>
  <title>Smokers fuming over new laws</title>
  <content>
SMOKERS in Oakleigh's popular Eaton Mall have been forced to butt out - and many are fuming, with some refusing to comply with tough new laws.
As of today, changes to the Tobacco Act 1987 ban smoking in all outdoor dining areas across the state.
When the Monash Leader visited the mall, several people were seen lighting up in designated smoking areas, but smoke was drifting towards people eating outside.
Meat Me worker Dimitri Baklavas said he was angered by the laws.
"It's just ridiculous because it's my choice to my smoke, and now I might as well stay home as I can't eat and smoke anywhere," Mr Baklavas said.
"It's really affected my social life and I don't think it's right to take away people's freedom."
Lorraine Evans, of Oakleigh, said the smoking bans were "well overdue".
"It's been a smoking overload here in Oakleigh for a long time. It's the smoking capital and I'm not down with this law of still being able to smoke with snacks and coffee," Ms Evans said.
"I don't think anyone will follow these new laws."
Dallas Goldburg, of Oakleigh, said the new laws were "confusing".
"There's very little signage and I'm yet to see council officers around enforcing these laws," Mr Goldburg said.
"There are venues around here using tomato tins as ashtrays and they should be brought to justice with the new laws."
However, Nikos Cakes manager Yianni Poupouzas said he not had any problems.
"Everyone's received it quite well and we haven't had any complaints from anyone so it's all been positive," Mr Poupouzas said.
"It's a good outcome for our business because we're not going to lose any customers this way."
Cr Geoff Lake said the new laws have made little impact, and not led to a smoke-free environment at the mall.
"Every family with their baby in a pram will be blanketed by Melbourne's worst location for passive smoke," Cr Lake said.
People can still smoke at venues when they are not serving meals.
A designating smoking space must be separated from outdoor dining areas by either a 4m buffer zone or a wall at least 2.1m high.
Monash Council has been contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikos Cakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Goldburg, of Oakleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Geoff Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tobacco Act 1987</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Poupouzas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorraine Evans, of Oakleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Goldburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dimitri Baklavas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eaton Mall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yianni Poupouzas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Baklavas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
