<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405313341352461</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/12/46/adelaide-archbishop-ian-george-investigated</url>
  <title>Former archbishop probed over how disgraced priest John Mounford fled Adelaide in 1992</title>
  <content>
Former Adelaide archbishop Ian George is reportedly under investigation over whether he played a role in encouraging a disgraced priest to flee the country.
South Australia Police has launched fresh investigation into the events leading to former St Peter's College priest and accused sex offender John Mountford fleeing Australia in 1992 after he was sacked from the college amid allegations of sexual abuse.
Senior policeman Grant Stevens  a police probe had been launched to investigate whether any of those who may have been involved in Mountford's rapid exit perverted the court of justice or impeded an investigation into his activities.
The disgraced priest fled Adelaide for Bali on June 6, 1992 after admitting to the sexual abuse of a Year 10 student.
He allegedly flew out within hours of being visited by then archbishop George, a chain of events detailed in the  into the Adelaide diocese's handling of sexual abuse allegations.
There have been allegations Mr George, who resigned as archbishop in 2004 in the aftermath of the report, had encouraged Mountford to escape - a claim he has repeatedly denied.
Commissioner Stevens said police had been referred an "additional perspective" by the Royal Commission into Institutional Responses to Child Sexual Abuse but would not comment further on the subjects of the probe.

Related Articles

"In fairness to those who are involved in this investigation, regardless of what's in the paper and what speculation is around, it wouldn't be appropriate for me to actually nominate anybody who might be a subject of an investigation," Commissioner Stevens said.
"The obligation of the South Australian police is to look at the referral from the royal commission as to whether anybody has perverted the course of justice or aided a person who has committed a serious crime to flee justice.
"So we will look at that and we will examine the parts of anybody who was involved."
Following his rapid 1992 exit, Mountford was extradited in 2005 to face trial from Thailand but the charges were withdrawn by the Director of the Public Prosecutions (DPP) due to the alleged victim being unfit to provide evidence on account of mental and physical illness.
He left Adelaide again in 2009 before he was murdered in Libya in 2009.
Commissioner Stevens said he could not put a timeline on the investigation.
"The fact a matter is referred to a royal commission gives a new lens on the information that is available and a royal commission is able to probe in a different way to what a police investigation is able to probe," he said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Mounford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissioner Stevens</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director of the Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Peter's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Child Sexual Abuse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Mountford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Institutional Responses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
