<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406137975085561</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/trivia-team-asked-not-to-play-at-hotel-because-they-win-too-often/news-story/e510f033aeda058c64eb2dea936a83a4</url>
  <title>Trivia dispute as team asked to leave</title>
  <content>
A BRISBANE trivia team has been left flabbergasted after they were asked not to play at a hotel because they might scare away new contestants.

Team Flora was ready to participate in a trivia night at the Prince of Wales Hotel on Sandgate Rd in Nundah last week when the host placed a letter from Harry on their table.

After first stating how much he appreciated the long-term team's loyalty and support, Harry, who does not use his surname, then pointed out they had also been a main winner of cash and prizes over the years and asked for a "favour."

"If one experienced team is dominant over all the other new teams, then the venue is doomed," he wrote.

"Can I please ask you to continue playing at an established Harry's Trivia venue, and give the Prince of Wales a chance to settle in?"

Harry pointed out it could take up to six months to establish new trivia locations before saying he did not think the venue would last two months if Team Flora started playing there.

One of Team Flora's six members, Geoff Nicholson, said the group had only played at the hotel for three weeks, as the Wednesday night venue was better for a new team member.

Previously, they mainly played in West End or at the Windsor Bowls Club.

Mr Nicholson, 46, the husband of News Corp journalist Jennifer Dudley-Nicholson, of Newmarket, said the team members were "a little bit shocked" by the letter.

"We didn't expect to go to trivia and get handed a letter saying I'd appreciate it if you didn't play there," he said.

"It's like saying you can't come to the casino any more because you're taking all our money.

"But I took it has a backhanded compliment. ... I'm more amused than anything."

Mr Nicholson, who has been a member of a trivia team since 2005, said although he could sympathise with Harry's request, he would have preferred to have received an email or phone call.

Over the years, Mr Nicholson guessed the team could have won a combined total of about $25,000 worth of cash, meal and drink vouchers.

"I don't really have a big issue with whether we win or lose, I just go and answer the questions," he said.

Harry, who operates trivia nights throughout the city on different nights, did not return calls seeking comment.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windsor Bowls Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team Flora</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry's Trivia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince of Wales</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nicholson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Dudley-Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newmarket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandgate Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nundah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nicholson, 46</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
