<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405309046385073</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/marriage/former-cheerleader-and-state-attorney-finalise-trump-divorce-with-press-release/news-story/a24be43cce9c041d66932e2bb3744dd3</url>
  <title>Former Cheerleader and State Attorney finalise 'Trump divorce' with press release</title>
  <content>
Trump tweets his 'disappointment' in China
0:24

US President Donald Trump says in the tweet he's 'very disappointed' in China for doing nothing on Nth Korea

July 30th 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/Politics/

President Donald Trump has been cited as a reason for a high couple profile's divorce. Picture: AP Photo/Alex Brandon, File)

Share

A FORMER Miami Dolphins cheerleader turned PR expert has settled her "Trump divorce" with her lawyer husband, saying her support for the President left her "isolated in the marriage".
Republican , who runs her own public relations agency,  declaring an "amicable" end to her relationship in "what some were calling the Trump divorce".
"After much consideration over the past few months, we've decided to respectfully and amicably part ways and end our marriage. We are, however, dedicated to remaining close friends. We kindly ask for your support in preserving our privacy as we start to navigate this new chapter of our lives," .
It went on to describe how she would receive "about $100,000 worth of benefits in exchange for her signature on the dotted line" and candidly explained she would get a new BMW and $40,000 in cash.

Trump with Lynn Aronberg in a picture from her Facebook account. Picture: Facebook.Source:Supplied
Her husband, Democrat Dave Aronberg, who serves as State Attorney for Florida, was now "eyeing a run" for US Congress it said. The statement also addressed their lack of children and conflicting political ideas as part of the reason behind the split.
"They have no children, which was a problem for Lynn: She said she wanted children, but Aronberg was in no hurry," the statement said.
"A staunch Republican and supporter of President Donald Trump, Lynn also said she felt increasingly isolated in the marriage."

With now First Lady Melania Trump. Picture: Facebook.Source:Supplied
Their different political opinions had apparently been a source of tension for the couple in the past, The Washington Post reports.
While her former husband had reportedly known the President well and attended fundraisers at his Florida home, Mar-a-Lago, she told the  her propensity for selfies with members of the Trump family became a problem for his liberal base.

"I'm walking through the red carpet, and he's sneaking through the bushes," she said about pictures she had with Trump and Melania.
"He'd ask me to not to take pictures. He wouldn't want me to post them," she said.
"I did not listen to him."
Mr Aronberg said via a spokesman he was "ready to just close this chapter" of his life.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FORMER Miami Dolphins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mar-a-Lago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Aronberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP Photo/Alex Brandon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Lady Melania Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nth Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aronberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook.Source</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynn Aronberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrat Dave Aronberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Attorney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/Politics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
