<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406133680118142</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/banana-and-masterchef-used-as-code-words-in-sulayman-khalidled-terror-plot-20170801-gxms90.html</url>
  <title>'Banana' and 'Masterchef' used as code words in Sulayman Khalid-led terror plot</title>
  <content>
Inside a suburban garage, a group of young men talked about motorbikes, parties, weddings and Masterchef.
This was not small talk between friends, but a coded terrorist plot to attack an Australian Federal Police building, Lithgow jail, and engage in warfare in a forest to "achieve martyrdom".Photo: YouTube
The six young men also used words like "banana" and "motorbike" for guns, "party" for a terror attack, "wombat hole" for their meeting place, and "China" for fighting with Islamic State overseas.
Sulayman Khalid, 22, Jibyrl Almaouie, 23, and a 16-year-old, who cannot be identified, in preparation for a terrorist act in the NSW Supreme Court on Monday.

Farhad Said, 25, and Mohamed Almaouie, 21, earlier admitted to possessing documents connected with the preparation of a terrorist act.
A sixth man, 21-year-old Ibrahim Ghazzawy​, pleaded guilty to possessing documents in 2016 and was jailed for at least six years and four months.

Justice Geoffrey Bellew​ lifted long-standing non-publication orders on the case, revealing the group's clandestine methods of discussing and planning an attack in late 2014.
The men were being monitored by counter-terror investigators who de-coded their conversations in text messages, phone calls, and during meetings in ringleader Khalid's Regents Park garage, known to the group as the "wombat hole".Photo: Supplied
According to a statement of facts tendered at Ghazzawy's sentencing in May, he was a member of the "Khalid group" and adhered to the religious ideology Wahhabi-Salafism, which inspires Islamic State.
During raids in December 2014, police found several documents in a black suitcase in Khalid's garage, which he used as his bedroom.Photo: Supplied
One note described an attack on an AFP building in the city or Parramatta.
"Helicopters and all that so we are going to fight till shahada [an Islamic creed] anyway so we might as well do something major," the note read.
Another document described plans for "gorilla" warfare.
"The plan is gorilla (sic) warfare ... we are going to go to the woods and attack the dogs there, Blue Mountains and the surrounding forests."
A third document identified Lithgow jail as a target.
"Insha Allah if we make progress we will attack it," the note said.
A torn and screwed up note found in Khalid's kitchen described 350 litres of fuel for "motorbikes" and mentioned "long ones" and "short ones".
Khalid also sent text messages in November relating to training for an attack.
"We're gonna try to get in the master chefs competition. It depends what the master chefs conditions are cause there a lot of mad chefs out there that know how to cook pasta then u got chicken lamb sheep all kinds of nice tender foods," he wrote.
Prosecutors' statement of facts described the notes as serious.
"The documents demonstrate an active and real consideration of the type of terrorist act contemplated, and its target. They outline different methods for the commission of one or more acts of terrorism and set out possible targets."
Ghazzawy told a psychologist he felt "uncomfortable" after the group's meetings, and went along with it because he didn't want to feel like a "nothing person".
"I didn't want anyone to think bad of me," he said.
The four men and the teenager awaiting sentencing will face a three-day hearing in October.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Almaouie, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khalid's Regents Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ibrahim Ghazzawy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterchef</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sulayman Khalid-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farhad Said, 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khalid</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sulayman Khalid, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wahhabi-Salafism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lithgow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jibyrl Almaouie, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Geoffrey Bellew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ghazzawy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
