<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406137975085658</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/police-raids-uncover-dozens-of-coast-crimes/3207579/</url>
  <title>Police raids uncover dozens of Coast crimes</title>
  <content>
ALMOST a dozen people have been busted for drug and property crimes after a string of Coast police raids over recent weeks.
Kawana Waters Police, along with the Sunshine Coast District Tactical Crime Squad, undertook 10 search warrants on homes in Wurtulla, Warana, Buddina, Aroona, Currimundi and Little Mountain, resulting in 11 offenders being charged with 29 drug and property-related offences.
Officer in Charge of Kawana Waters Police Station, Senior Sergeant Mark Cordwell said the public played a pivotal role in catching the offenders.
"Significant information was provided by members of the public, which greatly assisted police in identifying suspect persons and addresses and, ultimately, in taking this enforcement action," Snr Sgt Cordwell said.
"This assistance is appreciated and helps police in detecting those people involved in drug activity."
All offenders will face court in coming weeks.
Gofundme set up for better mobility equipment and ongoing costs
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
A MAN in his 50s is being treated by paramedics
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charge of Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waters Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast District Tactical Crime Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana Waters Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aroona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wurtulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snr Sgt Cordwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currimundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Mark Cordwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Mountain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
