<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406180924759289</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/nikorima-edges-out-marshall-for-halfback-spot-as-hunt-takes-injured-mcculloughs-no-9/news-story/e66e0a5f835a3313d8e1ad1bb85694a2</url>
  <title>Bennett shows faith in Nikorima</title>
  <content>
Cowboys face tough assignment

WAYNE Bennett has challenged Kodi Nikorima to pilot Brisbane to the premiership as the Broncos super coach searches for a title-winning formula without injured hooker Andrew McCullough.

Bennett has handed McCullough's No. 9 jumper to Ben Hunt, opening the door for Nikorima, who has edged out Benji Marshall at halfback for Saturday night's derby against the Titans at Robina.

Just five weeks ago, Nikorima's dream of being Brisbane's next long-term halfback appeared in tatters after he was hooked by Bennett in the Broncos' 30-20 defeat of the Raiders in Canberra.

But with McCullough to undergo surgery on Friday on a season-ending knee injury, Bennett is backing a Nikorima-Hunt half-hooker alliance to snap Brisbane's 11-year title drought.

Bennett gave serious consideration to handing the No. 7 jumper to Marshall, whose class and cool head hauled Brisbane out of trouble when Nikorima was benched against the Raiders.

But with Marshall likely to quit the Broncos at season's end, Bennett wants to invest in Nikorima's future and is giving the 23-year-old a golden chance to prove he can steer Brisbane to premiership glory.

"This is Kodi's chance," Bennett told The Courier-Mail.

"It's not a fill-in position right now, it's a permanent decision and I need to make a permanent call on our halfback and hooker so we can get on with the rest of the season and do our best.

"I want Kodi to know I have the confidence in him to do the job.

"If Kodi is going to play good football for us, he needs to know where he stands.

"Kodi was good at halfback for us earlier this year (when Hunt was sidelined with a hamstring injury).

"I'm giving Kodi the opportunity to be the halfback for the rest of the season and hopefully it helps his development leading into next year."

Nikorima has had mixed success in the No. 7 jumper this season.

He was outstanding between rounds 7-11, winning five straight games while Hunt recovered from a hamstring injury.

But when Hunt was cleared to return, only to later be axed to feeder-club Ipswich, Nikorima failed to take charge as starting halfback in wins over Souths and the Raiders.

Bennett admits the loss of McCullough is significant but said Hunt is a handy Plan B after he spent the first five seasons of his career operating as Brisbane's Mr Fixit off the bench.

The super coach will consider Sam Thaiday, Alex Glenn and Josh McGuire as back-up options if Hunt cannot get through the full 80 minutes against the Titans.

"It's not ideal having to make your halfback your hooker but at the same time we have some depth with our playmaking options," Bennett said.

"Ben has played a lot of games at hooker from the interchange bench. He played his first 100 games for the Broncos as a utility, he is very experienced at it and he is our best option right now."

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benji Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kodi</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCullough's No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikorima</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raiders</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Thaiday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Glenn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marshall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kodi Nikorima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCullough</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McCullough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Mr Fixit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plan B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikorima-Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
