<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406133680118161</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/city/a-character-bungalow-in-prospect-with-a-tennis-court-on-a-separate-title-is-sas-most-popular-listing/news-story/0889a17589527493d111c4074f25daa0</url>
  <title>A character bungalow in Prospect with a tennis court on a separate title, is SA's most popular listing. - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
4 Clifford St, Prospect.

A RENOVATOR's delight in Prospect with an overgrown tennis court, which is also up for sale separately was South Australia's most clicked-on property on realestate.com.au last week.
The sandstone bungalow at  has a 780sqm former tennis court, which sits on its own title. They are being auctioned separately by Ray White Unley's Blake Scholz and Josh Gillespie on August 19.
"These are two separate allotments, the land was a tennis court and is on a separate title," Mr Scholz says.

The overgrown tennis court next to the house.

The three-bedroom house, which is in original condition and on a 660sqm block, is being marketed with a price guide of $620,000. The 780sqm land has a guide of $500,000.

4 Clifford St, Prospect.

Mr Scholz says he is not surprised to hear of the listing's popularity.
"It's a pretty tightly-held suburb and there is a lot of scope there," he says.
"There's a character home, which is very popular, but also a block next door for people that want to make one large land holding or subdivide. There's just a lot of opportunity.
"The land is an entry-level price for that suburb."

4 Clifford St, Prospect.

Mr Scholz says he's fielded about 50 to 60 inquiries, including some from the eastern states, about the properties with most asking about the potential of subdivision and how the titles will work.
"It's pretty unique (the listing), I've probably only sold something like it twice before," Mr Scholz says.
"There's been quite a wide range of interest.
"I think it will sell to two different people, someone will build a house on the land and build or renovate the existing house."

4 Clifford St, Prospect.

The home, which sits on a 660sqm block with a 16.76m frontage, has three bedrooms, two bathrooms, formal and informal living areas, a timber kitchen and a landscaped backyard with established plants, an alfresco entertainment space and paving.
The separate block meanwhile, is approximately 19.8m wide and has a 39m depth.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Gillespie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scholz</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clifford St</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Unley's Blake Scholz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
