<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406180924759285</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/transport/automobile/crash-repairer-ama-group-expects-more-bingles-in-sydney-20170801-gxmqx8</url>
  <title>Panel beaters can't keep up in western Sydney </title>
  <content>
The $500 million crash repair firm AMA Group is expecting a rise in the number of bingles in western Sydney as it prepares to open three new greenfields sites, but will adopt a "wait" approach on ailing Automotive Solutions Group after snaring 31 per cent in a takeover.
AMA Group, run by entrepreneur Ray Malone, made a cheeky zero premium bid in May for ASG, a four-wheel drive and sports utility vehicle company that listed on the ASX in late December after a buy-up of eight separate businesses.
ASG downgraded its profits in late April just four months after listing with an issue price of $1. ASG is one of a number of ASX companies that have been lumped in the "dud float" category, , which stunned investors by downgrading profits on July 31 after just five weeks.
ASG is now under serious pressure to deliver on a turnaround plan built around using a single brand across its business rather than running separate branded entities in their local markets, cost-cutting and  But predator AMA has backed off for now.

AMA secured 31.3 per cent in its bid for ASG pitched at 35¢ a share. The bid has now closed and ASG's share price on Tuesday had slipped to 29.5¢, meaning investors are sitting on unwelcome paper losses.

An ASG quarterly report to the ASX on July 31 showed the company's cash receipts in the three months ended June 30, 2017 were $10.6 million, and outgoings were $9.81 million.
The AMA directors say the company "proposes to wait" for the outcome of the ASG turnaround strategy and will hold the board and management accountable for their performance against their projected forecasts and intentions.
But while AMA has adopted a patient approach when it comes to ASG, it has been accelerating fast in expansion of its core crash repairs business. ASG had more than 80 crash repair sites in its existing stable, and in mid-July revealed it had acquired a further seven vehicle repair centres that would deliver a combined $22.5 million in revenue.
The company, following talks with insurance companies, has also agreed to open three new sites in Sydney, at Narellan and Lansvale in the outer west and at Banksmeadow near Botany.

The company also said that talks were continuing with "insurer partners" on opening more greenfields sites and "we anticipate announcing further new sites over the next quarter".
ASG directors pleaded with their shareholders during the takeover bid not to sell out because the AMA offer of 35¢ did not represent full value, and used the P/E multiples at which much larger and more experienced rivals such as ARB Corporation and were trading to try to convince them to hold on.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lansvale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Automotive Solutions Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/E</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banksmeadow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Malone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narellan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARB Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASG</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
