<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406266824106609</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/university-sexual-assault-report:-anu-students-discuss-results/8763932</url>
  <title>University sexual assaults: What students say about revelations</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

The Human Rights Commission has released a damning report on sexual assaults at Australia's universities.
With more than half of all students reporting being sexually harassed in 2016 and almost 7 per cent being sexually assaulted over the past two years,
The Australian National University reported on-campus sexual assault rates at
Here's what students there made of the report:
Asante Addai, student

"It should start from school, just education about things like consent/ I think it all starts from school.
In Civic I hear about [sexual assault], people are aware of it, but not here on campus."
Eugenie Kim, student

"I went to an all girls school and we would always learn about consent but I obviously can't speak for everyone on campus because we are all from very different places - so I just don't know if everyone is aware of that."
Andrew Topp, student

"Residential colleges are kind of like a hotbed for this sort of stuff and I think it's the attitude that a lot of students take towards consent - especially being away from home for the first time ... I think that's a significant factor."
Nathalie Blakely, student and women's officer

"I'm not shocked, I have to say.
The university is acting now ... in the past it has been a historical failure that this has been happening to many students on campus
Declan and Shane McInerney, students

Declan:

"I don't really notice it. I'm sort of aware of it ... the numbers are still surprising."
Shane:

"I'm pretty blind to it, I haven't seen anything really. I've only been here one semester.
When you're put together with heaps of people and there's alcohol there and everyone's having a good time something's bound to happen. I've seen it with my friends."
Remy Wendel, student

"Half of us here have apparently been sexually harassed in the past year - that's scary."
Rishi Dhakshinamoorthy and Woody Rolph, students

Rishi:

"I did think it will happen more in clubs and going out places and stuff like that, but I didn't expect it to happen that often in universities."
Woody:

"There are a lot of residential colleges because lots of ANU students come from other places, whereas other universities have more local students where sexual assault obviously wouldn't happen on campus as much without residential colleges."
Jill Molloy, National Union of Students welfare officer

"With ANU, the unique issue is the high amount of students at college and living on campus. I myself went to a college here at ANU and we were never taught about consent or anything like that.
The fight doesn't stop today, it only starts."

Sexual assault support services:

National university support line: 1800 572 224 (until November 30, 2017)
1800 RESPECT: 1800 737 732
Lifeline: 131 114
Beyond Blue: 1300 224 636

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Remy Wendel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Topp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rishi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asante Addai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RESPECT: 1800 737 732</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Declan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Union of Students</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eugenie Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathalie Blakely</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rishi Dhakshinamoorthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 30, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue: 1300 224 636</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woody Rolph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Molloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane McInerney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
