<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406223874432920</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/antieuthanasia-group-targets-vic-mp/news-story/6e305cf52e550f7c180fe06d1b71b9ff</url>
  <title>Anti-euthanasia flyer sparks Vic MP abuse</title>
  <content>
A Victorian government MP and his staff have copped abuse from people confused by a Right To Life brochure campaigning against Labor's proposed assisted dying laws.
Member for Bentleigh Nick Staikos says he has "total disgust" for the group's campaign.
The abuse started on Monday with phone calls to his electorate office and tweets including: " if you ever send this to my house again I will f*** you up. Your ignorance is overwhelming. F***ing idiot."
The Right To Life brochure reads: "Do you believe in suicide prevention or suicide assistance from a doctor?"
It also contains Mr Staikos' contact information in large, bold type.
The Right To Life contact information is in much smaller print, on the back of the brochure.
"I can see why people think it's from me," Mr Staikos told AAP on Tuesday.
"If it wasn't the intention from the Right To Life group to make it look like the brochure came from me, it looks like an attempt to hide who it is from."
Mr Staikos says he is undecided on his party's move to legislate voluntary assisted dying for the terminally ill, which is expected to go to a conscience vote later in 2017.
He is consulting constituents, doctors and faith leaders to make up his mind.
"I have no interest in what Right To Life has to say other than to express my total disgust in their tactics here in my electorate," he said.
"As any backbench member of parliament, a conscience vote is probably the most important decision I will make.
"This is a matter of life or death and every member of parliament needs to make sure they're making the right decision."
He called for a respectful debate of the issue.
The Andrews Labor government hopes to introduce legislation to parliament that would allow terminally ill Victorians to choose when they die, in accordance with strict guidelines including that they have less than 12 months to live.
Right To Life have been contacted for comment.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Right To Life</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-euthanasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleigh Nick Staikos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Staikos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
