<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405704183381688</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/the-economy/rba-holds-cash-rate-at-record-low-15-in-august-20170731-gxmplz.html</url>
  <title>RBA holds cash rate at record low 1.5% in August</title>
  <content>
Reserve Bank has kept its cash rate on hold at a record low of 1.5 per cent , providing little indication of when it will allow rates to rise.
The decision at Tuesday's board meeting comes ahead of the release of the bank's Quarterly Statement on Monetary Policy which is expected to explain more of the board's thinking on Friday.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Super Wednesday to drive the AUD

Itas a big day of event risk on Wednesday with RBA governor Philip Lowe and Q2 CPI holding the potential to drive real volatility. (This video was produced in commercial partnership between Fairfax Media and IG Markets).

The decision came as the Australian dollar climbed back above US80¢, the second time in two weeks it has broken the threshold to trade at a two-year high.
Since the cash rate has been on hold, mortgage rates have been edging higher, particularly for investors and interest-only loans.

Tim Lawless, head of research at the property data firm CoreLogic said higher mortgage rates against a backdrop of record high household debt were gradually taking some heat out of the housing market without the Reserve Bank needing to act.
"With headline inflation tracking slightly below the 2 to 3 per cent target range, labour markets tightening and the economy continuing to grow, albeit at a pace below trend, the chances of a rate cut appear to have diminished," he said, adding that hikes might be some way off as well.Photo: Louie Douvis
Recent declines in the US dollar and strengthening commodity prices have placed added pressure on the Australian dollar. Financial markets believe the cash rate won't rise until late 2018.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Lawless</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IG Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quarterly Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q2 CPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
