<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406095025411773</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/lifestyle/health/mens-health/how-an-unwanted-gift-saved-me-from-advanced-bowel-cancer-20170731-gxmq3l</url>
  <title>How an unwanted gift saved me from advanced bowel cancer</title>
  <content>
When Tony Peake received a gift from the government on his 50th birthday, he opened the envelope, baulked at its contents and discarded it.
It was a bowel cancer test kit and Peake, a senior partner at PwC in Melbourne, had no intention of using it. The idea of providing two samples of faecal matter and sending them back for examination "grossed" him out.
The test detects hidden blood in faecal matter. This can be an ominous sign and Peake wanted nothing to do with it. He felt too fit and too young to worry about such things.
So he forgot about the gift until his wife, a doctor and "annoyingly compliant", ordered him a and firmly encouraged him to use it.

Supplied

She prevailed. A reluctant Peake posted off the samples and again forgot about the matter.

He didn't know about 80 Australians died each week from bowel cancer and that 92 per cent of them were over 50.
Neither did he know that bowel cancer could remain silent for a long time and that most people diagnosed with it had few, if any, symptoms.
As he had zero symptoms, he never worried about the test until the phone rang a couple of weeks later.
"It was my GP who wasn't in the habit of making social calls. He said both samples had come back positive for blood. He explained in most cases it is nothing but I need to have a colonoscopy."

Sebastian Kaulitzki

The polyp's presence

Once Peake understood that the presence of blood didn't necessarily mean cancer as it could have come from another source such as a tear or a haemorrhoid, he wasn't overly worried.
"There's a lot of mythology around men having a colonoscopy or the finger test for prostate cancer but having had the former, it was pretty much nothing."
Except that a 30mm polyp was discovered in his descending colon near his rectum. Rather than removing it, the doctor referred him to another specialist for another colonoscopy.

Peake still wasn't too fussed and was even less so when he woke from the second colonoscopy and the specialist said he'd taken it out in one piece and it appeared fine.
He gave Peake a photo. The polyp looked like a small, completely white finger of skin.
But if it was white, how could it bleed? As it turned out it hadn't bled at all. The blood had come from small, asymptomatic haemorrhoids, just inside his rectum.
The polyp went to a pathologist and Peake promptly went to Adelaide on business.  While he was there, the specialist called. They needed to talk.

"As he was telling me the bad news I had this surreal feeling. I listened intently, but at the same time I was panicking in the back of my head," Peake says.
"I was having this parallel conversation with myself which went: 'F--k, I've got cancer'... 'I can't believe I'm having this conversation'... 'How am I going to tell my wife and the girls?'... 'I might be in real trouble here'.
"Over the next few days I tried to compartmentalise the anxiety and tell myself nothing I can do will change the situation. I tried to cope with it myself but I was scared. I was also very lucky, however, to have a spouse who is a doctor because every time I had a question she would give me a data point."
Good news

In Australia, nine out of 10 cases of bowel cancer can be successfully treated and once back in Melbourne, Peake saw a surgeon who told him what he needed to hear.
"He was terrific and sold me heavily on the positives, saying this was very solvable. He painted a rosy picture telling me how curable early bowel cancer can be."
 A CT scan suggested his cancer had not spread and the surgeon booked him in to have a section of bowel removed a few weeks later.
When Peake told some close friends and colleagues, the news went viral. His firm was tremendously supportive. "There are two times when PwC is magnificent - when there is illness and when someone is going through a tough circumstance with a client."
What really pleased Peake was that his news prompted many others to have the test too. Those not eligible for a free government test could buy one for about $30.
Meanwhile, a relieved Peake took his family on a wonderfully distracting pre-booked holiday to Japan.
The day after he returned, he went into hospital to face the reality, which was grimmer than he remembered. The surgeon explained he would take out a long length of bowel, and its associated lymph nodes and blood supply.
Depending on what he found, Peake would or would not need to have a stoma bag, temporarily or permanently.

This was a shock but there was no alternative but to go through with it.
The procedure went well. Through a keyhole, the surgeon removed a 40cm section of bowel surrounding the tumour. No stoma bag was necessary and the pathology came back clear.
Passing the message on

Peake was cancer-free and didn't need chemotherapy or any other treatment.
During recovery, he reflected on what that 50th birthday gift had meant.
"Some years, while compiling my tax return, I have fleetingly felt aggrieved at the amount of tax I've paid - don't we all! - and I've wondered what the government has ever done for me."
With that question now clearly redundant, he turned his mind to the fact that  actually used it. What could he do to try to improve this?
He decided to tell his story in the hope that at least 10  more people would not discard their free test.

Research has shown that people invited to screen through the  have a 15 per cent lower risk of dying from bowel cancer and are more likely to have less-advanced bowel cancers when diagnosed, than those who are not invited.
The program began in 2006 and over the next 10 years, more than 3.5 million Australians were screened.  Of them, close to 6000 were found to have suspected or confirmed cancers.
A further 15,000 were diagnosed with advanced benign tumours that had the potential to become cancerous.
Peake, who is on non-profit boards including Methodist Ladies' College, The University of Melbourne and the Business/Higher Education Roundtable, took two months off.
Now that he is back at work, he is not shy to tell people that if they receive a test, it could be the best thing the government has done for them.
As the national government and public sector leader at PwC, he sees no conflict in sharing his story and advice as this service is offered by the Department of Health regardless of the government of the day.
Since his diagnosis,  Peake has learnt that not only his grandfather, but his great grandfather too died of bowel cancer.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PwC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Peake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Methodist Ladies' College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business/Higher Education Roundtable</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Kaulitzki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peake</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
