<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405914636782316</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/sandringham-hospital-opens-new-15-million-special-care-nursery-for-premature-and-ill-babies/news-story/2b55912f32ea0348eedbb6b4f202b398</url>
  <title>Nursery for tiniest patients reborn</title>
  <content>
PREMATURE babies needing specialist care have a new home at Sandringham Hospital.
A $1.5 million special care nursery in the public hospital's booming maternity wing was officially opened by Health Minister Jill Hennessy this morning.
The Women's at Sandringham's new refurbished nursery can also take up to eight babies, while the previous nursery only had room for six.
Ms Hennessy said it was important to have vital health facilities close to the families that needed them.
Sandringham Hospital's catchment covers Bayside and neighbouring Caulfield and Port Phillip.
"(These are) facilities that are wrapped not only around our babies as patients but our families that we have to care for them."
The hospital's acting chief executive Lisa Dunlop said the upgraded nursery allowed babies to get hospital care closer to home, minimising the time they were separated from their families.
"Over time, the Women's at Sandringham will be able to increase its capacity to manage more complex cases, reducing the need for some women, with a preterm baby, having to be transferred to the Women's at Parkville or Monash Health," Ms Dunlop said.
Second-time mother Rachael Read gave birth to Ambrose two-and-half months ago.
Born 12 weeks' premature, he weighed just 733g at birth.
They spent nine weeks at The Women's in Parkville before arriving at Sandringham two weeks ago.
"It's beautiful and new. We've been one of the first to make it messy. It's awesome," Ms Read said.
More than 1600 babies a year are born in Sandringham Hospital's maternity wing.
The Women's took over the special care services in September last year, caring for 141 babies since then.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Phillip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachael Read</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hennessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Jill Hennessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Dunlop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandringham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambrose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandringham Hospital</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Dunlop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
