<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406275414041368</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:53</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/cricket/tony-dodemaide-steps-down-as-new-six-plan-to-challenge-cricket-victoria-board-20170801-gxn4nw.html</url>
  <title>Tony Dodemaide steps down as 'New Six' plan to challenge Cricket Victoria board</title>
  <content>
Cricket Victoria chief executive Tony Dodemaide has revealed he plans to step down, coming at a time when a rival ticket wants to challenge the governing body's board of directors.
Dodemaide, 53, told the CV board on Monday night of his plans to quit in April next year, when the new Victorian Cricket and Community Centre at the Junction Oval will be finished.
As reported by Fairfax Media in April, there has been agitation for change from former players and Premier club officials for some time, and this has culminated with former Victorian players Geoff Richardson and Phil Hyde, along with Essendon Cricket Club president Simon Tobin, former Prahran president David Jones, former WACA delegate Peter Williams and Melbourne Cricket Club committee member Jane Nathan forming what has been called the "New Six" ticket.
They remain confident of toppling the six elected CV directors at the August 28 annual general meeting. There are also three appointed seats on the board. The New Six have made their feelings clear to CV chairman Russell Thomas and will need 13 of 25 votes to take charge.
They insist there is nothing "personal" in their fight. Rather, they claim there has been a "complete breakdown in confidence" with the board, pointing to an inability to set out a clear agenda for all levels of cricket, particularly at the Premier level, while also lacking in communication with delegates. In an email to clubs, they also claim CV has failed to provide "full financial transparency in relation to many of its decisions".
The elected directors under fire are Thomas, Tim Considine, Michael King, Paul Jackson, Claudia Fatone and David Maddocks.

The votes are held by Premier clubs (18 votes), the Victorian Sub-District Cricket Association (two), Women's Premier (three), Victorian Metropolitan Cricket Union (one) and the Victorian Country Cricket League (one).
CV patron Malcolm Gray, the former Cricket Australia and International Cricket Council chairman, told Fairfax Media he had met with both parties in the hope of bringing peace. However, the challenge is set to still go ahead, with delegates being consulted in recent days.
Dodemaide, a former Australian and Victorian fast bowler, has overseen great change in the sport since taking charge a decade ago.
"As an administrator, he has overseen a decade of impressive on- and off-field achievements," Thomas said. "These notably include the long-desired new home for Victorian cricket, arguably the most successful on-field period for the Bushrangers in Victorian cricket history and strong Victorian representation in Australian teams.
"This is in addition to the establishment of two thriving Big Bash subsidiaries, record levels of participation and the full integration of women's and girls' cricket into Cricket Victoria's core business."
Dodemaide, who said he was looking forward to a life outside of cricket, said the time was right for change.
"Of course there will always be new challenges on the horizon but, for me, the completion of, and transition to, the new home of Victorian cricket at the Junction Oval - a facility that will set up the sport in this state for the next 50 years - is an obvious and appropriate time to pass on the baton for a new phase of leadership," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cricket Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CV</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dodemaide, 53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Tobin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Dodemaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Six</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Maddock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dodemaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WACA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Metropolitan Cricket Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Considine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Hyde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Nathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Sub-District Cricket Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prahran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Junction Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Cricket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claudia Fatone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bushrangers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon Cricket Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Cricket Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Country Cricket League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
