<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406275414041420</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:53</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/basketball/nba-invite-shows-nbls-quality-says-melbourne-united-star-chris-goulding-20170801-gxn4ua.html</url>
  <title>NBA invite shows NBL's quality, says Melbourne United star Chris Goulding</title>
  <content>
Photo: Mick Connolly
Melbourne United star Chris Goulding believes the NBL can win respect when three clubs take on NBA sides in the US in October.
Goulding and United will take on Oklahoma City Thunder in Oklahoma City on October 9 (AEST), including reigning NBA most valuable player Russell Westbrook.
Goulding hoped the NBL's ability to win invites during NBA pre-season would silence critics of the league, considering the most recent clubs to face NBA sides were EuroLeague power teams.
"A lot of the time there is the casual fan who will disrespect the NBL," Goulding said. "But there are five guys in the NBL right now who were in our Boomers 12 for the Rio Olympics, so I think this is a big step for the NBL and our league in getting the respect we deserve.
"I'm not saying we are going to go over there to beat them. I'm saying only the biggest teams in the world get these opportunities, that's how it is.
"The last few years it has been Real Madrid, Barcelona and Maccabi Tel Aviv - those are the teams who get NBA pre-season games, and the first two are backed by the biggest soccer clubs in the world. So for three NBL teams to come along and take part as well, it's amazing."

Melbourne will have their full roster for the game, which comes between their first and second games of the NBL season.
NBL owner Larry Kestelman will fly the teams to the US and back in Qantas business class as part of a plan to keep the players as fresh as possible.
Goulding is one of the leaders on the United side, which will include several youngsters such as former AFL player Craig Moller, guard Kyle Adnam and Majok Majok.
Some people joked about the slightly built Adnam having to guard Westbrook, but Goulding said his side would look to shock the Thunder.
"We are going to roll the dice, have a red-hot crack, but we are not going over there to shake hands and take photos with them," he said. "That's not what I am going over there for."
Goulding is coming off ankle surgery, but is back on court and now working on his conditioning and match fitness.
"The ankle is really, really good," he said. "It took longer than expected to come along, but I had a lot of work done and it's like I have a new ankle."
He hopes to play some minutes when United host the University of Texas at Nunawading Stadium on August 16 and when they play University of Wisconsin at Casey Stadium on August 20.
Melbourne won't be distracted by their NBA pre-season game, as they learn new coach Dean Vickerman's system and prepare to battle back into the NBL finals this season.
"That is the last thing in our thoughts. The big thing for us is that we have an NBL season," Goulding said. "We need to get back on track after a disappointing season last year.
"We will do enough planning to be ready for the NBA game, but we have a game style we are implementing at Melbourne United and we are going to roll that out against Oklahoma City and have some fun.
"There is not one iota of pressure on us. It's a fantastic situation to be in coming into an NBL season where there is some pressure on us."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Madrid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Moller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maccabi Tel Aviv</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Goulding</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma City Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OKLAHOMA CITY</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wisconsin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulding</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Vickerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nunawading Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Adnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EuroLeague</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne United</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Majok Majok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boomers 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
