<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406266824106581</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/world-travel/europe/cancelled-y-not-music-festival-in-derbyshire-was-absolute-carnage/news-story/fb35563c76c8d2648b5409069975983f</url>
  <title>Cancelled Y Not music festival in Derbyshire was absolute carnage</title>
  <content>
By the end festival goers where going with not. Picture: Instagram

Share

YOU'D think Brits would know how to handle a bit of rain. Or not.
Festival-goers who attended the popular Y Not music festival in Derbyshire are furious after the event was cancelled on Sunday after acts had already been forced to abandon their performances due to heavy rain and extremely muddy conditions.
Headliners The Vaccines had their set cancelled on Friday, apologising to fans on social media and saying they had been told it was unsafe.
The swampy weekend also saw performances from Stereophonics and Jake Bugg rearranged, with acts reportedly playing under gazebos on stage to stay dry.
said the risk was "too severe" for the festival to keep calm and carry on.
"Unfortunately we've had to take the difficult decision to cancel Sunday due to the adverse weather conditions across the weekend, after consulting all the relevant authorities," the organisers said,
"The safety of our guests, performers and crew is our primary concern and the potential risk was too severe for Sunday to go ahead."
But attendees are having none of it, taking to social media to slam the organisers for failing to prepare for the realities of a British summer. The photos shared look like absolute carnage.

A post shared by Mike Kinder (@mykekinder) on

A post shared by Haz (@hippydippyhaz) on

this year's ynot in a picture
But the carnage didn't stop at the lack of preparation for the weather. In a scathing letter to the event organisers, one festival-goer described scenes of drugged-up mayhem and robberies.

"People were asked to leave with no organisation and it was mayhem. Two girls were on the floor clearly on drugs, covered in mud being trampled on and no-one even knew they were there," she wrote, according to the Derby Telegraph.
"I couldn't wait to get home and it has put me off ever going to any festival again for fear of being in these treacherous conditions again. Everyone was vulnerable and I am sure many were scared, as I was.
"One lady got pinned down in her tent by a group of lads. She had her two young children in there with her. They robbed her."
Others on social media had similar tales of destruction and lawlessness. The organisers of Y Not have not commented on these claims.
Police gave up this year I think
The organisers have said they will look at giving refunds to disappointed punters.
"We understand that people will have questions about refunds. We will be giving all our guests further information about this over the coming days," a statement on the Y Not website read.
Meanwhile, in Australia, festival-goers and media all gushed about the Splendour in the Grass festival in Byron Bay in July.
Summing up YNOT in a pic
Imagine a British festival that wasn't prepared for rain
YNOT Festival: Hold my beer
Getting back to the car after YNOT
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Bugg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YNOT Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Festival-goers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derby Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derbyshire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y Not</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YNOT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Kinder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stereophonics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
