<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406228169400353</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/grandmother-carolyn-hartz-blasted-cosmetic-surgery/3207561/</url>
  <title>Aussie grandma slammed over cosmetic surgery</title>
  <content>
A PERTH grandmother who stunned Australia with her model-like bikini body has been blasted for "fooling" viewers about her body after appearing on British television.

Carolyn Hartz made headlines around the country earlier this year when the 70-year-old revealed an .

Hartz said the secret to her success was two-fold.

"You have to watch what you put it in your mouth - that's number one - and two, you have to move your legs," she said.

However, that formula, inspired after she was treated for a pre-diabetes diagnosis, came under heavy criticism when she appeared on This Morning breakfast show.

This woman is 70 years old! Her secret? She stopped eating sugar 29 years ago. We're speaking to her now

"Who is this woman fooling?" one viewer wrote on Twitter.

'"I don't eat sugar blah blah can have toxic s--- injected in my face". Her forehead can't even move."

"Are we supposed to believe she looks so young through healthy eating?!" another wrote.

"You can clearly see she's had work done on her face!"

Hartz, a mother of four, admitted to having some cosmetic work performed in the past, but claimed it wasn't the major factor behind her eternal youth.

"Yes I do get some maintenance done, but surgery is not the answer to a healthy wellbeing," she said.  

Gofundme set up for better mobility equipment and ongoing costs
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
Coast applauds decision to upgrade major venue
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
And so BYTE - the Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence - was born.
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolyn Hartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hartz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
