<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405094298017089</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/classic-wclass-tram-to-offer-vintage-dining-in-preston/news-story/cb7ac3bf4137550476623c447980eee2</url>
  <title>Timeless tram's new restaurant role</title>
  <content>
PRESTON is getting its very own tram restaurant.
The Leader snapped these exclusive photos of a classic W-Class tram being installed at Vintage Garage in Preston.
Vintage Garage co-founder Marisa Gallagher said the tram was at the heart of a planned "mini-arts and food precinct", featuring world-class chefs, live music and vintage shopping.
"The whole idea is to have something new happening in there every couple of months," she said.
"We will probably book six to seven spots throughout the year where we will have a guest pop-up restaurant, with a purpose-built long banquet table," she said.
The tram could double as a daytime cafe, an art gallery and even a wedding space, when combined with the garage's generous open-plan warehouse.
The classic tram previously served as a bar at the Arts Centre in Melbourne's CBD, where it drew crowds of tourists lining up for a drink or the perfect selfie.
Ms Gallagher said she hoped it would draw similar attention in its northern home.
"We want to have people stay on site for a few hours at least," she said.
Vintage Garage pitches itself as "a collectively individual marketplace", offering 800sq m of vintage variety from more than 50 vendors.
Its flagship store in Smith St, Collingwood is one of the premiere boutiques for lovers of '50s and '60s vintage art and fashion.
Work will begin next week to refurbish the tram, with an expected opening in October.
The W-Class first went into production in 1923 and their familiar rattle was known to all Melburnians.
A handful still operates today on the City Circle and Colonial Tramcar Restaurant service.
is at 1 Newman St, Preston.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Circle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W-class</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colonial Tramcar Restaurant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newman St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gallagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marisa Gallagher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melburnians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vintage Garage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
