<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405742838087719</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/watch-fishermen-hand-feed-sharks-off-wa-coast/news-story/ee5108f3ad33f7f556d5bf592c2027ab</url>
  <title>Sharks hold no fears for WA fishermen</title>
  <content>
IF sharks were circling near your boat, would you try to hand feed them? 
These two WA fishermen did - and created some stunning footage.
Whaler sharks frequent the waters at Shelter Bay near Steep Point, where Michael Nock and his mate Adam took their boat on a fishing trip last month.
In possession of a new drone, they filmed themselves feeding the sharks, using fish to lure them to the surface before allowing them to take the food out of their hands.
"Yep, all the fingers are still there," Mr Nock said.
"You don't need to try and attract them, they are everywhere. As soon as you throw some fish frames in, they come from every direction."
An experienced fisherman, Mr Nock held little fear of the sharks - but still exercised a healthy dose of caution.
"They are actually quite placid with humans, we do a lot of diving there and always bump into them," he said.
"They not even interested in us when we are in the water.
"But we probably wouldn't get in (the water) when they are feeding like that."
Mr Nock said it was a successful fishing trip but he admitted that the sharks could pose a problem for their catch.
"You gotta be quick to get the fish up before the sharks get to them," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steep Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Nock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nock</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelter Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
