<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406266824106636</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/unis-dodge-a-crackdown-on-sexual-assault-offenders-20170801-gxn4jl.html</url>
  <title>Unis dodge a crackdown on sexual assault offenders </title>
  <content>
One in 15 university students were sexually assaulted in either 2015 or 2016, according to a new report produced by the Australian Human Rights Commission. Of these, less than one in 10 officially reported to the university and only 1 in 50 sexual harassment survivors reported.
On Tuesday, Universities Australia (UA) released a 10-Point Plan that outlines how the university sector intends to prevent sexual assault and support survivors. This follows their commitment to fund a national 1800 hotline for student-survivors of sexual assault.Photo: Karleen Minney
Earlier this year, The Sydney Morning Herald reported that students faced wait times of up to four weeks for counselling, and that university counsellors . It is a relief that students can now access 24/7 quality counselling from trauma-specialists, no matter where they are, due to UA's new hotline, which went live on Monday.
But the elephant in the room that no one seems willing to discuss is whether or not universities will ever discipline offenders.

Within UA's plan there is absolutely no mention of perpetrators or offenders, and nor does the 20-page document mention disciplinary measures. 
This is despite the fact that universities routinely discipline students for all manner of other breaches to student misconduct policies, including plagiarism, bullying, theft, and damage to university or student property.

While sexual assault is a crime and can be reported to police, it also falls under universities' student misconduct policies, and universities are obliged by federal legislation to provide a safe learning environment. Just like theft or property damage, sexual assault is both a criminal matter and a misconduct matter.
Yet even in cases where offenders have admitted guilt, universities have handed down highly lenient punishments. For example, at University of New England, which had the highest rates of sexual assault in the AHRC survey, offenders have been asked to pay a $55 fine (apparently less than the cost of a parking ticket); been asked to write apology letters; or in one case a student was required to perform a mere eight hours of community service after admitting to multiple sexual offences, including sticking a hand down the front of a female's underpants and refusing to stop when asked.Photo: Rohan Thomson
UA's complete silence on offenders in Tuesday's report will undoubtedly make victim-survivors question just how committed they are to making campuses safe for students.
After all, improving counselling services and reporting channels is all well and good, but if universities have no intention of ever addressing offenders - or acknowledging their clear presence on campus - there is still little or no incentive to report.
Last year Channel Seven conducted the largest-ever freedom of information investigation in Australian history. It found that in the past five years 575 official complaints of sexual misconduct (145 relating specifically to sexual assault) were made to universities.
These resulted in just six expulsions.
When one considers how low reporting rates are to begin with, the figures look even more concerning: if 145 reported sexual assaults represents approximately 9 per cent of all incidents, this would suggest that over 1600 sexual assaults may have occurred within the past five years (and that a whopping 21,500 sexual harassment incidents occurred in the same time frame.)
In that light, those six expulsions are looking even more paltry.
So why are universities so reluctant to discuss or acknowledge the presence of sexual offenders in their midst?
First, they prefer to believe that perpetrators are scary men in trench coats lurking in the bushes, not regular students in their lecture halls.
This is why they have been quick to refocus attention towards sexual assault and harassment occurring on public transport, as this reframing strategy pulls the focus away from the problems on campus and universities' complicity in the harm done to students.
Second, universities know that perpetrators are far more likely to sue universities over disciplinary actions than victims are. When perpetrators are excluded from their education they often become litigious.
Sexual assault is, by definition, a crime associated with power and entitlement, so it should come as no surprise that perpetrators often feel entitled to sue their institutions after being disciplined. They may also feel far more entitled to use institutional procedures to their own advantage.
Victims, on the other hand, are usually so traumatised by their assault that the prospect of taking on a powerful institution is simply overwhelming. Universities know this.
They also know that statistically, male students are more litigious, particularly following disciplinary matters. In 2009, a report commissioned by the Australian Learning and Teaching Council found that in disciplinary and grievance matters were male. 
Similarly, between 2013 and 2016, at least 75 young men accused of crimes in the US , complaining that they had been discriminated against in unfair disciplinary proceedings. 
As long as perpetrators of sexual violence are allowed to commit these acts with impunity, universities send a clear message that this behaviour is normal and excusable - a far cry from the "zero-tolerance" approach they claim to have in their press statements.
Nina Funnell and Anna Hush are ambassadors for End Rape On Campus Australia.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Learning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teaching Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nina Funnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Hush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>End Rape On Campus Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Point Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karleen Minney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Morning Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AHRC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
