<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406266824106645</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/helping-hand-plans-new-golden-grove-aged-care-home-for-110-people-creating-hundreds-of-jobs/news-story/595604f3e991dace4b04a82e71ccf40b</url>
  <title>Helping Hand for Golden Grove elderly</title>
  <content>
A NEW $37 million aged-care facility in Golden Grove catering for 110 people is expected to create hundreds of new jobs.
It's the third major aged-care centre slated for the region with Life Care building a $60m development, also in Golden Grove, with 78 independent living units, 24 serviced apartments and an 80-bed residential aged care centre for up to 250 residents.
Aged-care service ECH is also expected to build a 9800sq m multi-storey facility at Smart Rd, replacing a commercial carpark.
Helping Hand chief executive Ian Hardy said the $37 million project at 504 The Golden Way would open by January 2019 with 110 rooms.
"There will be 800 jobs connected to the construction of the site," he said.
"Golden Grove in our estimation is under-serviced for residential care.
"Looking at the pattern of ageing in the Golden Grove region, the number of people aged over 80 expands significantly over the next 20 years.
"Helping Hand was looking for an appropriate site at Golden Grove for a period of time.
"We're getting in and being ready to support that need."
He said Helping Hand realised the importance of keeping senior citizens close to family, their friends and the local community when moving into a care home.
Mr Hardy described the Golden Grove site as "ideally located nearby to a shopping precinct and arts centre".
A planning application for stage one of the project is currently before Tea Tree Gully Council.
It's expected to provide 130 ongoing jobs in health, caring, administration and management roles.
Tea Tree Gully Council has approved Life Care's development application - on vacant land at the corner of Surrey Farm Drive and The Golden Way - but timelines for works have not yet been announced.
It's expected to create 70 construction jobs.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Hardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surrey Farm Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEW $37</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smart Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tea Tree Gully Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tree Gully Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helping Hand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Way</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Care</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Grove</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
