<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406052075738120</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/shooters-like-their-chances-in-gladys-berejiklians-next-byelection-test-20170801-gxmx7n.html</url>
  <title>Shooters like their chances in Berejiklian's next byelection test</title>
  <content>
The Shooters, Fishers and Farmers secured more than 10 per cent of the upper house vote in the seat of Cootamundra at the 2015 election without running a lower house candidate, boosting the party's confidence about the forthcoming byelection.
But the Nationals say the electorate has been "very well served" by retiring MP Katrina Hodgkinson, who stood up for them over the contentious push to ban greyhound racing.

Up Next

Wheelchair-bound man dies after cliff fall

00:18

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Shooters Party secures seat of Orange

The Shooters, Fishers and Farmers Party has won its first seat in the lower house of the NSW Parliament after its candidate, Philip Donato, was declared victorious in the Orange byelection by just 50 votes. Vision courtesy ABC News 24.

Council amalgamations and the failed bid to close the greyhound racing industry are predicted to play into the byelection sparked by Ms Hodgkinson's announcement she will leave parliament at the end of August.
Last year the then Baird government forcibly amalgamated five councils in the seat into two - Hilltops Council and Cootamundra-Gundagai and there are several greyhound tracks.Photo: Katherine Griffiths
At the 2015 NSW election, the Shooters, Fishers and Farmers Party secured 4,694 upper house votes in the seat - the equivalent of 10.18 per cent.
Shooters Fishers and Farmers MLC Robert Borsak said the party has a stronger membership in Cootamundra than in the seat of Orange, which it won in last year's byelection with a two party preferred swing of 21.8 per cent against the Nationals.

Cootamundra is held by the Nationals on a margin of 20.4 per cent.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I never take anything for granted but we think with a base vote of at least 10 per cent at the last election then we have a very good chance of taking the seat," Mr Borsak told Fairfax Media.
"We'll give it a red hot go and hopefully the electors of Cootamundra will favour us as those in Orange did."
Mr Borsak said there was residual anger in Cootamundra over the aborted greyhound racing ban and that forced council mergers "is very much a live issue".
"Virtually every week we see someone from the National Party in Orange promising big dollars for Orange," he said.
"If that's what people get for voting for the Shooters, Fishers and Farmers then they can expect the same dollars flowing into Cootamundra."
But NSW Nationals director Nathan Quigley said Cootamundra and Burrinjuck, as the seat was known before a redistribution, "have been very well served by Katrina" for more than 18 years.
Ms Hodgkinson crossed the floor to vote against the bill to close the industry in the lower house last year, citing the "thousands of jobs" that would be lost in her electorate.
"Katrina is synonymous with the party there and has been for many, many years," Mr Quigley said. 
"They voted for a Nationals MP who stood up for them on the greyhounds issue. We're confident of having a large pool of candidates to stand to be the same kind of candidate Katrina was."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Donato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hodgkinson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burrinjuck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cootamundra</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katrina</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Borsak</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Katrina Hodgkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisher</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Quigley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cootamundra-Gundagai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Nationals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Quigley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmers Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilltops Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmers MLC Robert Borsak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
