<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406180924759188</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/26m-long-saltwater-crocodile-captured-by-rangers-at-port-douglas/news-story/e6b8fd338733ecee4121d4e788fcfe04</url>
  <title>Croc removed from Four Mile Beach</title>
  <content>
A SALTWATER crocodile has been removed by rangers from one of the Far North™s most famous beaches " but it may not have been the croc they were initially targeting.

Department of Environment and Heritage Protection wildlife officers today captured a 2.6m long saltie from Four Mile Beach, just weeks after the area was rezoned under the Queensland Crocodile Management Plan.

Environment Minister Steven Miles said the officers had deployed a trap at the mouth of Dickson Inlet at Port Douglas, after the croc was reported on July 12.

"A member of the public saw a crocodile leaving Dickson Inlet with a turtle in its jaws, around 200m north of the Four Mile Beach patrolled area and just 20m off the headland shore," he said.

The captured croc will be shifted to a farm or zoo, where it will spend the rest of its days.

However Mr Miles said the officers did not believe the reptile was the initial target animal, and the croc trap would remain in the area.

"It is possible that the target animal was only moving through the area," he said.

"Crocodiles are highly mobile animals and will use the ocean to travel between estuaries and inland waterways."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Environment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Crocodile Management Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Douglas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson Inlet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heritage Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Mile Beach</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
