<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405914636782305</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/lynette-daley-might-have-lived-with-medical-attention/8763812</url>
  <title>Lynette Daley might have lived with urgent medial attention, court told</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A jury has heard a woman who died on a secluded beach on the New South Wales north coast might have survived with timely medical assistance.
Lynette Daley died during a camping trip to Ten Mile beach near Iluka in 2011.
A Supreme Court trial in Coffs Harbour has heard the 33-year-old suffered severe internal and external lacerations caused by violent sexual activity.
Crown Prosecutor, Philip Strickland SC, told the jury Ms Daley suffered significant blood loss and lapsed into hypovolemic shock.
"She was only 59 kilograms and the amount of blood she lost was critical," Mr Strickland said.
"In short, she was bleeding to death.
"She was too intoxicated to do anything about it and she was in a remote location.
"[The accused] Adrian Attwater did nothing in a timely manner to do anything about it."
Attwater, 42, has been charged with manslaughter and aggravated sexual assault in company.

His barrister, Nathan Steel, today told the court his client had previously engaged in similar sexual activity with Lynette Daley.
"The same kind of sexual activity happened between himself and Lynette Daley on previous occasions," Mr Steel said.
"Although she had bled a bit before, she never had to go to hospital.
"He didn't mean for her to get hurt.
"Her getting injured was an unintended consequence of the activity they engaged in."
'He did all he could to save her life'

Mr Steel suggested Ms Daley may have lapsed into hypovolemic shock while swimming with his client.
"It wasn't until Lynette Daley collapsed in the ocean that he was aware she had a serious injury," Mr Steel said.
"From that point he did all he could to save her life.
"He called [co-accused] Paul Maris for help and started CPR."
Joanne Daley told the court her sister was scared of the ocean and never went into the water above her knees.
Maris, 47, is charged with aggravated sexual assault in company and hindering the collection of evidence by burning a blood-soaked mattress.
The prosecution told the court Maris burned the mattress because it stank, and then planned to go fishing.
It is alleged he tried to bury the burned remains and drove over the area in a four-wheel drive.
About 50 witnesses are expected to be called during the trial, which is scheduled to last another five weeks.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Maris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Steel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Daley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maris, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Mile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Strickland SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynette Daley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Attwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attwater, 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Strickland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iluka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Steel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
