<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405193082266449</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/hawks-milestone-man-hungry-for-more-glory/3207415/</url>
  <title>Hawks' milestone man hungry for more glory</title>
  <content>
AFL: Hawthorn captain Jarryd Roughead says the pursuit of a fifth premiership remains the driving force of his AFL career, saying it far exceeds personal milestones such as his 250th game against Richmond this Sunday.
The 30-year-old admits he has a greater appreciation for the game - and the club - since beating melanoma last year, and has been buoyed by the quick turnaround in the club's fortunes in recent months after a tough start to the season.
"I haven't really thought about it (his 250th game) too much," Roughead said. "My goal wasn't to come back and play 250 games."
"When I got the all-clear to come back and play (this year), it was all about playing footy again.
"Once something is taken away from you that you have known since you were 17 years old, you want to get back and play as soon as you can.
"The injuries happen, you understand in footy, but with what happened last year, your perspective changes a fair bit, and you understand that footy isn't everything."
Admitting the club was in trouble after losing five of the first six games of this season, Roughead said the future now looked bright for a revamped and revitalised Hawthorn, saying that even though the finals are still only an outside chance this season, he was confident better things would come next year and beyond.
"It still seems a fair bit away (another flag), (but) we will do everything right that we can here," he said.
"We have to get ourselves to our next one (flag). We are not here to keep racking up games, we are here to try and win flags, and hopefully we can win another one."
Roughead says he hasn't considered his own playing career nor looked beyond the end of his current contract, which expires at the end of the 2019 season.
"I'm 30 now, I have got two years left on a deal at the moment, so we will stay at that and see what happens," he said.
Meanwhile, the Hawks will appeal Luke Hodge's one-match ban from the MRP for striking Sydney's Tom Papley.
"We're confident that we have a case to argue and based on that we've made the decision to challenge the sanction," Hawthorn general manager of football operations Jason Burt said.
The tribunal will sit on Tuesday evening to decide the outcome of Hodge's appeal. If successful, Hodge will be available to face the Tigers at the MCG this Sunday.
If the challenge is unsuccessful, Hawthorn will be penalised just $2500 - there is no greater penalty in play for Hodge.
Despite helping orphans in Africa, Sam Childers had to fight to get in
Do you know when you should indicate while using a roundabout?
UPDATE: It's rare for whales to swim to where the pair was beached.
Architect of a region stops briefly on his final journey.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
OUR family was part of the first wave of sea changers.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Childers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Burt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodge</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
