<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406000536129642</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/interest-rate-remains-at-15-per-cent/news-story/56dbfb50c1c2a0c230457e6e7fb017d5</url>
  <title>Interest rate remains at 1.5 per cent</title>
  <content>
THE Reserve Bank has left official interest rates on hold while raising concerns about the strong Australian dollar.
Following its regular monthly board meeting, RBA governor Philip Lowe confirmed the official cash rate would remain at 1.5 per cent. The Reserve last cut rates in August last year.
While the decision was expected, Dr Lowe raised deliberate concerns about the strength of the dollar which has been at or above US80 cents for the past week.
He said the dollar was a risk to the economy.
"The higher exchange rate is expected to contribute to subdued price pressures in the economy. It is also weighing on the outlook for output and employment," he said.
"An appreciating exchange rate would be expected to result in a slower pick-up in economic activity and inflation than currently forecast."
Dr Lowe said there continued to be positive signs about the overall economy but much hinged on the strength of the dollar and the spending patterns of local shoppers.
He said the combination of low wages growth and high levels of debt was a risk.
"Retail sales have picked up recently, but slow growth in real wages and high levels of household debt are likely to constrain growth in spending," He said.
"Employment growth has been stronger over recent months, and has increased in all states. The various forward-looking indicators point to continued growth in employment over the period ahead.
"The unemployment rate is expected to decline a little over the next couple of years. Against this, however, wage growth remains low and this is likely to continue for a while yet."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lowe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
