<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405785787761285</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/crime-and-justice/tamate-henry-heke-pleads-not-guilty-to-manslaughter-over-gateway-motorway-death/news-story/4a64fdc33785cbbb90282875d4d34582</url>
  <title>'What have I done, what have I done?'</title>
  <content>
WITNESSES in the trial of a man accused of punching another who then fell into the path of a truck have described seeing him dry retch before allegedly telling one: "What have I done, what have I done?"
Tamate Henry Heke allegedly struck Shane Merrigan, 50, before he was hit by a rubbish truck on the Gateway Motorway at Eight Mile Plains on December 1, 2015.
Heke has pleaded not guilty to one count of manslaughter, as well as not guilty to an alternative charge of unlawful striking causing death.
Witness Jonathan Spillman told his Brisbane Supreme Court trial on Tuesday he had stopped to offer first aid after seeing a body lying on the road but when he got closer, realised it was too late.
While he didn't identify Heke directly, Mr Spillman told the court he then turned his attention to a "Samoan, Islander type of person" nearby who had bloodshot eyes and looked like he was in shock.
"I asked him if he was OK," Mr Spillman said.
"At that stage he held out his two hands and said to me, 'what have I done, what have I done?'" Earlier, fellow driver Eleanor Woodman also said she saw a "Maori" man punch a Caucasian man in the face, then grab his head, pace up and down and dry retch after the collision with the truck.
"He was very distraught," Ms Woodman said.
Another motorist, Jade Faulder, dabbed her eyes with a tissue as she recalled seeing a man fall back "kind of unconscious" on to the road after an encounter with a "Kiwi guy", followed by the moment of fatal impact.
Asked by crown prosecutor Clare Kelly what the man who delivered the punch did at this point, she said: "He began to panic (and) dropped to the ground".
The jury has previously heard both men had been making their way home from work before pulling over to the left shoulder of the road and facing each other "for about 13 seconds".
The New Zealander is then accused of then delivering a "heavy blow" to Mr Merrigan's head, causing him to fall into the path of the truck, which was travelling at 90km/h.
Photographs showing the truck's blood-splattered undercarriage were viewed by jurors on the first day of the trial.
They also saw graphic footage from a motorway camera showing the two cars pulling on to the road's shoulder, the men getting out and the moment of impact.
But defence barrister Anthony Kimmins has said his client, a father of three, told police he didn't intend to get into a fight when he pulled his Holden Astra over that day.
The trial continues.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spillman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateway Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Merrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eight Mile Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamate Henry Heke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Spillman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holden Astra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Kimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caucasians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jade Faulder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleanor Woodman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Woodman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
