<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405871687108729</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/national/sydney-counterterrorism-arrests-agents-interrogate-footy-fan-khaled-khayat-over-alleged-airline-attack-plot/news-story/d61d05bb44c89633bbf49687e9aa4d65</url>
  <title>Flight note not what it seems</title>
  <content>
FOREIGN spies from intelligence agencies in the United States and Britain helped Australia destroy a
The footy fan and butcher Khaled Khayat and three others are being held for questioning over the alleged plot to put gas substances in a common kitchen meat mincer, which .
No charges have been laid.
On Monday, police officers painstakingly sifted through with materials seized including a flight slip with the number of a route from Jakarta to Sydney and a frequent flyer number.
Police said today the document had now been ruled out of the investigation after confirming it had belonged to another occupant of the apartment block.
Five properties were raided on Saturday - one each in Lakemba, Surry Hills and Wiley Park, and two at Punchbowl.
Three days after AFP officers raided a Surry Hills townhouse following a tip-off about an alleged terror plot, police presence at the Cleveland Street property remains high.
Officers from the Federal Police and the riot squad are still at the house as the alleged terrorists remain behind bars under terror legislation.
Police have Goodlet Lane, which runs behind the row of terraced homes, blocked off to the public as they continue to search the raided property.
Yesterday, residents were forced to show ID as they arrived at and left their home while searches continued.

The Daily Telegraph can reveal an Etihad flight to Abu Dhabi, with as many as 500 passengers and crew on board, was the target of the alleged terror plot. It involved using a gas substance rather than explosives, which is harder for airport security to detect than a kilo of explosives.

Intelligence from Australia's Five Eyes partners, the United States, Britain, New Zealand and Canada, helped crack the alleged terror cell operating in Sydney's suburbs. However, national security agencies are confident they have destroyed the alleged terror plot and eliminated the threat posed by them.
Intelligence sources said there was no suggestion the four detainees had trained overseas, although they were in contact with Islamic extremist groups operating in Syria and Iraq.
The They can be held for seven days without charge while security services search for evidence- about the alleged terror plot.

One of those arrested was Khayat, a keen footy supporter who has posted pictures of himself on social media wearing his football jersey. He had no criminal history.
The former butcher was also a regular customer at the Darwiche Halal Butchery.
"He would just come in by himself, he was very nice so I am surprised by all this," part-owner Mohammed Darwiche said.
Along with the flight slip, police inspected a burnt out pump outside the Khayat apartment in Lakemba. They also discovered a business letter inside one bin addressed to the Surry Hills property that was also raided.
Among other materials taken in the past few days were pipes, gas bottles, SIM cards and components believed to be from a meat grinder that was allegedly being turned into an improvised device of destruction.

"The plot that we are investigating we believe was an attempt to put a device onto an aircraft, but beyond that the speculation is just that - speculation," Mr Colvin said.
"Until we finish our investigation, until we know which of our many working theories we have, and until we can put that information before the courts it's not helpful to keep speculating-."
In Surry Hills, friends of one of the others questioned were stunned to hear the hardworking paint sprayer had been implicated in a terror plot.
The man, in his early 40s, was one of 15 children who worked seven days a week at a factory in Botany and spent his Friday nights sipping water and betting on the horses at the Surrey Club Hotel in Cleveland St.
"He loved betting on horses, he's a gambler as is his dad," a friend said. "He would bet on horses while drinking water, he's a quiet guy who never troubled anyone, all he did was work at the factory for the last seven years.
"His father is sick in hospital with a lung condition and his mother suffers from heart problems so he lived at home to look after them.
"I'd be very shocked to learn he was radicalised as he never once went to the mosque. I saw his sister in Lakemba two weeks ago and none of the family were religious but her face was covered in headgear.
"Maybe things have changed in the family, but they were not the least bit religious growing up as children in Surry Hills."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khayat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Five Eyes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohammed Darwiche</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surrey Club Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jakarta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodlet Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwiche Halal Butchery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
