<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406223874432993</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/paul-mcgregor-fined-calling-referees-embarrassing-incompetent/8764300</url>
  <title>St George Illawarra coach Paul McGregor fined for calling referees 'embarrassing, incompetent'</title>
  <content>
St George Illawarra coach Paul McGregor has been predictably slapped with a $10,000 fine for criticising NRL referees after Saturday's loss to Newcastle.
Dragons backs Tim Lafai and Nene Macdonald controversially had tries denied by the bunker during the team's 21-14 defeat.
After the game, McGregor labelled the referees "embarrassing and incompetent".
"I think anyone that knows rugby league would agree," he said.
While it was a step or two down from , McGregor's criticism was still enough to earn him a fine.
The rules state "no club, club official or player shall, on a public occasion, comment on or with respect to the performance of a match official".
NRL head of football Brian Canavan said the league had applied logic in situations where comments had been made without the integrity or ability of referees being called into question.
"But it is our view that these particular comments crossed the line," Canavan said.
"All coaches should be aware that they risk sanctions if they discuss the performance of referees."
The Dragons have five business days to respond to the breach notice.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Lafai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nene Macdonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul McGregor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
