<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406086435476992</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/sport/basketball/nbl-boss-larry-kestelman-celebrates-teams-in-nba-preseason-matchups-20170801-gxmxy3.html</url>
  <title>NBL boss Larry Kestelman celebrates teams in NBA pre-season match-ups</title>
  <content>
 NBL owner Larry Kestelman has spent years building relationships and respect with teams and officials in the NBA.
At the NBA All-Star game this year, talks with Utah Jazz about a potential pre-season game got serious.Photo: Mick Connolly
Usually it takes ages for an NBA side and an overseas team to find a mutual time that fits, but when the Jazz suggested a date, Kestelman agreed immediately.
That split-second decision may have changed the future of the NBL and its clubs as the deal was done so quickly the NBL was able to lure two other sides to play.
In October, Sydney Kings, Melbourne United and Brisbane Bullets will face full-strength NBA sides in official pre-season games in the US.
The Kings will play the Jazz in Utah on October 3, Melbourne United will play Oklahoma City Thunder in Oklahoma City on October 9 and the Bullets will play Phoenix Suns in Phoenix on October 14.

"This was never not going to happen, if we had to charter a plane we were going to," Kestelman said.
"We started at one game and when they saw we would move heaven and earth to meet their requirements we were invited to play.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"They agreed on one game and once that process went reasonably smoothly it evolved to three.
"If this can evolve into a regular occurrence then I will be a very happy man."
It will be difficult for the teams, with the Kings and Bullets having their opening NBL home games on October 7 and United playing their first game in Adelaide on October 5 before flying to the US for the Thunder game, then returning for a second visit to Adelaide on October 14.
But Kestelman knows the chance to have his clubs take on NBA sides in front of potentially millions of fans worldwide was too important to pass up.
Kestelman has been on a mission to take the NBL to the top of the Australian sporting landscape and while many laughed when he first took over in May 2015, Tuesday's announcement stopped that laughter in its tracks.
Now he is turning his sights towards how the league can spin off its meetings with superstars such as NBA MVP Russell Westbrook and new Thunder swingman Paul George into commercial success at home.
Kestelman also knows success on court could push the case for a future game in Australia.
"This is serious. We know the difference in the level of play - it's the biggest stage in the world," he said.
"But it's part of the journey and I have no doubt we will have games here. They are a business, they are extremely good at what they do and they plan very far ahead so this is part of the stepping stones for them.
"I have no doubt we will have a game here."
ESPN is expected to show the games in Australia and NBA League Pass is also likely to screen the games.
Melbourne United stars David Andersen and Chris Goulding have already taken on Team USA while at the Rio Olympics and they're keen to take on the NBA's best.
"As we speak our team is looking for a 6'6 athletic [import] point guard to guard Russell [Westbrook]," Goulding joked.
"Guys like myself, Kevin [Lisch] and Joe [Ingles] were lucky enough to go up against the 'new age dream team' at the Rio Olympics so we have had a little taste of competing against athletes of that calibre.
"We have nothing to lose and will try and shock a few people."
Australian Utah Jazz star Ingles was at the launch on Tuesday and spoke glowingly about what a good performance could do for the NBL players.
But he warned with NBA sides down to only four or so pre-season games they will show no mercy to the NBL sides.
"They probably don't realise right now what it will mean to have a good game or a win for their team," Ingles said.
"I think Chris Goulding is a perfect example, he's similar to me, where he's obviously played in the NBL he's been with the Australian team now and proved that he's at that level.
"Come out and have a good game against Russell Westbrook, Paul George or one of the quote-unquote best defenders in Andre Roberson from Oklahoma City, it's a great opportunity.
"There's just so many opportunities that you just never know what might happen."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA All-Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Andersen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Goulding</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA League Pass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA MVP Russell Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma City Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OKLAHOMA CITY</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Team USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul George</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andre Roberson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne United</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kestelman</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thunder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
