<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406133680118157</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826998/breezing-through-to-the-airport/?cs=5445</url>
  <title>Breezing through to the airport</title>
  <content>
The new Mantra Hotel at Sydney Airport ... obviously a pent-up demand for more rooms on the airport's doorstep.

Get an upper-level room at the front of the new Mantra Hotel at Sydney Airport and you're in plane-spotters' heaven, watching plane after plane take off from a runway so close you feel you can almost reach out like King Kong and grab the next flight.
Not that the runway proximity is at all obtrusive. The excellent glazing takes care of that, well before the airport's curfew kicks in.

The new Mantra Hotel at Sydney Airport ... plane-spotters' heaven.
And not that you have to be a plane-spotter to find reason to book into the new 136-room property. In days of nightmarish Sydney traffic, anyone with an early-morning flight will easily envision missing that last boarding call while stuck on the Princes Highway, the Campsie bypass or in the M5 tunnel.
There's obviously a pent-up demand for more rooms on Sydney Airport's doorstep. You only have to look at the new hotel's advance bookings to figure that one out.

A studio king room ... functionality and the needs of road warriors foremost.
Mantra Hotel at Sydney Airport has only been open for a couple of weeks yet there have been nights when occupancy exceeded 85 per cent. Bookings for July exceeded 1300 room nights, with the hotel picking up an additional 50 or so rooms per day.
I'm sure there have been moments when staff paddled like crazy under the water while maintaining a veneer of serenity, but those moments certainly didn't show during a two-night stay that coincided with the hotel's official opening by NSW Tourism Minister Adam Marshall.

Cutting the ribbon to open the new property ... from left, Sydney Airport MD and CEO Kerrie Mather, NSW Minister for Tourism and Major Events Adam Marshall and Mantra Group CEO Bob East.
Everything seems to work. Accessing the carpark out the front is a breeze, check-in is speedy, the beds are comfortable and the rooms smallish but extremely well designed, with functionality and the needs of road warriors foremost.
Internet access is free and fast - as indeed it should be. When it isn't I'm always reminded of a young boy's reported conversation with his mother: "What do you mean there's no WIFI where we're going. It's just in the air, isn't it?"
There's even a bulletin board in the restaurant, providing latest details of airport arrivals and departures.
And talking of the on-site restaurant, the menu is limited but well chosen, with entrees such as salt-and-pepper squid and pirri-pirri king prawns, and with the main courses including beer-battered flathead and eggplant parmigiana.

On-site dining ... a limited but well selected range of dishes.
On separate occasions I tried a steak and prawns with linguine. The verdict on both occasions was clearly an appreciative thumbs up.
Regarding access to T2 and T3 domestic terminals, they really are within walking distance. I timed it and the walk took me just 15 minutes along well paved footpaths without any major road crossings.
There's also a regular shuttle service that will suit those who have luggage. It's available at a reasonably nominal charge and can be arranged through reception.
Rates start at $159 per night.
Phone 1300 987 604 or visit  

John Rozentals was a guest of Mantra.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>M5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major Events Adam Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Kerrie Mather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Rozentals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campsie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Tourism Minister Adam Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Airport MD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Internet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mantra Hotel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mantra Group CEO Bob East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
