<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405356291026009</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-advice/travellers-stories/i-moved-to-berlin-and-this-is-what-i-have-learnt/news-story/d9767e481fe4eb146138e4fab8a1080e</url>
  <title>I moved to Berlin and this is what I have learnt</title>
  <content>
Aussie Tiahn Wetzler has had to learn a lot since relocating to Berlin. Picture: Tiahn Wetzler

Tiahn Wetzler

Share

BERLIN is growing in popularity for Aussie expats due to its generally low rental prices, English friendly neighbourhoods and incomparably on-trend atmosphere.
London still certainly has its appeal, but there's something a little more adventurous and a lot more affordable about making Germany your new home.
I myself made this decision at the end of 2015 and have since enjoyed my time in the Deutsch capital, observing not only the benefits but the hilarious idiosyncrasies that set us apart from our Teutonic cousins.
While I have done my best to learn the language and absorb myself within the culture (go hard or go home!), there are certain behaviours and manners of conduct that I simply refuse to adopt. Some of them are adorable, some are infuriating and some are downright illogical. Yes, Germany, you: illogical.
The first example probably comes as no surprise to most - social graces are utterly out the window here.
If you mutter the German equivalent of "how are you" - "wie geht es dir" - in a cafe, supermarket or when receiving any kind of service, you will be met with one of two reactions.
The first, most common, will be a very strange look, wondering why a stranger would ask such a personal question and why that stranger would presume the person wants to engage in a conversation.

To a non-German, Berlin can be a confusing - but also amazing - place. Picture: Tiahn WetzlerSource:Supplied
The second option, which I have experienced on more than one alarming occasion, is that they take the question extremely literally and begin to tell you exactly how they are, what they are feeling and perhaps their entire life story. Your best bet? A quick hello, avoid eye contact and a quick goodbye. Simple, methodical, oh-so-Deutschland.
There is one brilliantly awkward exception to the "silence in the public sphere," rule however, which is the elevator.

In Australia, we generally avoid eye contact in elevators; shying away from unnecessary contact or sound when sharing in the strange activity of being lifted off the ground.
In Berlin, however, it's all bets off in the Aufzug (literal translation: up train) and there are hellos, how are you, comments on the weather, smiles and what's ups coming at you from every angle. It's rude, in fact, to say nothing. At the very least you need to say hello and goodbye. A normal phrase to say in this case is "I wish you a beautiful day" before exiting the elevator.
This is the soft side of German culture that needs to be spread. Once you're out though, it's time to get serious again.
TRAFFIC LIGHT ETIQUETTE

Do you stay or do you go? Picture: Andreas Rentz/Getty Images)Source:Getty Images
One of the most wonderfully contradictory behaviours common in Berlin is the refusal to jaywalk.
Germans are perhaps most renowned for their logical way of approaching situations, but they are also, generally speaking, a rule-obeying type of society, even in the capital of freedom, Berlin. Logic and rule obeying come directly to a head when we've got a red man on the traffic pole and no cars to be seen for days.
Walk or stay? They stay and wait patiently until that man turns green. No cars, one way street, they wait. Cars already stopped, man not yet green, they wait. If you walk, you will feel eyes burning into your back and some uncomfortable fidgeting as they fight the urge to step when the man says they can't.
SOZ, NOT SOZ
Perhaps the only difference that genuinely bothers me is that people usually don't say sorry when they bump into you or get in your way, be it in the supermarket, on the footpath or on public transport.
Germany is not a "sorry saying" nation and won't apologise for something unless it genuinely upsets them or they are genuinely at fault.
You will get an "entschuldigung", meaning "excuse me", or literally, "remove my guilt" if they are asking you politely to step aside or have done something wrong that could somehow pertain to guilt.
You'll get a "tut mir Leid", meaning "it makes me sad", if something happens that is unfortunate, but not their fault.

It's not just the weather that makes Germany seem totally different to Australia. Picture: Tiahn WetzlerSource:Supplied
While the English "sorry" has been adopted to an extent, the psychology behind the use of the word isn't quite there. Our culture can see us blurting out a flurry of sorries if we feel we've inconvenienced a person, the German approach suggests that the use of the word/this concept is only necessary when something truly worth apologising for, or about, has taken place.
This results in a lot of situations where you would expect an apology but don't receive one, so you end up feeling like you've really offended people when you actually haven't at all.
In the same way, they don't understand why we recklessly throw out sorries for minor inconveniences, and therefore we don't receive the all-so-necessary "it's okay". This has been the main ground for misunderstandings during my 18 months here.
BEST THING ABOUT BERLIN
The difference I like the most is the approach to working overtime, which is not as normal as it is in Australia. There is a concept here called "Feierabend", which translates to "evening celebration," and it's taken quite seriously. It's also the word/term generally used to explain when you finish work. They even have a monster word associated with it, Feierabendbierchen, which means "evening celebration little beer" and you better take one, drink it, enjoy it and head home on time.
Part of living in another country/culture is about experiencing the joys of our differences, and the more time you spend somewhere, the more those intricacies will show. Some of them will get on your nerves, others you'll find endearing but all in all you make the most of it.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feierabend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teutonic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THING ABOUT BERLIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiahn Wetzler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andreas Rentz/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LIGHT ETIQUETTE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SOZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feierabendbierchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aufzug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutschland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiahn WetzlerSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Tiahn Wetzler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
