<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405094298017065</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/tasmanian-mayor-tony-bisdee-loses-licence-for-three-years/8762970</url>
  <title>Tasmanian mayor who drove without licence, unregistered off the road for three months</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Tasmanian mayor Tony Bisdee has had his licence suspended for three months and been fined $500 for repeatedly driving without a licence and with an unregistered and uninsured motor vehicle.
The 73-year-old was pulled over in May and twice within 10 days last December.
Each time his licence was suspended and his car was unregistered and uninsured.
The Magistrates Court in Hobart heard Bisdee's licence was suspended by the Monetary Penalties Enforcement Section (MPES) as a result of accumulated fines.
The MPES also put a bar on the Southern Midlands Mayor being able to register his sedan until he paid the fines, which by June this year totalled about $3,000.
His lawyer told the court that like many people in public office Bisdee had been so busy with other people's affairs he had neglected his own.
He said Bisdee now had a payment plan in place with the MPES.
Magistrate Chris Webster said Bisdee should have taken steps to fix the situation after the first incident, not the third.
He delayed Bisdee's licence suspension until September to allow him to apply for a restricted licence.
The Mayor is up for re-election in October next year.
Bisdee, who has been an advocate for road safety in the Southern Midlands,

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Midlands Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Bisdee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPES</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Penalties Enforcement Section</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Midlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bisdee</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Chris Webster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
