<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405635463903917</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:24</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/british-tourists-are-now-europes-worst-when-it-comes-to-sunbed-stampedes-2017-8</url>
  <title>British tourists are now Europe's worst when it comes to sunbed stampedes</title>
  <content>
It's the war that never ends. Which tourists are worst when it comes to racing for hotel sunbeds in the morning - Germans or Brits?

For years, it's been widely acknowledged that the Germans were untouchable when it comes to laying down towels at 8am. But a new video shows the Poms bringing their A-game at the Hotel Servatur Waikiki in Gran Canaria.

Welcome to holiday resort hotel hell:

The guy owning the second row is clearly a seasoned pro, heading straight for the almost-best row in order to maximise towelage for the whole family:

that the worst offenders "are definitely the Brits followed by the Irish and then some Canarians who are on holiday here and appear to have started to become infected by their behaviour".

The British tourists were "sometimes disappearing again till the afternoon", one staffer said.

The Germans, however, appear to have calmed down and preferred to go to breakfast first before hitting the pool and taking their chances with the sunbeds.

In 2012, a survey by online travel agents sunshine.co.uk found that the Germans were seen as the worst sunbed baggers, followed by people from The Netherlands and Russia.

The feud goes back decades. In 1993, English brewer Carling even marketed British sunbed restraint as a source of national pride:

But the same study repeated in 2015 found the British had worked their way to the front, and they're now clearly dominating if the footage from Gran Canaria is anything to go by.

"To see that us Britons have overtaken Germans in the sunbed hogging stakes is a sign that our holiday etiquette has perhaps gone out of the window," Chris Clarkson, managing director of sunshine.co.uk, said after the most recent survey.

Still, at least they're not  while they swim.

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hotel Servatur Waikiki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Clarkson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canarians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gran Canaria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netherlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
