<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405055643310432</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/seven-diamond-creek-businesses-targeted-in-a-bungled-burglary/news-story/a996d52fc13dbb97760f794dee783a85</url>
  <title>Clueless crim bungles burglaries</title>
  <content>
A USELESS crook who bungled a burglary spree in Diamond Creek is being hunted by police as a business owner calls for the installation of more CCTV cameras.
Seven businesses in the shopping strips along Chute St and Main-Hurstbridge Rd were targeted in a spate of unsuccessful break-ins during the early hours of Wednesday, July 26.
Shops including Piccolo Meccanico, Degani, Indian Hub, Eltham Glass, Mr Rooster and D-Zine Hair Studio were hit.
In each case the crook tried to wedge open the door but failed, leaving just a broken lock behind, before walking away empty-handed.
D-Zine Hair Studio owner Maxine Ruzicka said she was disrupted until lunchtime by the time police and the locksmith were finished.
"We couldn't ring clients and say don't come because the appointment book was inside and we couldn't get in," she said.
Ms Ruzicka, who has owned the business for over 13 years, said security should be ramped up following the spree. She said the body corporate should install cameras in the walkway.
"We pay body corporate and I think it's something that should definitely be brought up at the next meeting," she said. "We were lucky one business had CCTV, because it wasn't worth taking fingerprints. So many clients come and go."
Eltham Glass owner Sue Constance, who is based in the Chute St strip, said increased crime in the once "sleepy little hollow" was a sign of the times.
"We've been here since 1981 and it was like a country town back then," Ms Constance said. "Now everyone knows Diamond Creek and it's not the sleepy little hollow it used to be, which is really sad."
Anyone with information about the attempted break-ins is urged to phone Banyule Criminal Investigation Unit on 9450 8000 or Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maxine Ruzicka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltham Glass</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rooster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piccolo Meccanico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D-Zine Hair Studio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ruzicka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main-Hurstbridge Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Hub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banyule Criminal Investigation Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Degani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chute St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
