<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405227442005296</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/sport/basketball/historic-preseason-matches-in-us-part-of-longterm-nbl-plan-to-bring-nba-games-to-australia/news-story/bc1145cfbb6b166751d9c0d0ba2faa30</url>
  <title>NBA game in Australia a step closer</title>
  <content>
NBL v NBA:

THERE'S a saying in business that to be the best, you've got to emulate the best.
It's a mantra some of the world's premier sporting organisations and athletes have lived by to reach the top in their chosen profession.
The NBL and the Sydney Kings are no different.
In a bid to return basketball in Australia to its glory years of the mid 1990s, the governing body and the Kings are working overtime to build a respected relationship with the world's best basketball competition.
This tireless effort, which has been years in the making, came to fruition on Tuesday with the NBL announcing an Australian triple-header against NBA teams in the US in October.
The Kings will clash with the Utah Jazz in Salt Lake City on October 3, pitting Australian internationals Kevin Lisch and Brad Newley up against fellow Boomers stars Joe Ingles and Dante Exum.
Melbourne United will play Oklahoma City Thunder, who feature reigning MVP Russell Westbrook and former Indiana Pacers star Paul George, while the Brisbane Bullets will play the Phoenix Suns.
For NBL boss Larry Kestelman, the pre-season matches are the culmination of a vision years in the making.
Speaking to The Daily Telegraph in January, Kestelman revealed he was in advanced talks with the NBA about NBL teams playing pre-season games in America.
Now after plenty of work building relationships, Kestelman's dream has become reality.
And he won't stop with games in the US. Kestelman is already in talks about NBA franchises playing in Australia in the coming years.
The Kings have also built a close relationship with the NBA, led largely by managing director Jeff Van Groningen.
The Kings' initiative has been on display in spades since Van Groningen and his team at AEG Ogden started at the franchise in May last year.
From building extensive relationships throughout the NBA, Europe and Asia to purchasing the biggest game-day screen in the southern hemisphere, the Kings' management have left no stone unturned in their bid for excellence.
It's a determined and thorough approach that has also extended to player recruitment and research.
This has been seen through the signings of respected and proven players like Lisch and Newley.
Then there is coach Andrew Gaze.
As Australia's greatest basketballer, Gaze needs no introduction.
The legendary former Melbourne Tigers and Australian Boomers icon is one of the country's most likeable and revered personalities.
Gaze's worldwide basketball reach and approachability has played a major role in putting the Kings back on the basketball map in Sydney.
The Aussie Hoops Hall of Famer can also be credited with helping the Kings attract players, sponsors and fans to the franchise.
And as we witnessed last month through his assistant coaching role with the Indiana Pacers at the Orlando Summer League, Gaze can play an influential role in building a respected connection between the NBA and the Kings organisation.
The Pacers don't just invite anyone to be on their coaching staff, so Gaze's selection was a testament to the high esteem he is held in.
More significantly for the Kings and Australian basketball, his invitation to work with Indiana will create an invaluable link with the NBA franchise moving forward.
According to Van Groningen, who helped foster the relationship between the Pacers and the Kings, Gaze's guest coaching appearance with the NBA franchise is all part of the club's grand plan to become the best.
"We are just trying to be as excellent as we can," Van Groningen said simply.
"Last year we talked about our catchcry of excellence in people and excellence in play and that has got to be our goal.
"And when you look at excellence you look to the leagues that do it best. In our sport, the NBA does it best.
"They do it most professionally, so it is all in line with that philosophy of trying to do everything we can."
Basketball is back, baby. And the historic Australian pre-season triple- header against NBA teams in America this October is just the beginning. Get on board.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indiana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MVP Russell Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dante Exum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Van Groningen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Newley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma City Thunder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Gaze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salt Lake City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indiana Pacers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orlando Summer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Hoops Hall of Famer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Van Groningen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kestelman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Lisch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEG Ogden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Boomers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
