<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406009126064385</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/councils-faces-of-frankston-campaign-to-change-perceptions-about-city/news-story/f517e4184f1467881af1044fb5e578c1</url>
  <title>Friendly faces to the fore for feel-good campaign</title>
  <content>
OUR friendliest locals are being celebrated as part of the Faces of Frankston campaign.
The campaign aims to change the conversation about Frankston and shine a light on what the city has to offer by focusing on the passionate people who live, work and study here.
The campaign features a series of photographs by Richard Simpkin, portraits of traders taken by VicRoads for its Business As Usual campaign and images supplied by Chisholm TAFE.
Mr Simpkin said he had a great time chatting with Frankston locals when he visited a few years back.
"When I got home I realised that people had a misconception about the city, so I decided to come back and capture the real Frankston - its diverse and passionate community members," he said.
His exhibition is now enjoying an encore at the Frankston Arts Centre, while some of his images are also featured on the Frankston line train.
Mayor Brian Cunial said the campaign was gaining momentum.
"From the Frankston Arts Centre to the interior of an entire train, large-scale projections on to buildings and stories in the media, portraits of friendly Frankston faces are beginning to appear here, there and everywhere," Cr Cunial said.
Frankston state Labor MP Paul Edbrooke said VicRoads' Business As Usual campaign created incentives for visitors to shop locally and support traders.
"There are major works under way and Frankston remains a vibrant place for shoppers to visit, with specialty shops, cafes and restaurants, clothing, jewellery stores, gift stores, services and a fantastic selection of recycled clothing options," he said.
"I encourage residents and visitors to check out what they've got to offer on the Faces of Frankston website and to take a wander down to Young St and its side streets, to meet our city's friendly and diverse traders for themselves."
FUNMILOLA OMIDIORA, ALL THINGS AFRICAN
Why did you decide to open a business in Frankston?
We moved down to the Mornington Peninsula seven years ago. We chose Frankston as it's the gateway to the peninsula and it is central to all business activities.
What is your family history?
My family unit of five consists of my husband, three kids and I. We moved to Australia from Nigeria in west Africa 16 years ago. We've lived in different parts of Australia but we love this area.
Tell us about your shop, All Things African
All Things African is the only business of its kind in the region. It is a retail/variety store that attends to the needs of Africans, African-Americans, African-Australians, and all lovers of Africa in the southeast. It is a specialty shop where quality African products and services can be acquired without any fuss. African communities in the Peninsula region no longer need to go to Dandenong or Noble Park for African food, hair products, or to have their hair braided. We offer easy secure online shopping as well.
What do you love most about Frankston?
Frankston is the best. I enjoy meeting my friends here and love shopping here. It has a great church community; I worship here with my church family. We have everything here, a beautiful foreshore, and fantastic food and cafes.
LUCKY FERRARO, LUCKY'S DELI
You have run a business in Frankston for over 30 years.  How do you feel about the city?
I'm Italian; from the south of Italy. Me and my wife both come from Italy. I migrated here in 1970. Frankston has been very kind to me and my family for over 30 years. We love Frankston and would like to see it prosper. I brought two kids up in this town. When we came into this country I had a little cardboard luggage - that's all I had. I'm 62 years old and I work 12 hours a day and sometimes I don't have lunch. Things don't come easy, they don't fall from the sky and you've got to work extremely hard to get them. I don't like to think of all the people who put us down. The negativity - I hate it, it's not good for us. We did prosper in this town and I want to see it prosper in return. The town is beautiful and we should appreciate it and do more to go forward.
Lucky's Deli carries your name. Can you tell us about its history?
In the 1980s we opened our first business in Wells St and from there we were in Wells St until 2000. In 2001 we relocated to Young St. In 2007 we had sold this business, but because the hardship that the town had been going through we had to come back because we owned the property and we had tenants that couldn't do it anymore.
Are you excited about the redevelopment happening in Frankston?
I'll be so happy when it's finished that I would like to run naked! No, it's all good. I had a chat with a real estate agent and they have recently sold a house in the Pines for $690,000. It's happening. It's a ripple effect. If Frankston prospers, me and my family will prosper as well. And we've worked hard for it. Frankston's already come a long way in the last six months. Even though Wells St businesses had a tough time during the works, look at how well they're doing now. We need to stay positive.
ROB WRIGHT, EENY MEENY CAFE
What is your family history?
I grew up in country NSW before making the move to Melbourne. After eight years living in inner suburbs like Fitzroy and Richmond, I moved to Seaford. At first I didn't know how I would survive - now, I can't imagine leaving.
What's unusual about your business?
We foster a sense of community and in return those communities support us. Whether it's the Peninsula GLBTIQ group or the intellectually disabled theatre troupe, the Life Begins at 60 Coffee Club or the Vision Australia Vision impaired Social catch-up. By opening our doors to all of these groups and more, we are able to offer a safe and supportive environment in which to build a cohesive community.
How do you feel about Frankston?
I love Frankston. I love the people and the places. I love the arts scene and the shopping. I love the beach and I love the bush. I love that we have the Arts Centre. I love the beachside festivals. I love the growing multiculturalism. I love the sense of community and the way so many locals believe in Frankston. I've always hated the way the media uses Frankston as the butt of jokes. It's an easy out for journalists to denigrate Frankston. I really hate it when locals denigrate Frankston. I believe in Frankston.
Are you excited about the redevelopment?
We are thrilled beyond belief about the changing face of Frankston. When I opened my business, I believed Frankston was on the cusp of something extraordinary. And now? Well it's all about to happen. Finally Frankston will look the part, to stand among the great waterside centres of Melbourne, Australia and the world.
To find out more about the campaign, or if you'd like to get involved in becoming one of the Faces of Frankston, click .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula GLBTIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Brian Cunial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MP Paul Edbrooke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Simpkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seaford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EENY MEENY CAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>27</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston Arts Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads' Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faces of Frankston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigeria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Things African</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Cunial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffee Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALL THINGS AFRICAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chisholm TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FERRARO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Begins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FUNMILOLA OMIDIORA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young St. In 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vision Australia Vision</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African-Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wells St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Simpkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LUCKY'S DELI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
