<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405571039393436</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/indooroopilly-shopping-centre-extension-with-new-exit-ramp-98-units/news-story/21034d9e9846b79ec9cdd8760b10458f</url>
  <title>Shopping centre congestion cure?</title>
  <content>
A BRISBANE shopping centre has proposed a solution to ease its significant carpark congestion while cashing in on prime real estate.
Indooroopilly Shopping Centre intends to build a new seven storey ramp on the western side of the centre that will exit onto Grosvenor Rd plus two towers of 98 units.
The shopping centre has continually made headlines for its congested carpark, with some shoppers stuck in their cars for hours trying to exit the centre.
The applicant's original plan was that the tower with the ramp would be 20 storeys, despite only 12 storeys being allowed on the 2437 sqm site under the neighbourhood plan.
The tower is now 16 storeys with the ramp and nine storeys of units, plus new retail and office tenancies.
Brisbane's planning team allowed the change because the ramp provided a strong benefit and the site area was only 63 sqm under 2500 sqm, which would allow 15 storeys.
City Planning chairman Julian Simmonds, who is also the local councillor, welcomed the recommendation from council planners to approve the development.
"We hope it eases traffic congestion around Indooroopilly Shopping Centre, particularly as our biggest trouble is people exiting the shopping centre on Musgrave Rd," he said.
Opposition City Planning spokeswoman Shayne Sutton said it seemed much easier now for developers to argue "for that next little bit of density" under performance outcomes.
"People used to have to argue really, really hard to get approvals under performance outcomes and really, clearly show a clear public benefit," she said.
"The extent of public benefit they have to prove has grossly deteriorated."
Cr Simmonds said the developer had proposed a solution to the congestion-plagued shopping centre "and we're sure as heck not going to stop them from easing the congestion".
He said under performance outcomes the council needed to demonstrate the project would not cause greater stress on the road network or community amenity than a building built exactly to code.
"What we've actually got is a proposal that creates far less burden that what the neighbourhood plan envisaged when it said we're going to transfer it to residential," he said.
The development will be built in two stages.
The application from owners Commonwealth Superannuation Corporation was endorsed by the City Planning Committee.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Musgrave Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Planning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shayne Sutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Simmonds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grosvenor Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Simmonds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indooroopilly Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Planning Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Superannuation Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
