<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405137247690669</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/wa-university-sexual-assault-victim-speaks-out/8762788</url>
  <title>'Your body is no longer your own': UWA student and black belt Zee Ibrahim froze during sex assault</title>
  <content>
It wasn't the first time Zee Ibrahim had been sexually harassed. But the assault by a male friend in the toilets of the UWA tavern shocked her the most.
Ms Ibrahim was a first-year university student when she was attending a social event at the tavern in 2012.

Sexual assault support services:

National university support line: 1800 572 224 (until November 30, 2017)
1800 RESPECT: 1800 737 732
Lifeline: 131 114
Beyond Blue: 1300 224 636

She was heading to the bathroom when she came across the friend, who pushed her through the female toilet doors.
"There was quite a big crowd, so no one really saw it," Ms Ibrahim said.
"He pushed me up against the wall and he started taking off my clothing and I kept trying to push him off."
"He was quite a big guy, very well built, very tall and muscly."
"I have a black belt in taekwondo that I got when I was 15, I started training when I was 10, so I'm very capable of defending myself but I found at that time I was so paralysed with fear.
"There were all these people just outside the door and it was as if I was just in a complete sphere by myself. I was just terrified."
Ms Ibrahim said the incident was disrupted when another woman came through the bathroom door.
She said she managed to break away and immediately left the event.
"It's terrifying to go through that because it's very much your body is no longer your own."
"Unfortunately that wasn't the first time I'd been harassed. It was one of the worst, it wasn't the last time either.
"It happens all the time on campus, there are so many stories like mine."
WA universities respond

All five of Western Australia's universities participated in the Human Right's Commission  campuses, released today.
It found that nationally one in five students were sexually harassed in a university setting in 2016 and 1.6 per cent of students were sexually assaulted in a university setting on at least one occasion in 2015 or 2016.
The Vice Chancellors of the University of Western Australia, Curtin University, Murdoch University, Edith Cowan University and Notre Dame University signed a joint statement vowing to "make our campuses safer for students, staff and the community."
"One case of sexual harassment and sexual assault is one too many," the statement said.
"We are working individually and collectively to address the issues highlighted in the Respect. Now. Always. national survey"

External Link:

Sexual harrassment and assault locations

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RESPECT: 1800 737 732</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UWA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ibrahim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 30, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Notre Dame University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice-Chancellor of the University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murdoch University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue: 1300 224 636</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zee Ibrahim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edith Cowan University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
