<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406232464367736</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/michael-hussey-rapt-with-frustrating-cricket-australia-pay-dispute-set-to-end-20170731-gxmpzn.html</url>
  <title>Michael Hussey rapt with 'frustrating' pay dispute set to end</title>
  <content>
Canberra's Big Bash League chances are set to get a huge boost with Australian cricket's biggest industrial war since World Series Cricket almost over.
Cricket Australia and the Australian Cricketers Association are edging closer to inking a new memorandum of understanding and ending the pay war that has left the game in crisis.Photo: Kate Geraghty
However an announcement isn't expected until Wednesday with the CA board, ACA executive and the players all needing to sign off on a new deal.
The end of the bitter dispute will save a huge summer of cricket with England coming down under to defend the Ashes and enhances Canberra's chances of hosting elite men's cricket.

A new deal being struck will .
It also means Australian cricket great Michael Hussey can finally get on with his job of putting together a Thunder roster capable of challenging for their second Big Bash League crown.

Each club has been given an extra home game in an expanded competition, but Thunder are yet to announce a venue for their fifth home fixture against the Melbourne Renegades on January 24.
Manuka Oval has firmed as the favourite but no deal is in place with the Thunder also considering using their normal home ground at Spotless Stadium.
Government officials said all parties were in a holding pattern until the pay dispute was ironed out and now talks can finally speed up.
Hussey has played under lights at Manuka Oval for the Prime Minister's XI and the Thunder's director of cricket would be "rapt" if the club brought a game to Canberra.
"It's been frustrating for everyone. Everyone wants to get this sorted out so we can all get on with the rest of our jobs," Hussey said. 
"Mine is trying to help put a squad together, but negotiations about where games are being played and all that stuff, plus it's a big year with the Ashes coming up.
"We want to make sure everything is in place so we can enjoy a great Ashes series.
"It's been a bit tough while we haven't been able to sign players up due to the MOU dispute but hopefully they can sort it out pretty quickly and we can get on to actually signing our players and finalising our list before the season starts."
Hussey is glad he's on the other side of the picket fence and not embroiled in the pay war that could permanently scar relationships between players and administrators.
The 79-Test veteran forged a reputation as one of the greatest batsmen Australia has ever produced and says it's absolutely vital August's tour of Bangladesh goes ahead.
Hussey says touring Bangladesh will be beneficial for both the game and Australia's Test squad as they prepare to win back the Ashes urn this summer.
"I'm glad I'm removed from all that side of things. It's been hard to watch," Hussey said.
"Hopefully, fingers crossed, they can sort it out in the coming days. Australia needs to go to Bangladesh. It would be a shame if we didn't tour Bangladesh for a second time.
"We pulled out for security reasons last time, and to pull out again would be awful.
"I think from a player's point of view, you want to play in different parts around the world. Obviously we know our conditions really well, but if we want to succeed, playing overseas it's a great challenge.
"I think it's important and I'm hoping they get this MOU sorted. I don't miss the stress and the pressure that the players have to go through, that's for sure."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotless Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Series Cricket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra's Big Bash League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bash League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hussey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Renegades</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister's XI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hussey</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Geraghty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thunder</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
