<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405059938277792</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/11/59/flight-plan-lacking-in-tas-plane-crash</url>
  <title>Flight plan lacking in Tas plane crash</title>
  <content>
Two Tasmanian pilots who survived a light plane crash took off with no flight plan and both believing the other was in charge, an investigation has found.
The pair left from Bridport in the state's north in July last year, but were forced to ditch in a paddock when the plane's engine failed.
The pilot from Scottsdale suffered spinal injuries, while his co-pilot walked away relatively unharmed.
An Australian Transport Safety Bureau report released on Tuesday found the plane ran out of fuel.
"There was inadequate communication between the pilots ... with no defined flight plan, no pre-flight brief and each pilot believing the other was in command," it said.
"The lack of a flight plan prevented the pilots from ensuring there was sufficient fuel and reserves available to ensure safe flight."
The bureau said uncertified maintenance had been carried out on the amateur-built Europa Aircraft Classic, which increased the flight's risk, but didn't contribute directly to the crash.

Related Articles

"The aircraft's log book was incomplete with respect to fuel system maintenance and the aircraft's fuel filter had been replaced with an unapproved part," it said.
The accident highlighted the importance of pre-fight planning, the investigation concluded.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europa Aircraft Classic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scottsdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Transport Safety Bureau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
