<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405055643310456</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/breaking-news/spat-intensifies-over-cbd-homeless-tents/news-story/1c5e484d32a726eebd43dc56eebb7627</url>
  <title>Spat intensifies over CBD homeless tents</title>
  <content>
Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore has been accused of not doing enough to remove a homeless camp threatening to become a permanent fixture in the city centre.
Dozens of tents have been erected along the iconic Martin Place forecourt since December, with the number continuing to grow, despite attempts by the council and state government to move them on.
Family and Community Services Minister Pru Goward on Tuesday accused Ms Moore and the council of not undertaking public safety or compliance requirements seriously.
"I call on the mayor of this city to do so," Ms Goward said in a statement.
"The public expect her to act."
FACS Housing staff have visited the site 41 times to offer services and accommodation to those who are sleeping rough, with about 60 of them now in permanent housing.
"Just yesterday and again today, FACS Housing staff visited the area to help people experiencing homelessness find accommodation and spoke with every person sleeping in a tent," Ms Goward said.
The minister says it's "ludicrous" her department had to apply for a council permit to erect a tent for the homeless in the camp opposite the Reserve Bank.
Premier Gladys Berejiklian threw her weight behind the calls on Tuesday, saying the tent city makes her "completely uncomfortable".
"I'm concerned that some (homeless) people there are not there for the right reasons and that's why we've written to Clover Moore asking her to do what's in her powers to move them on," Ms Berejiklian told reporters in Sydney.
"We have made sure that anybody who needs emergency accommodation is given that and unfortunately some people are choosing not to take that up that offer," she said.
"I don't think that's appropriate."
The City of Sydney council in June moved away much of the previous camp, which includes a kitchen, on the Macquarie Street end of the thoroughfare.
Ms Moore has been contacted for comment.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Services Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FACS Housing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Goward</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
