<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406137975085598</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/aerial-images-reveal-extent-of-storm-damage-in-perth/news-story/70b76607446e85cb0583b0f4bf8dccd3</url>
  <title>Aerial images reveal storm damage</title>
  <content>
AERIAL images have revealed the scale of the damage from yesterday's storm.
A suspected tornado tore through the northern suburbs, tearing the roof from a home in Duncraig.
Destructive winds and torrential rain lashed the state yesterday, with the Perth suburbs of Sorrento, Duncraig, Warwick, Hamersley and Balga copping some of the worst damage.
The aerial images show roofing insulation exposed in one home, while the house next door appears unscathed.
In Rochester Circle in Balga, a tree crashed through a house into a kitchen, tiles blew off roofs, a wheelie bin lid blew off and crashed through a home and a powerline fell.
It's going to be particularly cold in Perth on Wednesday, dropping down to just 5C with frost likely in the eastern suburbs.
It was a wet and wild day

The rain returns again on Thursday, with a high chance of showers in the afternoon and evening, and it will linger over weekend and into Monday.
The cold change will bring morning frost to several areas in the South West as well, with Collie set for an overnight minimum of just 1C.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rochester Circle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamersley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sorrento</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncraig</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balga</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
