<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405880277043449</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/hanley-toughened-by-a-hard-year-in-the-suns</url>
  <title>Hanley toughened by a hard year in the Suns</title>
  <content>
Pearce Hanley hasn't played as many games for the Suns as he'd have liked

GOLD Coast midfielder Pearce Hanley says navigating a tumultuous 2017 has made him a better person and could even make him a better footballer next year.

Hanley left the Brisbane Lions last off-season and has endured the death of his teenage brother, a horror run with injuries, and a losing first season with the Suns.

But it hasn't dulled the 28-year-old's enthusiasm for his change of clubs.

"I've had a lot of stuff go wrong," Hanley said.

"I had a really good pre-season and was set up for a big year and it obviously didn't eventuate.

"The last few months has only made me stronger as a person on and off the field.

"I think next year it's going to shape and motivate me to get back to my best form."

Hanley returned to Ireland following Gold Coast's round one loss to his former club, to spend time with his dying brother, returning a fortnight later.

In his first game back in the NEAFL he injured his heel and didn't play senior footy again until round 10.

Hanley said the loss of his brother hit hard.

"I think anyone that's lost a family member, it doesn't take a month or two to get over," he said.

"Every day it's on your mind and going into most games.

"I think I've dealt with it very well. I don't think my leadership amongst the group has fluctuated and I'm super proud of that.

"In the end, it's only a game. Footy's a business, it's a job, I have to do it, but it puts it in perspective."

Hanley played arguably his best match in Suns colours on Saturday night, overcoming a few first-quarter mistakes to finish with 31 disposals playing in an inexperienced backline.

He said despite the club's struggles this year, he was adamant he'd made the right decision to move 70km south to his new club.

"I love what we're doing here," he said.

"My teammates, everyone strives to get better.

"We've had a few things go wrong this year but we're all confident in the direction we're going.

"And that gives me good faith going forward and makes my decision correct in my eyes.

"I've had an indifferent year on and off the field but I've loved my time on the Gold Coast and helping these young kids, and we're building something here.

"We've had a poor year, but the next few years are very exciting."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce Hanley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
