<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405961881423384</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/mystery-artists-turn-council-bollards-at-the-gap-into-animated-characters-20170731-gxm38u.html</url>
  <title>Mystery artists turn council bollards into animated characters</title>
  <content>
The Simpsons and colourful Lego characters have mysteriously appeared atop cement bollards in Brisbane's west.
A pair of anonymous artists converted about 30 cement bollards into the colourful characters around Yoorala Street Reserve at The Gap.Photo: Facebook / Preserve our Parks, Civic Centres for Community Groups: The Gap Qld
It is understood the Simpsons characters were installed in May, while more than 20 lego characters appeared in July.
The Gap Resident's Association member Chris Taylor said the clever decorations popped up from nowhere.Photo: Facebook / Preserve our Parks, Civic Centres for Community Groups: The Gap Qld
"We're not sure who is responsible for them, but we've seen a number of families who have enjoyed stopping and looking at them as they walk along the creek trails in The Gap," he said.
"We think they are great."

 It is understood the characters are mainly crafted of paper mache.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

A Preserve our Parks The Gap spokeswoman said one of the artists was a local, while the other used to lived in the area, but they wanted to remain anonymous.Photo: Facebook / Preserve our Parks, Civic Centres for Community Groups: The Gap Qld
"The bollard art serves two key purposes, one to highlight the boundary of the park from the area of conservation/rehabilitation of the creek waterways/corridor, and two, to reclaim the park as a place for families and kids," the POP spokeswoman said.
It is understood the art installation to reclaim the parkland may have stemmed from an ongoing feud between residents and members of the Ashgrove Men's Shed.
The Ashgrove Men's Shed group moved to their current site at Yoorala Street in October, 2015.
"The men's shed needs to be in a more appropriate location to enable them to their light industrial equipment in a more suitable location away from family homes," the POP spokeswoman said.
"We support the goals of the men's shed as a support group, however they need to [be] in a suitable location."
The spokeswoman said, to her knowledge, the appearance of the characters had not attracted any negative comments.
"Most just love the playfulness of them," she said.
"The Simpsons ones are all paper mache, non-destructive of council property.
"The Lego ones are a mix of paper mache, foam, thermal plastics and foss-shape, then pained."
The art work can be found at the park boundary, as well the the boundary of the off-leash dog area.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashgrove Men's Shed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lego</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gap Qld</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Groups</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yoorala Street Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gap Resident's Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yoorala Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gap.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Centres</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
