<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406284003976121</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:55</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/british-gas-electricity-price-rise-for-31-million-people-2017-8</url>
  <title>British Gas is putting up electricity prices by 12.5% for 3.1 million people</title>
  <content>
LONDON - British Gas is raising electricity prices for 3.1 million of its UK customers by 12.5% from September.

British Gas owner Centrica , the first rise in electricity prices since November 2013. The company

The hike follows a price freeze announced in February that British Gas said would last until August.

British Gas said the increase will add £76 to the typical annual bill of a household on its dual fuel standard tariff, taking it to £1,120. However, customers can fix their energy price until August 2019 on a specially discounted deal, Home Energy Secure, which will cost £1,107 per year, British Gas says.

While 3.1 million customers will be hit by the price rise, British Gas says 5.3 million people will be unaffected. 200,000 vulnerable customers are being protected from the increase.

The price hike "reflects the increasing costs of energy policy, and delivery to customers' homes since 2014," British Gas says in a statement. "In that time, overall electricity costs have increased by 16%."

The price rise may draw criticism from the government. Theresa May  and

Centrica Consumer CEO Mark Hodges says in a statement:

"We held off increasing prices for many months longer than most suppliers in order to protect our customers from rising costs, so it is a difficult decision to have to announce an increase in electricity prices. This rise reflects an underlying increase in policy and transmission costs."

Centrica Consumer also on Tuesday reported a 20% fall in operating profit in the first half of the year  Group revenue was up 7% to £14.3 billion and adjusted operating profit was down 4% to £816 million.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrica Consumer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Secure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Gas</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrica Consumer CEO Mark Hodges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theresa May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
