<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405656938740632</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/health/how-this-bachelor-contestant-lost-22kg-in-8-months/news-story/2be673daf984d024e7ed37255b8d9779</url>
  <title>How this Bachelor contestant lost 22kg in 8 months</title>
  <content>
SHE'S currently one of the 19 women vying for Matty J's heart on The Bachelor, but love coach Belinda Rygier has already achieved one of her biggest goals - losing 22kg.
The 34-year-old has revealed on Instagram how it's taken her years to figure out what works best for her body.
"For years I hid my body out of fear of being called fat and ridiculed," she wrote on Instagram.
"It took me 16 years to work out why I couldn't lose weight. I tried everything you can think of."
She consulted a personal trainer and a naturopath and now sticks to a mostly gluten free, dairy free, sugar free diet.
"I finally found out my liver wasn't functioning properly and when I fixed it I lost 22kg," she said.
"I got the exact formula for me and I finally lost [weight]. It wasn't just about the diet and training.
"16 years of hard work, wrong advice and many different options to work out why I couldn't lose weight.
"I finally got the right advice, fixed my health and lost 20kg in only eight months.
"When I look in the mirror now I see the same person I always was, just different."
She says she now feels "happy, healthy and sexy".
The Bachelor returns to Channel 10 this week on Wednesday and Thursday nights.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Rygier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
