<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405064233245420</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/moreton/wyllie-park-overnight-stays-banned-after-complaints-end-trial/news-story/eb4440858a32e03ddd4b85d5ed8280e0</url>
  <title>Campers shut out</title>
  <content>
WYLLIE  Park will be permanently closed to overnight campers after a decision this week by Moreton Bay Regional Council.
The park had been undergoing a 16-month overnight stay trial, which the council ended due to a number of issues and complaints.
"The council received more than 145 complaints from local residents during the trial period regarding a number of issues including people overstaying the 48-hour period and camping overnight in cars and tents rather than self-contained motorhomes and caravans," a spokesman said.
"Other issues included damage to council infrastructure, increased waste accumulation and the use of petrol generators at night."
He said there was also a significant increase in the resources and time required to police the site rules.
The move will be a blow to grey nomads in particular, who regularly use free or low-cost camping grounds across the country.
Camper Karen McKenna told the Pine Rivers Press it was getting harder for travellers to find free or reasonably priced parks for caravans.
Wyllie Park was recently fenced off to replace ageing slash pines with hoop pines and eucalyptus trees. It will reopen on August 7.
"Hoop pines and eucalyptus trees are intrinsically linked with the Petrie area, so I'm thrilled to see planting of these native varieties now complete for the community to enjoy," Division 7 Councillor Denise Sims said.
"The eucalyptus trees have been strategically planted close to the river bank to enhance koala habitat, while the hoop pines have been planted in a radial pattern as a nod to the site's past."
The works form part of the site's vegetation management plan, which is approved by the Department of Environment and Heritage Protection as part of the park's listing on the Queensland Register of Heritage Places.
Temporary fencing will remain in place for a period of time as the trees continue to establish themselves in their new home.
Cr Sims extended her appreciation to the community for their patience during the tree planting work, which also coincided with a review of the park's overnight stay trial.
A list of alternate overnight stay locations in the region is available at visitmoretonbayregion.com.au/blog/posts/camping-moreton-bay-region
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Sims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Environment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 7 Councillor Denise Sims</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyllie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Register of Heritage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pine Rivers Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyllie Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heritage Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen McKenna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
