<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406271119074032</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-brett-deledio-finally-set-to-make-gws-giants-debut-in-canberra-20170731-gxmpy8.html</url>
  <title>Brett Deledio finally set to make Giants debut</title>
  <content>
Brett Deledio will finally play his first game for the Greater Western Sydney Giants in one of the best comeback stories of the AFL season.
The Giants will play their final match at Manuka Oval for the season when they host the Melbourne Demons on Saturday afternoon.
Deledio's long-awaited return will bring an end to an agonising hard-luck story that has seen him spend more than 13 months on the sidelines battling injury.
The 30-year-old was traded to the Giants this season having played the last of his 243 AFL games for Richmond in July last year.
Deledio has finally emerged into the light at the end of the tunnel after the calf injuries that plagued the latter stages of his career threatened to derail his Giants career before it even started.
Giants coach Leon Cameron says Deledio will give his side a massive boost ahead of a top eight showdown in Canberra.

"He can give us a list in some areas that we need to get a lift in and it'll be good for confidence as well. Just to play again will be great for him because he's had a tough 15 months.
"He's got good levels of persistency and resilience so we look forward to seeing what he can do.
"It's a funny game AFL, you mightn't play much during the year but if you're up and running at the right end of the year then you could be a chance in some really big games."
Deledio is contracted to the Giants until the end of the 2019 season and will look to start his playing career for the western Sydney-based outfit on the right foot against the Demons.
AFL ROUND 20
Saturday: GWS Giants v Melbourne Demons at Manuka Oval, 1:45pm. Tickets available from .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL ROUND 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manuka Oval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
