<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406090730444388</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/world/three-members-of-the-same-family-were-killed-while-on-holiday-in-devon-uk/news-story/cc5e60fa3de0f846e5b63aed3fa1fc38</url>
  <title>Dad watched family die in rear-view mirror</title>
  <content>
A HUSBAND watched in horror as his wife and two children were killed in a car crash on Monday during a family holiday.
The youngsters were travelling with their mum when their silver car collided with an M&S lorry in the second week of the school holidays.
reports the stepdad was in a separate car and is believed to have witnessed the tragedy in his rear-view mirror while -driving ahead of them.
His family was on holiday together in Devon, in the UK, when his wife's car collided with a lorry on the A361 near Barnstaple at around 8.25am in the morning.
The woman and one of the children died at the scene - between Aller Cross and Landkey.
The other youngster was taken to -hospital by air ambulance but died a short time later.
The family was believed to be from the Milton Keynes area, in southern England.
Police Inspector Richard McLellan said from the scene: "It seems at the moment we had two cars travelling towards Barnstaple - a family on holiday in the area - when for an unknown reason the vehicle had crossed the centre lines and collided with an HGV coming the other way."
He confirmed her husband was in front of her when the crash happened and saw what happened.
Police are appealing for witnesses to the incident to get in touch.
North Devon Tory MP Peter Heaton-Jones branded the A361 "not a safe road".
He said: "We don't know the causes at the moment but people are taking too many risks because there are short overtaking lanes that suddenly merge at not much notice."
A spokesman for M&S said: "Our thoughts and sympathies go out to the family and friends of the individuals involved."

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Devon Tory MP Peter Heaton-Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HGV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aller Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnstaple</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector Richard McLellan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milton Keynes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
