<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406271119073995</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:52</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/millies-eating-disorder-battle-is-helping-others/3207593/</url>
  <title>Millie's eating disorder battle is helping others</title>
  <content>
IT has been a long road for Ellie Potter.
After moving to the Sunshine Coast a little over two years ago she was searching for a support network to help with her eating-disorder battle.
This is when she came across Millie Thomas and EndED, a Coast-based organisation which is a permanent support network for those suffering from eating disorders.
Ellie said the time she had spent with Millie had been invaluable in being able to share in the struggles Millie knows all too well, having also struggled with an eating disorder for much of her life.
"You can go to psychologists and doctors but it's hard for them to connect with what you're going through," Ellie said.
"Just being able to open up and express feelings - its something I would 100% recommend."
Millie, 29, became a mentor with EndED after a 15-year battle with anorexia and now provides support for more than 20 Coast women also going through the same circumstances as she did.
"I want to do everything I possibly can to educate people about eating disorders," she said.
And she is doing just that by encouraging the Coast community to get involved with Waterlife 2017 which will be directly supporting EndED as well as other Coast charities, Wishlist and No Limits Adaptive Paddling.
"Through Waterlife - which raised a total of $39,000 last year - we hope to help create an environment in which women and men feel comfortable in their own skin," Millie said.
"At present Waterlife really is the lifeblood of endED.
"Without the funds raised from the event last year we wouldn't be able to make nearly as much of a difference to people's lives as we currently are."
Funds raised by this year's Waterlife event will allow endED to launch awareness campaigns about services endED offers, as well as giving the team access to the latest eating disorder research to work with sufferers and their parents or carers.
Waterlife will also help Wishlist raise funds for Queensland's first public exercise physiology service for cancer patients which will be based at the Sunshine Coast University Hospital.
It will also support the growth of No Limits Adaptive Paddling, a group changing the lives of people living with physical disabilities.
The Waterlife event will be held at Lake Kawana on August 19.
To register or to find out more information, visit .
Gofundme set up for better mobility equipment and ongoing costs
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
Coast applauds decision to upgrade major venue
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
And so BYTE - the Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence - was born.
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millie Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WaterLife</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterlife 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellie Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millie, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Limits Adaptive Paddling</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
