<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405270391678845</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/hope-of-buying-keeps-melbourne-market-strong-corelogic/news-story/47dab98101ff8960c4b1706dcd24ffd7</url>
  <title>Hope of buying keeps Melbourne market strong: CoreLogic - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
41 Imbros St, Hampton, sold for $2.51 million in July.

BUOYANT buyer demand has kept Melbourne's property market motoring ahead of the rest of the nation.
The latest CoreLogic Home Values Index, released today, showed the Victorian capital notched up 15.9 per cent growth in home values in the past year, compared to a 12.4 per cent gain in Sydney.
RELATED:
RELATED:

The Victorian capital has experienced 15.9 per cent price gains during the past year.

CoreLogic head of research Tim Lawless said the city had well and truly firmed as the country's best performing capital.
"You've seen that net interstate migration into New South Wales is starting to fade, while it continues to go from strength to strength in Victoria, and ultimately I think people still think they have a chance in that housing market," he said.
"Wages are fairly similar, the economy is performing quite strongly in Victoria as well, but you can still afford to buy a house, which is not really the case in Sydney for a lot of people now.
"As long as Melbourne still offers affordable housing, and it does at the moment but obviously if it continues to grow it won't, I would expect that the Melbourne housing market will continue to be probably stronger relative to Sydney."

3/10-12 Ida St, Fitzroy North, sold for $605,000 during July.

The index showed values were up 2.2 per cent and 2.1 per cent in Brisbane and Adelaide respectively, and down 2.1 per cent in struggling Perth, over the same 12 month period.
It also showed a 3.1 per cent jump in Melbourne during July, as well as a quarterly increase of 4.1 per cent.
Despite Melbourne's strong overall growth, Mr Lawless said there was still a gap between the booming house market and the softer apartment market.
Advantage Property Consulting director Frank Valentic said he was not shocked Melbourne was leading the way.
"I'm not surprised we are ahead of Sydney," he said.
"They peaked quite high and are still a lot more expensive. Melbourne is probably about 30 per cent more affordable than Sydney."
The strong price gains Melbourne had experienced were consistent with solid clearance rates and good buyer demand, he said.

CoreLogic head of research Tim Lawless said the city had firmed as the country's best performing capital.

"Good houses are still selling well and with clearance rates around 75 per cent, it shows Melbourne is not slowing down," Mr Valentic said.
"The market is still pretty solid and buyer activity and clearance rates support that. There are very strong numbers at open for inspections and auctions.
"I can't see Melbourne starting to settle down until major economic change, such as interest rate or unemployment rate rises. Melbourne is performing steadily."
He said that while growth was once being led by inner suburbs, middle and outer ring suburbs were now catching up.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Lawless</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Consulting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lawless</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imbros St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ida St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Valentic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic Home Values Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Valentic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzroy North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
