<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406387083193164</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-01/calls-for-national-approach-to-abandoned-mine-rehabilitation/8763538</url>
  <title>Expert calls for abandoned mine national plan at Senate inquiry</title>
  <content>
A national approach to the regulation of thousands of abandoned mines across Australia is needed to ease problems for landholders.
A Senate inquiry into the rehabilitation of the nation's abandoned mines has heard from a researcher with 30 years' experience of the issue, who claims landholders are in ''no man's land''.
Corrine Unger, a researcher from the University of Queensland, said state-by-state guidelines should be scrapped in favour of a national framework.

"It really isn't clear how we protect values of national significance through the current abandoned mine framework," Ms Unger said.

"That legislative framework is broken, the Environmental Protection and Biodiversity Conservation Act does not address abandoned mines."

Ghost mine: The tailings dam at Mount Oxide, near Mount Isa.

Ghost mine: The tailings dam at Mount Oxide, near Mount Isa.

Supplied: Georgie Spredborough

National data base of abandoned mines

Ms Unger said with many abandoned mines low on the priority list there was growing concern about their environmental impact.

"While we continue to manage abandoned mines at a state level it does become fragmented," she said.

Ms Unger used the National Orphaned/Abandoned Mines Initiative in Canada as an example of a program providing a national data set.
She said it was group made up of many stakeholders from all the of the country's provinces as well as Indigenous groups.
"They've made significant progress. They now have a national database on abandoned mines, it's online, it's interactive and you can go and search for it," she said.
"Through those groups there's a recognition that the problem exists, so that's the first step," she said.
Ms Unger said a national stakeholder group would help landholders like Brussie Spreadborough, of Chidna Station, near Mount Isa in Northern Queensland.
Mr Spreadborough has had a long-running battle with authorities over the Mount Oxide copper mine, north of Mount Isa, which was abandoned in 1971.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Unger</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgie Spredborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrine Unger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spreadborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brussie Spreadborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Isa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environmental Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Oxide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Orphaned/Abandoned Mines Initiative</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biodiversity Conservation Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chidna Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
