<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405742838087753</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/casey-street-watch-cranbourne-man-arrested-for-wallace-st-house-fire-help-find-missing-man-eli-cohen/news-story/4e4978c9ef80cb9552b421e498bd489f</url>
  <title>Cranbourne man, 35, arrested for house fire</title>
  <content>
CRANBOURNE
Police have arrested a man in relation to an arson attack on a Cranbourne home on July 25. Officers were called to the Wallace Rd premises about 12.50pm, after reports a man had set fire to a house. The 35-year-old Cranbourne man left the scene armed with a knife and was arrested at a nearby oval. He will be taken to hospital for assessment. Another man was treated by paramedics after receiving minor lacerations and burns. No injuries to the police or other members of the public were reported. Anyone with information about the incident is urged to phone Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
Police are appealing for public assistance to help locate Eli Cohen. The 28-year-old Cranbourne man was last seen in Cranbourne on July 11. Police and family members hold concerns for his welfare due to the length of time he has been missing. He is described as about 173cm tall, with black hair, brown eyes, an olive complexion and a medium build. He is known to frequent the Cranbourne area. Police have released an image of Mr Cohen in the hope someone may recognise him and be able to provide information on his whereabouts. Anyone who sees him is urged to contact the Cranbourne Police Station on 5991 0600 or Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
CRANBOURNE EAST
A 47-year-old Cranbourne East woman and 45-year-old Crib Point man will face court for allegedly driving while under the influence of the drug ice. Police pulled the woman over while she was driving on McMahons Rd, Frankston, about 5.30pm on July 13. She allegedly tested positive for the drug. A short time later, the same highway patrol unit pulled the same car over, this time being driven by the Crib Point man, who was unlicensed and also allegedly tested positive for ice. Both are due to appear in court soon.
BERWICK
A 25-year-old, unlicensed woman from Berwick has had her vehicle impounded after police busted her driving an unroadworthy car while on drugs and with an unrestrained 18-month-old child in the back seat. The woman was intercepted by police on the Princes Highway on July 25. The vehicle had two bald tyres and was slapped with a defect notice. Police were left shaking their heads when they discovered the 18-month-old child in the back seat was unrestrained. The female driver returned a positive reading for drugs and is due to appear in court for an array of offences.
Police are looking for the owner of a necklace with a religious pendant attached. The necklace was found in the Berwick area. Anyone who is able to provide a description of the pendant is asked to phone the Cranbourne Police Property Officer on 5991 0649.
NARRE WARREN
A young woman was surprised in her home by a burglar who ran off when he saw her. Police said the man went to the Garden View Court home between 1.45pm and 2pm on May 23, after breaking in through a back door. The man is described as caucasian,
18-20 years old, about 185cm tall, with tanned skin and dark hair. He was wearing a yellow, high-visibility jacket, shorts and work boots. Anyone with any information about the incident is asked to phone Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or visit crimestoppers
vic.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>McMahons Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eli Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne Police Property Officer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallace Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crib Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garden View Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berwick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narre Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRANBOURNE EAST</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
