<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406391378160509</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/retro-food-blogger-pineapple-princess-offers-recipes-for-glut/8763664</url>
  <title>Retro food blogger offers hundreds of recipes to solve Queensland's winter pineapple glut</title>
  <content>
With news that Queensland pineapples are in oversupply this winter due to the summer heatwave, it is timely that Hunter Valley-based food blogger Anne Fisher should notch up a milestone.
Ms Fisher's blog Pineapple Princesses this month marked five years as a project, with more than 500 recipes tested in her Dungog, NSW kitchen.
"I think I am the biggest buyer of pineapples in Dungog," she said.
With consumers being , Ms Fisher is confident her blog contains more than enough ideas to help clear the nation's pineapple glut.
"I've definitely got enough recipes now for the rest of my life, and more come up on the internet all the time," she said.
The versatility of pineapples

The humble pineapple is nothing if not versatile, bringing its own zesty flavour to most dishes, from desserts and salads to appetisers and mains.
"A family favourite is to grill a whole pineapple on a spit and baste it with butter melted with brown sugar," Ms Fisher said.
"You bake it over about three hours and then slice it. It is delicious and you can eat it as a dessert or as an accompaniment to meat."
As a demonstration of her commitment to the pineapple cause, Ms Fisher made a 76km journey to hand-deliver a pineapple slice to ABC staff.
"There's a shortcrust pastry, but the mix around it is mostly almond meal and eggs, some butter and some sugar," she said.
"It puffs up with heating around the pineapple; the cherries go on last."

Taking the mickey out of Golden Circle recipe book

Ms Fisher started her blog five years ago with a friend as a tribute to Ruby Borrowdale, the home economist behind the Golden Circle Tropical Recipe Book.
"A friend of mine and I were looking through it one time and we found it very amusing," she said.
"Especially some of the recipes using jelly. And we thought well, why don't we do a Julie & Julia and cook our way through it while writing a blog?"
Julie & Julia is a 2009 film starring Meryl Streep and Amy Adams, about blogger Julie Powell's 2002 challenge to cook all the recipes in her culinary hero Julia Child's first book.
Ms Fisher admits the blog started out taking the mickey out of the dated recipes, but has since become a passion she believes may never come to an end.
"It's been great fun. It's been a challenge," she said.
"Every few days we'd have to come up with a new one, and I'd try to emulate photographs from the book as well with my own arrangements."

In defence of the spiky topped fruit

The Queensland-based Golden Circle brand grew out of a grower cooperative in the 1940s, with the pineapple cannery starting production in Northgate in 1947.
Initially producing about 40,000 tonnes of canned pineapple annually, the Northgate cannery now produces more than 150,000 tonnes per year of canned pineapple, fruit juices and cordials, according to the company website.
The company, which was taken over by US food producer Heinz in a deal worth $288 million, continues to publish retro recipes on its website, in addition to modern takes on some of the old classics.
ABC Radio presenter James Valentine recently published an episode of his afternoon program , in which he took aim at the humble pineapple.
Ms Fisher featured in the episode, which focused on callers' stories about horrendous pineapple recipes.
She used the episode to defend the spiky topped fruit, underlining a serious side to her quirky blog.
"It has led on to many recipes that we do love," she said.
As well as sending in recipes, followers of Ms Fisher's blog send her objects from around the world featuring pineapple motifs, which she posts on the blog.
She said it had now evolved into a virtual museum.
"And I think it's important that a lot of cookery blogs do that," she said.
"They're a record of trends in cooking and fashions."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Valentine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Powell's 2002</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruby Borrowdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Child</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meryl Streep</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Circle Tropical Recipe Book</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland-based Golden Circle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Valley-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dungog</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Circle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heinz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northgate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pineapple Princesses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fisher</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
