<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406425737899744</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/southeast/extension-heralds-new-era-for-camp-hill-shopping-centre/news-story/b85ba1818ae2b32a0a2a5ceb2fbea47d</url>
  <title>Works to link centres</title>
  <content>
EARTHWORKS were completed on the $10 million stage 2 extensions to Whites Hill Village last week, paving the way for a new era for the centre.
Stage 2 construction started last month and is expected to be completed in March 2018 with a two-level building including 10 stores and office space to open in April.
Owners of the adjoining Samuel Village, the Hamell Group, bought Whites Hill Village in 2011 with the intent to link the two centres into one shopping complex.
Hamell general manager Catherine Hartley said on completion of the $20 million extension, the centre would be rebranded as Camp Hill Marketplace.
The extension features a small performance stage in stage one and a green space area planned for stage two.
"We wanted to create a community hub. The design has a sense of Queensland lifestyle with the big, open undercover areas with lots of outdoor dining," Ms Hartley said.
"The stage area is great in terms of servicing the needs of the community whether it be music on a Friday night, the local vet having a puppy preschool or a local school doing a concert.
"It's all about a community area where people can come together in the local area. The green hub going into the next stage really expands on that to be the heart of the community.
"That's the idea too of having offices. People won't just come here to shop but to work here."
STAGE 2
■ 10 new ground-floor stores
■ 500sq m level-one offices
■ Green space area connects to stage one courtyard
■ Expected to open in April 2018
ON COMPLETION of stage two, Camp Hill Marketplace will be home to 60 food, fashion and lifestyle shops as well as offices.
Hamell general manager Catherine Hartley said the centre was focused on international food and premium fashion and lifestyle shops.
She said there had been strong interest in stage two, with leasing now under way.
Stage one, which opened in September, has 11 new shops and restaurants.
The final stage of the extension at 25 Samuel St and 35-39 Thomas St, Camp Hill, was approved by Brisbane City Council in November.
Councillor Ian McKenzie (Coorparoo) said he raised concerns about the traffic implications of the proposal.
"I know that a focus of council's assessment was traffic, including impacts to Samuel St, Boundary Rd and Thomas St," Cr McKenzie said.
"Council is taking real action on traffic congestion and safety in Camp Hill, with a $3 million upgrade to the intersection of Chatsworth Rd, Boundary Rd and Samuel St. Construction on this project will commence next financial year.
"The extension is fully contained within the existing shopping centre precinct and council required 42 additional car parks as part of the approval, to accommodate larger visitor numbers to the centre."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Hill Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hartley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamell Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whites Hill Village</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Councillor Ian McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chatsworth Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Hartley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel St. Construction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coorparoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
