<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406387083193096</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/business/breaking-news/lending-growth-boosts-credit-corps-profit/news-story/f2fe8ff36fe5717a71e762e47a680439</url>
  <title>Lending growth boosts Credit Corp's profit</title>
  <content>
Petrina BerryAustralian Associated Press

Share

Shares in Credit Corp have surged after its full year profit rose 20 per cent and the debt collector and lender forecast further growth.
The company buys unpaid consumer debts from banks, utilities and telecommunications providers, and also lends to people with limited access to credit.
Chief executive Thomas Beregi said lending was now a critical part of the company's future, and in just five years has built its customer base to 150,000.
Credit Corp's lending business, which includes the Wallet Wizard brand, was the main driver of earnings growth in 2016/17.
"It now accounts for 28 per cent of our investment and 22 per cent of earnings and will propel Credit Corp's growth over the next few years," Mr Beregi said in a statement.
The company made a net profit of $55 million in 2016/17, and has forecast a net profit of between $60 million and $63 million in 2017/18.
Credit Corp shares gained $1.13, or 6.7 per cent, to $18.09.
Mr Beregi said the company's expansion into the US, the largest consumer credit market in the world, had also paid off.
"Our long-term aspiration is to have a debt purchasing operation in the US as large as our core Australian and New Zealand business," he said.

Record purchasing of debts in 2017 will support the business in 2018, the company said, and more than $100 million in undrawn funding lines and the generation of free cash flow means it has the capacity for future acquisitions.
LENDING GROWTH BOOSTS CREDIT CORP'S PROFIT
* Full year net profit up 20pct to $55.2m
* Revenue up 17pct to $266m
* Final dividend up 4 cents to 31 cents, fully franked
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrina BerryAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beregi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GROWTH BOOSTS CREDIT CORP'S PROFIT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Beregi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Corp</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallet Wizard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
