<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405966176390768</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/business/breaking-news/vodafones-nbn-will-have-mobile-backup/news-story/bdd37d3b90cbf09d518693347ed83644</url>
  <title>Vodafone's nbn will have mobile backup</title>
  <content>
Vodafone Australia will offer its new nbn-connected customers a back-up mobile connection to cover them between sign-up and installation and in case the broadband connection fails.
Customers who sign on for Vodafone's nbn-based fixed broadband offering will get a wi-fi hub modem that provides regular broadband wi-fi and a built-in 4G mobile connection as a backup.
Vodafone says the mobile connection will be available to use for free between sign-up and installation and whenever repairs are carried out by the NBN Co - for individual outages, but not mass network faults.
Vodafone general manager of fixed broadband Matthew Lobb said Australian broadband customers are looking for simple solutions.
"They want a service that works, they don't want to be bamboozled by all these connections options," Mr Lobb said.
As the NBN continues to build its national grid, more Australians are migrating with high expectations to the network but encountering slower-than-expected experiences.
Mr Lobb rejected the implication that Australians are becoming discouraged with the NBN experience, saying Vodafone was simply responding to a market need.
"Our decision to offer this innovative solution was motivated by the reality that fixed services - be they NBN or legacy DSL - take time to connect," he said.
He said Vodafone was meeting a consumer need by providing a back-up to keep people connected.
With five million current mobile customers, Vodafone expects to capitalise on consumer disenchantment in the fixed line sector where the NBN themselves have noted that - in such a massive rollout - sometimes things go wrong.
"Everyone has a war story of a bad connection experience or of being left in the lurch," Mr Lobb said.
"What we've been seeing in the rollout of the NBN is more of the same, ubiquitous internet service and consumers don't like it and we want to offer a different experience that's more reliable and that meets the customer's needs," Mr Lobb said.
Vodafone plans to rollout fixed line services on the national broadband network later this year, becoming the largest new entrant to the tough retail telco market.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lobb</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodafone</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodafone Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Lobb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
