<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406348428486446</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/man-in-serious-condition-after-coast-motorbike-col/3207558/</url>
  <title>Man in serious condition after Coast motorbike collision</title>
  <content>
UPDATE: A MOTORBIKE rider has been transported to hospital in a serious condition after a collision with a car.
The man in his 50s was transported to the Sunshine Coast University Hospital with a critical care paramedic and is in a serious yet stable condition.
He is reportedly suffering from neck and lower leg injuries.
BREAKING: A MAN in his 50s is being treated for a leg injury after a car and motorbike collided in Cooroibah this afternoon.
Ambulance crews were called to Coral Fern Dr and McKinnon Dr at 3.11pm and a critical care paramedic is on scene.
It's believed the patient, who is also suffering neck and back pain, is the motorbike rider - but this is yet to be confirmed.
Traffic updates indicate lanes are blocked and drivers are advised to avoid the area.
More to come.
Gofundme set up for better mobility equipment and ongoing costs
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Coast applauds decision to upgrade major venue
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
And so BYTE - the Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence - was born.
I guess everything was impressive as I grew up in Eudlo.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinnon Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooroibah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coral Fern Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
