<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405141542657989</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/investors-switching-to-cheaper-owneroccupier-loans-says-ubs-20170801-gxmrws</url>
  <title>Investors switching to cheaper owner-occupier loans, says UBS</title>
  <content>
Investors switching to cheaper owner-occupier loans could be thwarting regulatory efforts to cool the housing market, research from UBS shows.
The Australian Prudential Regulation Authority took the housing market to task in March by tightening investor loans -  - and .
"Over recent months Investment Property Lending (IPL) has slowed considerably, from a peak of 0.76 per cent in December, down to 0.41 per cent in June. However, the slowdown in total housing lending has been much more muted, bouncing between 0.50 per cent and 0.55 per cent a month," UBS' Jon Mott and Rachel Bentvelzen said in a housing note on Tuesday.
The strong mortgage numbers meant that either the gap left by investors has been filled by new owner occupiers - upgraders and first home buyers - it was also likely that investors, on the back of more expensive loans, have reclassified their loans to owner-occupier mortgages.

First-home buyers are still at near record lows and upgraders are not a large part of the housing market.

"We would not be surprised if borrowers are tempted to apply for or reclassify themselves as owner occupiers given the approximately 60 basis point differential in interest rate between owner occupiers and investors," UBS said.
Investors have been known to deliberately falsify applications in order to take advantage of  as evidenced by other UBS research last year. 28 per cent of 1228 Australian borrowers sampled said their applications were not accurate.
UBS said at the time  the results were "disturbing" given the housing market re-acceleration, elevated household leverage and mortgages accounting for 62 per cent of bank loans.
"While banks have tightened underwriting following APRA's 'sound lending' guidance, it does not appear to have prevented applicants 'stretching the truth'," UBS said.

, following another lift in June, despite being traditionally slower winter months, Corelogic's home value index shows. Melbourne posted a large 3 per cent rise while Sydney prices went up another 1.4 per cent.
While regulatory controls could be slow in creating an impact - the last round of regulatory changes in 2014 took 12 months to take effect - equally concerning was the impact of falsified investor-owner occupier loans.
"While it is likely to take time for the banks' recent mortgage repricing to take effect, we believe that unless the housing market and growth in household debt slows considerably APRA is likely to further tighten macro prudential measures in the second half of 2017," UBS said as has been done in other overheated markets such as Singapore and New Zealand.
UBS also warns investors to "tread carefully" with bank stocks.

"Overall we would not be surprised to see the rally in Aussie banks continue near term. Multiples are off their highs and money is likely to flow into the banks as investors trim underweight positions and avoid USD plays into reporting season. That said, the medium term outlook is clearly challenging which caps the upside potential," UBS said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APRA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Prudential Regulation Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Bentvelzen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investment Property Lending</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS' Jon Mott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
