<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406425737899752</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/breaking-news/etihad-helping-with-nsw-terror-probe/news-story/022c7f72662dbe24a73b390e6e6a7d54</url>
  <title>Etihad helping with NSW terror probe</title>
  <content>
Etihad Airways is helping with the investigation into an alleged Sydney-based terror conspiracy to bring down an aircraft, which was said to be "fairly well along".
Four men remain in custody over the alleged plot but are yet to be charged following weekend raids in four Sydney suburbs.
News agency Reuters has cited two US officials familiar with the arrests as saying the Australian investigation wasn't a sting operation but the result of the detection of a developing plot.
One said it was "fairly well along" when Australian authorities disrupted it.
The target, the other official said, appeared to have been a commercial flight from Sydney to the Gulf.
Australian Federal Police officers have been searching several properties for evidence of the conspiracy which reportedly involved a bomb or gas-emitting device.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull confirmed the plan was to "bring down" a plane.
"The Etihad Airways aviation security team is assisting the AFP with its investigation and the matter is ongoing," the airline said in a statement on Tuesday.
"Etihad is complying fully with the enhanced security measures at airports in Australia and monitoring the situation closely. Safety is the airline's number one priority."
Investigators on Monday found a Qantas release slip relating to a Sydney to Jakarta flight near one of the raided Sydney properties.
But AAP understands the plot did not involve Qantas or the Qantas Group and the document was likely not linked to the suspects.
Two other US officials, also speaking on condition of anonymity, said communications between the alleged plotters in Sydney and members of Islamic State in Syria were intercepted by a foreign intelligence service.
The US officials declined to identify the service and United Kingdom officials refused to confirm or deny playing a role in detecting the plot.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Airways</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jakarta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gulf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
