<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406430032867065</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4826598/injured-jaffas-duo-still-in-limbo/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Injured Jaffas duo still in limbo</title>
  <content>
KEY: Jobe Wheelhouse was man of the match in Jaffas' 2014 grand final win.

LAMBTON Jaffas coach James Pascoe is not banking on having Jobe Wheelhouse or Nathan Morris back for the business end of the season.

Wheelhouse hurt his ankle on June 10 in the 5-0 FFA Cup loss to Edgeworth and it was initially thought he would miss at least six weeks when scans appeared to show a chipped bone. However, Pascoe said the midfield general was in pain when running recently and further scans revealed a different fracture and cast doubt on the apparent chipped bone. He said Wheelhouse had a gel injection last week and was "touch and go" for the finals.

"He will do everything he can to get right, but he's lost a lot of match fitness and we'll just have to see where he's at when he gets the all clear," Pascoe said.
Morris re-injured his knee against Charlestown on July 15 after six weeks out. Pascoe said Morris was having a specialist appointment this week but initial advice was that he risked serious injury if he played on with the medial ligament damage.

"I think we'll be lucky to see him again," he said.
"But we'll know more later in the week."
Despite the setbacks, Pascoe said last week's bye was good for the Jaffas, who were able to rest minor injuries and put extra training into other players.

The Jaffas, now three points off the lead in third, host Maitland and the Jets Youth to close out the regular season. 
"I think we'll be in a good position physically and mentally to finish things off," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Pascoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaffa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaffas' 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LAMBTON Jaffas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pascoe</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jets Youth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe Wheelhouse</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edgeworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
