<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406425737899730</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/depraved-victorian-real-estate-agent-jailed-for-nine-months-over-child-porn-images-20170801-gxn0bg.html</url>
  <title>'Depraved' Victorian real estate agent jailed for nine months over child porn images</title>
  <content>
A Victorian real estate agent who posed as a young girl online and created "graphic and disturbing" sexual fantasies has been jailed for nine months.
Layne Richard Pearce, 38, was also found with more than 11,000 child porn files on several computers and devices, including "depraved" images, some featuring infant children, County Court of Victoria judge Mark Gamble said on Tuesday.Photo: Vince Caligiuri
Pearce earlier pleaded guilty to accessing, possessing and transmitting child pornography.
The court was told he created an online alias called "hurtmeplease" with an associated email address and profile images of a young girl in scant clothing.

In August 2015, Pearce was in contact with a man online discussing bondage and other erotic practices.
He fabricated stories in which girls aged 14 and 11 went on camps with adult women and were sexually abused.

Pearce was arrested in July 2016, when police seized seven devices with 11,122 images and video files featuring children aged 18 months to 15 years.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

About 10,000 of the files were considered lower "category 1" child-porn images.
However Pearce also possessed files rated category 5, or most extreme, which Judge Gamble described as "depraved".
The Mount Eliza real estate agent's marriage broke down after his arrest, but his estranged wife wrote him a personal reference, the court was told.
Judge Gamble said Pearce's treating psychiatrist considered his prospects for rehabilitation good and that he was attending regular yoga sessions and reading about spirituality.
He also said Pearce, who has been on bail, had shown a willingness to take responsibility for his crimes and had shown remorse.
While imposing a jail sentence, Judge Gamble noted Pearce's "fragile mental state" and lack of experience in custody.
"Your mental state will likely deteriorate once you are incarcerated," he said.
Pearce has been placed on a recognisance release order, where he must be under supervision, be of good behaviour, and undergo a sex offenders program upon his release.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Eliza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Layne Richard Pearce, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Gamble</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>County Court of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince Caligiuri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Gamble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
