<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405699888414277</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/medal-of-honor-to-army-medic-48-years-later/8763116</url>
  <title>Donald Trump's issues first Medal of Honour to retired Army medic James McCloughan for Vietnam War</title>
  <content>
James McCloughan today became the first Medal of Honour recipient under US President Donald Trump, 48 years after the selfless acts of bravery for which he is now recognised.

Key points:

James McCloughan becomes first Medal of Honour recipient under US President Donald Trump
White House says the retired Army medic "voluntarily risked his life" to rescue and defend his comrades
Pentagon credits Mr McCloughan with saving 10 lives

Mr McCloughan "ran into danger" to save wounded soldiers, despite his own serious wounds, during a Vietnam War battle.
The former Army private first class mouthed "thank you" as Mr Trump placed the distinctive blue ribbon holding the medal around his neck.
As the President and Commander in Chief shook Mr McCloughan's hand, Mr Trump said "very proud of you" and then pulled the former soldier into an embrace.
"I know I speak for every person here when I say we are in awe of your bravery and your actions," Mr Trump said after describing Mr McCloughan's actions for a rapt audience that included numerous senior White House and administration officials.

Retired Marine General John Kelly, sworn in hours earlier to be the new White House chief of staff, attended.
Mr McCloughan said in a brief statement on the White House driveway after the ceremony it was "humbling" to receive the medal.
Now 71 and retired, he pledged to do his best to represent the men he fought alongside, "as the caretaker of this symbol of courage and action beyond the call of duty".
Mr McCloughan was a 23-year-old private first class who had been drafted into the Army when, in 1969, he found himself in the middle of the raging, days-long battle of Nui Yon Hill.
He voluntarily entered the "kill zone" to rescue injured comrades, even as he was pelted with shrapnel from a rocket-propelled grenade, the back of his body slashed from head to foot.
In its announcement last month, the White House said Mr McCloughan, "voluntarily risked his life on nine separate occasions to rescue wounded and disoriented comrades".
"He suffered wounds from shrapnel and small arms fire on three separate occasions, but refused medical evacuation to stay with his unit, and continued to brave enemy fire to rescue, treat, and defend wounded Americans."
Mr McCloughan, who lives in South Haven, Michigan, told AP in an interview last month the battle was, "the worst two days of my life".
He described the shrapnel as "a real bad sting" and recalled, "I was tending to two guys and dragging them at the same time into a trench line".
He said he looked down to see himself covered with blood from wounds so bad they prompted a captain to suggest he leave the battlefield to seek treatment.
"He knew me enough to know that I wasn't going," Mr McCloughan said.
The combat medic stuck around until the battle ended, coming to the aid of his men and fighting the enemy, even knocking out an enemy RPG position with a grenade at one point.
In all, the Pentagon credits Mr McCloughan with saving the lives of 10 members of his company.
The Medal of Honour is given to armed forces members who distinguish themselves by going above and beyond the call of duty in battle.
Mr McCloughan left the Army in 1970 and spent decades teaching psychology and sociology and coaching football, baseball and wrestling at South Haven High School.
He retired in 2008.
In 2016, defence secretary Ash Carter recommended Mr McCloughan for the Medal of Honour.
But since the medal must be awarded within five years of the recipient's actions, Congress needed to pass a bill waiving the time limit.
Former president Barack Obama signed the measure in late 2016, but he did not get the opportunity to recognise Mr McCloughan with the medal before his term ended this year.
"President Donald Trump will be putting that on me for the first time in his experience of doing such a thing," Mr McCloughan said.
"That's pretty special."
AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. McCloughan</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medal Of Honour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pentagon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James McCloughan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Haven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine General John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Haven High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nui Yon Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam War</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
