<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651405575334360837</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/cricket/english-legend-geoff-boycott-in-ultimate-prank/news-story/d4af4a7060c7c0951e65bdaf92af541e</url>
  <title>Legend caught in 'greatest gee-up'</title>
  <content>
BBC cricket commentator Jonathan Agnew has delivered one of the great wind-ups of all-time on colleague and English cricket legend Geoffrey Boycott.
The intricately-planned plot played out on air during the final day of play in the Third Test between England and South Africa at The Oval.
Agnew started stringing his co-host along by reading out a hoax press release which claimed the International Cricket Council had decided to strip matches played between England and a "Rest of the World" team in 1977 of first-class status.
Agnew maintained perfect discipline - and the right amount of early nonchalance - as he detailed the "decision" had been made because the matches were played while South Africa was gripped by Apartheid and banned from playing international sport.
Agnew said the ICC had ruled England's participation in the matches against a composite side on South African soil was "against the spirit of the Gleneagles Agreement" - a pact between Commonwealth countries to discourage sporting contact with South Africa.
"In the interests of keeping cricket free from political interference, all matches will be removed from first class records," Agnew read.
The "media release" was delivered on an official ICC letterhead as "breaking news". Boycott immediately took the bait and - when it became clear the decision would have a significant effect on his career - launched into a passionate defence.
"That's a load of tripe. Isn't it ridiculous," Boycott said. "Write to him, he's an idiot putting that out. That's politics alone, because you've got a black government in South Africa asking them because of politics to take it out. Cricket should say hey, we're not getting involved in politics, and that's what they should be saying. There might be other records that have to be taken out."
Agnew continued his masterplan by having the BBC's statistician reveal the disastrous impact on Boycott's career. The century he made in the series would no longer count on his record, meaning the famous 100th first-class century he scored at his beloved home ground of Headingley would now be his 99th.
Instead of that celebrated moment his 100th ton would now have occurred on a nondescript tour game in Pakistan.
BOYCOTT: Faislabad! I got one in Faislabad, wonderful. Well, a much better place Faislabad to get your hundredth hundred.
AGNEW: What are you going to do?
BOYCOTT: Nothing, I just think it's wrong for everyone. It's silly that, politics.
AGNEW: No, it's a great day for cricket and humanity. I'm sure the players involved will take it on the chin.
BOYCOTT: Yeah ... well done, see what people say.
But Aggers wasn't done there. He continued to connect the dots to create chaos around plans Boycott had made to celebrate the anniversary of his milestone - which occurred on August 11, 1977.
AGNEW: Being serious for a minute, that's coming up isn't it? We haven't got anything planned have we? We're not doing anything are we?
BOYCOTT: We are actually. We're having a do at my house, 180 people, we're raising money for the Yorkshire Air Ambulance!
AGNEW: Well, you're going to have to cancel it!
BOYCOTT: We're not cancelling it, it's all sold and done. Put it this way Samuel Hassan (the fictional ICC representative listed on the release) will not get an invite that's for sure.
AGNEW: But you can't celebrate your 99th hundred?
BOYCOTT: No we're celebrating it, because it's nonsense. There'll be other people as well, two or three after me got a hundred hundreds. I mean you can't go changing history just like that for politics.
AGNEW: You actually invited me to that. But now you've invited me under false pretences.
BOYCOTT: Well, they way you're carrying on, I'm taking that (invite) back.
AGNEW: I mean I wasn't expecting that, it's a mess.
BOYCOTT: You're right, it's an absolute mess!
Finally he put the old man out of his misery.
AGNEW: It is a mess ... and also an absolute wind-up!
BOYCOTT: "You Muppet, you ... it's never. Is that a wind-up? You Muppet, Agnew, I'll get you for that. You've got me a few times, but that's the biggest one. You've done me easy haven't ya, like a kipper!
Former Australian star Dean Jones congratulated Agnew on his fine get, calling it the "greatest gee-up of all-time" on social media.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Agnew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muppet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agnew</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorkshire Air Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Headingley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faislabad</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gleneagles Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel Hassan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Third Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rest of the World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aggers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Cricket Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoffrey Boycott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
