<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406606126529622</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/mfb-chief-officer-quits-joining-mass-fire-services-exodus/news-story/4fc04515096a727d230b1e83b8d39632</url>
  <title>MFB acting chief officer quits</title>
  <content>
A MASS exodus of experienced leaders from Victoria's fire services has continued with the MFB's acting chief officer Paul Stacchino quitting.
Mr Stacchino has been in the role since his predecessor Peter Rau resigned in September last year, amid an ongoing health battle and a bitter brawl with the United Firefighters Union.
The departure of Stacchino, a 35-year emergency management veteran, follows the, and other senior staff last year calling time on long careers, including deputy chief officer David Youseff.

Acting chief executive Russell Eddington told staff that Mr Stacchino had "helped steer the organisation through some challenging times".
"In a fast paced and complex environment (he) has ensured that our operational service delivery and leadership within emergency services is exceptional," Mr Eddington said.
The turmoil at the MFB emerged alongside chaos last year at the CFA, when both organisations fought UFU demands in new workplace deals.
Those demands, which were accepted by Premier Daniel Andrews after a meeting with UFU secretary Peter Marshall, sparked the resignation of former Emergency Services Minister Jane Garrett, the sacking of the CFA board, and the resignation of CFA chief executive Lucinda Nolan and chief officer Joe Buffone.
The incredible saga that has engulfed the Andrews Government has recently seen the premier seek to restructure Victoria's fire services and create a single body for all paid firefighters called Fire Rescue Victoria.

Paid CFA firefighters will now join the MFB in a new body known as Fire Rescue Victoria. Courtesy: Seven News

CFA break up
New laws for the restructure have stalled in the upper house while a parliamentary committee examines the plan that was created by a Cabinet taskforce.
Mr Stacchino raised concerns about the proposal during hearings, at which Emergency Management Commissioner Craig Lapsley called for urgent reform.
A senior source said Mr Stacchino "saw the writing on the wall" and decided to leave the MFB after a long career in emergency services.
Opposition Leader Matthew Guy on Tuesday night said a wealth of experience had left the state in the past year.
"Victoria has lost over 300 years of emergency services experience during Daniel Andrews' war with the CFA," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire Rescue Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stacchino</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFB</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Eddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucinda Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Services Minister Jane Garrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stacchino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Firefighters Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Stacchino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Management Commissioner Craig Lapsley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Youseff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Buffone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Matthew Guy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Rau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Eddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
