<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406344133518976</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/members-of-eastern-sward-golf-club-bangholme-say-they-have-a-little-slice-of-heaven-to-play-on/news-story/1c667f15dbf8e0cb29a39b7432dee960</url>
  <title>Melbourne's best kept golfing secret is out</title>
  <content>
SOUTHEAST'S  "best-kept golfing secret" is out - there's a little slice of heaven in Bangholme.
And users of the Eastern Sward Golf Club are happy to spill the beans in a bid to attract new members.
"It's the best-kept golfing secret in the southeast," club president Bob Martello said.
He said Eastern Sward had a unique history and was a deceptively challenging course, perfect for the "working class" golfer.
"We are the men's shed of golf clubs in that we have down-to-earth members," he said. "It's a flat course, but it's not easy - it's very tight with small greens and tree-lined fairways, water hazards ... it's got the lot."
Built on Melbourne Water land by a manager who filled the brief of compulsory green space on the organisation's property by establishing fairways and flags, the course was opened to staff in 1977.
It is a survivor - being chopped and changed at least four times as Melbourne Water reallocated parts of the land and EastLink was built.
In the early 1990s, the course was almost lost until a group of players leased the land from Melbourne Water and established a club that welcomed members from outside the organisation.
Life member John Rust was involved in that process and, at 81 years old, still gets about the course in his personalised golf cart.
Mr Rust knows every bump on every fairway and every slant on every green.
He came to Eastern Sward in 1989 as a greenkeeper who had barely picked up a golf club, but fell in love with the game and the course.
"I think this will be my club for life," Mr Rust said.
"I've seen a lot of people and holes come and go.
"There are only four holes that haven't changed since I started here."
The nine-hole course has alternate tees on each hole, changing the distance and direction to give players a new challenge for a full 18 holes.
Long par-threes and difficult greens test even the low handicappers, which is reflected by the course record - a one-under-par 67.
Eastern Sward is a private course with a range of membership options.
Visit the golf club's website at easternswardgc.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southeast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Water</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Sward</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Rust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Sward Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangholme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Martello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rust</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
