<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406640486268660</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/special-reports/trailblazers/successful-leaders-change-culture-to-drive-transformation-20170728-gxktso</url>
  <title>Successful leaders change culture to drive transformation</title>
  <content>
by
Mark Eggleton

This content is produced by The Australian Financial Review in commercial partnership with Salesforce.  
Shortcomings in organisational culture are among the main barriers to business success in the digital age, according to a recent article in McKinsey Quarterly. Another recent report, titled "How cognitive technologies are transforming capital markets" - also from McKinsey - argued that machines are poised to replace up to 30 per cent of jobs in banks over the next few years.
While both reports sound like solid reasons to press the big red button marked "panic", it would seem many bankers are quite sanguine about the future. In fact, the general consensus is that technology will "free-up" capacity and create opportunities, rather than replace humans.
The CEO of JPMorgan Chase and Co, , even went so far as to predict that head count within his firm will rise significantly over the next couple of decades.

This not-so-gloomy view of digital transformation was shared by most of the participants at the recent Trailblazers round table, co-hosted by The Australian Financial Review and Salesforce in Sydney. The key is to address any cultural shortcomings.

Participants at the round table echoed a common refrain from the business sector: it's a people story, but with a few caveats. To put it bluntly, we are going to work either on, with, or  in the coming decades - so we probably have to be aware of that.
Going further, the real story behind digital transformation - and wider business transformation aimed at new growth markets - is that companies need to get their organisational culture right before they can effect real change.
Deloitte's national lead partner, Innovation Strategy, Andy Bateman, said change is "like an ever-accelerating train."
"It's not just one transformation - it's multiple transformations. And I think the people aspect is the most critical, most overlooked part of a transformation. The key for organisations is they need to get a better understanding of the implications of change and design new types of work to do," he said.

"Turkeys don't vote for Christmas, and people generally don't like change. So you have to bring the people with you."
Chief customer officer at Mercer, Cambell Holt, agreed that change fundamentally comes down to the people story. "Whether you're a small or large company, an incumbent or startup, the impact on the people and how they're managed is a fundamental element in effecting change."
Bringing people along on the journey requires leaders to rethink how they manage people. The old command-and-control style of leadership - an overhang from all the management theories written off the back of two world wars last century - basically needs to be thrown out the window.
According to the co-founder and CEO of Expert360, Bridget Loudon, values-driven leaders are the leaders who will succeed "because ultimately that's the glue that holds an organisation together."

"Employees are looking for companies with values. I think leaders need to be very clear about what those values are, and set those from the top down, and then that will allow autonomy within the organisation. Values provide guardrails for behaviour [within an organisation]," Loudon said.
She said the challenges and themes most organisations are confronting now are universal, so to build resilience inside a company everything needs to be values-driven, and people need to feel free to get out there and make decisions and contribute.
As SapientRazorFish ANZ Group vice president and managing director Marcos Kurowski said, "Leadership is a team sport. It's not about an individual leader."
GE's Digital country manager for Australia and New Zealand, Belinda Vassallo, believes getting transformation right is about embracing and empowering people - "Helping them have the right to advocate their position, as there are people at all levels of an organisation with very switched-on ideas who can actually help drive change."

She said : "For me, it's all about trying to weed out those individuals who have embraced change."
"They are the early-adopters who can take their peer group on the journey with them because leaders can't do it all on their own," Vassallo said.
Also vitally important in Vassallo's eyes is a deep understanding of the customer, and having a high level of empathy for their needs. "Basically, companies have to understand leaders exist at all levels in an organisation. So they have to be willing to empower people."
Salesforce Asia Pacific Senior Vice President, Eileen O'Mara, said great leaders tend to share a number of characteristics, and a key one (especially in a period of transformation) is transparency. "Transparency is vitally important in ensuring you're creating an environment where people feel counted and accountable," O'Mara said.

"Leaders need to create a platform of inclusion. So, while technology is driving change it's only part of the story. It's really about what kind of organisation are you? What kind of ecosystem do you want to create?"
For Loudon, part of that people story is the need for Australian business leaders who have had it pretty easy for 26 years of continuous growth to stand up to their boards and tell them we are in a global market - margins are under pressure, as are our business models.
"It's hard to say it but we need to tell investors and shareholders that we need to take some money and we need to invest it and we're not going to see that for three years."
She says there is a clear need for businesses to take a few risks as they transform.
Managing director of Bambu Digital and chairman of cloud-based social media software company Manalto, Jim McKerlie, agreed that companies need to have some strong conversations with boards and more broadly.
In addition to his digital businesses, McKerlie is also the chairman of ASX-listed Lithium Consolidated Minerals Exploration, allowing him to bring two different perspectives to the discussion.
"It's a massive people story because the level of change we're seeing in society goes well beyond the corporate level. There are issues for government, public administrators and companies to confront. Big issues - like an ageing population, the number of jobs we will have in the future with some being replaced by automation. We're seeing fundamental changes in the workforce, in the way we work, and the sort of work we do."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GE Digital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinsey Quarterly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcos Kurowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SapientRazorFish ANZ Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKerlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambell Holt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovation Strategy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salesforce Asia Pacific Senior Vice President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loudon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Expert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Eggleton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridget Loudon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bambu Digital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Mara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of JPMorgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salesforce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed Lithium Consolidated Minerals Exploration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Bateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim McKerlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eileen O'Mara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manalto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vassallo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Vassallo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
