<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406558881888356</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/markets/iron-ore-jump-a-shortterm-treat-analysts-dont-think-it-will-last-20170731-gxmpt8.html</url>
  <title>Iron ore jump a short-term treat but analysts don't think it will last</title>
  <content>
Iron ore experts are divided over the direction of Australia's largest export, with Chinese analysts convinced the bulk commodity is set to enter a bull market while local analysts say this week's surge is only a short-term burst.
The  during Tuesday's session as Chinese authorities inspected local low-grade steel mills, and surprisingly strong construction figures released last week caused the iron ore price to play catch-up to higher steel prices.Photo: Fairfax Media
"All of this sends a strong signal to the market the government will try and remove smaller mills and encourage the development of bigger mills, which is good for iron ore," said Qiu Yuecheng, an analyst at steel trading platform XiBen New Line.
"Steel mills are making so much money so they are happy to pay a higher price for high-grade iron ore."
Local Chinese futures traders reacted dramatically to the prospect of tighter steel supply on Tuesday, following Chinese Premier Li Keqiang's reiteration over the weekend that low-quality producers will be shut down.
"Can prices surge higher from here? Of course they can," says Glyn Lawcock, managing director of resources research at UBS.

"But we don't see this as a sustainable move higher in the longer term. It's important to remain cognisant that the futures markets in China are heavily influenced by retail volume, and they respond quite rapidly and strongly in both directions to newsflow."
About 70 per cent of the Dalian market is made up of retail investors and, thanks to the proliferation of smart phones, there is a  from iron ore future to cotton and eggs.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But there is optimism that the Chinese economy is performing better than previously thought. Government spending on infrastructure and widespread property investment, despite a regulatory clampdown, saw  jump to 62.5 from 61.4 in June.
As such,  to $US70 a tonne from $US55, and the year-end target by $US5 to $US60.
Du Hongfeng, a senior analyst at research group SteelHome, says this continued growth is set to power the iron ore higher for longer. 
"We are entering into a bull market. Prices of raw materials are increasing because the performance of the economy is better than expected," he said. 
Mr Du said Premier Li Keqiang's renewed commitment to shutting down low-quality mills will mean that "steel production using iron ore increases".
He also said "rebar​ prices are at a four-year high while iron ore hasn't managed to reach this year's high again so it's not surprising to see the rally."
Resource giants BHP Billiton and Rio Tinto enjoyed solid buying support on Tuesday, closing up 1.2 per cent and 0.2 per cent respectively. 
Fortescue Metals was closed up 1.4 per cent while Atlas Iron enjoyed a 4.8 per cent boost.
"There's has been some underperformance from some of the majors as well, which is contributing to this price hike," says Paul Young, resources analyst at Deutsche Bank.
"But we see iron ore drifting between the $US50 and $US70 band, and when you get north of that a lot of high-cost swing supply is in the money, so our view is that the market will then rebalance and the price will come off."
The Aussie

While investors are pouring into iron ore stocks on the back of this week's jump, many are wary about a parallel rise in the Aussie dollar, which complicates things for exporters.
Since the beginning of June, the Australian dollar has soared 8.7 per cent and is  afternoon.
"This rally in iron ore is just another boost for the local currency," says Janu Chan, an economist at St Geroge.
"But it's not just iron ore, there's been a broad recovery in commodity prices, like copper, oil has firmed and commodity prices go in hand with US dollar weakness."
Traders are jostling for position on Tuesday, ahead of the Reserve Bank of Australia's decision on interest rates, and are expecting the central bank to talk down the Australian dollar strength.
"We think in the near term the Aussie has probably gone a bit too far, but markets are preparing for interest rate rises from others apart from the US Federal Reserve, that's quite a shake up for global markets," says Ms Chan.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlas Iron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glyn Lawcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SteelHome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Chan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Geroge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Billiton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Premier Li Keqiang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qiu Yuecheng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janu Chan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Du Hongfeng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xiben New Line</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Li Keqiang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue Metals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Du</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$70</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
