<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406485867443048</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/culture-hinders-tas-uni-harassment-reports/news-story/4b3376e4d3383cfaa00cbb4c34cf1610</url>
  <title>Culture hinders Tas uni harassment reports</title>
  <content>
Cultural barriers are hindering University of Tasmania students from reporting sexual harassment, after a Human Rights report found non-reporting in such cases is more than double the national figure.
Nearly 500 UTAS students were surveyed as part of a national Australian Human Rights Commission report.
Of students not reporting sexual harassment, 24 per cent said it was because they were from a different cultural background and found aspects of Australian culture offensive.
That's more than double the national figure of 11 per cent.
Following the report's release on Tuesday, the university announced the appointment of professor Marg Otlowski as vice-chancellor of culture and wellbeing.
She says her role is to understand the nuances of why people aren't coming forward.
"We need to understand boundaries and messaging about what is and what is not okay," she said.
"We have diverse communities on our campuses - certain conduct that may seem to some quite normal, perhaps oversteps the mark of what is acceptable."
Executive director of student experience, Stephanie Taylor, says the university will work to make services more visible.
Rates of students being sexually harassed at UTAS in 2016 were marginally higher than the national average at 54 per cent compared to 51 per cent, the report found.
"We anticipate that there may actually be an increase in reporting as a result of this data," Ms Otlowski said.
"We share a sense of deep regret for any incident of sexual harassment or assault that have occurred for any students
"It's deeply disturbing."
UTAS has committed to adopting all the report's recommendations.
Tasmania Police has said it will work with the university to encourage people to report all crimes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Otlowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marg Otlowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTAS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
