<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406563176855737</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65450/2018-subaru-levorg-price-and-features-new-engine-new-variants-added-to-refreshed-range</url>
  <title>2018 Subaru Levorg Price And Features - New Engine, New Variants Added To Refreshed Range</title>
  <content>
has tweaked the line-up of sporty mid-size Levorg wagon, introducing a new entry-level engine and adding a new flagship at the top of the range.
For the 2018 model year Subaru has deleted the previous entry-level 2.0 GT model replacing it with a more affordable two-tier line-up powered by a new 1.6-litre turbocharged petrol engine. The 2.0 GT-S variant remains as a mid-grade variant, while the previous GT-S Spec B has been replaced by the new flagship 2.0 STI Sport variant.

2018 Subaru Levorg STI Sport

Starting from $35,990 before on-road costs, the entry-level 1.6 GT costs $7000 less than the previous 2.0 GT model and takes its power from a turbocharged 1.6-litre petrol engine which produces 125kW and 250Nm. As before the range remains exclusively automatic-only, with a CVT automatic transmission paired to all wheel drive
The 1.6 GT comes standard with cloth seat trim, a leather trimmed steering wheel, 17-inch alloy wheels, auto adaptive headlights, auto vehicle hold, rain-sensing wipers, keyless entry and start, heated door mirrors, rear privacy glass, and a 6.2-inch touchscreen infotainment system. Fuel consumption for the new engine is rated at 7.4 l/100 km.
Safety features include Subaru's camera-based Eyesight driver assistance suite including adaptive cruise control, lane departure and sway warning, lane keep assist and pre-collision steering, braking, and throttle systems including autonomous emergency braking.

A new 1.6 GT Premium also joins the range with the same engine, priced from $42,890 (plus on-road costs) with added features like leather seat trim with blue stitching, heated sports front seats with driver's lumbar support, a larger 7.0-inch touchscreen with satellite navigation, anti-dazzle mirror and 18-inch alloy wheels.
All models from the GT Premium and above also feature Bilstein front and rear suspension, retuned compared with the previous model for a smoother ride while retaining a sporty driving feel.
Safety tech also grows to incorporate blind spot warning, rear cross traffic alert, high beam assist, a wide front view camera and side view monitor plus a new 'Smart Rearview Mirror' that utilises a camera mounted at the top of the tailgate and displays the image on the rear view mirror - free from obstruction by passengers in the way a regular mirror would be with an added display mode that functions like a traditional rear view camera, concentrating on the area immediately behind the vehicle.

Moving up to the Levorg GT-S from $49,140 (plus on-road costs) sees a return to the same 2.0-litre four-cylinder turbo petrol engine previously used in the Levorg range, with outputs of 197kW and 350Nm. The GT-S also gains an extra Sport Sharp driving mode and black wheel accents.
At the top of the range the new Levorg STI Sport variant, priced from $51,990 plus on road costs, gains a revised appearance package thanks to a restyled front bumper and grille, maroon leather seats, and a range of STI goodies including STI exhaust tips, and STI-branded instrument cluster, STI side sill plates, an STI steering wheel logo, 18-inch STI alloy wheels, suspension tuned by STI and the availability of Subaru's WR Blue hero colour.

Despite the generous application of STI parts, the STI Sport model goes without any performance upgrades, with outputs from its 2.0-litre engine matching those of the the GT-S.
The updated Subaru Levorg is now available in local showrooms.
Pricing

Levorg 1.6 GT - $35,990
Levorg 1.6 GT Premium - $42,890
Levorg 2.0 GT-S - $49,140
Levorg 2.0 STI Sport - $51,990
Manufacturer's list price excluding on-road costs.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levorg 2.0 GT-S - $49,140</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levorg 2.0 STI Sport - $51,990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levorg 1.6 GT - $35,990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bilstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levorg STI Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sport Sharp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Engine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levorg 1.6 GT Premium - $42,890</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Variants Added To Refreshed Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru Levorg STI Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STI Sport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru Levorg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levorg GT-S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STI</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levorg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smart Rearview Mirror</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT Premium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru's WR Blue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STI-branded</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT-S</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subaru Levorg Price And Features</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT-S Spec B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CVT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
