<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406511637247339</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:48</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/rba-singles-out-amazon-australian-dollar-over-inflation-20170801-gxmvjg</url>
  <title>RBA singles out Amazon, Australian dollar over inflation</title>
  <content>
Australian retailers already struggling to deal with Amazon's pending arrival are unlikely to find much joy in what the about the "Amazon effect" in its latest statement.
But consumers will definitely like it.
Not only are they in line for cheaper goods, the world's largest online retailer could help keep a lid on inflation and make it difficult for the central bank to hike the official cash rate.
In the US, Amazon gets blamed for job losses and disruption in the retail space as bricks and mortar stores close down and traditional retailers go broke at a rapid rate.

But if cheap goods can lead to lower inflation rate here, at a time when households are also faced with higher tobacco and electricity prices, consumers won't complain.

In a longer than usual accompanying statement to its August rate decision, the RBA also made a point of talking about the higher , also noting the impact on inflation from the "increased competition from new entrants in the retail industry".
That's the Amazon effect.
Although the RBA still expects inflation to "pick up gradually as the economy strengthens" it also made a point of mentioning higher prices for electricity and tobacco" that are tipped to increase the CPI.
That's "bad" inflation and doesn't help spending when households are already labouring under record high debt levels and low wage growth.

But thanks to Amazon there's a chance there will be some "good" inflation that will offset those increases.
In the US, Amazon has had a big impact on the labour market but this wasn't mentioned by the Reserve Bank on Tuesday.
A few months ago, Federal Reserve Bank of St Louis president James Bullard was in Melbourne and spoke about how many jobs were being lost in the internet retailing space.
He warned that eventually central bankers would also need to understand the impact of Amazon on the labour market.

Perhaps given the recent run up to US80¢, and comments last week from RBA Governor Philip Lowe that he would rather a lower Australian dollar, the main focus of Tuesday's statement was always going to be anything linked to the local unit.
It's a tough one as the bank really can't do much , which really has been the main driver of the $A, but some economists were a little bit surprised there wasn't more jawboning to talk the dollar down.
In every meeting since April 2016 the bank has used the line that "an appreciating exchange rate would complicate [the economy's adjustment]".
But not this time around.

And the last time the dollar was this high against the US dollar, back in March, 2015, the RBA noted at the time that a lower exchange rate was "needed" .
But, again, not this time.
Investors were, however, reminded, that "an appreciating exchange rate would be expected to result in a slower pick-up in economic activity and inflation than currently forecast".
In other words that high $A will also help keep inflation low at a time when it's been below the bank's target range for six straight quarters.

What the RBA wants is for the Fed to keep going with its rate raising program but financial markets are betting that won't happen.
The Australian dollar was hovering around US80¢ in late afternoon trading but it was under US74¢ just two months ago.
Iron ore prices are also flying giving global investors another reason to buy it.
If the Australian dollar keeps edging higher, the likelihood of a rate hike higher gets pushed back to 2019, and if inflation stays low then rate cuts could be back on the agenda.
Right now most experts think the Australian dollar will fall back towards the low US70¢ level.
But over the past few years most of the big calls in markets have been wrong.
Market watchers will now turn to Friday's Statement on Monetary Policy to see if the bank changes their growth and inflation forecasts. Some are already predicting they will hold their forecasts steady but push out the timeline.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Bullard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve Bank of St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monetary Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday's Statement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA Governor Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US74</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
