<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406563176855684</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/jury-sent-out-in-case-of-ashleigh-watterson-accused-of-repeatedly-smothering-her-baby-daughter/news-story/6a817ec734a0b55845af22a299941b2a</url>
  <title>Jury to decide on accused mum's guilt</title>
  <content>
THE fate of a Brisbane mother accused of repeatedly smothering her baby is now in the hands of a Supreme Court jury.
Late this afternoon the 12 jurors in the case of Ashleigh Watterson retired to deliberate after hearing two weeks of evidence from dozens of doctors, nurses and ambulance staff who treated her five-month-old daughter Sarah.
The baby was hospitalised several times in October and November 2010 with breathing difficulties which prosecutors allege were caused by Watterson deliberately smothering her baby on three occasions.
She is accused of obstructing Sarah's airway while at their Rothwell home on October 28, 2010, and again on November 2 - this time with the intention to kill her.
She is also accused of smothering Sarah with the intention to kill her on November 24, when Sarah was a patient at the Royal Brisbane Hospital.
The alleged attempt to kill Sarah occurred in a locked hospital toilet, prosecutor Danny Boyle alleged.
The court heard that Watterson - a devoutly religious stay-at-home mother - may have used her hands, or a blanket, toy or pillow to smother her baby.
She vigorously denies all claims against her, saying she would never hurt, and never did hurt her child.
Her barrister Peter Richards told the court that Wattterson should be acquitted because the prosecution medical evidence did not meet the standard of proof required in criminal trials.
Watterson allegedly confessed to trying to kill her baby to police, saying the devil made her do it.
She has told the jury the confession was false and she was under extreme strain at the time.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wattterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watterson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Brisbane Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rothwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashleigh Watterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
