<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406644781235992</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/sydney-terror-raids-australia-issues-strong-denial-it-was-rushed-into-raids-by-british-travel-warning-20170801-gxn9yx.html</url>
  <title>Australia issues strong denial it was rushed into terror raids by British travel warning</title>
  <content>
The Turnbull government has vehemently denied that police were rushed into arresting four alleged plane bomb plotters by a British threat to issue a public travel warning about Australia.
As police held the suspects for a third day, more details of the alleged network emerged with confirmation two men are related to a hardened foreign fighter in Syria and reports that another has a brother believed to be a senior Islamic State figure.

Up Next

Universities brace for sexual assault report

02:02

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Sydney terror raids: Tip-off from foreign intel

An alleged plot to smuggle a bomb onto a passenger plane was uncovered after a tip-off from foreign intelligence agencies.

Police raided five properties and arrested four men on Saturday and have claimed they planned to put a homemade bomb on a plane, though as of Tuesday night no charges had been laid.
 Abu Dhabi-based Etihad Airways issued a statement on Tuesday saying it was helping Australian police with the investigation.

"The Etihad Airways aviation security team is assisting the Australian Federal Police with its investigation and the matter is ongoing," the airline said.
"Etihad is complying fully with the enhanced security measures at airports in Australia and monitoring the situation closely."

Security sources said the suspects allegedly planned to use a meat grinder that would either explode or disperse a deadly gas. The plot was uncovered after intelligence was provided by United States and British authorities.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The ABC has reported the British government wanted to issue a public security alert about Australian travel, forcing Australian police to launch their disruption operation earlier than they would have liked for evidence-gathering purposes.Photo: AAP
But an Australian government spokesman said that "any suggestion that Australian authorities took action to disrupt the terror plot because of pressure from international partners is absolutely wrong".
"Authorities took action when they determined necessary and not under threat or pressure from any third parties. Public safety was the top priority," he said.Photo: AAP
The spokesman said information-sharing among partners in the "five eyes" network - Australia, the US, Britain, Canada and New Zealand - was always vital combating terrorism and that Australians should be reassured by this.
Two of the men arrested, Khaled Merhi and his son Abdul Merhi are understood to be related to Ahmed Merhi, who has been with the so-called Islamic State group in Syria since 2014 and was once regarded as an active recruiter but has gone quiet in the past year.
Deakin University terrorism expert Greg Barton said of Ahmed Merhi that "you get the sense he's a bit of a thug and not too bright so if you were managing him you'd see him as a liability".
He said this was one possible reason he'd been inactive in the past year - that he had been told to stay quiet by the Islamic State hierarchy.
The ABC reported that another of the other men arrested, Khaled Khayat, has a brother who is a senior Islamic State figure in Syria.
While the involvement of allied intelligence agencies make clear there was significant overseas involvement, it remains unclear exactly what role either Ahmed Merhi or the Khayat brother played in the planning and direction of the alleged plot.
Professor Barton said that the four men had links to known jihadists but were reportedly not being closely watched prior to last week "raises the question that we haven't had the resources to take care of that very large outer circle of people who have an association but not any criminal record".
"It's just not practicable," he said. "This is a reminder of the number of people they're dealing with in that circle."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Merhi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tip-off</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Airways</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abu Dhabi-based Etihad Airways</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
