<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406640486268670</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/another-executive-departs-metropolitan-fire-brigade-as-crisis-deepens-20170801-gxn8i9.html</url>
  <title>Fire exit: Fourth brigade chief quits as crisis deepens</title>
  <content>
The Metropolitan Fire Brigade's acting chief officer has become the latest executive to flee as the crisis engulfing Victoria's fire services heats up.
Paul Stacchino's resignation comes as a controversial restructure looms for Victoria's fire services and follows the departures of at least three other senior officeholders.Photo: Paul Rovere
Last month chief executive Jim Higgins left the brigade after three years in the job.
Mr Stacchino is stepping away from the MFB after accumulating decades of experience in emergency services including roles in metropolitan and country fire brigades. He has also worked interstate and in the US.    
In a note to staff on Tuesday, MFB acting chief executive Russell Eddington said Mr Stacchino had led the brigade through "challenging times".
"His commitment to the role, the organisation, and the sector has stood MFB in particularly good stead over the years," he said. "I will miss his wise counsel."

Meanwhile the Country Fire Authority has also been rocked by shock departures, including the sacking of the previous board and the resignation of former chief executive Lucinda Nolan.
Emergency Services Minister James Merlino thanked Mr Stacchino for his dedication to his work.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"This is a decision made by Mr Stacchino and I wish him all the best into the future," he said.
But Opposition Leader Matthew Guy said Victoria had now lost more than 300 years of experience during the government's "war with the CFA".
"A government I lead will protect those that protect Victorians," he said. 
The Andrews government is attempting to restructure Victoria's fire brigades so that the CFA becomes a volunteer-only service.
Under the proposed model the MFB will be transformed into Fire Rescue Victoria, which will represent paid firefighters, including those in regional Victoria.
The restructure has the strong backing of the influential United Firefighters Union but is fiercely opposed by the Volunteer Fire Brigades Victoria.
But the bill to implement the restructure has not yet passed through Parliament and is now being scrutinised by a parliamentary inquiry.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire Rescue Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Matthew Guy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stacchino</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFB</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucinda Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Fire Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Firefighters Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Stacchino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan Fire Brigade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Minister James Merlino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Rovere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volunteer Fire Brigades Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Eddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
