<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406567471823145</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/speedy-hawk-could-return-after-five-weeks-out</url>
  <title>Speedy Hawk could return after five weeks out</title>
  <content>
Danger decision, fixture revealed
Nat Edwards with the latest news

Paul Puopolo has missed the last five weeks due to injury

HAWTHORN appears set to be bolstered for Sunday's huge MCG clash with Richmond by the return of Paul Puopolo.

The lively small forward and three-time premiership player, whose pressure acts are an important weapon for the Hawks, has not played for five weeks because of a groin injury.

"He trained fully today, we'll see how he pulls up," Hawks high performance manager Andrew Russell told hawthornfc.com.au on Tuesday.

Fears that emerging defender Blake Hardwick would miss the clash have also been allayed. The youngster went off with concussion last Friday night against Sydney.

"It was probably a line-ball decision whether he came back on but the doctors made the right call there," Russell said.

"He has recovered really, really well. He actually did some training today, so we expect him to be available to play this week."

Jaeger O'Meara's long-awaited to return to football now appears set for next weekend, with the midfielder back in full training and looking "fantastic" according to Russell.

Meanwhile defenders Josh Gibson and James Frawley have also returned to skills training and are rated a chance to play again before the end of the season.

The Hawks remain an outside chance to play in the finals but would need to win their remaining four games to keep those hopes alive.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Puopolo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nat Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Hardwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaeger O'Meara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Frawley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
