<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406601831562168</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/moreton/100-million-dollar-morayfield-health-hub-will-open-in-october/news-story/7fa7d9c21a82e623c3b256105bd3afcd</url>
  <title>$100 million Health hub open soon</title>
  <content>
THE first stage of the $100 million dollar Morayfield Health Hub will open in October, with a GP clinic and an urgent care clinic.
The 14,000sq m site at Dickson Rd will have a range of health services including primary and specialist services, allied and oral health services, acute care and day procedures, preventive health and rehabilitation services and diagnostic and medical support.
Health Development Corporations Director Dr Evan Jones and Moreton Bay Regional Council Mayor Allan Sutherland toured the site to inspect progress.
"The Health Developments Team spent a large amount of time on demographic research around the health needs of the Moreton Bay area," Dr Jones said.
"The research showed much of the current care patients were receiving was disjointed, slow, costly, and less effective than it could be.
"By incorporating a fully functional urgent care clinic, general practice, and a large range of allied health services as a predominantly bulk billed service, the health hub is aiming to lead the way, and help set the future standard, for what true patient centred care looks like in Australia."
Last week Moreton Bay Regional Council Mayor Allan Sutherland inspected the site.
"The health hub will play a vital role in helping meet current and future healthcare needs in a region where the population has grown by more than 12.5 per cent in just the past five years, and will be home to more than 618,000 people in the next two decades - more than a third of which will be aged 50 and over," he said
"The Morayfield Health Hub will also help to deliver the jobs of the future right here in Morayfield, with more than 300 ongoing jobs expected in healthcare and administration once fully operational, including up to 90 general practitioners. That's in addition to the 100 building and labouring jobs currently supported on site."
The second stage of the project is expected to open early 2018.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay Regional Council Mayor Allan Sutherland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morayfield Health Hub</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Development Corporations Director Dr Evan Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Developments Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr. Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
