<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406515932214685</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/reckless-parents-putting-children-at-risk-with-online-sitters/8753950</url>
  <title>Free online advertisements for babysitters can come at a cost for desperate parents</title>
  <content>
My friend's recent au pair wasn't work out exactly as she had hoped.
"He's lazy. He just hangs around the house all the time. He doesn't do very much."
I empathised with her. "What did his other employers say about him?" I asked. "I don't know," my friend replied, "I never checked with them."
I was surprised at her admission. She generally just went with the "feel" of a person. He seemed nice and she felt she could trust him. And despite his shortcomings she thought he was good with the kids.
No wonder parents are reckless

My friend isn't alone in relying on unvetted strangers for child care. Many Facebook groups have been set up in response to the large number of parents looking for someone to care for their kids.
There, parents and nannies, babysitters and au pairs can place ads for free. It seems like a straightforward and cost-effective way of finding child care.
Childminding websites often charge parents a fee for finding babysitters and nanny agencies can charge high rates for placements.
No wonder parents are reckless when there are so few affordable childcare choices available at night time.
Recently I saw an exchange between a 15-year-old and an exhausted mother of a newborn arranging babysitting on Facebook. It rang alarm bells - the girl didn't have any experience with babies, but her rates were cheap.
It worried me. I emailed the admin of the group but they weren't too concerned.

With Facebook groups and odd job websites such as Airtasker - which recently  for allowing parents to auction care for their children - the risk sits with the parents.
You would hope that parents will do the right checks when leaving their children under the care of a stranger. However not everyone does.
In most registered child care or family day care, workers must have police checks and first aid qualifications as a minimum. Many will also require their childcare workers to have formal qualifications.
However, these places only operate during office hours. What do you do when you need someone to look after your children after hours?
A gap in the market

Babysitters have long served the needs of parents needing a night off or to fill in the gaps when child care isn't an option. As technology becomes more part of our lives, using social media or websites to find someone to look after you children seems a natural progression from getting your neighbour's teenage daughter to look after your kids.
Of course things have changed since the old days. For one child care is more expensive than it has ever been before. When you're done paying $140 or more a day for your child to attend child care (as is done by parents in our inner cities), there is little left over if you want to have a night off.
And of course the more children you have the more expensive child care becomes.
Secondly, we used to know our neighbours a lot more than we now do. Most people living in inner-city neighbourhoods would struggle to tell you the names of their neighbours, let alone if they have a daughter or son willing to babysit.
It takes a village to raise a child - except no-one lives in a village anymore. We are living increasingly isolated lives, away from family, with parents who are older or still having to work.
This leaves many parents without options. I know when I have looked at getting a babysitter just for the evening I've found many experienced sitters charge a minimum of $25 per hour - which by the time you leave your house, have dinner and head home you're at least $100 out of pocket before you've even paid for the night out.
Few people have this kind of money to spend. But no parent wants to jeopardise their child's safety.
Most people believe that no-one will go out of their way to harm a child, but are the lack of checks worth the risk?
I guess it is up to individuals to answer that, but I know I couldn't have a stranger living in my house looking after my children if I hadn't done any background checks.
For my family, the cost of getting a babysitter has meant very few nights out - I can probably count on two hands the number of times my husband and I have gone out for the evening since having children.
But for others it's not just about a night out, but getting to work and putting food on the table.
Until something is done to support parents in accessing affordable child care, not just during the day but out of hours, many are forced to put their children at risk.
Saman Shad is a freelance writer.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Childminding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airtasker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saman Shad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
