<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406606126529625</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/st-augustines-take-netball-success-to-higher-level/3207159/</url>
  <title>St Augustine's take netball success to higher level</title>
  <content>
ST Augustine's College's Firsts netball team has come home with a swag of silverware after their recent success at the Queensland Independent Secondary School Netball (QISSN) tournament.
The St Augustine's team was undefeated in winning Division 5 of the prestigious series.
The accolades kept coming for St Augustine's first team, which was also awarded the coveted Captain Vivian Bullwinkle Trophy. This is presented to the team displaying the best sportsmanship throughout the tournament.
"It was an amazing experience for the St Augustine's students which began last year,'' head coach Kylie Thomas said. "It was a fabulous result for the team and capped off a lot of hard work from both the girls and the coaching staff."
As well St Augustine's College team doing fantastically, there were also many individual standouts.
St Augustine's student Monaliza Fepuleai was selected in the 2017 QISSN All Star team. This team is made up of the best 10 players from the 600 players who competed at the tournament.
Monaliza was thrilled to accept her position in the representative side.
"Overall the experience was awesome,'' team manager Elle Kuteman said.
"This team was fantastic on and off the court.
"Vicki Wilson, who was selecting the QISSN All Star team, said that St Augustine's had the best defence in the competition.
"The whole coaching staff is looking forward to next year as the team could potentially go back-to-back winners in Townsville."
The girls continued their success, finishing runners up at last week's Vicki Wilson preliminary carnival for the Metropolitan West region.
The girls won all their round matches, finishing top of their pool.
In the crossover matches they played St Peter Claver College, where they had a narrow win followed by a win against St Mary's College (Ipswich).
St Augustine's College Firsts netball team go on to represent the Metropolitan West region at the finals series.
This is where the top 20 schools in the state will compete for the Vicki Wilson Cup.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>QISSN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaliza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Vivian Bullwinkle Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Independent Secondary School Netball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaliza Fepuleai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ST Augustine's College's Firsts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Augustine's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Augustine</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elle Kuteman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Mary's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QISSN All Star</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicki Wilson Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Peter Claver College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicki Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
