<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406554586920980</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/ct-editorial/university-sexual-assault-crisis-cant-be-fixed-with-words-alone-20170801-gxn19o.html</url>
  <title>Universities must agree to ongoing monitoring of sexual assault policies and incidents</title>
  <content>
It is one thing for universities to apologise to victims of sexual assault or harassment and to pledge to do better in the wake of Tuesday's Human Rights Commission report.
It is quite another to back those words up with the actions needed to reduce the frequency of such occurrences and to improve responses.
If Australia's universities are to rebuild some badly needed credibility on what seems to be a major failure in their duty of care they should commit to a follow up review within, say, five years.
This would provide data on what progress, if any, was being made and allow policies to be finessed to ensure the highest possible level of effectiveness.
As it stands the HRC's findings are damning. The report said that of the ANU students who responded 116 were sexually assaulted in 2016. This is believed to be double the level of such assaults nationally. 52 per cent of these assaults were on campus. 
Of the more than 840 students who reported being sexually harassed over the same period 183 were males.

These figures may just be the tip of an iceberg given only 31,000 of the 60,000 students invited nationally to take part by the HRC responded. They represent a small fraction of a national university student population well in excess of one million people.
The University of Canberra also fared poorly with 7.2 per cent of respondents reporting they had been victims of sexual assault. Just over one per cent said these assaults had happened in a university setting.
While nobody would disagree with ANU Vice-Chancellor, Professor Brian Schmidt, when he says: "One incident (of assault or harassment) is more than we should accept" the obvious question is why has this taken so long to get the attention it deserves?
The HRC study, whose findings are purely indicative thanks to its opt-in nature, was only commissioned by Universities Australia after a National Students Union report in 2016 found almost three-quarters of female university students had been sexually assaulted or harassed.
Both studies came years after the "Skype" scandal at the Australian Defence Force Academy which saw that institution, which runs its academic program under the aegis of the University of NSW, embark on a protracted and painful period of culture change.
It would appear that instead of responding to this, and other, "red flags" that should have rung alarm bells, the ANU, UC and other universities failed to take significant enough steps to deal with so-called cultural practices and traditions leading to unacceptable behaviour.
Then, when assaults did occur, they all too often failed to offer the victims the support they needed and deserved.
While it is excellent our universities have now committed themselves to honouring their clear responsibility for student welfare, this situation must be closely monitored to ensure it gets better, not worse in the years to come.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skype</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HRC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Students Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU Vice-Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday's Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force Academy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
