<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406481572475660</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/more-than-10000-struck-down-by-flu-in-qld/news-story/70e1a87f26c24be5ccbe21e1b3bfcef8</url>
  <title>More than 10,000 struck down by flu in Qld</title>
  <content>
Australian Associated Press

Share

Flu season is here and has already hit more than 10,000 Queenslanders, but the state's health department is expecting many more people to be struck down.
Almost a fifth of those fell ill in the last week of July and more people have fallen sick this year than last, with flu season also starting earlier, communicable disease director Dr Sonya Bennett said.
"We can expect to see large numbers of flu notifications over the coming weeks," she said on Tuesday.
So far, 1324 Queenslanders have been hospitalised and 126 of those needed intensive care.
About 78 per cent of the 10,831 cases recorded this year were for influenza A while 22 per were for influenza B, Queensland Health says.
Vaccinations are being offered for two variants of each strain and Dr Bennett is urging people to have the injection, which can take up to two weeks to work.
"It is the best way of protecting yourself against the flu and often if people are vaccinated and they do get the flu, they'll get a less severe illness," she said.
About 800,000 subsidised vaccines have been dispatched across Queensland for people in risk groups including pregnant woman and those older than 65.
Flu can be a severe illness, Dr Bennett warned.

"Stay home when you're sick, cover your nose and mouth when sneezing and coughing and wash your hands regularly," she said.
"Combined with vaccination, these simply steps can reduce the likelihood of spreading the flu and combat the rise in flu notifications."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Bennett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Sonya Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
