<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406477277508305</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4827318/corrimal-playground-vandals-hit-where-it-hurts/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Corrimal playground vandals hit where it hurts</title>
  <content>
Police are calling for public assistance following repeated acts of vandalism at Corrimal's landmark inclusive playground, Luke's Place. 

The playground, in Corrimal Memorial Park, has been targeted by firebugs multiple times in the past six weeks. 
Most recently, the park's dish swing was set alight and cordoned off to undergoe repairs. 

East Corrimal parent Davina Reid condemned the vandalism. 
"It's actually happening at a lot of parks," she said. 

"It's horrible. You want your children to be safe and if it's damaged, you're not going to let them play on it. 
"It's sad that they [vandals] are ruining things that little kids are playing on."
Luke's Place was opened in April 2014 after a collaborative design process that included input from community members including area children with disabilities.

It is designed to let all children play side by side, with wheelchair-friendly carousel, colour-coded, textured sections for visually-impaired children, areas where hearing-impaired children can interact with noise and vibration and different active and quiet zones, including a water play area, for children with autism or other cognitive disorders. 
It was named in honour of Corrimal four-year-old Luke Rapley, whose parents Sean and Rita pushed for a park that their son - diagnosed with multiple disabilities - could use safely and in company with other children. 

Wollongong Police are requesting any suspicious behavior at the park be reported. Phone 4226 7899 or Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Corrimal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Rapley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke's Place</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal Memorial Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davina Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
