<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406601831562164</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/patrick-dangerfields-selfless-act-will-set-the-stand-for-geelong-teammates-says-cameron-ling-20170801-gxn9uy.html</url>
  <title>Dangerfield's 'selfless act' will set the stand for teammates: Ling</title>
  <content>
Geelong premiership captain Cameron Ling believes Patrick Dangerfield's selfless act in not challenging his one-match suspension will "set the standard" for his teammates to sacrifice their own games for the ultimate team success.
Dangerfield and Geelong opted to accept his ban for the tackle he laid on Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer, a move that renders him ineligible to win a second consecutive Brownlow Medal.Photo: AAP
The decision now creates the genuine possibility that Dangerfield, as the previous winner, could poll the most votes and have to physically hand the medal to second place.
Both the Cats and Dangerfield were too wary of missing a second game - against fellow top-four aspirant Richmond - if the tribunal hearing was unsuccessful.
Ling, who captained Geelong's 2011 premiership, said Dangerfield's act would resonate with the rest of the playing group.
"It sets the standard, in a different way, a way you wouldn't think was possible," he told Fairfax Media. "One of your leaders, one of your best players has said - 'I'm going to be selfless in order for us to achieve what we want to achieve this year and we as a club are going to be selfless and not try to win an individual award but try to win the premiership'.

"Others now have to come up to that standard."
Geelong sit in second position and would be guaranteed two home finals if the season ended now.
But, with the Cats only two points ahead of Greater Western Sydney and Richmond, and with four games remaining, things can change quickly.
The next two games against Sydney and Richmond are likely to prove pivotal in whether Geelong can finish in the top two.
"There are a lot of things that can happen between now and ultimately what they want to achieve," said Ling.
"Players get hurt. Do players try to play through that injury or do they do the selfless thing and say that they're not right to go?
"If you're asked to play a different role in qualifying final, trying to limit a particular player that doesn't end up with you getting the ball 25 or 30 times - how can you argue with that when this bloke didn't challenge his Brownlow because it meant that he could play an extra game for us.
"It means you've got no room to move."
Dangerfield was suspended by a reduced, three-pronged match review panel consisting of former St Kilda champion Nathan Burke, former Essendon hard nut Jason Johnson and recently retired Carlton defender Michael Jamison.
The MRP's other two members were absent. Michael Christian is away in the United States, while Jimmy Bartel had a business meeting with boot manufacturer XBlades.
Andrew Dillon is also in just his second week as acting head of football operations, following the recent departure of Simon Lethlean. 
As AFL head of football, Dillon has the power to lay a charge himself if he believes the match review panel has missed an incident or has come to a conclusion that he didn't believe was accurate.
Former footy boss Lethlean had a very firm few on rule interpretations and was known to challenge the match review panel from time to time.
He also became the first football operations manager in AFL history to appeal a tribunal finding; a decision that ultimately proved correct in the most recent case of Richmond defender Bachar Houli.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Lethlean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachar Houli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Christian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Ling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Dillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ling</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jamison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Bartel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XBlades</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lethlean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
