<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406472982540769</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4826021/new-works-flow-into-past/?cs=305</url>
  <title>New works flow into past</title>
  <content>
BRIGHT FUTURE: The upgraded North Stockton boat ramp area, including a fish-cleaning pavilion and car and trailer park, on the bank of the Hunter River's north arm. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

TIME and tide have done much to shape the Stockton shoreline. But in recent months, it has been a team of workers giving a makeover to the area around the North Stockton boat ramp. 
As well as workers, a group of politicians and officials trod the freshly laid turf and new bitumen car park to officially launch the upgrade on Tuesday. 
Parliamentary Secretary for the Hunter Scot MacDonald said the $850,000 project was funded by the state government and Newcastle City Council, and that the improvements would primarily benefit recreational boaties.
Lord Mayor Nuatali Nelmes described the work as "a fantastic community outcome" and said there was particular interest in the new fish-cleaning area.

A few hundred metres to the south, the Stockton boat harbour is still waiting for a similar revamp. A collection of commercial fishing boats and pleasure craft are berthed at old, rickety-looking finger wharves. 

In January, the state government announced a $4.3 million refurbishment for the boat harbour, but work isn't expected to begin until February.

After the ceremony at the boat ramp, the Roads and Maritime Services' acting operations manager in the Hunter, Alex Hamilton, inspected the harbour and said the planned work was necessary "for safety, and for community expectations".

"I think when the work is done, it will be a much better facility than what's here now," Mr Hamilton said. 

Alex Delmoni is a Stockton resident and keeps a boat in the small harbour. He is also on the committee for its planned upgrade, which is expected to accommodate 26 vessels. Mr Delmoni hopes that as well as assuring the boat harbour's future, the refurbishment will uncover some of the past.

He said a sandstone wall, almost a century old, that ran for kilometres along the Hunter River's north arm had been all but buried. He asserted the new works at the boat ramp had also covered some of the old wall.  

"I'm very disappointed about that," he said.

"I'm hoping they ... dig out the wall and restore it [at the boat harbour]. It's a historical feature, and it's sad to see this little bit of history lost."

History lies just below the surface around Stockton's edges. Sailing ships used to berth along the shore, dumping their ballast.

"A lot of it was rubble that came from San Francisco after the [1906] earthquake there," said local history researcher Ron Haug.

Mr Haug said at the site of the revamped North Stockton boat ramp, the renowned boat-building family, the Towns, used to have a shed. The family had a business hiring rowboats to visitors. So along Stockton's shores, the maritime past flows into the present.  

HISTORY: Ships berthed at Stockton wharves in the early 1900s.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Delmoni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ron Haug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Scot MacDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Delmoni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Stockton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter River</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Haug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Nuatali Nelmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockton</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
