<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406606126529613</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/boxing-mma/joe-cortez-reveals-he-had-to-separate-conor-mcgregor-and-paulie-malignaggi-in-fiery-sparring-session/news-story/5d0bc4ebb42802b6cdf21ef6573bf8d6</url>
  <title>'Out of control': McGregor's sparring spat</title>
  <content>
VETERAN boxing referee Joe Cortez had to separate Conor McGregor and Paulie Malignaggi during a fiery sparring session.
The 73-year-old was brought in to teach UFC star McGregor the rules of boxing ahead of his superfight with Floyd Mayweather.
But he ended up acting peacemaker as the Irishman and Malignaggi got heated in the ring.
Cortez said both fighters started of firing verbal shots at each other - leaving the session out of control.
He told RUSH 93: "It was the real thing, I had to stop the action, say 'you guys are a little out of control here, you've got to stop this.' You know, they got a little rough.
"They were both roughing each other up and I had to stop the action like it was a regular fight.
"They were holding too much - they were trying to punch each other.
"So I had to call 'time, alright guys you've got to stop this right now, I won't a good, clean, strong - give me a sportsman like conduct you understand?'"
McGregor called out Malignaggi after the American's claimed the MMA fighter was being disrespectful to the sport of boxing by wanting to fight Mayweather.
He said: "Yeah, look, Paulie talked a lot of shit.
"Look he's been brought in to spar and then he'll answer to what he's been saying and then we'll go from there after that.
"But we're gonna have a knock in the gym.
"I mean, look, we're going have a knock and he's gonna have to answer to what he's been saying.
FLOYD'S OUTRAGEOUS DEMAND
Eddie Hearn has revealed Floyd Mayweather wants his fight with Conor McGregor to cost £100 on pay-per-view in the UK - but Sky want to charge £19.95.
With around only four weeks to the cross-sports fight, fans are still without an official announcement on how much the mega-money fight is going to cost on TV ... and what channel it will even be on.
According to the Los Angeles Times reporter Lance Pugmire, the pay-per-view mega fight will set you back $89.99 in standard definition and $99.99 in high definition.
The $99.99 price tag matches the record for the highest priced PPV for a combat sports match from when Floyd Mayweather Jr took on Manny Pacquiao in 2015.
Eddie Hearn during an interview with GQ says the Mayweather would like the PPV to cost £100 in the UK.
That would be a record for PPV with the average being almost £15.
Hearn told GQ: "Mayweather wants the price to be £100."
But Hearn doesn't believe the price will be above the normal price for a PPV.
"The price will be within the same realms as it always has. I don't set the price, but my gut feeling is £19.95.
"If it went to £24.95 ... I can't see it, it wouldn't be my decision. Sky won't want to go beyond £19.95. That is their price point."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd Mayweather Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FLOYD'S OUTRAGEOUS DEMAND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malignaggi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayweather</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulie Malignaggi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPV</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cortez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Pugmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hearn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irishman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Cortez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUSH 93</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Hearn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manny Pacquiao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd Mayweather</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
