<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406902479278788</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/ct-letters/time-to-change-attack-tack-20170801-gxncrr.html</url>
  <title>Time to change attack tack</title>
  <content>
Amanda Vanstone, if your ad hominem attack on Bill Shorten is the best you can do to criticise the Labor Party ("When a workers warrior is found wanting", July 31, p15), then please step aside and let people with an actual agenda for bettering the nation have a go.
The Liberal Party hates Shorten calling Malcolm Turnbull "Mr Harbourside Mansion", and calls it "ugly political posturing", so your attack is just as bad. If you don't like the words, don't say them yourself.
Have you got anything to say about inequality? Gonski 2.0? Come on, you're from South Australia - maybe you can say something about renewable energy policy and climate change?
Perhaps you could discuss jobs and growth?
Or is personal attacks the only thing you have to say about Labor?
Paul Wayper, Canberra

PM a disappointment

No, Amanda Vanstone, you've got it terribly wrong. The reason Malcolm Turnbull was not rewarded at the last election had nothing to do with his distaste for personal attacks on the opposition.
Malcolm's ballot-box problem was that the general public's high hopes for him had already been dashed.
We were (and are) disappointed in his failure to be true to his own values because of his deal with the Coalition's conservatives. "Behaving with decorum" is what we expect from prime ministers but we also expect them to deliver the policies we know they believe in, such as marriage equality and climate change.
Bettye Pearce, Lyons
Section 44 a joke

What a joke is Section 44 of the constitution and its impact on elected senators.
We have already lost two wonderfully able people in Scott Ludlam and Larissa Waters and a potentially good contributor in Matt Canavan.
Why can't something simple and quick be done to fix things without long drawn-out proceedings, legal costs, stress etc. And also without slow, costly uncertain change to the constitution via referendum.
Our constitution is outdated (a 1901 document) and clearly needs changing eg inter alia to recognise Indigenous people. How do we sensibly do this? Constitutional lawyers with common sense please step up to the plate!
Also there is a Ph.D in this for someone - how many MPs have there been who were not born in Australia? King O'Malley, a federal minister falls into this category.
After all, we were all British nations up until the 1960s.
Graeme Mayo, Hawker
Sanitising history

Michael Piggott (CT, July 31) commends the National Archives for returning to Japan certain documents seized in World War II.
Perhaps the NAA and other cultural institutions could also return documents held that supported the bringing of war crimes charges against Japanese military officers after World War II.
These documents might help to bring to the attention of some Japanese the fact that they have a government, a large element of which, still refuses to acknowledge World War II, referring to it as an "incident" and, bans literature and movies portraying it and sanitises school curriculums.
Roger Terry, Kingston
Reining in North Korea

Scott Swift, US commander of the Pacific Fleet, may be pessimistic in his assessment that the world will have to accept a nuclear-armed North Korea as a fact of life.
Just this month the United Nations has concluded a treaty signed by 166 nations outlawing nuclear weapons. Stigmatising these weapons of mass destruction as illegal at last will help the majority of nations who have been working towards a nuclear-free future.
Australia, once at the forefront of this movement, should now rejoin. We don't need rogue states to have these weapons.
If we can discourage North Korea from its expensive launching into rogue state status, that will be a start.
Harry Davis, Campbell
Why I'm really afraid

While the threat of terrorism is real, I am sceptical about the recent increased threat to us in this country.
I no longer trust our government has our best interests at heart, but is driven by self interest and a need to flex its muscles. The recent appointment of Peter Dutton to the new super-Ministry of Home Affairs, instead of giving me a sense of security, fills me with unease and dread.
The unwelcome term "fascist" springs to mind as I read more of the policies of this government and "marvel" at the political appointments and decisions made on our behalf. Be afraid, be very afraid of the lack of unintelligent and uninformed decisions.
Vee Saunders, Weetangera
Shorten wins our vote

Bill Shorten's pledge, as future PM, to hold a yes/no vote on support for an Australian republic, definitely wins him our next election vote. We expect most Liberals would also welcome settlement of the republic question which involves formal establishment of our total constitutional independence.
Bryan and Elizabeth Lobascher, Chifley
Finer points of law

The Greek embassy in Canberra has confirmed that Julia Banks "would have acquired the right to [Greek] citizenship by blood when she was born . . . but that it needed to be 'activated' ".
She has not done so. But isn't she nevertheless currently entitled to acquire the rights or privileges of a Greek citizen?
If she has this entitlement, isn't she in Parliament illegally?
Michael McCarthy, Deakin
Self-driving vehicles taking over?  Bring on the teleporters instead

It's touching that there are still one or two starry-eyed optimists like Barry Faux (Letters, July 31) who are convinced that self-driving vehicles will be taking over our roads in a decade or so and obviating the need for public transport.
These vehicles will, of course, be reliable, legally acceptable, cheap enough to be available to all and magically able to solve all our transport needs without clogging our roads. This will, naturally, happen in much the same way that (as everybody knows) in the 21st century nuclear power will be too cheap to meter, robots will be doing all the work, we'll only be working one day per week and we'll all be flying around in silver jump-suits powered by personal backpack jets.
Then again, given the demonstrated reliability of such predictions and the fact that cars are just so twentieth century, we might do better to wait for teleportation. Beam me up, Scotty.
Felix MacNeill, Dickson
Rebel-Brumbies

I am an 81-year-old Brumbies and Rugby tragic. I'm sure I'll be initially howled down by Brumbies supporters as I suggest that the Brumbies need to amalgamate with the Melbourne Rebels for the future of Australian rugby and the Brumbies.
Just to stoke the fires of dissent I add it would not be important whether the Rebel/Brumbies team is based in Melbourne or Canberra, with home games shared between Canberra and Melbourne.
Point 1/ Australian Rugby cannot sustain five teams financially or competitively but cannot afford to kill off any of the support base of the five major or potential rugby cities.
2/ Although the Brumbies have been the most successful franchise in Super Rugby, both Canberra and Melbourne have a very small and fickle crowd support and sponsorship base.
3/ The Rebels/Brumbies are the best fit for amalgamation, geographically and socially. Perth and Brisbane are simply too far away to be an option and I believe Sydney is best left to its "Silver Tail Old School Tie" rugby culture.
The merger would certainly create a rugby power, financially and competitively, both in Australia and the Southern Hemisphere.
We would need major financial support from the ARU to establish this merged franchise to relocate to one home base and settle terminated contracts for players, administration and coaching staff.
As both cities stand to lose half their home games each season, the other three franchises should agree to play their home games against the merged franchise in Canberra or Melbourne for the first three seasons.
Lyle Swann, Gilmore
Save the green space

I have read many letters opposing the "development" of our once beautiful city, have been to a consultation meeting and had many discussions with other like-minded lovers of Canberra.
There is anger and disappointment out there, Andrew Barr.
Alistair Coe, where are you? Do you believe that what is happening to our fair city with developers appearing to take every bit of green space and building a monstrous "invigorating-lifestyle" apartment block on it to be in the best interests of our citizens Alistair?
What has happened to people power? Is there a rally anywhere to object to all this "development"? I'll be there.
Pauline Green, Chisholm
Housing priorities

Jon Stanhope's analysis ("More houses a priority", July 29, Forum p10) of current ACT government practice in relation to an inadequate supply of land for standalone houses is to be welcomed.
It sounds like an ALP opposition critique of a developer-driven government unconcerned with the social and economic impacts of its policies.
For example, Stanhope says there has been a 29 per cent increase in the median price of standalone houses between 2012 and 2016.
Hang on. Isn't an ALP government already in power in the ACT? Something is seriously wrong.
Murray May, Cook
Hospital fire risks

It's an idea for hazard reduction burns and under storey clearing to be ramped up around habitable parts of the ACT.
Meandering pre-op adjacent to Calvary hospital, I was concerned to note the level of the fuel hazard, which I would rate as extreme.
It would be a great folly if the hospital was damaged or inaccessible during the next bush fire emergency.
Matt Ford, Crookwell, NSW
Harassment at ANU

Professor Brian Schmidt (ANU vice chancellor) is right to point out the criticality of taking steps to minimise the incidents of sexual harassment and indeed harassment generally in workplaces including centres of learning, like the ANU.
It is just a pity that Brian does not respond to the approaches made to him by staff, ex-staff and representatives of staff and ex-staff about the systemic level of bullying and harassment practised by many of his senior administrators when dealing with staff with the university.
The ANU now has one of the highest compensation claim rates of any institution in the country and its most senior representatives and council seem incapable of addressing the causes.
Professor Schmidt needs to lead by example.
David Lander, Belconnen
Data downside

Back when Australia rejected the Australia Card, many people I know did so because they were scared that it would enable the various governments, and government departments and agencies, to pool their data on a particular person.
Rather like how Centerlink and the ATO recently combined to enable the Robodebt program.
Now we have the downside of pooled government data anyway, but without any of the advantages of the Australia Card.
Well done Australia. Bloody brilliant.
S W Davey, Torrens
Ducks grounded

After last weekend's terror arrests I note even the ducks around my place are afraid to fly at the moment. Four of them were hiking down the road on Tuesday morning.
M. Moore, Bonython
TO THE POINT

DON'T RELY ON CHINA
North Korea test-fires another ICBM and the usual suspects in Washington, Tokyo, Seoul and Canberra yell at China to make them stop. This, after endless threats and verbal bombast directed at North Korea. China and North Korea have been allies for 60-plus years. It's risible to expect China will destabilise North Korea on the say-so of these countries.
Peter Moran, Watson
OUT OF THIS WORLD
To become President of the US you have to be born there. As Donald Trump clearly comes from another planet he should resign immediately.
John Galvin, Weston
COOL FYSHWICK
M. Moore has a problem with, "Cool Fyshwick? ("Fyshwick turns cool", July 28, p1). When hell freezes over!" (Letters, July 29). It has always been so. Red light districts have always developed into bohemian centres of art, revelry and culinary indulgence. Kings Cross, La Rive Gauche, Soho and Times Square spring to mind. A degree of gentrification inevitably follows.
Gary J. Wilson, Macgregor
REVAMP UNNECESSARY
It's interesting that the seemingly successful raids on suspected terrorists in Sydney were conducted comfortably under the current security arrangements. How would the outcome have been improved by creating an unwieldy and unaccountable security mega-department?
David Jenkins, Casey
WHITE HOUSE TOUGH
Is there any truth to the story that Bear Grylls is preparing to host a new Survivor series: "Survivor White House". Should be enough material to last a whole year.
Chris Mobbs, Hackett
IF IT AIN'T BROKE
O ye that would call on a republic - lay off, or your fall will be even worse, this time round. For never has homo politicus been in such bad odour as now, never the trust so low. Last time, opponents said, "If it ain't broke, why fix it". Now that is more than a groan from the apathetic and the ignorant, it's partly true. With what we've got now, warts and all, at least we know what we've got.
Barrie Smillie, Duffy
THE GAY VOTE
Let the people have their say on gay marriage, not the politicians who have a vested interest. The Labor pollies, regardless of their true feelings, must toe the Labor line upon pain of dismissal. Government members, however, have a vote free of such penalty. Mr Shorten, release the shackles on your members and find out what they really believe in. My local federal member does not represent my view.
John Madelly snr, Melba
Email: . Send from the message field, not as an attached file. Fax: 6280 2282. Mail: Letters to the Editor, The Canberra Times, PO Box 7155, Canberra Mail Centre, ACT 2610.
Keep your letter to 250 words or less. References to Canberra Times reports should include date and page number. Letters may be edited. Provide phone number and full home address (suburb only published).
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary J. Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Fleet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebel/Brumbies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WHITE HOUSE TOUGH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W Davey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GAY VOTE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fyshwick</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonython</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macgregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair Coe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Vanstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vee Saunders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hackett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Swift</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duffy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weetangera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Banks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Mayo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Mail Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PO Box 7155</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanhope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Lander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Mobbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Lobascher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chisholm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Galvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Moran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael McCarthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King O'Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Hemisphere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larissa Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crookwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ministry of Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gonski 2.0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Harbourside Mansion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calvary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Times Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Faux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Rebels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robodebt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Wayper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Times</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centerlink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Archives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT 2610</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RELY ON CHINA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Stanhope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bettye Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seoul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felix MacNeill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Rive Gauche</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Card</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barrie Smillie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Ludlam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ph.D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bear Grylls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Madelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray May</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Barr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chifley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICBM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Section 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Piggott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyle Swann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belconnen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silver Tail Old School Tie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
