<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406911069213512</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/what-queen-drinks-day/3207662/</url>
  <title>What the Queen drinks in a day</title>
  <content>
QUEEN Elizabeth II throws back four alcoholic beverages a day, making her a binge drinker by government standards.

She never changes up her alcohol intake and her drink choice is just as classy as you'd expect.

According to , Her Majesty drinks a gin and Dubonnet with lemon and ice before lunch, a wine with lunch, and a dry martini and glass of champagne at night.

While she might indulge in four cocktails a day, she's always doing it on a full stomach.

The first thing she eats when she wakes up is tea and biscuits, and washes that down with some fruit and cereal. The Queen prefers Special K over any other cereal.

Sometimes she'll swap that out for scrambled eggs with smoked salmon.

Her Majesty has a no-starch rule at lunch and will have a low-carb meal. But she always indulges in some chocolate afterwards.

The  reported royal chef Darren McGrady said she was a bit of a chocoholic, but also loved kale and quinoa.

Her favourite dessert is a pie with a chocolate base, filled with layers of meringue, white chocolate cream and chocolate.

"When you get older, you know what you like, and the Queen has her favourites," Mr McGrady said.

"When alone she will have maybe grilled sole with vegetables and a bowl of fruit or pudding.

"She is very disciplined with her diet but is happy to try new things and likes kale and quinoa."

When it comes to dinner time, Her Majesty has a strict ban on garlic. In fact, she's banned it throughout the entire palace.

As the Queen celebrates her 60 years as head of state, The Independent has revealed facts about Her Majesty. She is the 257th richest person in the UK and is worth about £300m (AUD$495m).

It was also revealed the Queen can be a bit of a hothead.

In 1954 during a visit to Australia, the Queen had an argument with her husband Prince Philip and writer Robert Hardman said she was filmed "hurling shoes, threats and sporting equipment, and venting the sort of regal fury that, in another age, would have cost someone their head".

She later apologised for the interlude and said "as you know, it happens in every marriage".

There's also one thing that is guaranteed to make the Queen laugh, which is something nobody would expect. According to her grandson Prince William, the Queen is quite fond of Ali G impressions.

Her majesty is quite the jetsetter too, and in the last 60 years has gone overseas on official business 261 times, to 116 different countries. She has also had to sit still for 129 portraits during her time as head of state.

Gofundme set up for better mobility equipment and ongoing costs
MOTORBIKE rider transported to hospital in a serious condition
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
KEN has more than a passing interest in the evolution of music.
And so BYTE - the Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence - was born.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Majesty</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubonnet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Hardman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD$495</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Special K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGrady</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren McGrady</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
