<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406739270518280</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/soccer/daniel-de-silva-cleared-to-make-debut-for-central-coast-mariners-in-ffa-cup-20170801-gxn4j6.html</url>
  <title>Daniel De Silva cleared to make debut for Central Coast Mariners in FFA Cup</title>
  <content>
Central Coast Mariners coach Paul Okon confirmed marquee signing Daniel De Silva is eligible to make his club debut on Wednesday night despite fears red tape would delay his registration. 
The former Roda JC and Perth Glory attacking midfielder is set to play some part in the Mariners FFA Cup match against Blacktown City at Lily Holmes Stadium, with his international transfer clearance having been approved by Football Federation Australia. 

Up Next

Plays of the Week

01:59

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Craig Foster remembers Les Murray

SBS Chief Football Analyst Craig Foster has spoken to SBS World News regarding the passing of his friend and colleague Les Murray AM. Courtesy SBS

A complicated transfer from his former parent club, AS Roma, to the Mariners was reported as having been held-up by the FFA but Okon says De Silva's registration has come through, deeming him eligible to play make his debut. 
"I didn't quite understand what was written and what was said [about De Silva's registration]," Okon said. "Daniel is available for selection."

But Okon was coy as to whether De Silva is fit and ready to start against Blacktown. He is tempted to use the youngster as a bench option in their first competitive game of the season. The Mariners trained in Sydney on Tuesday where De Silva had one final chance to push his claim for a starting position in the Cup. 
"He's working incredibly hard in recent months and he's put himself in a position where he's not at full 90-minute fitness so we'll manage him and get him up to the level," Okon said. "He's available for selection, he's itching to get minutes ... whether that's from the start or off the bench, we'll decide later on after training."

Mariners fans will have to wait to gain a glimpse of their new Spanish signing, Azdrubal, who will not feature on Wednesday night. The former Las Palmas striker only recently joined the club and not will be rushed into the first-team. 

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Dutch international Wout Brama was announced as the Mariners' fourth visa-player but will not arrive until next week. However, his compatriot Tom Hiariej and Spanish defender Alan Baro are set to start against Blacktown for a much more experienced Central Coast side. Photo: AAP
The club has recruited strongly in the off-season, adding quality and experienced foreigners but Okon denied they are steering away from their ethos of developing local talent. 
"I don't think we've replaced a young player with an older player so we've still got,  I think, up to six boys born in 1997-98," he said. "To have senior players around me, it made me learn so much and I'm sure our younger boys will appreciate it in time to have the possibility to be training everyday and playing alongside not only experienced players, but good professional players."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roda JC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS World News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast Mariners</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Baro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray AM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hiariej</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariners FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS Chief Football Analyst Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lily Holmes Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Okon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariners</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel De Silva</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Foster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Palmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Glory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Azdrubal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wout Brama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Silva</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
