<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406687730909861</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/17/58/fiveyearold-boy-walks-more-than-2km-after-escaping-melbourne-kinder</url>
  <title>Five-year-old boy walks more than 2km after escaping Melbourne kinder</title>
  <content>
A five-year-old boy has been found after going missing from kinder and walking more than two kilometres along a busy Melbourne highway.
Jacob Ford was dropped off by his father at St. Clare's Primary School, in Officer, about 9.30 this morning.
Soon after, Jacob used a chair to reach the high door of the facility and snuck out, walking onto Majestic Drive then onto the bustling Princes Highway.
He was found alone by passer-by, Laura Hayson, an hour later, having walked at least 2.5km.
"I noticed a small child running along the highway," Ms Hayson said.
"I just put myself in the parent's situation. I would want someone to stop to help me."
Jacob's mother, Sonia, said she was "shocked" to receive a call from police officers when she was at work.

Related Articles

"My husband dropped him off... then we got a call from police telling us Jacob was in custody," Ms Ford told 9NEWS.
The mother said that the kinder had "no idea" her child was missing until they were informed by authorities.
"I'm really shocked... you never expect anything like this to happen. You never think your child is walking along a highway left to their own devices," she said.
Ms Ford said the staff at Jacob's daycare were "very apologetic", and are now conducting a "full investigation".
"I'm just so grateful that we've got Jacob with us," she said.
Jacob said he left kinder because he wanted to see "his dad" and "go home".
The five-year-old added that he "loves police" and hopes to be an officer when he grows up.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Majestic Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hayson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Hayson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Clare's Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
