<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406472982540857</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/darren-berry-takes-aim-at-port-adelaide-fans-massive-error/news-story/1fdaacf57b8d951f0d19fcae58cccd04</url>
  <title>Legend blasts 'disgraceful' fan act</title>
  <content>
ANYONE watching the footy on Saturday afternoon knows Port Adelaide pulled off a serious comeback to seal one of the most nailbiting wins seen this season.
The stage was set for the Saints to take home a victory as they kicked four consecutive goals to put themselves 10 points ahead of the home side with two minutes to go.
Port's Aaron Young pulled off a hasty goal to bring the margin to four points with seconds to go until the final siren.
Then, something magical happened.
Power star Paddy Ryder pulled off a remarkable tap out of the ruck to caress the ball into Robbie Gray's hands. The 29-year-old Gray then slotted in an impossible goal with seven seconds left on the clock to bring the final score to 9.9 (63) - 8.13 (61) and end St Kilda's hopes at a finals series. Fans erupted as the Power looked around at their teammates in shock.
Saints coach Alan Richardson said it was a "bloody costly way to learn a lesson", while Power coach Ken Hinkley said his side's win was nothing short of season-defining.
"That's a pretty good effort. Together they did well ... we train that sort of stuff to hopefully get one of those wins for us and in a season as tight and tough as it is, it's pretty significant," he said.
"We haven't felt that thrill from that type of win for a long, long time and that's important to remember.
"There's some parts of the game that clearly we shouldn't have done or didn't do, but that's a pretty emotional win for the football club."
But before the Power pulled off their ridiculous win, a serious number of fans had already checked-out of the stadium.
Power supporters left the Adelaide Oval in droves earlier in the match, obviously adamant their side were unable to seal the deal.
SEN expert and former cricketer Darren Berry took a swipe at the mass exodus on Afternoons Tuesday.
"This is a quick smack for the Port Adelaide fans for when they were walking out of the ground," he said.
"(It was) disgraceful. Never walk out and leave your team. I don't like that.
"No matter what, I've been through many of times where the Saints have been belted at Waverly Park. And I sat there painfully before I left. I never leave. So I hate that."
Twitter erupted after Port sealed the deal, blasting the disloyal fans for leaving.

Port Adelaide fans that left should have their memberships revoked!
Typical 😂😂😂

I love knowing that all those port fans who left early just got to the car, turned on the radio, and went "WHAT?"

The Power's triumph was substance rather than style - both sides struggled to score in tricky winds and slippery conditions as Port led 5.7 to 3.12 at three-quarter time.
The dour battle sparked in a frenetic finale with Port appearing safe when Brad Ebert served up a 55m bomb for a 14-point lead midway through the term. But plucky Saints replied with four unanswered goals - when Tim Membrey slotted this third, they were 10 points up.
But Port's Young scrambled a snap and then Gray stole the show, converting on the run from 50 metres for a famous win.
Port were well served by reliable onballer Ollie Wines (23 disposals), Jared Polec (30 touches) and Gray (27 possessions), while Hamish Hartlett and Jasper Pittard were in the thick of it defensively.
Spearhead Charlie Dixon was among seven goalscorer's for Port, who meet hometown rival and ladder leaders Adelaide next Sunday.
The Saints, who host West Coast next Sunday, had a midfield with plenty of punch led by Seb Ross (31 possessions) and Luke Dunstan and Jake Carlisle was superb in defence.
- with AAP
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Hartlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jasper Pittard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port's Aaron Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waverly Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afternoons Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port's Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Dixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ollie Wines (23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Ebert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gray, 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Membrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Carlisle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Polec (30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Dunstan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seb Ross (31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
