<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406726385616215</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:38</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/bull-victim-alexandra-henderson-loved-working-with-livestock/news-story/a537ead1c90e3f57feb14afe18361f3c</url>
  <title>Bull victim 'loved working with animals'</title>
  <content>
THE parents of teen who was killed by a large bull in WA's south say they are devastated by the loss of their beautiful daughter.
Alexandra Henderson was found unresponsive by a co-worker at a farm on the South Coast Highway in Dalyup, near Esperance, on Monday.
The 19-year-old had been herding the large bull when she was struck by the animal and pushed into a fence railing.
On Tuesday, Ms Henderson's family said the teen died doing what she loved.
"As any family would be, we are devastated by the sudden loss of our beautiful daughter Alexandra," the teen's parents said in a statement.

"We are consoled at this time by the fact that she was in a happy place at this time in her life.
"She was working on a property she loved, with people she cared for and respected, and who cared for and respected her.
"Alexandra was only young but she had worked with animals and farm livestock in particular her whole life, including cattle."
Ms Henderson's family described the teen as a competent horsewoman and a compassionate person, and thanked those who desperately tried to save the 19-year-old at the farming property.
"We are buoyed at this time by the fact that we have spent so much time with her, and that we live in a community which has supported us with an outpouring of love and support," Ms Henderson's parents said.
"We are also incredibly appreciative of those who tried to keep our lovely child with us, those attending the scene at the farm, the ambulance crews and the team at the Esperance District hospital who did all within their power to prevent her from leaving us too soon."
Worksafe are investigating Ms Henderson's death and a report will be prepared for the coroner.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Henderson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WorkSafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalyup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
