<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406730680583565</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/child-care-fees-could-triple-says-learning-centre-owner/8764498</url>
  <title>Childcare fees could triple under Tasmanian Government's school start plan, learning centre warns</title>
  <content>
Tasmanian childcare provider Discovery Early Learning Centres is threatening to scrap plans for a new centre in Bridgewater and is warning six other centres will close if the Government pushes ahead with changes to the school starting age.
The Upper House will soon be tasked with deciding on the move to lower the voluntary school starting age to three and a half, which the Government has trumpeted as a bold move to better engage children in education.
Discovery operates 10 centres across the state, and business manager Lyndon Walsh warned Education Minister Jeremy Rockliff the plan would result in reduced access to child care.
He said if the legislation passed, the drop in enrolments would force fees to more than triple.
"Minister Rockliff says he's trying to improve access to early education, especially for those in disadvantaged communities, but I can tell you first hand that's not going to happen," Mr Walsh said.
"Child care will become too expensive and out of reach for many families."
Mr Walsh said Discovery's Bridgewater centre would be forced to increase fees for low-income families from $16 a day to $52 a day, or to even close.
The company has plans to build a new centre in the area, which would employ 40 people.
"We just simply won't be able to go ahead with that," he said.
Mr Walsh said the Ravenswood centre in Launceston was also earmarked for closure.
No evidence to support plan, White says

The State Opposition opposes the move, and leader Rebecca White visited the Bridgewater centre today.
She said Labor would reverse the changes if it won government next year.
"There is no evidence to support lowering the school starting age," Ms White said.
"We are hoping very much the legislation won't be supported by the Upper House."
"We want to make sure Legislative Councillors are aware of the impacts of this policy right across the community."
Premier Will Hodgman said he understood the plan would have impacts, and that was why the Government had commissioned a report.
He said it was a bold plan that aimed to improve Tasmania's poor retention rates.
"That's why we aren't rushing to make a decision on the best way forward," he said.
"It's an important conversation for the whole community and it would be a tragedy not to have the courage to have that conversation."
Several MLCs raised concerns with the plans when the reformed Education Act went to Parliament last year.
The Government's compromise was delaying a decision on the school starting age for a year so an expert panel could report back.
That is due to happen on September 1.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Jeremy Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyndon Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Discovery's Bridgewater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ravenswood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRIDGEWATER</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Discovery Early Learning Centres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legislative Councillors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Will Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MLCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Walsh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
