<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406773630257200</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/richmond-to-honour-alannah-madeline-foundation-with-purple-jumpers/news-story/99930504bf38437a1f50fbb889c1cee5</url>
  <title>Tigers to show their purple hearts</title>
  <content>
WHEN Richmond continues its march towards the finals this weekend, a patch of purple will be worn proudly on the yellow and black guernseys.
Apart from representing a 72,535-member Tiger army, Richmond stars will, in their MCG clash with Hawthorn, wear special jumpers on Sunday featuring the Alannah & Madeline Foundation logo.
In a show of support for the not-for-profit organisation which protects children from violence and bullying, the Tigers will dedicate the match to the charity.
Richmond defender Dylan Grimes visited St Bede's Primary School in Balwyn North to spread the message.
"We've played in some big games this year but we've had such a long affiliation with Alannah & Madeline that we've seen all the work they do to protect kids," he said.
"It means a lot to the playing group."
Grimes spent six months as an intern with the charity, helping to produce an anti-bullying program to be used in sporting clubs.
"Unfortunately there is such a desperate need for the help that the Alannah & Madeline Foundation offer," he said.
"It's really gratifying to know that we've partnered with such an important cause."
The foundation, set up in memory of Alannah and Madeline Mikac who in April 1996 were killed with their mother and 32 others in the Port Arthur massacre, helps children recovering from trauma and violence.
It also sends backpacks full of essentials to children in emergency accommodation and runs anti-bullying and anti-cyber-bullying programs in schools and libraries across Australia.
Foundation chief executive Lesley Podesta said the five-year partnership with Richmond had been rewarding for the players as well as children.
Richmond chief Brendon Gale said the club was proud to help build awareness around bullying and help to create safe environments for children.
Go to  to donate.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grimes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Bede's Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balwyn North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeline Foundation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Grimes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alannah</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Gale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeline Mikac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lesley Podesta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 1996</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
