<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406730680583529</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/canberra-hospital-fire-risk-identified-year-before-blaze/8764576</url>
  <title>Canberra Hospital fire risk identified a year before switchboard blaze forced evacuations</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

The ACT Government was warned the main switchboard at Canberra Hospital was a risk more than a year before it caught fire.
Up to 60 patients and staff were
The hospital was forced to cancel all outpatient services and elective surgeries as a result.
A report released today but handed to the Government in February 2016 identified four items of extreme infrastructure risk at the hospital, including the switchboard.
The report prepared by AECOM Australia identified other areas of extreme concern, which demand urgent action,  including structural works to the helipad and windows in building one.
There were $71.1 million worth of issues identified at the hospital, with $16.5 million of those risks in the extreme range.
Opposition health spokeswoman Vicki Dunne said the 147 extreme and high risks identified in the report must be fixed urgently and with public transparency.
"The minister needs to tell the community what she is doing to fix our decaying hospital, particularly with regard to the sub-standard switchboards and helipad," she said.
The Government has been approached for comment.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicki Dunne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AECOM Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
