<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406881004441845</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4826940/rookie-trainer-breaks-maiden/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Rookie trainer breaks maiden</title>
  <content>
Luke Thomas thought it was about time he got into training after seeing the likes of The Mission go on to glory after being in his care.

Jockey Belinda Hodder on Princess Lottie at Cessnock on Tuesday. Picture: Newcastle Racecourse
A month after taking out his licence, the Glendon Brook trainer scored his first winner with Princess Lottie at his home track of Cessnock on Tuesday. Princess Lottie raced outside leader Levine before kicking clear to win by 2  1/2 lengths in the 900-metre maiden.
The three-year-old filly, formerly trained by John Bannister, is one of many horses Thomas has broken-in or pre-trained on his property.

A successful rodeo rider, Thomas, 34, switched focus six years ago and has broken in many for champion Newcastle trainer Paul Perry, including 2017 Champagne Stakes winner The Mission.
"I started to pre-train a fair few and they were leaving home and having a lot of success, so I thought I better get my licence and have a go at this," Thomas said.
His main business remains in education as he works with a racing team of 12.

"It's really good," he said of his win. "I broke her in and educated her, then a mate of mine trained her, but I always rode her work and helped out until I got my licence.
"She was second in the Wellington Boot, but she'd probably had enough by then although she tried her guts out. She had a good spell of three months and here we are. 

"I was confident but I thought 900 might be too short, but once they got to the corner, I knew she'd out tough the other one because she's probably looking for the 1100. That's when you'll see the best of her."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Bannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Lottie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Racecourse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champagne Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas, 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Hodder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glendon Brook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington Boot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
