<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406739270518269</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/01/universities-vow-overhaul-response-sexual-harassment-after-damning-report</url>
  <title>Universities vow to overhaul response to sexual harassment after damning report</title>
  <content>
Universities have vowed to overhaul how they respond to sexual assaults and harassment after a damning report exposed the shocking number of students being preyed upon by peers and staff.

8 HOURS AGO  UPDATED 1 MIN AGO

One in five students from Australia's 39 universities were sexually harassed either on campus, travelling to or from uni, or at uni-related events or workplaces in 2016, while 1.6 per cent were sexually assaulted in the past two years, a report by the Human Rights Commission found.

Most incidents weren't reported, according to the commission which urged universities to swiftly adopt its nine recommendations on how to better protect students.

The university rate of sexual assault is four times higher than the national figure revealed in a bureau of statistics survey which found that .4 per cent of Australians were sexually assaulted in 2015-16.

Universities Australia chair Margaret Gardener offered a public apology to students and announced a 10-point plan to prevent assault and harassment, better support students, and introduce specific training for staff.

"We are sorry that this happened to you," Prof Gardner said.

"Sexual assault is a crime. The person who sexually assaulted you had no right to do what they did. It is not your fault."

Australian students respond to sexual assault and harassment report

The report - based on a survey of 30,930 students after years of accusations about how universities covered up the extent of sexual assaults and harassment - found women were almost twice as likely to be harassed as men.

About half the students who responded to the survey knew the perpetrators, most of whom were male students.

One in five sexual assaults occurred at a uni or residential social event, while 15 per cent were on public transport and 10 per cent each on campus or a university residence.

However, most incidents went unreported as victims either didn't know how to make an official complaint to their university or didn't believe their experience was serious enough.

Alcohol, outdated attitudes towards women, easy access to bedrooms in residential colleges, and abuses of power by older students and staff were all highlighted in the report as contributing to the problem of assault and harassment.

The Human Rights Commission was provided with disturbing accounts from students, including how one woman had a classmate expose his genitals to her during a lecture, while another was raped by a senior student running an Orientation Week camp.

Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins said the rates of sex assault and harassment among students were unacceptable.

"Students have done their part, and universities now owe them swift action to address these issues. It cannot wait," she said.

National Union of Students president Sophie Johnston described the findings as heartbreaking.

Other student groups were critical of what they say is Universities Australia's lack of action against perpetrators of assault.

"The lack of any explicit reference to disciplinary measures or sanctions to hold perpetrators to account in UA's plan draws into question just how robust any future university policies and procedures will be - and serves to continue to undermine student confidence to report incidents," says Nina Funnell, End Rape on Campus Australia Ambassador.

Federal Education Minister Simon Birmingham said the government would work with universities to ensure they address the report's recommendations and improve student safety.

One in five students assaulted: AHRC

Several universities pledged to adopt all the recommendations, with many adopting a zero tolerance policy towards sexual harassment and assaults.

ANU vice-chancellor Brian Schmidt said he was shocked by the findings and hoped the report would be a "game changer" that shakes universities to the core.

"I will not stop until we have a campus that is seen as being one of the safest places in Australia and indeed the world," he said.

The findings

51 per cent of university students sexually harassed at least once in 2016.

One in four students was harassed in a university setting (on campus, while travelling to university, at a university-endorsed social event or in university employment).

One in three harassment incidents happened on university grounds or in classrooms.

6.9 per cent were sexually assaulted (about one in 15).

1.6 per cent of students were assaulted in a university setting (almost one in four of the total who were sexually assaulted).

One in five of these assaults happened at university or residence social events.

Women almost twice as likely as men to be harassed, and more than three times as likely to be assaulted.

Men overwhelmingly reported as the perpetrators.

51 per cent of those who reported assault or harassment knew the perpetrator - most likely to be a fellow student.

94 per cent of those harassed and 87 per cent of those assaulted at university did not make a formal complaint or report.

Six in 10 students said they didn't know how to formally report or complain about incidents.

Related reading 

National 24-hour support line for university students 1800 572 224, with access to Rape and Domestic Violence Services Australia counsellors (until November 30).

National domestic violence helpline: 1800 737 732 or 1800RESPECT. In an emergency call triple-zero.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's 39</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nina Funnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 1 MIN AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Union of Students</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campus Australia Ambassador</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Education Minister Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>End Rape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domestic Violence Services Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AHRC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orientation Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Gardener</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
