<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406734975550913</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/real-estate/rate-review-could-mean-big-changes/news-story/f3ca2814f97d8452abf68fbe4c5f4161</url>
  <title>Rate review could mean big changes - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Palmerston Council - "The Dickheads been Floored" sign at in Marlow Lagoon.

MARLOW LAGOON ratepayers could soon see their bills reduced, after Palmerston official manager Mark Blackburn ordered an independent review into council's current rating strategy.
Mr Blackburn said a number of people who provided feedback on council's municipal plan and annual budget were concerned about the way rates were charged across the municipality.
"They were concerned about the current rating strategy itself," he said.
"They have moved from a flat rate to a UCV (unimproved capital value) rate - there being a special rate for Marlow Lagoon.
"What we proposed to do is to have an independent review of the strategy around the rating fees - and that will be then fed back into the new council that comes in," he said.
Rates will remain as is for the 2017-18 budget.
Results from the review will be handed to the next council, who will consider recommendations when setting rates in the 2018-19 budget.
Marlow Lagoon resident Bernie Maloney said the previous flat rate system served the community fairly.
"Many long term Marlow residents are retired or nearing retirement and the UCV is an unnecessary financial burden," he said.
Mr Blackburn said the majority of Palmerston ratepayers would see minor changes to their rates this year.
"While the residential rates multiplier has increased by 3.01 per cent, the minimum rate of $1177 remains the same as last financial year," he said.
"Over 8570 households will therefore pay the same rates as in 2016-17."
One Bellamack mother objected to the three per cent rate increase.
"I object to the huge rates increase, as the economy in the Territory needs stimulus and this will put pressure on some residents in Palmerston unnecessarily," she said.
Council adopted the 2017-18 budget and municipal plan last week.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UCV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlow Lagoon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie Maloney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmerston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Blackburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Blackburn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmerston Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
