<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406816579930992</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/daly-cherryevans-backs-manly-sea-eagles-to-beat-odds-and-reach-nrl-finals-20170801-gxn1vd.html</url>
  <title>Daly Cherry-Evans backs Manly Sea Eagles to beat odds and reach NRL finals</title>
  <content>
"I'm not a betting man," Daly Cherry-Evans grins when asked if, at the start of the season, he would have accepted his Sea Eagles sitting in seventh spot on the ladder after 21 rounds. "But I would have been very tempted to cash in."
Manly have been the surprise packet of the season so far. However, the odds appear stacked against them after conceding 92 points in the past fortnight.

Up Next

Did McGuire intentionally stomp Mannah?

00:29

More Rugby League Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Cherry-Evans: Defence the issue for Manly

Daly Cherry-Evans insists the Sea Eagles can rediscover their groove.

They come up against the high-flying Roosters on Sunday, in a match that will reveal whether their past two losses are an aberration or the start of a disturbing trend.
The Silvertails are in a precarious position. A win against the tri-colours - a side they have already beaten in 2017 - and they are back in contention for a top-four berth; a loss and there is the very real possibility of slipping out of the top eight altogether.

"I believe we're still a good side," Cherry-Evans said. "While two weeks is a form slump, it all goes away if we win this weekend. Like everything in rugby league, winning silences all critics. We just need to go out and put in a good performance and really good opposition.
"How we're going to do that is train hard, address a few things we feel have been letting us down. From there you set yourself up to play well. We've still got a good side, so there's absolutely no reason we can't win this weekend."

Manly's goal-line defence, for much of the season the side's greatest strength, has been porous in recent outings.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It makes me extremely uncomfortable talking about it," Cherry-Evans said. "It's uncomfortable to talk about, 92 points is not something you want to be talking about when it comes to points being scored against you. It's not ideal, but I do believe it's easily fixed."
Manly endured a scare when Dylan Walker suffered a foot injury in last weekend's loss to Melbourne. The centre hobbled around the club's Narrabeen headquarters on Tuesday in a moon boot, but has declared himself fit to take on the Roosters.
"I got stood on ... in last Sunday's game and it was a bit sore to run on, so they had to make a call pretty quickly," Walker said.
"Just bone bruising, I got the scans done yesterday and it was just swelling and bruising. Pretty embarrassed coming off like that, but it will be all right."
Sea Eagles pivot Blake Green is aware the good work done at the start of the season will come undone unless the side emerges from its slump.
"We're going to have to get back to those performances we were putting in a month ago," Green said. "It's just basic things - holding the ball, defending well, kicking the ball really well. They are things we haven't done well the last couple of weeks and the ruck speed has been too fast, and then we've been on the back foot coming out of our own end."
The Sea Eagles have five matches to play and Cherry-Evans believes they can win all of them.
"That would leave us on about 36 points, which is pretty close to top four," he said.
History will show that a top-four finish is essential to go deep into September. But even if the Sea Eagles don't achieve that lofty goal, "DCE" believes his side can mount a run from the bottom of the eight.
"History does suggest you need to be in the top four to win the comp, but this side in particular has shown anything is possible," he said. "We're not even meant to be in finals contention. If we can give us an opportunity to be in the finals, that's exciting enough for me."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narrabeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silvertails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sea Eagles</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherry-Evans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daly Cherry-Evans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
