<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406773630257181</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4826426/uni-vow-to-fix-culture-depicted-in-hazing-video/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Uni vow to fix culture depicted in 'hazing' video</title>
  <content>
SOBERING FIGURES: University of Newcastle student Lucinda Iacono and Vice-Chancellor Caroline McMillen at the NeW Space campus on Tuesday, after the release of the Human Rights Commission's report. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

IT'S the footage of a passed-out young woman that's telling for Lucinda Iacono.
The scene is a University of Newcastle student residence party, in a video called "TEDS GEE UP 2015 Extended Cut", that briefly involves the woman and a young man.
"She's knocked out," he says over the music.
But he looks unmoved as she slumps to the floor and, as an afterthought, he takes the cup from her hand.
"Save your drink."

"Teds" is Edwards Hall, the oldest residence at the University of Newcastle and home to 383 students. "Gee up" videos are put on YouTube to generate buzz for upcoming parties and Ms Iacono, a student and former Women's Convener at the university, was shown this one by a Teds fourth-year student at a bar.

Spliced through the party footage of the pool, games rooms and dorms of Teds are male students' party comments like "I said, who do you reckon's gonna get their t--s out?".

At one point, a male student is shown rubbing his genitals in the face of another male who appears to be lying unconscious on his bed.
"Be a lion, don't be a liOFF," reads the caption.
"There's this sense of bragging about it, and I think it provides permission for more sinister things to happen," Ms Iacono said.
"It means 'that girl passing out is something normal that happens at our parties'. It's disgusting."
Third and fourth-year students, she said, come to be seen as leaders in the residences with the power and responsibility to promote parties to the colleges' fresh intakes of students.
"It's the same stuff we've seen time and time again in Sydney colleges, and people tend to think it doesn't happen in Newcastle," Ms Iacono said.
"It's probably the most obvious example of rape culture that Newcastle university has."
University of Newcastle Vice-Chancellor Caroline McMillen said the university's ResLife department had been made aware of the video, which was taken down on Tuesday afternoon.
"Colleges and residences can be hotspots for that sort of hazing behaviour, and we are making that behaviour a thing of the cultural past," Professor McMillen said.
"We now ensure that residential mentors undergo rigorous training. Whether you're in a Sydney college, a Melbourne college or a Newcastle college, [sexual misconduct] is never appropriate."
The university delivered its response on Tuesday to a Human Rights Commission survey of 31,000 Australian students across 39 universities which found that, while there were few cases of reported sexual assault at Newcastle, a higher-than-average percentage of local students reported being sexually harassed in 2016.

An above-average proportion of Newcastle students said they had been sexually harassed at university, including on transport to-and-from class, around campus walkways and gardens, and at social events including student residence parties and pub crawls.
For Newcastle students who were harassed, the most recent violation was also more likely perpetrated by a fellow student who was known to them, and lived in their place of residence.
But Newcastle students were also slightly more likely to seek help from their university, and to know how to access their university's support.
In response to the survey and other feedback, the university has consolidated its website to make it easier for victims to find help and support services.

It has developed two courses with Oxford University Press-based Epigeum, one for staff and student leaders who respond to disclosures of sexual violence, the other a mandatory test for students living on campus called "Consent Matters".

And in August it will review its Sexual Misconduct Working Group in line with the Human Rights Commission findings.

The university's efforts to engage with students over on-campus behaviour will emphasise the role of bystanders, and alcohol-soaked socialising will be discouraged.

"We really want to build that next generation culture, and not the previous generation culture," Professor McMillen said.
"We want to shift the dial on this culture as far as we can away from events that are based on alcohol."
The university's 21 per cent of male student respondents who said they had been sexually harassed is "higher than our community might expect", Professor McMillen said, but it is unclear whether the figure indicates a prevalence of hazing, other types of male-on-male harassment, or harassment by females.
From a low statistical base, Newcastle students responding to the Human Rights Commission survey said they had been subject to "repeated or inappropriate advances" by email, social media and online chat rooms at more than twice the national rate.
That doesn't include a University of Newcastle subgroup of students who reported, at three times the national rate, encountering "other unwelcome conduct of a sexual nature".
"It tends to be female students who have that experience," Professor McMillen said.
"Our approaches to education and prevention have to include the online space."
Nationally, the survey found women were four times more likely to have been sexually assaulted than men in a university residence, with post-graduate students more likely to have been harassed or assaulted by a university staff member. 
- Former university women's convener Lucinda Iacono, on a campus residence party "gee up" video.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ResLife</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Convener</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor McMillen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford University Press-based Epigeum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Iacono</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>liOFF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice-Chancellor Caroline McMillen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucinda Iacono</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NeW Space</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexual Misconduct Working Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TEDS GEE UP 2015 Extended Cut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
