<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406687730909812</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4827291/student-calls-on-uow-to-sort-out-lad-drink-culture/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Student calls on University of Wollongong to sort out 'lad drink culture'</title>
  <content>
ADDRESS LAD CULTURE: ​University of Wollongong student Fances Johns has encouraged UOW to tackle the drinking culture on campus. Picture: Adam McLean

University of Wollongong student Frances Johns is adamant the ''lad drinking culture'' on campus is a problem that needs urgent addressing.
The 21-year-old hoped UOW management would sort this out as a matter of urgency in light of the findings of the new Australian Human Rights Commission (AHRC) national report into sexual assault and sexual harassment at Australian universities.

''I think the culture is what they need to address from day one,'' Miss Johns said.
''We need to look at breaking down that lad drinking culture straight away. Education in what is and what isn't acceptable behaviour should be compulsory.

''I think as soon as alcohol is involved in different events on campus it kind of blurs the line of was he drunk or was it harassment.'' 

The media and international studies fourth-year student said online harassment was also a big concern for females on campus.

''Boys would create group chats and talk about different girls in those chats or like photo-shop stuff or like rate their attractiveness,'' Miss Johns said.

''It happens across the board on campus.

''Even like when they get the party bus back and get into the songs and the jeering.

''It is kind of like a lad boy culture. They probably wouldn't even realise that we take it as sexual harassment I guess.

''I think if a lot of people looked at the definition of sexual harassment they would be surprised to find out what falls in the parameters of that definition.

''I think there is a gap in education. I used to be a student leader on campus and we would have all this sexual assault training and first-responder kind of stuff which is really good but I think we probably should have covered it more in O-Week and address it quickly.

''We talk about sexual assault but we really don't discuss sexual harassment and what that means and how that can effect students on campus.''
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LAD CULTURE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O-Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frances Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fances Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AHRC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
