<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406902479278812</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/technology/sbs-program-dateline-explores-water-wars-in-california/news-story/264fb4f97ff3a2ba89930c8b69a758c5</url>
  <title>California in grip of never-ending dry spell</title>
  <content>
WATER is more precious than gold in one American state, and it could run out after suffering through five years of drought.
California is in the midst of a water war, with locals in thirsty cities battling big corporations to turn on the taps.
SBS explores the serious threat of water running out in California on Tuesday night's episode of Dateline. The program meets people in Owens Valley, a town in eastern California that has been in the grip of a water war with Los Angeles.
As the city started to populate in the 19th century, it started to outgrow its water supply, and started to divert some water from Owens Valley. Locals in Owens Valley tried to destroy the channel that allowed water to flow to Los Angeles in 1924, but they lost the battle.
Since the water has been streamed from Owens Valley, farmers have found it difficult to maintain its agriculture, especially since the drought hit five years ago.
Dateline reporter Dean Cornish speaks to locals who are struggling to survive as water dwindles.
Native American Kathy Bancroft tells the program her ancestors had been buried deep in the valley and decades of water mismanagement and the drought had uncovered the dead.
"The vegetation all died and the sand started blowing away and whole burials are becoming uncovered. We've got some that are thousands of years old," she told SBS.
Dateline reveals 100 years ago Owens Valley's underground river was diverted to LA, using a 300km aqueduct. It has helped LA thrive but those in Owens Valley are feeling the struggle.
Dateline also tells the story of Angelica, a mother of three. She saw her backyard completely dry up four years ago.
"It was one of those hot days and we just woke up one morning and there was completely, like, sand coming through the faucets, and really dark water, brownish water, muddy water," she said.
"It's easy to say 'let's move' but when you realise that you're stuck here with a property that in the future has no value because you can't be selling a property without a well."
Dateline reports water scarcity could be a problem across the world, with one expert suggesting two thirds of the world population will live in conditions of water scarcity in just eight years.
A UN water scarcity report in 2014 also claimed there would likely be armed conflict in our lifetime in relation to water scarcity.
The American Society of Civil Engineers claims the US needs to spend $255 million in the next five years to preserve its water infrastructure, but there are only plans to spend half that.
Dateline asks the question, if the world's sixth largest economy can't manage water, what chance do the rest of us have?
Watch the full Dateline report, California Water Wars, on Tuesday August 1 at 9.30pm on SBS.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angelica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Cornish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Kathy Bancroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dateline</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Society of Civil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California Water Wars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owens Valley</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
