<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406859529604845</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4825734/stockland-focuses-on-inclusivity-photos/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Stockland focuses on inclusivity | Photos</title>
  <content>
New facilities: An artist's impression of the five star parents' room that will soon open at the revamped Stockland Green Hills.

A quite room for children with sensory disorders or intellectual disabilities is among the new facilities to be unveiled at Stockland Green Hills in the coming months.
A new five star parents' room - where children can be changed, fed or given some time out from the hustle and bustle of the shopping centre - is also part of the $412 million revamp of retail precinct in Maitland's east.
The quiet room was designed as a calm, safe space in a low sensory environment for parents and children.
It's expected to open in November.
"We believe it is important to remove the barriers experienced by the four million Australians with a disability, so they can have the same access and opportunities that we do," Stockland development manager Daniel Brabant said. 

Stockland focuses on inclusivity | Photos

Jeff Wall from Multiplex and Tim Beattie from Stockland at the construction zone for the next stage of work. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

Jeff Wall from Multiplex and Tim Beattie from Stockland at the construction zone for the next stage of work. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

Jeff Wall from Multiplex and Tim Beattie from Stockland at the construction zone for the next stage of work. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

Andrew Biady from Blooms with Maitland Mayor Peter Blackmore.

Andrew Biady from Blooms, gives Maitland Mayor Peter Blackmore a blood test, and Peter Green, manager of Blooms.

Paterson MP Meryl Swanson with a Knights jumper, manager of Best and Less Karen Roe and Maitland Mayor Peter Blackmore.

Opening of stage one of the big new Stockland Green Hills shopping centre.

Opening of stage one of the big new Stockland Green Hills shopping centre.

Paterson MP Meryl Swanson, Jeff Wall from Multiplex, Tim Beattie from Stockland, member for Maitland Jenny Aitchison, and Maitland Mayor Peter Blackmore.

Jeff Wall from Multiplex, Tim Beattie from Stockland, member for Maitland Jenny Aitchison.

Jeff Wall from Multiplex, Tim Beattie from Stockland, member for Maitland Jenny Aitchison.

Stockland Green Hills centre manager Chris Travers and member for Paterson Meryl Swanson.

Stockland Green Hills centre manager Chris Travers, member for Paterson Meryl Swanson, Maitland Mayor Peter Blackmore, member for Maitland Jenny Aitchison.

Just Cuts manager Vicki Kirkland, Stockland Green Hills manager Chris Travers, Maitland Mayor Peter Blackmore, member for Paterson Meryl Swanson, member for Maitland Jenny Aitchison.

Just Cuts manager Vicki Kirkland, Stockland Green Hills manager Chris Travers, Maitland Mayor Peter Blackmore, member for Paterson Meryl Swanson, member for Maitland Jenny Aitchison.

exit
"We are proud to be delivering the quiet room facility as part of the Stockland Green Hills redevelopment, allowing people with sensory disorders a safe place while shopping - making it a much less stressful experience."
Quiet rooms and retreats featured prominently in research Stockland conducted in 2015 to find out what sort of facilities customers wanted.
A spokesperson for the organisation said Stockland opened two quiet rooms at its Shellharbour shopping centre last year, which "have proved very successful".
"Children with sensory and intellectual disabilities often find shopping centres very challenging with common issues surrounding anxiety, crowds and sensory overload," the spokesperson said.
Next month, a new state-of-the-art parents' room will open at Green Hills, including change tables, private feeding rooms, a microwave to warm bottles and a children's play area.
New disability amenities, including an adult change room, a changing table and assistance lifter will also open.
"We are proud to not only deliver first class retail, but also first class amenities for the people of Maitland," Mr Brabant said. 
The major shopping centre upgrades are expected to be complete in mid 2018. 

Related content:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brabant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Biady</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paterson Meryl Swanson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland Green Hills</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Less Karen Roe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Beattie</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paterson MP Meryl Swanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Mayor Peter Blackmore</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Travers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockland</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Brabant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Jenny Aitchison</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicki Kirkland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Wall</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
