<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406945428952617</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4827369/former-jet-scores-in-millwall-trial/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Brymora scores at Millwall</title>
  <content>
IN THE MIX: Newcastle product Kristian Brymora is targeting an under-23 deal in England. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

Former Newcastle Jets striker Kristian Brymora scored a goal and set up another for Championship club Millwall's under-23s in the latest stop on his English football adventure.

The 18-year-old, who packed his bags for Europe a month ago after turning down a scholarship to stay at the Jets, impressed in a 20-minute cameo against Isthmian League semi-pro side Greenwich Borough last week and will resume training with the Lions youth squad on Wednesday.

Brymora started his English journey by training for three days with a group of about 26 trialists at non-league Bromley before a trial with Premier League club Watford's under-23s.

The teenager's father, Rafael, said his son was on a steep but rewarding learning curve in a sometimes intimidating and highly competitive football environment. 
"I think his first week and a half was tough," Rafael said. "We got a few phone calls. But he didn't have that constant training. As soon as he went to Watford, boom, 'Hey, this is what I want.' He's been good ever since. But they do get homesick."

Brymora scores at Millwall

Brymora spent two weeks at Premier League club Watford trialling with the Hornets' under-23 side.

Brymora challenges Jets captain Nigel Boogaard at Newcastle training last year. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

exit
Watford, who are at the business end of their pre-season, gave him 45 minutes in an under-23s practice game against non-league Wealdstone and invited him back for a second week of training.

"He went there Monday to Thursday the second week. On the Thursday the coach brought him in and said, 'Listen, you've done really well with this, this, this. Thanks, but no thanks,'" Rafael said. 

Brymora moved on to Millwall last Thursday and played the last 20 minutes of the game against Greenwich, scoring with a shot across the keeper from 10 metres out. 
"They were happy. He's back there Wednesday and he'll find out where he goes from tomorrow," Rafael said. "They did say they are lacking in strikers at the moment, so who knows."

He said his son's assessment was that Wealdstone, who play in England's sixth-tier National League South, were "better than an NPL team" and Greenwich were "like a good NPL side".

Former Jets coach Scott Miller signed Brymora to his first professional contract in September, but the teenager played only seven minutes in the A-League last season.  
Rafael said his son, who has Polish citizenship and a European passport and is staying with his ie:sports agent in south-west London, was targeting an under-23 deal rather than a first-team contract.

"He's certainly going to become a better player. There's no two ways about it. Even if Millwall doesn't turn out, then there'll be the next one, because QPR have said they can have a look at him as well. Sheffield United they mentioned."
Brymora will pursue a contract in Poland if he cannot secure a deal in England.  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheffield United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Jets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watford</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Boogaard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hornets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenwich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rafael</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bromley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenwich Borough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isthmian League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brymora</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National League South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristian Brymora</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wealdstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millwall</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
