<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406988378626369</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/entertainment/music/makeupfree-adele-steps-out-looking-almost-unrecognisable/news-story/5d68f2942352f7d5b523749b06eb5f5e</url>
  <title>Adele steps out looking almost unrecognisable</title>
  <content>
SINGER Adele spent time with disadvantaged kids on Saturday in her efforts to give back following her global success.
Her visit to an education centre came amid speculation she may never tour again after  , .

She chatted with youngsters and posed for selfies at IntoUniversity in Kensington, West London.
Volunteer Padrinio Blaque got the star's autograph on his hat and shared a video of the moment.
He says: "Bombshell, Adele has just signed my hat."
Adele then replies: "You can't really see it."
Padrinio also tweeted a snap of him with the smiling singer.
He said: "Wow. I'm still trying to process the fact that I met Adele - the Adele - whilst volunteering for Carnival 2K17."
Sources said Adele has been enjoying doing good deeds now the pressure of her world tour is over.

A source said: "Adele has always been very warm-hearted and she cares enormously about making time for people when she can. She's a proud Londoner.
"She's passionate about giving something back, but likes to keep it all low-key."
Tottenham-born Adele  after the fire tragedy to meet and help those affected.
She also dropped in on a group of firefighters who tackled the blaze for a "cup of tea and a cuddle".
This story originally appeared on and is republished here with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tottenham-born Adele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Padrinio Blaque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adele</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Padrinio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IntoUniversity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carnival 2K17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Londoners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
