<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407121522615061</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/zak-jones-resigns-with-sydney-on-twoyear-deal-snubbing-hometown-return-to-victoria/news-story/eb3e22994542155b36feba73261644dd</url>
  <title>No return: Jones sticks with Swans</title>
  <content>
Sydney's hard-nosed street-fighter Zak Jones has knocked back heavy interest from Melbourne clubs to sign a new two-year contract with the Swans.
It's a short-term deal but one Sydney football boss Tom Harley is confident will in time develop into a career in red and white.
One of the most promising up-and-coming footballers in the AFL, Jones' decision to stay loyal to Sydney forms an important pillar for the Swans' future.
NO DANGER:
PODCAST:
Harley says the 22-year-old has learnt from the on-field ill-discipline issues that had resulted in him being pulled into line by senior players earlier in the season, and is supremely confident Jones is a future leader himself.
There was strong speculation linking Jones with a return to his hometown, and perhaps a union with his brother Nathan - the co-captain of the Melbourne Demons.
It's understood Jones is backing his football to do the talking by only committing to a two-year deal, but Harley is confident the ace midfielder sees his long-term future in Sydney.
"Two years is where it landed and we're really happy with that," Harley told The Daily Telegraph.
"We think Zak is developing really nicely on and off the field and we think that he's got a long career ahead of him with the Swans. If the first part of that is a two year commitment we're happy with that.
"It's a good day for the footy club. We're obviously very excited that Zak has accepted our future and wants to be a key part of that."
Jones is a bulldog who plays aggressively and always on the edge. However, after some run-ins with the match review panel this year, Harley is confident Jones has turned a corner and is learning how to control the all-or-nothing approach that makes him so valuable.
"I think so. I guess as a youngish player you're constantly learning the game. It constantly challenges you," said Harley.
"He's fallen foul of the MRP a couple of times this year and he understands there is a line and he's got to play physical, ... but there is a line ... we obviously don't want our players rubbed out and Zak is acutely aware of that.
"He's best placed to answer that specifically, I won't talk about specific conversations that might have been had inside the footy club but that's part of his natural development and maturation.
"We love the fact he is very competitive and he's absolutely committed to having a career. From a footy sense I think he brings that and we're starting to see that come through this year.
"What's been pleasing has been his development in an off-field sense. Our side is younger than it has been in previous years and he's a young leader of our group and he's got high personal standards.
"We're really encouraging him to drive the young group and be one of the next generation of players coming through. I think that's the next step for him to continue to develop on the field but we think he has some great capacity to develop his leadership off the field as well."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Harley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
