<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406988378626360</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/world/police-officers-act-of-kindness-for-broke-shoplifting-mum/news-story/b80b029d455ec2fe49ee66fb623ebfa0</url>
  <title>Officer bails out shoplifting mum</title>
  <content>
A YOUNG mum had spent her money on groceries, and with not enough left to by nappies for her son, tried to steal them.
Security officers caught her with the nappies worth about $18 as she tried to leave the supermarket, and called police.
But when Officer Bennett Johns arrived at the supermarket in Laurel, Maryland, instead of arresting her, he paid for the nappies himself.
His act of kindness has resulted in accolades for the police officer himself, and a flood of donations to help others in need.
News of Officer Johns' actions went viral after Laurel Police posted a picture of him buying the nappies on the organisation's Facebook page.
"Though we often joke that our field trainees are still in diapers, it turns out that rookie Officer Johns was not buying these for himself," the post accompanying the picture read.
"Officer Johns considered the situation and then made the decision to purchase the diapers out of his own pocket so that the young child would not suffer.
"It's worth noting that the female was still issued a criminal citation for the theft.
"Though it's but a snapshot of some of the work your officers are doing daily, we still wanted to take a moment to thank Officer Johns for not just fairly enforcing the law, but also showing empathy to an innocent child put in a difficult situation."
The woman has since been referred to an advocacy service which helps families struggling in the area to get more help.
While some people criticised Officer Johns for issuing a criminal citation for the theft, it's understood if it's store policy to press charges, he had no choice.
The citation means the woman will have to appear in court
Since the Facebook post on July 23, Laurel Police have fielded a flood of requests from people wanting to donate money, nappies and other household necessities to help the mother out.
Some also offered to reimburse Officer Johns.
Laurel Police said they can't release the mum's information for confidentiality reasons, and they can't accept donations for Officer Johns..
Instead they have directed all donations requests to a local advocacy service which offers services struggling locals with "short-term financial assistance to prevent evictions and utility stoppage; assistance with rent, vouchers for eyeglasses, hearing aids, clothing, and furniture. LARS also assists clients with submitting applications for SNAP (food stamps) and other federal benefit programs".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News of Officer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurel Police</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officer Bennett Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officer Johns</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
