<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406606126529604</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/western-bulldogs/having-lost-their-bite-western-bulldogs-find-what-they-were-looking-for-20170801-gxmy8z.html</url>
  <title>Having lost their bite, Western Bulldogs find what they were looking for</title>
  <content>
While Gillon McLachlan once said the Western Bulldogs played "sexy" football", their surge to a premiership last year was built on hard graft. Goals did not come easily, forcing the Dogs to will their way to a breakthrough flag with  their fine work in the contest.
All manner of questions were asked about the Dogs just weeks back, with fears their hopes of repeating would be dashed even before September arrived. One question raised was what did the Dogs stand for?Photo: AAP
"We've been questioned by the outside world about what our identity is. That grates on you," coach Luke Beveridge said after a 59-point loss to Adelaide in round 16.
"It's time to make sure that quarters and halves like that just don't happen. What happened in the second half was unacceptable."
The Dogs had conceded 10 straight goals in that second half at the Adelaide Oval.
The following week was to prove a turning point, for the Dogs have since won three straight and rediscovered what they stood for last year, that being a strong contested-ball side.

In terms of contested possessions, they have vaulted from 10th (+1) from the end of a harrowing round 16 to third (+15) in the ensuing weeks. That's on a par with their efforts last year, when they averaged 16.5 more contested possessions than their opponents - the second-best differential recorded, according to Champion Data. Mitch Wallis has been important in this regard, lifting his average from 12.6 to 14.3 a game in recent weeks.
From 13th in clearances (-2.1) after round 16, they have jumped to fifth (+4.7). That's more like their premiership year when they were second in this key area (+5.7). Their ability to win more ball at the "source" has helped them to score more from clearances, leaping from 15th (-5.8) through the opening 16 rounds to first (+22) in the league.
Heightened pressure has also led to a significant leap in scoring from opposition turnovers, from 10th to third, helping to generate an overall scoring surge from 16th through 16 rounds (80.6 points) to second (106.3) since round 17.
"As soon as we get those forward-half turnovers, we score regularly," midfielder Luke Dahlhaus said.
Conversely, greater midfield pressure, along with a sounder structure, has led to a dip in the average number of points the Dogs have conceded.
"In those three games, I think we have been defensively on, whereas that poor patch we had in the middle of the year, we lacked that 'Bulldogs defence'. I think that has come back really highly in the last three weeks," Dahlhaus said.
Playmaker Jason Johannisen said the Dogs had "simplified" their game plan in recent weeks, having been "frustrated with how we were playing".
Marcus Bontempelli provided similar remarks after the high-scoring win over Essendon on Sunday, declaring he and his teammates had been able to maintain pressure on opponents and outnumber them for longer over the past month. Bontempelli had been central to that against the Bombers, having a team-high 15 contested possessions among his 23 disposals and two goals.
"We just have to continue to build and give ourselves every chance to lock ourselves in there [top eight]," he said.
That the Dogs and Johannisen appear to have found a way for him to exert major influence and escape the physical pressure that came with being targeted for two months cannot be underestimated. He spent time on the wing, up forward and in his customary spot across half-back against the Bombers, booting four goals among 18 disposals.
Wins over Carlton, Gold Coast and the Bombers have left the Dogs in ninth spot, behind Sydney, Melbourne and West Coast only on percentage. Victory over bottom-placed Brisbane on Saturday at the Gabba could well have them in the lower regions of the top eight - and we know what they did from seventh spot last season.
The "killer" Dogs, as they were dubbed by Jonathan Brown on Fox Footy, will hope to have fully rediscovered their mongrel by the time they leave the Gabba. For Greater Western Sydney, Port Adelaide and Hawthorn then await.
They have the fifth-worst record of any side against top-eight opponents, having won only two of nine matches (the Power have won two of eight). That is one statistic the Dogs will need to correct if they are to challenge for back-to-back flags.
BULLDOGS REGAIN THEIR CONTESTED-BALL BITE
Form ladder since round 17
                                     Rds 17-19      Rank    Rds 1-16   Rank
Disposals:                         +38            3rd             +7.7      8th
Contested Poss:              +15.3          3rd               +1      10th
Clearances:                      +4.7            5th              -2.1      13th
Inside 50s:                        +11.7          3rd              +1.1     10th
% Goals Times Ins 50:     +5.4            3rd             -3.4       17th
Points from Turnovers:   +14.7          3rd             -0.6       10th
Points from Clearances:  +22            1st              -4.8       15th
Points For:                        106.3         2nd             80.6      16th
Points Against:                  71.7           6th              87.7        7th
* Source: Champion Data
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poss:              +15.3          3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bontempelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillon McLachlan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnovers:   +14.7          3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champion Data</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Dahlhaus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Wallis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BULLDOGS REGAIN THEIR CONTESTED-BALL BITE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dahlhaus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Times Ins 50:     +5.4            3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Against:                  71.7           6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus Bontempelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clearances:  +22            1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
