<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406567471823097</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/giants-see-deep-talent-pool-at-this-years-draft</url>
  <title>Giants see deep talent pool at this year's draft</title>
  <content>
The unsigned Devon Smith (r) helps first-year player Tim Taranto celebrate a goal

GREATER Western Sydney doesn't hold a first-round pick at this year's NAB AFL Draft, but that hasn't stopped Giants recruiting manager Adrian Caruso being full of praise for this year's crop of prospects.

The Giants were stripped of 1000 draft points as part of the Lachie Whitfield saga last year, which has essentially seen their first-round selection (which would have been No.16 under the current ladder) pushed to the end of the draft.

Their two second-round picks are tied to other clubs - Collingwood and St Kilda - and Caruso believes there should be plenty of options available for clubs in comparison to the 2016 pool.

"I can only really compare it to last year because that was my first year full-time in recruiting, and I think it's a much better draft than last year in terms of the depth," Caruso told AFL.com.au's Road to the Draft podcast.

"If I look at the guys who are probably going to get picked this year in the top-30, I like a lot more of them than what I did last year."

The Giants were active players at the top end of last year's draft, moving up in the trade period from pick No.7 to No.2, where they selected Victorian midfielder Tim Taranto.

They then matched Carlton's bid for Will Setterfield at pick No.5, before taking fellow academy selections Harry Perryman and Isaac Cumming with top-20 picks.

Caruso said the very best players may not be as complete as last year's top group, but there were was a better balance to the draft. 

"With Tim, Harry and Will, we brought in three players who we rated in our top 10 or 12 [last year], and I had a feeling it dropped off significantly after that," Caruso said.

"This year the first three-to-five picks might not be at the level of what we rated Andy (McGrath) and Tim at last year, but I think the overall depth in terms of the first couple of rounds is better."

The Giants are waiting for star midfielder Josh Kelly to make a decision on his future, with Kelly weighing up a contract offer from the club against a return to Victoria, where several clubs are circling with lucrative deals.

Caruso reiterated the Giants' stance that "we want to keep Josh", but said the uncertainty meant the club needed to keep on top of the best draftees out there in case early picks come their way during the trade period.

"We need to do our work on all the top-end players because we just don't know what's going to happen in trade period. We could end up with early picks and we might not, so we need to do the work on all the guys in the top end," Caruso said.

"Our job is to be across the pool, be across everyone, and then hopefully whatever happens in the trade period we're prepared for."
Jacob Hopper and Devon Smith also remain unsigned for next year, with Caruso confirming the club has offered the pair new deals.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Perryman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB AFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Whitfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devon Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Taranto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caruso</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Setterfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Hopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac Cumming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Caruso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
