<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407117227647556</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/athletics/athletics-world-championships-2017-coach-craig-hilliard-backs-the-next-generation-to-step-up-20170801-gxn0n5.html</url>
  <title>Australia's next-gen athletes prepare for next step up</title>
  <content>
Tonbridge: Young pole vaulter Kurtis Marschall and javelin thrower Kelsey-Lee Roberts have been earmarked as the rising stars who could jump into medal contention at this year's world athletics championships.
Head coach Craig Hilliard said they were in a group of young athletes capable of taking the step up to the podium.

Up Next

Plays of the Week

01:59

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

LA to host 2028 Summer Games

Los Angeles has agreed to host the 2028 Summer Olympics, paving the way for Paris to host the 2024 Games.

Hilliard is reluctant to predict a likely medal haul from the biggest team Australia has ever sent to a world championships, but said outside of the obvious big names who had all won Olympics or world championships medals - Sally Pearson, Fabrice Lapierre, Jared Tallent, Dane Bird Smith and Dani Stevens (nee Samuel) - there was a strong tier of athletes emerging.
"I never predict medals, it's an exercise in futility [because] on any given day we can win between nought and five. In Rio we could have won five, we ended up with two, but we missed three by very small margins. I would be happy if we got two medals in these games," Hilliard said.Photo: Melissa Adams
"It's a big team, 62, certainly the largest team we have had going away but I think that is a plus. It shows some of the depth we have got moving on from Rio.
"We had 40 debutants in Rio, 17 debutants here and of those 40 in Rio we have 20 of them here so we have 37 basically who have had one experience of a major championships or none.

"This is our next crop realistically in terms of the next four-year Olympic cycle. In terms of expectation we have our core group of medal hopes.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Athletes performing well in Europe, I want to see them make top eight. Kurtis Marschall has been competing well in Europe. He is a bright talent for the future; whether it can progress in this world championships - it's an event where you can, it's a technical event and [the field looks open] - I would be happy with him getting through to top eight this year and spring boarding from there.Photo: Daniel Pockett
"Kelsey-Lee Roberts is another who has stepped up to another level now and these are the athletes who missed top eight last year and that is the next bridge for them and from there you start thinking I can medal from here. You rarely get a leapfrog."
Ella Nelson, who starred in Rio in the 200 metres, has had a disrupted period since then.
"She has had a few issues this year, she hasn't recaptured what she had last year but hopefully she can come out and get close to what she did in Rio," Hilliard said.
"For whatever reason it hasn't worked, her preparation hasn't worked this year and it is what it is. It's sad and it's hard. It's hard for athletes when you have such a jump and a spike and you think it will go on but you have seen it before you sometimes get to here and plateau or drop down a fraction."
He said middle-distance runner Pat Tiernan in particular had had "a sensational last 12 months" after Rio while champion race walker Tallent had had a disrupted training preparation.
"Jared is always a medal chance ... I don't think he is quite in Rio shape but he is Jared Tallent.
"[World silver medallist long jumper] Lapierre is always hit and miss and when he is on he is scary and when he is off he is off. But he is in good shape," Hilliard said.
The 10-day world championships start in London on Friday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Summer Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Hilliard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonbridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tallent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Tallent</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Summer Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lapierre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dani Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Tiernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Bird Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ella Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Pockett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilliard</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fabrice Lapierre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelsey-Lee Roberts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
