<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406945428952610</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/councillor-jonathan-sri-labels-highgate-hill-bus-stop-merger-class-warfare/news-story/94cc054da5e35711f058128b2eb9789b</url>
  <title>Bus stop stirs up class warfare</title>
  <content>
A SUBURBAN Brisbane bus stop has ignited a class warfare debate.
Brisbane City Council is planning to consolidate two Highgate Hill bus stops on Dornoch Tce into one on the same street as part of a bus stop improvement program.
However, Greens Councillor Jonathan Sri told a council meeting today he believed the move was being made because wealthy locals objected to having poor people sitting outside their homes.
He said older people with reduced mobility would find it difficult to walk further to a bus stop.
"I would again suggest to you that the decision to relocate or amalgamate the bus stops at this time is motivated largely by prejudice and by the fact that certain wealthy residents in the vicinity of the existing bus stop object to the presence of poor people using that bus stop," Cr Sri said.
Deputy Mayor Adrian Schrinner accused the Gabba Ward councillor of using a bus stop to ignite a class warfare. He objected to "the absolute ridiculous and outrageous claims about the motives behind this decision."

Jonathan Sri, the first Greens Brisbane City Councillor, used poetry in his maiden speech at City Hall.

First Greens Brisbane City Councillor uses poetry in maiden speech
However, Cr Sri claimed to be misrepresented.
"I would suggest they only call it a class war when the poor fight back," Cr Sri said. "In this case, I'm not starting a class war over a bus stop. This was started by wealthy residents who didn't want poor residents sitting outside their homes."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Sri</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dornoch Tce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Mayor Adrian Schrinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Sri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Councillor Jonathan Sri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUBURBAN Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highgate Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Brisbane City Councillor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
