<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406730680583593</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/alexandra-henderson-named-19yo-victim-of-bull-crushing-esperance/8764714</url>
  <title>Alexandra Henderson named as teenager crushed to death by bull in Esperance</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A 19-year-old woman crushed to death by a bull in WA's south has been described by her family as a "beautiful daughter" and "compassionate person" who was also a skilled horsewoman.
Alexandra Henderson died while trying to herd the large bull in a paddock on a farm at Dalyup, 35 kilometres north-west of Esperance.
Ms Henderson, a Dalyup local, had been working alone when the bull pushed her into a gate, crushing her head on Monday afternoon.
In a statement released by WA Police, her family said they were "devastated" by the loss of their daughter.
"We are consoled at this time by the fact that she was in a happy place at this time in her life," they said.
"Alexandra was only young but she had worked with animals and farm livestock in particular her whole life, including cattle.
"She was a competent horsewoman, breaking and training our horses. She was also a compassionate person who cared deeply about her world and the living things she shared it with.
"We are buoyed at this time by the fact that we have spent so much time with her, and that we live in a community which has supported us with an outpouring of love and support."
Teen trapped between bull and gate

Esperance Police officer in charge Richard Moore said Ms Henderson had been pushed into a gate by the animal.
He said workers at the farm found her lying unconscious about five minutes after she was injured and immediately began performing CPR.
"Somehow, she's become trapped between the bull and the gate ... unfortunately her head was crushed and she's sustained some serious injuries," Senior Sergeant Moore said.
She was rushed to hospital but died from her injuries a short time later.
"The medical staff there did their best to try and revive her, but unfortunately they weren't able to do so and she passed away around 1:30pm," he said.
Ms Henderson's family also thanked those who tried to save her.
"We are also incredibly appreciative of those who tried to keep our lovely child with us, those attending the scene at the farm, the ambulance crews and the team at the Esperance District hospital who did all within their power to prevent her from leaving us too soon," they said.

Senior Sergeant Moore said WorkSafe inspectors were expected to begin investigating the accident scene later today.
He described the accident as a particularly sad case.
"I've had people die as a result of falling off horses," he said.
"But to be trapped by a bull against a metal gate is not only tragic for the victim and the family, but the ambulance officers having to deal with it."
He said it was difficult to draw many further conclusions while the police investigation was ongoing, but farm work remained relatively safe.
Bulls unpredictable: Farmsafe

Farmsafe WA spokeswoman Maree Gooch said it was a tragic incident for the Dalyup and Esperance communities.
"At this stage, all we can offer is support to the family and the community," she said.
"Esperance has been through enough tragedies already.
"I would think the community would rally together ... I would encourage people to seek support if they do need it."
A former cattle farmer from Bremer Bay, Ms Gooch said fatalities were rare, but people who worked with the large and often temperamental animals needed to be wary of the risks.

"They're quite unpredictable at times, so we do have to be very vigilant and very careful," Ms Gooch said.
"At the snap of a finger, they can turn and you don't see it coming."
She said three people had died on WA farms this year - a rate she described as "much lower" than other states.
"But that's still three families that don't have their family member," Ms Gooch said.
A report will be prepared for the coroner.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Henderson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gooch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmsafe WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Henderson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maree Gooch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farmsafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WorkSafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalyup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bremer Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
