<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407125817582413</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/more-surgery-to-end-eagle-scott-lycetts-season</url>
  <title>More surgery to end Eagle Scott Lycett's season</title>
  <content>
Scott Lycett's season is over after he required more surgery on his troublesome shoulder

WEST Coast has lost winged big man Scott Lycett for the rest of the season, but fellow ruckman Nathan Vardy is expected to be fit for Sunday's crucial clash against St Kilda. 

Meanwhile, Lewis Jetta (calf) is set to miss another game, and uncertainty surrounds Matt Priddis' potential return for the must-win trip to Etihad Stadium.

Lycett's horror run with injury will see him sent for a second bout of surgery on the shoulder he dislocated in a WAFL practice match in March.
The 24-year-old, who underwent a PCL reconstruction at the end of last year, only made it back to the AFL in round 16 for one game before shoulder pain resurfaced.

"We've decided that we just can't get him to the level where we can get a consistent lot of training and pain-free outcomes," football manager Craig Vozzo told westcoasteagles.com.au.

"It got to the point where we've decided to take our medicine ... have it operated on again and get it done so he doesn't miss any of his pre-season.

"Unfortunately, that means he won't be able to play again this season." 

Lycett's injury-ravaged 12 months has compounded the season-long absence of star ruckman Nic Naitanui, who was put through his paces at training on Tuesday and is still aiming to return from a knee reconstruction this year.

With the Eagles' two first-choice big men sidelined, former Cat Vardy has battled manfully alongside veteran Drew Petrie for most of the campaign.
Vardy missed his first game for the year last week against the Brisbane Lions due to a glute strain, but he only needs to train Thursday to be available to take on the Saints.

Jetta is aiming to be back against Carlton in round 21 after a calf strain forced him out against the Lions, while retiring champion Priddis is no certainty after a quad issue.

"He will be touch-and-go. We'll see how he goes with that quaddie, we'll have to see how he pulls up this week," Eagles coach Adam Simpson told Channel Seven.

Simpson refused to acknowledge speculation Priddis was pushed to hang up the boots, or that he decided to call time after being dropped for the Lions clash.

"I just think it's almost disrespectful to talk about that about Pridda," Simpson said.

"Let's just celebrate the fact he's had a wonderful career. He made a really brave decision last week.

"Let him play out the year and give him some grace."

The Eagles expect Luke Shuey to be fine to face St Kilda after spraining his ankle last round.

Young defender Josh Rotham (hamstring) and Tom Lamb (knee) are aiming to play for East Perth next weekend.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cat Vardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Vozzo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Naitanui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Rotham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Shuey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Jetta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Lycett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Vardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pridda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagle Scott Lycett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lycett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
