<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406988378626312</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/horticulture-industry-sets-ambitious-export-targets-to-drive-growth-20170801-gxmy8d.html</url>
  <title>Horticulture industry sets ambitious export targets to drive growth</title>
  <content>
The Australian horticulture industry has set bold new export targets that would lift export earnings by at least hundreds of millions of dollars a year if they are reached.
The targets include massive jumps in the exports of vegetables, cherries and almonds, and a significant new focus on the export of fresh strawberries.Photo: Graham Tidy
The industry has also unveiled a new brand to help market Australia's sought-after fresh produce overseas, known as "Taste Australia", which will feature in trade shows, export campaigns and in overseas retail outlets stocking Australian produce.
Hort Innovation chairman Selwyn Snell said there was significant potential to increase Australian horticulture exports, pointing to "untapped opportunities" and Australia's reputation for growing high-quality food.Photo:  Supplied
"Australia is known for delivering high-end produce that has undergone the most rigorous food safety inspections along all stages of the supply chain," he said.
"We want to build upon that. The first way we are doing this is through Taste Australia, which tells the unique story of Australian horticulture products."

Launching the trade push in Sydney on Tuesday Assistant Agriculture Minister Anne Ruston said the horticulture industry was embarking on the biggest trade drive in its history.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Our horticulture industry today made a bold statement about its intent to seize the opportunities global food demand presents," she said.Photo: Yann Avril
"Global food demand alone will require a 75 per cent increase in world food production by 2050, compared with 2007 levels. In China, food consumption is projected to more than double between 2009 and 2050. Much of this demand will be for the high-value, high-quality produce Australia is known for," Senator Ruston said.
Some of the targets in the new horticulture trade drive include:

Increase the value of vegetable exports by 40 per cent to $315 million by 2020.

Export 12,000 tonnes of cherries by 2020-21, a jump of 340 per cent over 2015 levels.

Increase almond exports from 64,000 tonnes in 2016 to 110,000 tonnes in 2022.

Increase strawberry exports so that the share of total strawberry production exported grows from 4 per cent, to at least 8 per cent, by 2021.

Export at least 10 per cent of Australia's avocado production by 2021, up from about 2 per cent today.

Senator Ruston told Fairfax Media that the new targets sent a message to all Australian horticulture producers "that there's a huge opportunity for export. Up until now some of our horticultural industries have embraced export, you've only got to look at industries like the citrus industry and the table grape industry etc.
"But a lot of our other horticultural industries really haven't had an eye to export.  By providing targets, as ambitious as they are,  makes everybody focus on the opportunity that's there."
Senator Ruston also welcomed the new "Taste Australia" brand, which she said promoted Australia's reputation for growing high-quality produce in a clean environment.
Michael Rogers, general manager, trade, at Horticulture Innovation Australia, said the new export targets were "industry driven" and developed in consultation with industry. "[They] reflect both the opportunity overseas, but also the enthusiasm here in Australia to export," he said.
Mr Rogers said there was potential to increase horticulture exports to existing markets and develop new markets.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taste Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Tidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hort Innovation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday Assistant Agriculture Minister Anne Ruston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Ruston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwyn Snell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rogers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Rogers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horticulture Innovation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yann Avril</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
