<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406734975550918</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/anu-students-protest-sexual-assault-report-outside-chancellery-20170801-gxn4cw.html</url>
  <title>'I don't have the words': students respond to sexual assault survey</title>
  <content>
Australian National University students gathered outside the campus Chancellery on Tuesday with a megaphone and a message: enough is enough.
Protesters taped their mouths shut, sexual assault survivors shared their stories and dozens more people joined both groups to demand immediate change in how the institution responds to sexual violence.Photo: Rohan Thomson
ANU student and National Union of Students welfare officer Jill Molloy told the crowd Tuesday's report and response was well overdue.
"The impact of these crimes can cause alcohol, drug abuse, anxiety, and I've seen many slip through the cracks and have to drop out," she said.Photo: Rohan Thomson
"The most concerning part is that people didn't even think they were legitimate ... in fact, 40 per cent of those who were sexually assaulted [nationally] didn't report it because they didn't think it was serious.
"Another 40 per cent didn't even think they needed help, and more concerningly, 63 per cent didn't know where to report."

A survivor and ANU student attending the rally, who asked not to be named, said she felt a mix of emotions on Tuesday: relief, apprehension, and overwhelming sadness.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The report from the Human Rights Commission is massive for anyone who's ever thought they weren't listened to, and the vice-chancellor's presence this morning especially is affirmation that at least at this stage it's being considered very seriously," she said.Photo: Rohan Thomson
"I don't have the words to explain to you how massive this is. I didn't realise this morning that this would be one of the biggest days of my life in a very long time."
Former ANU queer officer and ANU Student Association general secretary Kat Reed acknowledged that lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and intersex students were overrepresented in the sector-wide data.
She said there were many reasons queer people did not report their assault.
"The release of the report has said there are queer students who are being affected, especially bisexual women and asexual people," Ms Reed said.
"Disclosure is one thing, but we need to stop people from raping."
The ANU Student Association and ANU Postgraduate and Research Students' Association made five demands to the university, with ANU vice-chancellor Brian Schmidt accepting the majority of the bodies' recommendations.
The demands included that the university establish a centralised sexual assault and harassment policy, create a centralised office to respond to reports of sexual violence in all forms and resource and fund specialised staff to properly support student survivors and responders.
The university would explore introducing a restorative justice process for people whose cases were mismanaged, Professor Schmidt said.
If you or someone you know is impacted by sexual assault or family violence, call the Canberra Rape Crisis Centre on 02 6247 2525. Nationally, call 1800RESPECT on 1800 737 732. In an emergency contact 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Reed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Union of Students</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Research Students' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kat Reed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU Postgraduate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU Students' Association</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Molloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Rape Crisis Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
