<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406988378626325</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/palazczuk-government-kills-of-asf-casino-on-gold-coast-20170801-gxmzb7</url>
  <title>Palaszczuk kills ASF's Gold Coast casino</title>
  <content>
The Palaszczuk Labor government has canned Chinese consortium ASF Group's proposed $3 billion casino and integrated resort on the Gold Coast, but has kept open the possibility of a new cruise ship terminal at The Spit.
The decision, announced by Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk on Tuesday, is a major boost for The Star Group which owns the Gold Coast's only casino, Jupiters, as well as Brisbane's Treasury casino. The company is also building the $3 billion Queens' Wharf integrated resort and casino in Brisbane's CBD.
ASF, as the preferred developer of the site, had planned to build a five-tower development on The Spit, including a casino, hotels and apartments, which would tower over existing developments including Palazzo Versace and Seaworld.
But after years of vocal campaigning by locals to kill the project, Ms Palaszczuk said ASF's bid would not proceed, saying there should not be any developments over three storeys on The Spit. She said The Spit was unique to the Gold Coast and needed to be preserved through a master plan.

"This is a unique site - the equivalent to what Central Park is to New York. It should be preserved for generations," she said.

"What the Spit really needs now is a master plan to revitalise it and increase its benefit to the Gold Coast as a community asset."
ASF Group went into a trading halt on the Australian Securities Exchange after the announcement and has not yet commented on the government decision.
State Development Minister Anthony Lynham said ASF was "disappointed" by the decision but said the preferred developer process made it clear the government had the right to terminate the contract at any stage.
Deputy Premier and Planning Minister Jackie Trad said the master plan would lock in low-density, three-storey developments on the site.

"A master plan will help get the balance right between protecting environmental and community values and allowing appropriate commercial development."
Ms Palaszczuk said the decision to knock back ASF plans for The Spit did not mean the end of another casino and integrated resort for the Gold Coast, but after years of planning it seems unlikely there will be any developments soon.
The Palaszczuk government has left the door open for the development of a cruise ship terminal on the ocean side of The Spit.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Minister Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jupiter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queens' Wharf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Development Minister Anthony Lynham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palazzo Versace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASF's Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASF Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SeaWorld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASF</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
