<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406945428952649</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/policy/tax/company-tax-rate-confusion-creates-chaos-20170801-gxmyun</url>
  <title>Company tax rate confusion creates chaos </title>
  <content>
Tax time has been plunged into chaos by uncertainty over of 27.5 per cent but the nation's biggest accounting bodies are split over what should be done.
Chartered Accountants Australia and New Zealand is demanding the Turnbull government end the uncertainty with a legislative fix when Parliament returns next week.
"Because Australia's tax system is based on self-assessment, it is up to taxpayers and their advisers to lodge tax returns based on what they think they should be paying," Chartered Accountants' tax leader Michael Croker said.
"But without clarity we will see differing tax calculations for taxpayers in similar circumstances, impacting their ."

Under the government's Enterprise Tax Plan, small businesses with turnover of up to $10 million have moved on to a 27.5 per cent tax rate for the 2016-17 income year. The lower rate will progressively apply to bigger and bigger companies.

The confusion stems from the fact that the Australian Tax Office's interpretation of the law appears to designate companies holding passive investments, including so-called bucket companies linked to family trusts, as eligible for the lower rate.
But that's at odds with the government's stated policy intent, which is to afford tax relief to "active" businesses, the so-called mum and dad businesses fuelling jobs and growth. 
While CPA Australia agrees there is a big problem, it does not want the government to intervene.
"The situation is unclear and some tax practitioners are now in the position of being unable to complete 2017 company returns and associated individual returns," CPA Australia head of policy Paul Drum said.

"However, we disagree with a call for immediate legislation to be introduced."
Mr Drum said everybody was waiting for further ATO guidance. Some companies would not want to be classified as a small businesses entity and therefore qualify for the lower rate.
"Some may seek to stay on the 30 per cent rate," he said. "For example, some members have complained about franking credit wastage where a private company receives a fully franked dividend from a publicly listed company and can't pass on the full franking amount to its shareholders. They are likely to want to stay on the 30 per cent rate.
"On the other hand, there might be a passive investment company that owns property that would want to be classified as a small business entity and qualify for the 27.5 per cent rate even though in the strictest sense they are arguably not carrying on a business."

Along with which companies should pay lower rates, the loss of franking credits is occupying the minds of many.
Under the Enterprise Tax Plan, tax is payable on a company's current year turnover whereas franking is based on the past year's turnover. That means tax is paid at 30 per cent but credits can only be franked at 27.5 per cent, leaving a 2.5 percentage point gap.
Tax experts say Treasury has made it clear that this was an intended outcome. That is, it will help pay for the tax cuts, the Coalition's end goal being a universal 25 per cent rate. 
Revenue Minister Kelly O'Dwyer has been eager to quash the idea that wealthy families might be beneficiaries of the government's small business tax cuts, which were "not meant to apply to passive investment companies".

Mr Croker said: "Based on the revenue minister's comments, the law as enacted does not fully reflect the intention that the small company tax cut apply only to "active" companies. So let's get this sorted when Parliament returns next week."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chartered Accountants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Croker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chartered Accountants Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Croker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Tax Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Drum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Drum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enterprise Tax Plan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
