<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407125817582473</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/tough-swan-locked-in-with-new-deal</url>
  <title>Tough Swan locked in with new deal</title>
  <content>
Zak Jones has re-signed with the Swans for a further two years

SYDNEY speedster Zak Jones has turned his back on significant Victorian interest and signed a two-year contract extension with the Swans.

Jones, who has been one of the Swans' most consistent performers in 2017, has extended his deal to the end of 2019.

The attacking defender had been linked in a move to Melbourne to play alongside brother and Demons co-captain Nathan, attracting interest from other clubs in his home state.

But the 22-year-old announced a new deal with the Swans on Tuesday night, continuing a run of important re-signings for the Swans this season.

"Zak's game has continued to develop each year he's been at the Swans," football manager Tom Harley said in a statement. 

"This year in particular his game has added another dimension to our team.

"Zak's commitment is a good endorsement of the environment we try hard to foster here at the Swans and we all look forward to Zak's continued growth as a player and future leader."

The Swans have been able to secure young stars Isaac Heeney and Callum Mills to new contracts this season with Will Hayward, Oliver Florent, Jordan Dawson, Lewis Melican and Darcy Cameron also recommitting to Sydney in 2017.  

The club hopes to confirm a new deal for tall forward Sam Reid, who is out of contract and has also attracted interest from Victorian clubs as the most valuable tall in this year's free agency pool.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Harley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Dawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Melican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac Heeney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darcy Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Florent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Hayward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
