<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407160177321643</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/opinion/columnists/samesex-marriage-may-be-coming-soon-20170731-gxmmmb</url>
  <title>Same-sex marriage may be coming soon</title>
  <content>
Australia looks increasingly likely to legalise same-sex marriage very soon via a vote in Parliament featuring renegade Liberals.
Rather than the plebiscite promised by the Coalition but unable to be delivered, probably decisively.
The determination of a handful of  to bring on the debate as soon as possible and then to cross the floor if necessary means it no longer seems possible for the government to indefinitely delay the problem.
Instead, on the numbers this week, it looks inevitable that a bill will be introduced into the House of Representatives as early as next week when Parliament returns. It would pass the House and the Senate - assuming around five and possibly more Liberal backbenchers follow through with their willingness to force the issue. The trigger would be by supporting a suspension of standing orders if necessary. A bill could then edge through with the support of Labor and the Greens.

Luis Ascui

In normal circumstances, such internal rebellion within the Liberals would be ruthlessly put down. But little is normal about politics these days and .

So the next few days will involve frantic manoeuvring and negotiations by senior ministers over how to best handle this ticking political time bomb.
For Malcolm Turnbull, there are no safe options.
If he allows a free vote, he risks a spill motion by irate conservatives blaming him for reneging on a Coalition promise as well as being generally disgruntled with his leadership.
If he does not allow a free vote and some MPs anyway, the government hands ownership of the issue to Labor and a few renegade Liberals to claim victory at last. That's hardly the look of a leader in control of his party - or even of his own personal views given Turnbull's long-held support for same-sex marriage. After all, allowing a free vote on matters of conscience is supposed to be one of the differences with the Labor Party's "authoritarian" rules binding their MPs - as Turnbull pointedly reminded everyone this week.

Richard Wainwright

Conservative warning

The volatility of the Liberal party room means nothing is predictable about the immediate political impact of all this. Some conservatives are publicly warning any move to allow a free vote would be a broken promise, but even many of them would be reluctant to move against yet another sitting prime minister, no matter their frustrations in general. A spill motion against the Prime Minister, even if lost, would be catastrophic for Turnbull's already weak authority. Others are more focused on ensuring Turnbull doesn't accept a clean energy target and see that as the defining test of his leadership. The Nationals would be deeply unhappy with any change that resulted in the legalisation of same-sex marriage and have warned it could lead to a split in the Coalition.
The risks for the stability of the government are obvious, including to Bill Shorten who will want to maximise the sense of crisis.
But the real drama is likely to play out in the party room as early as next Tuesday. This naturally becomes another proxy fight representing the increasing Abbott-Turnbull friction. No doubt Tony Abbott will have something sharp to say to his colleagues. In contrast, MPs  such as Warren Entsch believe continued patience with the official refusal to change position makes the party look ever more out of touch with modern Australia.

The Prime Minister and other ministers had tried to make a virtue out of the commitment to a plebiscite inspired by Abbott as Prime Minister and then backed by Turnbull as part of his appeal to conservative MPs. That has led to the government's criticism that Labor doesn't trust the Australian people enough to allow them to decide. The idea of a "people's vote" has also belatedly garnered some public support.
Dead end

But Turnbull can argue he attempted to follow party policy, but was thwarted by Labor, making that commitment to a plebiscite impossible to fulfil in practice. Even one of the most senior conservative ministers, Peter Dutton, now a key backer of the Prime Minister, suggested last month the issue had to be resolved.
, but that proposal will go nowhere except into a dead end. It certainly won't dissuade the core group of moderates that something's gotta give right now and will do so as long as they push the government hard enough.

AAP

Dean Smith, a Liberal Senator from Western Australia, put the case in commentary published on Monday in different newspapers, including The Australian Financial Review. He is finalising his own bill. Dissident Liberals would rather propose their  version than simply follow Labor.
According to Smith's analysis, the most compelling argument for dealing with the matter now is its importance to younger voters - 35 per cent of the enrolled population.
"The government should not feel obligated to commit political suicide by handing its opponents a massive political cudgel by allowing the question of marriage equality to remain unresolved over the next two years," he wrote.
"Australian voters are perplexed about why so much time and energy is being expended on an issue where the community attitude is now crystal clear ..."

Other Liberal MPs are now making public comments in support of dealing with same-sex marriage well ahead of the election, if only to clear the air to allow the government to prosecute its agenda on other matters of great importance to voters.
But the Liberal politics and how they play out in leadership terms remain much murkier.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Wainwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott-Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Ascui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
