<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407289026342889</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/world-travel/europe/hilarious-footage-captures-the-mad-morning-scramble-to-get-the-best-sunbeds/news-story/6ae457fbf33691ee14ed42f9907a7b93</url>
  <title>Hilarious footage captures the mad morning scramble to get the best sun-beds</title>
  <content>
British tourists race for sunbeds
0:26

THESE are the amazing scenes every morning at a holiday hotel in Gran Canaria packed with British tourists - who show rest and relaxation is the last thing on their minds when it comes to bagging the best sunbed round the pool.Tourists queue from 7.30am every day at the four-star Servatur Waikiki in the popular resort of Playa del Ingles in the south of the island.

August 1st 2017
10 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World/

Hilarious footage captures the mad morning scramble to get the best sun-beds. Picture: Solarpix.com/australscope

The Sun

Share

THESE are the amazing scenes every morning at a holiday hotel in Gran Canaria packed with British tourists.
The extraordinary video lays bare the lengths holiday-makers are going to in order to bag the best sun-beds on one of Spain's Canary Islands.
The hilarious video, taken by a fellow guest this morning, shows that when the pool opens at 8am guests sprint like Usain Bolt to get as near as they can to the water.
In many cases they lay their towels down and head into breakfast before returning at their leisure.
The drama unfolds every day at the four-star Servatur Waikiki Gran Canaria in the popular resort of Playa del Ingles in the south of the island.
The hotel has almost 500 rooms and several hundred loungers can be seen in the video.
Today hotel insiders revealed the worst offenders were in fact the British and Irish.
They say Germans, who have traditionally been accused of nabbing beds, are far more likely to have breakfast first and look for a lounger afterwards.

Tourists race for sun-beds every morning at a holiday hotel in Gran Canaria. Picture: Solarpix.com/australscopeSource:australscope
The problem of sun-bed bagging has got so bad hotel staff have now been instructed to remove towels from loungers left empty for two or three hours.

One well-placed source at the hotel, where an estimated seven out of 10 guests are currently Brits, said the worst were definitely the British followed by the Irish and then some local Canarians who were on holiday and appear to have picked up some bad habits.
The source said: "I know the British have traditionally regarded the Germans as the worst offenders but our experience is that they have breakfast first and look for a sun-bed after.
"The pool opens at 8am and there's always a queue of people waiting at this time of the year.
"It's a bit hard to fathom really because there's enough sun-beds to go round.
"We get guests laying their towels out in the morning and sometimes disappearing again till the afternoon.
"The problem has been getting so bad recently that hotel staff are now under instructions to remove towels on sun-beds which have been unattended for two or three hours."
Another insider added: "Guests need to try to understand that rather than bagging the best sun-beds, all they're going to achieve if they carry on racing around the way they do in the mornings is an accident."
Footage of the mad morning dash at the Servatur Waikiki appears to show holiday-makers ignoring the sun-beds furthest from the pool and making a beeline for those nearest the water.
One man in a white T-shirt and blue shorts with a white stripe down them can be seen throwing four towels on four different beds next to each other in the second row of sun-beds back from the pool.
Another man in a green top goes even better and bags four in the front row.
Hotel staff admitted today an adults chill-out area was very sought-after as well as the sun-beds nearest the water.

Tourists queue from 7.30am every day at the four-star resort. Picture: Solarpix.com/australscopeSource:australscope
Research a couple of years ago showed that contrary to the stereotype, British holiday-makers were now more likely to hog the sun-beds on holiday.
Online travel agents sunshine.co.uk questioned 2,150 UK adults for a survey which revealed 71 per cent of Britons were guilty of unfairly reserving sun-beds on their last holiday abroad - and 52 per cent had actually been in trouble for it.
A whopping 98 per cent admitted to feeling irritated when other holiday-makers reserved sun loungers that they would otherwise like to lie or sit on.
Eighty-seven per cent said they had witnessed just that from fellow travellers.
Asked what nationality they were, Britons came out top (21 per cent) followed by Germans (19 per cent) and Dutch (14 per cent). The French and the Russians came in fourth and fifth.
It comes after German daily tabloid Bild outed the English as the worst sun-bed baggers in a report from Costa Brava resort Lloret de Mar, showing towels including a St George's flag towel and an England World Cup flag towel in prime position at 7.36am at one hotel.
One British tourist insisted to the paper despite the killer evidence: "It was the French."
Servatur Waikiki Gran Canaria, right next to Playa del Ingles' famous beach, boasts on its website that it's a "hotel perfect for families looking for a holiday experience full of options".
It adds: "Our hotel is a mix of sun, fun and numerous leisure activities."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain's Canary Islands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lloret</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Servatur Waikiki Gran Canaria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Servatur Waikiki</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch (14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>australscopeSource</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canarians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germans (19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gran Canaria</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bild</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solarpix</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Playa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa Brava</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
