<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407031328299933</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/flu-outbreaks-in-nsw-aged-care-facilities/8764420</url>
  <title>Flu outbreaks on rise in NSW aged care facilities; state sees worst seven months of influenza</title>
  <content>
There has been a spike in flu outbreaks in NSW nursing homes and health authorities are warning visitors who are sick to steer clear.
More than 50 aged care facilities have had outbreaks in the past week alone, taking the total number of outbreaks this year in such facilities to around 140.
Vicky Sheppeard from NSW Health said it could affect many nursing home residents because they are so frail.
"The attack rate in aged care homes can be up to 25 per cent higher," Dr Sheppeard said.
"And very often up to four people then require transfer to hospital and we do not infrequently see deaths associated with outbreaks in aged care facilities.
"Many of the residents have multiple underlying conditions and a flu infection on top of that can be fatal."
Dr Sheppeard said high levels of both influenza A and B strains were circulating in the community and older people were more susceptible to severe infection from the influenza A strain.
"With this particular influenza A strain that's circulating we know that older people don't have a good level of immunity to it," she said.
"Each year more than 800 people die in New South Wales from complications associated with influenza and the elderly are particularly vulnerable.
"Family and friends of the elderly are risking the life of a loved one if they visit them with flu-like symptoms."
Government caught unprepared for flu season: Secord

The State Opposition said there had been more than 18,000 confirmed influenza cases in NSW so far this year, making it the worst seven months on record.
Dr Sheppeard confirmed there were record numbers of influenza cases but said much of it was due to increased use of a more sensitive test which meant influenza was diagnosed more rapidly.

More about colds and flu ...

"That's a good thing because it then means antiviral treatment can be started," she said.
"The number of notifications is not an indication of the severity of the condition.
"But we are near the peak of the flu season and are seeing very high numbers of presentations to emergency departments, and many outbreaks in aged care facilities so this is where the focus of our activity is."
Opposition health spokesman Walt Secord said the Government had been caught unprepared and the outbreaks were putting pressure on the entire health and hospital system, especially overstretched emergency departments.
But Dr Sheppeard said every year the emergency departments and ambulance service prepared for flu season and were managing the current influx of patients.
She reminded people it is not necessary to seek hospital attention unless you are experiencing breathing problems or have an underlying health condition that puts you at risk of severe flu.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walt Secord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicky Sheppeard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Sheppeard</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secord</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
