<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407246076669272</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/business/other-industries/nurofen-makers-offer-to-settle-after-consumers-misled-over-pain-relief/news-story/01515ab031609b71380e062ffbf44496</url>
  <title>Nurofen makers offer to settle after consumers 'misled' over pain relief</title>
  <content>
Don't bother. These products were found to have "misled" consumers after they contained the same ingredients as the basic version of Nurofen.

Share

THE makers of pain-relief drug Nurofen have apologised to consumers who may have been "misled" by their Specific Pain Range packaging after a class action against the product.
The company said in a statement it had made an offer to settle the suit subject to court approval.
"Nurofen has offered to settle the Specific Pain Range class action in Australia to ensure that consumers who may have been misled are appropriately and swiftly compensated," a spokeswoman said.
"It was never our intention to mislead, but we recognise that we could have done more to assist our consumers in navigating the Nurofen Specific Pain Range in Australia."
"We have taken the Nurofen Specific Pain Range cases seriously, and have taken steps to ensure that future marketing campaigns are sensitive to the risk of misinterpretation and confusion, while providing consumers with an informed choice."

Nurofen has offered to settle with customers but the deal will be subject to court approval.Source:News Limited
The settlement offer follows a  that called for a refund and damages for customers that bought Nurofen Migraine Pain, Tension Headache, Back Pain and Period Pain pills between 2011 and December last year.
Bannister Law said Reckitt Benckiser Australia, who make and distribute the products, had misled and deceived customers by claiming products were specially formulated to treat separate ailments such as back pain, period pain and headaches.
"However, each product contained the same active ingredient and could not specifically treat one pain as opposed to another," the claim said.
The law firm wants customers who bought the products to receive a full refund, saying "we believe that the consumer would not have purchased the product if they had known that it was not more effective on targeting pain than any of the other Nurofen Specific Pain products."

At the time the class action was launched, Bannister Law's founder and Principal Charles Bannister said the advertising "exploited" customers who were "duped" into paying more for basic products.
"None of these costly tablets actually targeted these specific pain symptoms. Australians have a right to feel duped by the deceptive marketing and selling of these expensive pain tablets which were sold at a premium price," he said.
Nurofen Australia has already accepted a Federal Court judgment that sided with the ACCC and found that the company "engaged in conduct that is misleading or deceptive" when marketing the pills.
The company said it took immediate action to provide additional information on the packs.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Period Pain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen Specific Pain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Principal Charles Bannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reckitt Benckiser Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Back Pain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen Specific Pain Range</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Specific Pain Range</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen Migraine Pain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bannister Law</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
