<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406816579930996</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/more-than-20-per-cent-of-students-at-australias-top-universities-sexually-harassed-by-staff-20170801-gxmwyz.html</url>
  <title>'We should all be shocked' leader of university with worst results comforts students</title>
  <content>
Australian universities have been hammered by the results of the world's largest survey into sexual assault on campus after the Human Rights Commission labelled its findings "unacceptable". 
In a warning to the sector, the Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins and the Education Minister Simon Birmingham said there would be repercussions if the multibillion-dollar university industry failed to act. 

Up Next

New security measures puts police at breaking point

01:48

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Universities brace for sexual assault report

A landmark survey of 31,000 students by the Australian Human Rights Commission is likely to raise further allegations of sexual assault on campus.

The Human Rights Commission data reveals that more than 20 per cent of students at some of the country's top universities including the University of Technology, Sydney; Deakin; and Flinders who responded to the survey of 31,000 students have reported being sexually harassed by staff, while the Australian National University, Charles Sturt University and the University of New England have the highest rates of sexual assault on campus in the country.
Thousands of students (6.9 per cent) reported being sexually assaulted on or off campus in the past two years, according to the survey of 31,000 students, which showed more than a quarter of students at the University of Sydney and 21 per cent at UTS and Western Sydney University reported being harassed.Photo: Rohan Thomson
In Victoria, one in five students were sexually targeted at Monash, Melbourne University, RMIT, and Victoria University. 
"To put this in context, in a lecture theatre containing 100 students, at least one, and possibly two, students have been sexually assaulted in the past two years," Ms Jenkins said.

On Tuesday, Ms Jenkins released graphic details of some of the more than 1800 sexual assault and harassment submissions received by the commission: 

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

A male student approaching a female student in the library to expose his erect penis while asking her to perform oral sex on him. 

A student having sex with her tutor because she didn't want to fail her course. 

A man forcing a crying student onto her knees outside a university party to perform oral sex on him. 

A college resident waking as she was raped by a fellow resident who told her that if she told anyone he would kill her.

Students being forced into college "stag nights", where male residents sang songs referring to female residents as "pigs to bend over backwards and f--- when they get home". 
Photo: Louie Douvis

Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
She labelled the figures "unacceptable", and warned universities they would be punished if they were unable to change their campus culture.
The ANU vice-chancellor Brian Schmidt was seen comforting sexual assault survivors in Canberra on Tuesday afternoon after his university recorded the worst overall results, with 35 per cent of students being sexually harassed and 3.5 per cent assaulted. Photo: Paul Jeffers
"On behalf of the university I want to start by saying sorry," he said. "The stories told by survivors are shocking. The results are shocking. We should all be shocked." 
Ms Jenkins published nine recommendations, including sweeping education programs, targeted support for first responders and widespread audits of counselling services. 
She called on vice-chancellors to take direct responsibility for implementing changes within 18 months.
"I think that the expectation is that we'll see action, and if we don't see action, that further things will be considered," she said. 
Senator Birmingham reminded universities of their "legal obligations to provide a safe environment", after sexual assault lawyers warned of looming legal action by survivors on Tuesday. 
Senator Birmingham and university leaders will be keen to protect against the damage to the $20 billion international student sector, Australia's third largest export. 
At the University of Sydney more than 200 international students [2 per cent] reported being sexually assaulted in the past two years while 1.9 per cent reported being assaulted at Western Sydney University and 1.1 per cent at Melbourne University. 
Ms Jenkins took particular aim at the university residential colleges, where up to 34 per cent of University of New England students reported being sexually harassed, while 11 per cent suffered similar experiences at ANU and 2 per cent at Melbourne. 
She called for a sector-wide independent investigation into residential colleges. 
"We found that college settings are a particular area of concern, particularly for women who were four times as likely as men to have been sexually assaulted in this setting," she said. 
- with Conal Hanna and Soren Frederiksen 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Birmingham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Sturt University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Technology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jenkins</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of New</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conal Hanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney University</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MONASH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soren Frederiksen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
