<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406391378160644</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/lifestyle/fashion/kendall-jenner-raises-eyebrows-in-an-australian-design-20170801-gxn138.html</url>
  <title>Kendall Jenner raises eyebrows in blouse by Australian brand Bec & Bridge</title>
  <content>
Kendall Jenner is no stranger to freeing the nipple, so it came as no great surprise that the model and half-sister of Kim Kardashian-West stepped out this week in a heatwave-ridden New York with gal pal Bella Hadid in her trademark look - sans bra.
However, this time Jenner, 21, caused a stir, not for her eye-catching get-up, but because the sheer red blouse she wore by Australian fashion label Bec & Bridge is not available to buy by mere mortals for another two months.
"We have had an influx of enquiries over the past 24 hours since Kendall wore it ... but The French Kiss shirt isn't actually available until October 1 online and in stores. It's part of our Resort '18 collection," a spokeswoman for Bec & Bridge told Fairfax Media on Tuesday.

"Can I at least pre-order it?" you might ask.
"Customers will just have to wait it out until October 1," the spokeswoman added.

Becky Cooper and Bridget Yorston, the duo behind the Sydney-based label also worn by the likes of Kardashian-West, Beyonce and Miranda Kerr, admired how Jenner rocked their blouse paired with a pair of high-waisted denim jeans and white boots.
"She pulls it off with ease," the spokeswoman said.
But for those not feeling so bold, she added: "We also offer a number of little bralettes and bandeau tops that can be styled under our sheer tops."
For the posterchild of the "Free The Nipple" campaign, it's just like any other day.
"I really don't see what the big deal is with going braless!" Jenner wrote on her blog in 2016.
"I think it's cool and I really just don't care! It's sexy, it's comfortable and I'm cool with my breasts. That's it."
Jenner stepping out in Bec & Bridge last year in Paris.
Jenner has been a fan of the label for some time. When she stepped out in their blush, satin, belted midi-dress in Paris last year, it directly translated into sales and Cooper and Yorstan decided to named it after her.
"We call it the Kendall dress now, because when she wore it, we had to re-cut that dress like three times. I think we just had no idea of the effect [a celebrity can have],"  earlier this year. 
The spokeswoman added: "It definitely helps you get noticed when such amazing It girls, such as Kendall, are wearing our pieces in their day-to-day wardrobe."
Kim Kardashian West wearing Bec & Bridge in April.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Kardashian West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resort 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendall</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French Kiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenner</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miranda Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorstan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Becky Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridget Yorston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendall Jenner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bella Hadid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenner, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kardashian-West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
