<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407293321310253</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/i-half-expected-to-see-my-eye-sitting-in-my-hand-riewoldt-reveals-moment-behind-accident/news-story/ff81384677959291171259f07eef5bd2</url>
  <title>'I half expected to see my eye sitting in my hand'</title>
  <content>
Riewoldt missed Saturday night's clash against the Gold Coast Suns because of the freak accident and remains in doubt for this weekend's blockbuster against Hawthorn.
"It was like the last drill on Thursday night training and I went to pick up the ball from the ground when someone came from the other direction, missed the ball and poked me straight in the eye," Riewoldt said on Fox Footy's AFL 360.
"My first initial thought was that my eye had popped out.
"So I put my hand over my eye, looked down and had a pool of blood in my palm and half expected to see my eye sitting in my hand."
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 19 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
Riewoldt couldn't see out of his right eye for six hours, with what he described as "a cloudy film of blood" blocking his vision.
The pressure in his eye was three times what it was supposed to be, with the white part of his eye torn and his cornea grazed.
The 28-year-old received stitches on the white and top of his eyeball.
And while he said he was initially unfazed by the mishap, a phone call to his fiancee Carly quickly changed his demeanour.
"It was a bit surreal," Riewoldt said.
"Once I spoke to Carly about it and let her know what had happened ... she had a bit of panic in her voice which rocketed me a bit."
Riewoldt said he would see an eye specialist on Thursday to hopefully get the green light to face Hawthorn.
Until then, however, he said he was on "light duties".
"I can't run around for five days post healing in case the clot starts to bleed again," Riewoldt said.
"Gravity pulls the blood back down to my eye and gets rid of itself naturally.
"When I go for a run it's like a snow dome: if you shake it up and all of the snow flakes come up into the dome, that's sort of like my eye."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 19 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
