<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407293321310232</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/violeta-tupuola-expects-to-play-for-wallaroos-at-womens-rugby-world-cup-ireland-20170801-gxn0e4.html</url>
  <title>Tupuola expects to see action for Wallaroos at World Cup</title>
  <content>
​She may be one of the youngest on the squad but newly minted Wallaroo Violeta Tupuola says she expects to get game time at the women's World Cup in Ireland.
The 19-year-old Canberra prop and the rest of the Wallaroos, including ACT teammates Millie Boyle and Sharni Williams, flew to Ireland on Tuesday to start their quest for the game's highest honour.Photo: Jay Cronan
The Wallaroos will play against hosts Ireland, France and Japan in the pool stages, and Tupuola says she is not there to make up the numbers.
"I'm not training to not play, so I do expect to get game time," Tupuola said.

"If I don't then I respect the coach's decision, they do have to put the best players on the field but I'm still going to push to get as much time as I can.
"Being younger it's easy to just follow the older girls and be in their shadow but I actually think it's better to raise my voice at training and maybe even show them a few things that I have learnt."

Wallaroos players will now have a degree of financial support at Rugby World Cup thanks to $1000 payments that have been donated by Buildcorp's co-founder Josephine Sukkar. 
The national women's XVs program is kept afloat by the Australian Rugby Union and is understood to cost the game's governing body around $500,000 per year. 
The majority of Wallaroos players, aside from a handful of Australian sevens representatives, will not be paid by the ARU to represent their country at the World Cup, which starts on August 9. 
The ARU pays for accommodation, flights, food and all other expenses associated with an overseas trip but does not give match payments or any salary because of the amateur status of women's XVs.  
Most female players have had to take annual leave for the tournament and some will not be paid for close to a month. 
However, Sukkar, Principal and co-founder at Buildcorp who is also the president of Australian Women's Rugby, has offered her support by providing grants of $1000 to each player in the squad. 
Wallaroos captain Shannon Parry said money was not a factor for players and assured that passion would come through when the team took to the field. 
"They [teammates] have to take leave without pay and not many people would do that in the economy that we're in," Parry said. "So for these girls this jersey means a lot and for them to give up money to be able to represent their country.
While confident of making an impact, the St Clare's College product was surprised she won selection in the final Wallaroos squad.
"It's still a bit overwhelming," Tupuola admitted.
"Last year still being a schoolgirl, playing for Australia at a World Cup was a completely unrealistic goal.
"Last year was my first with the Brumbies women's team and to be honest I thought that was the highest achievement for myself, but then I was selected in the Australian squad and it's just grown from there.
"It's such a big thing for me to get selected and I see it as a reward for all the sacrifices I've made."
Those sacrifices have seen Tupuola play various rugby formats while at school, take on both schoolgirls and seniors programs with the Brumbies and she switched clubs to improve her game.
"I started playing club rugby for Vikings in year 11 and played there for two years," she said.
"They're a very good club, very skilful so I actually decided I wanted to change it up and play against them to help my development so this year I moved to Royals."
Tupuola said the Wallaroos were targeting a top-four finish, despite struggling against the best teams in the world at warm-up tournaments.
"But to reach that goal we have smaller goals so our first is just to beat Ireland in our first game. Even winning that game, especially on their home turf would mean so much to us," Tupuola said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Parry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josephine Sukkar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rugby Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Cronan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallaroo Violeta Tupuola</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millie Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tupuola</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Clare's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharni Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Women's Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vikings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buildcorp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XVS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brumbies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sukkar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
