<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407164472289019</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/malcolm-turnbull-losing-control-of-party-over-samesex-marriage-20170801-gxmy8y</url>
  <title>Turnbull losing control of party over same-sex marriage</title>
  <content>
Malcolm Turnbull is losing control of his party over same-sex marriage with a group of rebels determined to force the issue to a vote, despite threats to their preselections and even the Prime Minister's leadership.
With Parliament to resume on Tuesday, Mr Turnbull and his senior ministers are looking for ways to defuse the issue which is worsening the factional tensions already tearing at the government and overshadowing entirely its domestic agenda.
Options include trying again to have the Senate pass legislation for a plebiscite, persist with a postal plebiscite, or have the party room debate and adopt a new policy - a free vote - but take it to an election first.
The latter option has the broadest support given neither side could argue with the majority view of their colleagues and nor would it break the election promise not to have a free vote this term.

Richard Wainwright

But none has satisfied the moderate rebels who have the numbers to cross the floor in the House of Representatives .

Such an outcome would risk an implosion the Liberal Party, threaten the coalition with the Nationals and put further strain on Mr Turnbull's leadership.
"If they cross the floor, it will be precarious to say the least," said a senior conservative. "There's no easy solution on the table."
But leading conservatives dismissed speculation Mr Turnbull would be automatically challenged should the rebels - nicknamed "the suicide bombers" by colleagues - carry out their threat.
"If he had his fingerprints on it or didn't try hard enough to stop it, maybe," said one.

David Rowe

Abbott loyalist Eric Abetz said it would be an "exceptionally grave matter" for Mr Turnbull.
As he fought for control, Mr Turnbull said while Liberal MPs were free to , they would be in breach of government policy which is that there be no vote in Parliament this term without a plebiscite first.
"We went to the last election promising that the Australian people would have their direct say on this issue. The only reason that plebiscite or vote has not been held, the only reason every Australian has not been given the opportunity to vote on this is because of Bill Shorten's opposition," he said.
"We made a commitment to give every Australian a say on this issue and that is our policy. It has not changed. Our policy is very, very clear."

ROB GRIFFITH

The rebels argue the party has discharged its obligation toward a plebiscite and the issue needs to be resolved to get it off the table and end the distraction.
The chief rebels are Liberal Senator Dean Smith and lower house MPs Trent Zimmerman, Trevor Evans, Warren Entsch and Tim Wilson. All face threats to their preselection if they carry out their threat.
"They're hard-core up there," said a source of the Queensland Liberal-National Party which could end the preselections of Mr Entsch and Mr Evans.
"We can't allow this to happen, Trevor won't lose preselection but if there's a free-for-all, that will happen," he said.

Alex Ellinghausen

LNP boss Gary Spence issued a statement condemning Mr Evans and Mr Entsch.
Just over a month ago, Mr Turnbull proposed debating a policy change now but taking it to the next election first. This is consistent with the position of his predecessor, Tony Abbott.
"The next election is two years away and we will examine our policy in the lead-up to the next election, but we made a commitment at the last election that we would have a plebiscite," he said.
There will be a party room showdown on Tuesday when Parliament re-convenes after a six-week winter recess.

Just over a month ago, Mr Turnbull proposed debating a policy change now but taking it to the next election first.
"The next election is two years away and we will examine our policy in the lead up to the next election, but we made a commitment at the last election that we would have a plebiscite," he said.
But the senior conservative said that, too, would be tough.
"If we go for a free vote, the membership will go nuts."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Liberal-National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROB GRIFFITH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Wainwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Evans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
