<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407160177321632</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/brownlow-medal/hopefully-thats-a-bit-of-karma-that-comes-his-way-corey-mckernans-best-wishes-for-patrick-dangerfield-20170801-gxn9we.html</url>
  <title>'Hopefully that's a bit of karma that comes his way': Corey McKernan's best wishes for Patrick Dangerfield</title>
  <content>
North Melbourne great Corey McKernan says not winning the 1996 Brownlow Medal was one of the best things that ever happened to him and hopes Patrick Dangerfield's 2017 season plays out like his 1996 campaign did.
McKernan finished on the same amount of votes as joint Brownlow winners James Hird and Michael Voss  but was  ineligible because of a one-match suspension  for kneeing Geelong ruckman John Barnes.Photo: Sebastian Costanzo
While the powerful ruckman/forward admitted it would have been nice to win the Brownlow, he insisted it didn't bother him one bit and that winning the premiership with North Melbourne  that year was his main focus.
Dangerfield,  the Brownlow favourite until his suspension on Monday, cannot win it now after accepting his one-week ban for his tackle on Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer who left the field concussed and did not return. Photo: Viki Yemettas
McKernan said it was unfortunate that Dangerfield didn't get a chance to defend himself under the current tribunal system, with the risk of an extra week's suspension dangling over his head while his team strives for a top-two spot. He now hopes the Geelong superstar can taste premiership success for the first time, as he did 21 years ago.
"I sincerely hope for 'Danger' that he gets the same result as what I was lucky enough to do in 1996," McKernan told Fairfax Media.

"You go, 'OK you lost it. Who cares?' And you just move on and hopefully you get a premiership medallion that he highly craves and hopefully that's a bit of karma that comes his way.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I was in a fortunate position that year  that we had much bigger things to look forward to and I think 'Danger' would be thinking the same thing.
"You're never going to knock those things back, but seriously? We're all here to win one of those great little silver cups that we all get.
"It was like a blip on the radar for us because when you consider all the stuff that was happening in 1996, we were going through a potential merger [with Fitzroy] and there was all these other things.
"It [Dangerfield's suspension] has actually revived good memories because I didn't really care about it that much because all I was focusing on was winning the premiership.
"It never really affected me, I didn't let it affect me ...That whole week, the way I handled grand final week is one of the best things that I've ever done.
If we're going to have this asterisk club, Chris Grant and I are probably going to have a meeting because 'Danger' has already won one so we don't know whether he can join us yet

"It bothers everyone else more than me."
McKernan joked that he was probably fortunate not to win the Brownlow  because Hird and Voss went on to endure terrible injury runs in the few years that followed. The two-time premiership Kangaroo won the AFLPA MVP in 1996 and he holds that achievement in high regard.
"From a player's perspective it's probably the award you want to win because it's voted for by your peers," he said.
While McKernan felt sympathy for Dangerfield, he quipped that the star Cat might not be allowed in the "asterisk club" just yet with him and Chris Grant, who was ineligible to win the 1997 Brownlow despite having the most votes.
"If we're going to have this asterisk club, Chris Grant and I are probably going to have a meeting because 'Danger' has already won one so we don't know whether he can join us yet," he said. 
McKernan felt for modern-day players as he believes more is expected of them on the field by the powers that be than in any other era.
"At certain times of the game you want them to slow down and I've likened it to The Matrix - you're meant to slow it down and see all the different angles and then you're meant to move forward," he said. "It makes it incredibly hard for the players with how quick the game is."
McKernan said it would be an "awkward situation" if Dangerfield polled the most votes, but the awkwardness would be lessened if Richmond's Dustin Martin won it.
"Out of those two you were going to have a very, very deserving Brownlow winner. I don't think anyone disputes that," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Voss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKernan</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey McKernan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Voss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matrix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Costanzo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFLPA MVP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond's Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Barnes.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Grant</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Viki Yemettas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield's 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
