<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407160177321620</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-shelters-forced-to-turn-away-homeless-due-to-rising-demand-for-beds-20170801-gxn4nh.html</url>
  <title>Canberra shelters forced to turn away homeless due to rising demand for beds</title>
  <content>
Welfare organisations have warned they may be forced to turn more homeless people away from Canberra shelters due to an unprecedented surge in demand for accommodation.
At the start of July the demand for overnight shelter had jumped by 600 per cent, according to Safe Shelter Coordinator Richard Griffiths, who said that number is continuing to rise.
The only other service of this kind, Samaritan House, is also full every night, and often volunteers are forced to turn people away.
Safe Shelter provides accommodation for Canberra's homeless over the winter months and have this increased their operation from three nights a week to five.
"You will always find people in hidey holes sleeping rough." Mr Griffiths said.
To combat the shortage Safe Shelter stores numerous swags and jackets on site. They regularly give away these essentials to those without shelter, and many now have their own personal set.

"If we need a new box of swags, which costs $800, there will always be someone willing to put their hand up," Mr Griffiths said.
Many skiwear retailers have also provided the foundation with jackets either donated or sold at a discounted price.
Those who live on the streets have access to breakfast during weekdays at Uniting Church on Northbourne Avenue. Now Safe Shelter guests will receive a hot-breakfast on a Saturday morning.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It's been going for a month now, and has been going well. In the beginning there weren't too many people, but now we are starting to see an increase," owner of Coffee Rukus, Sastra Kurniadi said.
Mr Griffiths said the shelter intended to open everyday during the cold Canberra winter next year, extending their service to include weekends.
Safe Shelters has approximately 125 volunteers, at each shelter three must stay overnight.
Mr Griffiths said the shelter was fortunate to have caring volunteers who regularly went above and beyond to help those in need.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samaritan House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uniting Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Safe Shelter Coordinator Richard Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffee Rukus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northbourne Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Safe Shelter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sastra Kurniadi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Griffith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
