<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406644781236021</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/flu-cases-in-queensland-triple-in-few-weeks/8764552</url>
  <title>Flu cases in Queensland triple within weeks but worst is yet to come</title>
  <content>
Queensland looks set to endure another horrific flu season, with the number of recorded cases tripling over the past few weeks.
The number of flu cases has jumped from 600 in early July to almost 2000 this week, and with biting Ekka winds just around the corner the worse is yet to come.
Queensland's Health's executive director of communicable diseases Sonya Bennett said the outbreak was worse than this time last year.
Dr Bennett said it was "concerning" the number of cases was rising so fast early in the season.
"In 2017 so far, 78 per cent of notifications were typed as influenza A and the remaining 22 per cent were influenza B," she said.
"We've seen 1,324 public hospital admissions across the state for influenza ... 126 of those required intensive care.
"We will expect to see some deaths, as we know flu can be a severe illness.
Queensland Health has already delivered 800,000 free vaccines around the state for high risk individuals.
"There is no better time than to remind people to consider getting vaccinated to protect themselves," Dr Bennett said.
There was an increase in flu cases earlier in the year, particularly in North Queensland, which can reflect people travelling and bringing the flu back from overseas.
I was 'coughing uncontrollably'

Alexandra Faros has been hospitalised for a heart condition, after suffering a severe bout of the flu.
Ms Faros said she got the flu vaccine last year but did not get around to it this season.
"Agony, sheer breathing, agony, not pleasant at all," she said.
"Just coughing uncontrollably no matter what they gave me, nothing seemed to work.
"It was like somebody sitting on my chest, that is a good way to describe it."
The Pharmacy Guild's Chris Owen said last year's flu season resulted in a critical shortage of the vaccine, but this year it was plentiful.
The 2017 variety protects against two 'A' and two 'B' strains of flu which had been the most prevalent around the world this year.
After a Queensland trial, pharmacists can now deliver vaccines in store for as low as $20 or $30, he said.
Dr Bennett reminded Queenslanders to practise good hygiene.
Queenslanders eligible for the government-funded influenza vaccine can access it from their doctor or immunisation provider from today.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Faros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pharmacy Guild's Chris Owen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Bennett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Health</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Faros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonya Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
