<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406902479278757</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/utas-student-speaks-up-about-her-sexual-assault/8764836</url>
  <title>UTAS student speaks up about her sexual assault to help other victims feel validated</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Laura Nilssen was sexually assaulted by another student in her first year at the University of Tasmania.
After moving to Hobart to study at the age of 19 she found drinking was the "number one social activity" at uni.
But at the start of her second semester in 2009, Laura went out with students from her college and ended up at a nightclub in the city.

Sexual assault support services:

National university support line: 1800 572 224 (until November 30, 2017)
1800 RESPECT: 1800 737 732
Lifeline: 131 114
Beyond Blue: 1300 224 636

"I was very drunk," she said.
"I think I had drunk a whole bottle of wine in the hour previous to that.
"We somehow had bottles of wine in the nightclub."
Laura said she was dancing with and kissing an older student known as a college "old boy" when he started suggesting they "go somewhere more private".
"He took me out of the club, and walked me around - I don't remember where," she said.
"I was so drunk that I don't think I could even walk by myself.
"He was holding onto me, walking me and I think I knew what was going to happen but I was so drunk I just went along with it.
"Eventually, he found this little hidey hole thing and then I guess I was on the ground and he was having sex with me.
"I ended up with a graze on my back which stayed there for a while and it was painful and whenever I thought about it, I thought about that night and it made me feel sick and that was awful."
In the months afterwards, Laura said her mental health deteriorated and she struggled to concentrate and failed some classes.
Men need educating on consent

Laura did not ever report it to the university because she did not know how to.
She also questioned whether what had happened to her was assault.
"It took months or years to label it assault, and I still have trouble calling it rape because I didn't say no and other people have such more traumatic experiences than this," she said.
"But then there are probably hundreds of thousands of women with stories like mine, and I want them to feel validated and that their experiences were a big deal."
Laura Nilssen said there needed to be a focus on educating men about consent.
"The focus doesn't or shouldn't be on telling women that if they're drunk, they can't consent," she said.
"It should be telling men if someone's drunk, don't have sex with them.
"If someone's saying no, don't have sex with them and if someone is not saying yes, don't have sex with them because then it's not sex, it's rape."
UTAS creates new leadership role

The Human Rights Commission survey found 54 per cent of students at UTAS were sexually harassed last year, compared to the national rate of 51 per cent.
Across Australia, 6.9 per cent of students were sexually assaulted in the past two years, while the University of Tasmania recorded a rate of 6.5 per cent.
In response to the report, UTAS has created a new pro vice-chancellor role to focus on culture and wellbeing.
The role is believed to be the first of its kind in the country.

More on this story:

"We are intent on taking a leadership role, working with the community, because we believe that one incident of sexual harassment is one too many," vice-chancellor Professor Peter Rathjen said.
The University's Dean of Law, Professor Margaret Otlowski, will take on the position and will lead a university review and look at how to implement the report's recommendations.
"The very nature of the portfolio is a very strong signal and statement that the university takes this area very seriously," Professor Otlowski said.
'What we need is action'

The response is being backed by the university's student union but the president of the Women's Collective, Saffire Grant, is concerned it is tokenistic.
"I don't feel like we need another person in another position, or another working group," she said.
"What we need to see is action.
"What we need is to have more trauma-informed staff, so that when people do disclose they're told, 'I believe you. It's not your fault'."
"You're not alone and it's your choice if you want to report it and this is how you report it."

External Link:

Sexual harrassment and assault locations

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saffire Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia, 6.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RESPECT: 1800 737 732</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Otlowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTAS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Collective</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 30, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Margaret Otlowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue: 1300 224 636</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University's Dean of Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Nilssen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Peter Rathjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
