<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407207421962864</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/screen-diversity-and-inclusion-network-pushes-for-more-diverse-tv-20170731-gxm5kq.html</url>
  <title>New push for diversity on Australian television with a charter for inclusion</title>
  <content>
Growing up in western Sydney, Roxie Vuong came to expect white-bread casts on Australian television shows.
The 27-year-old budding filmmaker, who makes promotional and training videos for a living, remembers an Asian character on Neighbours once but that was about the extent of ethnic diversity.Photo: Peter Braig
"I guess it was super norm not really seeing yourself on screen so I didn't question it that much," she says.
Vuong, whose parents are from Vietnam, has a new favourite show that reflects that Australian television is becoming more diverse - the SBS comedy The Family Law.The Family Law
Like many under 30s, she watches it on the channel's catch-up service as part of a viewing diet dominated by Netflix rather than traditional TV.
"I feel like there's a shift happening," Vuong says. "This year in particular, with shows on Netflix, there's definitely change happening."

After Waleed Aly won the Gold Logie last year, the signs of change on Australian TV include the popularity of the indigenous drama Cleverman, the multicultural comedies Here Come The Habibs, Ronny Chieng: International Student and The Family Law and the inclusively cast Masterchef, My Kitchen Rules and Gogglebox Australia.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The breakout hit Australian Ninja Warrior featured an Aboriginal male, an Asian-Australian female and a deaf contestant.Here Come the Habibs
But the whiteness of the cast of The Bachelor shows that not everything has changed.
Now a group of broadcasters, industry guilds and business associations have joined the Australian Film, Television and Radio School in a push for more opportunities for those, like Vuong, who are under-represented both on screen and behind the camera.Cleverman
They have formed the Screen Diversity and Inclusion Network and signed a charter to "actively reflect the diversity of Australian society at every level of our workforce, by gender, age, race, sexual orientation, nationality, religion and disability or geographic location, both in our employees and the stories we tell."
Members include the ABC, SBS, Foxtel and the Ten Network - though not the Seven and Nine networks yet - as well as Screen Australia, Create NSW, Film Victoria, Screen Producers Australia and the Australian Directors Guild.Masterchef
The film school's chief executive, Neil Peplow, says the network is a response to a Screen Australia report last year that showed people with Asian, African or Middle Eastern backgrounds, and those with disabilities, were under-represented in TV drama compared to the country's population.
Mr Peplow hopes the charter will be a step towards bringing "the dynamic diversity of contemporary Australia" to the screen.
"We're doing this to build a strong, competitive industry," he says. "If you look at the US, they've worked to bring in more diverse filmmakers and TV content creators and they're finding it opens up new sources of revenue.
"[One recent study showed] films with more diverse casts on average made more money."
Mr Peplow hopes the Seven and Nine networks will also sign the charter.
"There's a moral aspect to it, which is that everybody deserves a fair go and we should be open to people who want to come into the industry," he says. "But there's also a commercial aspect which is about reaching audiences authentically who make up a sizeable chunk of the market."
For Vuong, success for the network would just mean more opportunities.
"It would be great to see relationships form and projects initiated," she says. "It's a base for people to get together and hopefully help each other's projects."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Film Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inclusion Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Habib</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waleed Aly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronny Chieng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Peplow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleverman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vuong</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gogglebox Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Peplow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterchef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Student</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Screen Diversity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roxie Vuong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ten Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Create NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Braig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Law</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kitchen Rules</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Film</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Screen Producers Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Directors Guild.Masterchef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Logie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Screen Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
