<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407289026342881</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/world/exgeneral-john-kelly-directs-broad-shakeup-at-white-house-20170801-gxn1rd</url>
  <title>Ex-General John Kelly directs broad shake-up at White House</title>
  <content>
by
Michael Shear, Glenn Thrush and Maggie Haberman

John Kelly, President Donald Trump's new chief of staff, firmly asserted his authority on his first day in the White House , telling aides he would impose military discipline on a free-for-all West Wing.
And he underscored his intent by firing Anthony Scaramucci, the bombastic communications director, 10 days after he was hired.
Scaramucci was forced out of his post, with the blessing of the president and his family, just days after unloading a crude verbal tirade against other members of the president's staff, including Reince Priebus, Kelly's beleaguered predecessor, and Stephen Bannon, the chief White House strategist, in a conversation with a reporter for The New Yorker.
Trump recruited Scaramucci as a tough-talking alter ego who would ferociously fight for him the way others had not. But "the Mooch," as he likes to be known, quickly went too far, even in the eyes of a president who delights in pushing the boundaries of political and social decorum. As Kelly, a former four-star Marine general, began his first day on the job, Sarah Huckabee Sanders, the White House press secretary, announced that Scaramucci was out.

Pablo Martinez Monsivais

"The president certainly felt that Anthony's comments were inappropriate for a person in that position," Sanders said. "He didn't want to burden General Kelly, also, with that line of succession."

In a post to Twitter just hours before the announcement, Trump insisted that there had been "No WH chaos!" Yet even as he sought to reassure supporters that all was well, several administration aides fretted that the impetuous president and the disciplined Marine were already on a collision course.
Kelly, the first former general to occupy the gatekeeper's post since Alexander Haig played that role for President Richard M. Nixon during Watergate, is charged with quelling the chaos that has defined, distracted and often derailed Trump's White House. But the president gave Priebus many of the same assurances of control, and then proceeded to undercut and ignore him - to the point where Priebus often positioned himself at the door of the Oval Office to find out to whom the president was talking.
In his brief time at the White House, Scaramucci seemed to epitomise its chaos. A wealthy New York financier, he burst onto the political scene with a memorable performance in the White House briefing room, where he portrayed himself as a major, new player who had been assured he would report directly to the president, without the interference of intermediaries like Priebus or Sean Spicer, the president's first press secretary.
It was soon clear that Scaramucci would not be a fixture of the administration, but a transitory figure who created an opportunity for Trump, with his daughter Ivanka and son-in-law Jared Kushner, to undertake the far-reaching shake-up intended to purge the White House staff of leakers and aides viewed as not sufficiently loyal to his cause.

Spicer quit the day Scaramucci was hired; Priebus left shortly after the rant in which Scaramucci accused him of undermining the president through leaks of information to reporters.
Kelly, who was Donald Trump's first secretary of homeland security, arrives at a critical juncture, when the president is confronted with North Korea's growing nuclear ambitions, Russia's aggressive diplomatic moves and continuing fighting in Iraq and Syria. The new chief of staff will also be charged with reviving a stalled legislative agenda.
And despite his desire for discipline, it took only hours on Monday for Kelly to face his first White House leak, and it was about him. CNN reported that Kelly had been so upset about the president's firing of James Comey as FBI director in May that he called Comey to say he was considering resigning, an account that was confirmed by a former law enforcement official who was told of the conversation.
Kelly resisted the president's entreaties to take over for Priebus during the past several weeks. After his appointment was announced on Friday, he met with Trump and demanded assurances that he would wield the usual sweeping authority over personnel, the flow of information and access to the Oval Office that chiefs of staff have traditionally been given.

In early morning staff meetings at the White House on Monday, Kelly made it clear that the president had agreed to let him impose more discipline over what had been an unruly and inefficient decision-making and communications process under Priebus.
Kelly also made it clear that everyone in the staff - including Bannon, Ivanka Trump and Kushner - would clear policy proposals, personnel recommendations and advice from outsiders through him.
"General Kelly has the full authority to operate within the White House, and all staff will report to him," Sanders told reporters.
Donald Trump was initially pleased by Scaramucci's harsh remarks, directed at Priebus as well as Bannon. But that view seemed to change as people around Trump told him that Scaramucci's over-the-top performances were not well received.

In addition, Scaramucci seemed to be, at least for the moment, overshadowing him - a fact that Breitbart News, which Bannon used to run, pointed out in a headline describing Trump as second fiddle to his communications director.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Shear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maggie Haberman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Richard M. Nixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Thrush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanka Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watergate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bannon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-General John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breitbart News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Haig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pablo Martinez Monsivais</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
