<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407207421962810</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/city-council-claims-railbus-union-wants-to-call-shots/news-story/34a5b006f733efe026d6ba91b095fb11</url>
  <title>Council blames state for bus strike</title>
  <content>
BRISBANE'S deputy mayor has accused the Rail Bus and Tram Union of wanting to "control City Hall" ahead of another .
As the administration faced questions on its alleged "industrial relations crisis", public and active transport chairman Adrian Schrinner pointed the finger at George Street.
He said the council had delivered and was implementing its bus driver safety review and had agreed to put on more security guards during EBA negotiations.
Cr Schrinner said the State Government had still not released its safety review into bus driver safety, expected in March, but the union had decided the council "was 100 per cent to blame".
"They won't picket outside the state parliament," he said.
"The unions control George St and they want to control City Hall and they're not getting it."
A spokeswoman for Transport Minister Jackie Trad said the bus safety review had concluded and the Government would "release its full response shortly".

Brisbane bus drivers to strike, with Council warning it will impact about 100,000 commuters and up to 200 school routes. Courtesy: Sunrise/7 News

Brisbane bus strike to impact 100,000
She said the Government had introduced several recommendations of the review including a trial of shatter-resistant window film on Cairns and Gold Coast buses.
The state has also increased the frequency of Bus Safety Forum meetings from two to six per year.
Earlier in the meeting opposition leader Peter Cumming said the Lord Mayor was facing an "industrial relations crisis".
Lord Mayor Graham Quirk said he believed the pay offer was fair and promised the union would not have control of bus rosters while Brisbane was "under my control".
He said it was his duty to present an offer that was fair to staff and fair to ratepayers.
The Rail Bus and Tram Union has been contacted for comment.
There is another bus strike planned for Wednesday, August 2, from 10am to 2pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunrise/7 News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Schrinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rail Bus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Safety Forum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Schrinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Cumming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tram Union</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
