<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407203126995465</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/20/14/iconic-parramatta-pub-to-be-knocked-down-as-light-rail-rolls-in</url>
  <title>Iconic Parramatta pub to be knocked down as light rail rolls in</title>
  <content>
A historic Parramatta pub will be destroyed to make way for the government's billion-dollar light rail network.
The Royal Oak Hotel has been on Church Street for about 200 years, but will be bought up and knocked down as construction commences on the rail project.
Patrons of the pub told 9NEWS they are "devastated" by the incoming demolition.
"No one has been consulted about the impact that this is going have on the community. And I think it's a disgrace," customer Roman Dechnicz said.
"Absolutely devastated, it's a good family local hotel."
Minister for Transport and Infrastructure Andrew Constance said the government plans to "work with pubs".
"We will work with everyone to assist businesses during this obviously difficult period for some, as we get on and build infrastructure for everyone," he said.

Related Articles

Today some of the 67 metre-long trams which will be used in the network came off the ship at Port Kembla.
The trams can carry 450 people, equating to the number of commuters nine buses can transport.
NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian said she is confident the new transport will be popular.
"Once we know this line is up and running everybody who uses it will love it," Ms Berejikilian said.
The remaining trams for the network are expected to arrive here by mid-next year.
Some of the locomotives are being built in France, the others in Barcelona, raising questions as to why they cannot be built locally.
"This project is just another example of a government that's forced jobs off shore and delivered a botched program in the process," Tim Ayers from the Australian Manufacturing Workers' Union (AMWU) said.
But the premier maintained that the project is creating "thousands" of jobs within New South Wales.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Church Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Kembla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Dechnicz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Ayers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infrastructure Andrew Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Manufacturing Workers' Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMWU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Oak Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejikilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
