<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407246076669260</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/champion-swimmer-geoff-huegill-finds-a-new-career-in-the-pool-cleaning-business/news-story/ac344df4db77c27ef2f4737278f5cf6d</url>
  <title>Geoff Huegill's new career as a pool cleaner</title>
  <content>
IMAGINE Olympic medallist Geoff Huegill rocking up to clean your pool. That's a reality this summer for many Eastern Suburbs pool owners with the legendary butterflyer taking on the role of client manager for The Pool & Spa Whisperer, a premium swimming pool and spa service.
It seems the most natural fit in the world - from pool medal winner to pool cleaner - after a rough year that saw his beloved grandmother die and him considering relocating his family to Singapore to pursue work opportunities.
Huegill said he and his wife Sara and two daughters Milla, 5, and Gigi, 3, have decided to stay put in Bondi and embrace the opportunities here.
"It's been good, I've really enjoyed it because I'm not stuck in an office," the ever-beaming Huegill said last week at the glorious Bellevue Hill home of Di Maloney.
"I've been around swimming pools for 35 years of my life so I understand filtration systems and pumps and backwashes and what's not to love?" he said pointing at the harbour view on a warm Sydney day.
"So for me I've fallen into the business by chance, but it's always one of those things when you are asked how you got into it - especially with jobs that people didn't expect - well, yes, I fell into the business but it's something I've really enjoyed. It suits my personality to a tee."
Huegill has worked in the corporate arena for some time, but said this new path was perfect. He is also swim coaching and mentoring at Cook & Phillip Aquatic Centre with his HBT Swim Academy.
"At the start of the year unfortunately my grandma passed away and I thought about relocating my family overseas," said the champion who is no stranger to overcoming adversity having made a successful swimming comeback at the age of 31.
He won silver in the 4x100m medley relay and bronze in the 100m butterfly at the Sydney Olympics in 2000 and came back to win gold in the 2010 Delhi Commonwealth Games in the 4x100m medley relay and 100m butterfly.
"We went to Singapore and a couple of opportunities presented themselves there, but decided as a family to stay here and follow up opportunities here," he said.
"The good thing about this, regardless of anything, is we are now rebuilding everything again. We are connecting with our networks again. We're rebuilding our businesses again. Life is better which is the most important thing."
His main role within the organisation, which does pool fence compliance, pool maintenance, pool management, filtrations systems and repairs, is working in the client management side and working with real estate agents, property managers and winning business.
Huegill laughed that people got a shock sometimes when he walked into their backyard.
"Occasionally I rock up to people's backyards and people do get that shock of 'wow what are you doing here?' But we work with a team of guys and a team of technicians that come and take the headache and the pain away for the real estate agent or the pool owner."
Huegill is also loving coaching his weekend warriors, planning a trip to Japan for with them at the end of the year.
"As a mentor to a group of young athletes, yes you want them to get the best out of themselves, but you can't use them as a churning wheel for the next one to come through. A coach has to have a responsibility to that child that they are halfway through to the next phase of their lives," he said.
"Swimming has to be used in a positive way. Perhaps to get to a good university in the States. So when they reflect on the sport, they don't think: I hated swimming and think of it negatively.
"It's important to get coaches and parents to look at it through that point of view and not about focusing on just winning."
He said pool safety was always top of mind and that his girls were in learn to swim programs.
"With my background in swimming - and for a lot of families, it's sacrilegious not having kids involved in learn to swim programs. The biggest fear as a parent is if you turn your back right? You have to be over the top with it.
"My girls love swimming. They absolutely love it. They have that mongrel in them. I would encourage them but I wouldn't push them. I would encourage them to not give up. I would work with them on building a future and help them to see what they want to achieve.
"Everything you learn in sport, from vision goal setting, punctuality, teamwork, discipline. That never give up attitude. That's the stuff you don't get in the real world."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delhi Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milla, 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastern Suburbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gigi, 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Huegill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellevue Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Di Maloney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillip Aquatic Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huegill</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spa Whisperer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBT Swim Academy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
