<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406773630257172</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/why-geelong-decided-against-challenging-patrick-dangerfield-suspension-20170801-gxnblm.html</url>
  <title>Why Geelong decided against challenging Patrick Dangerfield suspension</title>
  <content>
In the context of the AFL landscape heading into the last month of the season it's difficult to imagine a more cataclysmic decision by the match review panel than to defy the expectations of the entire industry and suspend the Brownlow favourite.
Equally it's difficult to remember a more dramatic season for an individual - generally in a good way - than Patrick Dangerfield's past 12 months.Photo: AAP
A Brownlow in his first season at Geelong, a lone, brave and defiant stand on behalf of the players' pay push, a follow-up champion season, a slick, multi-layered and expanded media career in which he admitted to his own past mental frailty and the private decision to seek professional help. And he just kept playing better.
Some felt Dangerfield went over the top when he hammed up a press conference hobbling out like a casualty victim poking fun at suggestions he overplayed an injury and then promptly moved to full-forward and kicked 5.6 apparently on one leg.
The impression is that this external criticism baffled him and you have to wonder whether that, too, has played a part in his decision to back away from media for the next month. Certainly, and despite Dangerfield's protestations that the Brownlow was the last thing on his mind, he would be flat right now.
This is despite the fact that he, too, pushed against appealing the bombshell decision by the MRP, a maligned outfit this year and one that has been challenged at times by the recently departed football boss Simon Lethlean.

You could say the three-man judiciary that suspended Dangerfield backed the AFL machine into a corner on Monday but, of course, that was exactly the position it found itself in when faced with the incident that divided the football community.
Its call was backed in the end by Geelong and the advice of not one but two Queen's counsels who could not support an appeal.
The Cats' gut feeling despite expectations on Monday night was not to challenge the Match Review Panel, unwilling to risk a two-game suspension with Sydney and Richmond ahead and a home final with a double chance to play for. But they still exhausted several legal avenues.
The club's regular QC, Peter Murdoch, felt Geelong's chances were 50-50 at best regarding the appeal and the second opinion put forward by the experienced David Grace was even more pessimistic. His advice was that Dangerfield had held on to Matthew Kreuzer for too long and was more likely to double his suspension on appeal.
Grace told the Cats that even in accepting Dangerfield's explanation that he thought Kreuzer still had the ball this did not exonerate him because the tackle still constituted rough conduct.
Grace, who has regularly defended big-impact cases at the AFL Tribunal and also originally appeared on behalf of the Essendon players and successfully defended Fremantle during "Sirengate", said Dangerfield had other alternatives at his disposal other than pinning Kreuzer's arms and that he could have let Kreuzer fall on top of him.
He pointed out that Kreuzer was not only concussed but missed the rest of the game with concussion and harked back to the examples put forward by the AFL at the start of the season in the rules explanations regarding sling tackles, rough conduct and head protection.
So as tough as it might be for Dangerfield, and the AFL, on Brownlow night - particularly given the scenario of the player himself winning the vote count and then presenting the medal to another - the legal advice backed the MRP and Geelong's bosses including the coach appear comfortable with the call not to appeal.
Dangerfield has put his team first and that cannot hurt the Cats' morale. Nor will a week's rest do his body any harm. And surely the AFL will not consider calls to revisit the game's most sacred individual medal.
As tough as this sounds the overwhelming view from the game's chosen judges, along with two QCs, was that Dangerfield, one of the game's best-and-fairest players, did not tackle fairly on that one unfortunate occasion. Those are the rules.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirengate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Grace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Lethlean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
