<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407246076669236</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/18/19/queensland-police-commissioner-stares-down-the-doubters</url>
  <title>Queensland Police Commissioner Ian Stewart stares down the doubters</title>
  <content>
The re-appointment of Ian Stewart as Queensland Police Commissioner this week hasn't surprised many, not in policing circles anyway.  
He's the incumbent, and eight months out from the Commonwealth Games, for the premier he's the obvious choice.  
But there's an aside.
It's well known, as is often the case with our leaders, that Mr Stewart has his critics. They come from within and outside the service.
He knows it too.
"You talk about cherry picking different views," Mr Stewart said. 
"I'm glad there's people out there who have different ideas about how they would run the police service."

Related Articles

At 63, Mr Stewart is due to lead the service for another three years, but he's yet to provide a guarantee he'll see the full term through.
"That's a decision I'll make on a day by day basis. Obviously my health, my family issues, my passion for this job will always be factors in that."
One of the biggest thorns in the commissioner's side is a recurring grumble journalists hear on the crime round - officer morale is low.
Over the past four years, the state's crime rate has also risen by around 10 percent every year.   
Mr Stewart owns the decisions he's made, but admits they haven't always been popular.
"I've been a 'change agent' and we know that history tells you that change agents, particularly ones that have created dramatic changes as I have in this organisation, you do have your detractors, you do polarise people on how things should be done."
The commissioner's biggest challenge, and perhaps his legacy maker too, is the upcoming Gold Coast Commonwealth Games.
Mr Stewart says, under his watch, the service will be ready.
"If there's one thing I know, we as an organisation and I think the community deserve stability across the security envelope that we're providing for the games."
Political police games or not, Mr Stewart is in charge again.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stewart</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Commissioner Ian Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
