<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406387083193176</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/sydney-swans/sydney-swans-great-jude-bolton-puts-heat-on-midfield-tyros-to-cover-for-josh-kennedy-20170801-gxn30d.html</url>
  <title>Sydney Swans great Jude Bolton puts heat on midfield tyros to cover for Josh Kennedy</title>
  <content>
Former Sydney star Jude Bolton says the Swans' next-generation midfielders need to seize the moment should injured captain Josh Kennedy be ruled out for Friday night's blockbuster against Geelong.
, the Swans have their own midfield issues with

Up Next

Cancer changed Roughead's perspective

00:23

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Swans knocking on door of top four

An unlikely six goal haul from recalled forward Callum Sinclair delivered a 42-point Sydney win over St Kilda in the pride game.

Should he miss it would leave a massive hole in the Swans midfield, which was found wanting last week with their premier ball-winner hampered by a hamstring injury.
The club's contested ball and clearance king, Kennedy has competed at more centre bounces than any Swan - and by a considerable margin. His 83 per cent is well clear of the next best midfielder Luke Parker (64), Isaac Heeney (45) and Dan Hannebery (40).

Swans coach John Longmire will need to look elsewhere to find the 15 contested possessions Kennedy averages a game this season.
Encouragingly for Sydney, the club has won three of the four games Kennedy has been sidelined since he arrived in 2010.

Parker and Hannebery can expect to feel the heat from Geelong's midfield if Kennedy misses, which will would put pressure on Heeney, Zak Jones, George Hewett and Tom Papley to step up.
The quartet have been given extra responsibility this season in a midfield that has lost Tom Mitchell and is planning for life after Jarrad McVeigh and Kieren Jack.Photo: AAP
"They have to keep their high standards - you get into trouble if you try to play above and beyond," Bolton said of Parker and Hannebery.
"If they bring their usual high standard, it will hold them in good stead. Other players have gone through the middle - Heeney, Papley, Jones need an impact.
"They certainly need to find someone willing to get their hands dirty."
The chances of young gun Callum Mills being pushed into the midfield are slim with Longmire reiterating his preference for last year's Rising Star winner to continue in defence, where his ability to intercept and launch counter-attacks is highly valued.
Dangerfield's absence leaves arguably a bigger hole for the Cats, who have relied heavily on him and Joel Selwood, and is a shot in the arm for the Swans as they aim to end Geelong's run of seven consecutive wins at their Simonds Stadium fortress.
The Swans won in 2011 and at the Cattery but it's otherwise produced few moments of joy for the red and white faithful.
Bolton is confident the Swans can bounce back after last week's loss to the Hawks.
"They had too many blokes who weren't contributing," Bolton said.
"They've come off the back of an incredible run of wins so they don't need to change too much.
"If everyone lifts 10 per cent you'll get a big lift across the game."
Bolton said the Swans needed to be careful their forwards did not get pushed too high up the long and skinny Simonds Stadium as they did against Hawthorn, which affected their ability to lock the ball inside their forward 50.
"They lost structure, that was the biggest drop-off between the St Kilda game and the Hawks game - the ability to have a contest inside the forward 50 in the air and on the ground," Bolton said.
"It starts pinning around their quickly if you don't have the forward pressure."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jude Bolton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrad McVeigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Hannebery (40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rising Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Parker (64</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cattery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Selwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Sinclair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieren Jack.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heeney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac Heeney (45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callum Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannebery</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roughead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Hewett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
