<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407374925690630</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826427/who-is-the-wollongong-masturbator/?cs=298</url>
  <title>Joggers could hold key to identifying Wollongong bike path attacker</title>
  <content>
The assault occurred east of WIN Stadium, on a bike path that runs between Bank Street and Marine Drive. Picture: Adam McLean

Two joggers likely crossed paths with an "unusual" man moments before he launched a disturbing attack on a woman in Wollongong on Sunday night, investigating police say.

Police believe the joggers could be key to advancing their investigation into the case, and are appealing for the male pair to come forward. 
The attack occurred on a cycle path between Bank Street and Marine Drive, about 7.30pm. 
Two women aged 20 and 23 were walking south when they were confronted by a man who stood in the middle of the path, masturbating. 
Detective Inspector Brad Ainsworth said the women were disturbed by the man's actions and attempted to run away from him, but he grabbed one of them and pulled her to the ground. 
"Her screams were heard by a member of the public, so they called triple-zero," he said. "She was physically shaken, most definitely."

The women were international visitors and the investigation had been made difficult by a language barrier, Insp Ainsworth said. 

Detective Inspector Brad Ainsworth. Picture: Adam McLean
The women have been able to provide only a very limited description of the man, telling police he possibly wore a hooded jacket and that he was smoking. He was last seen heading north along the path. 
"It [the description] is very vague, that's why we're appealing to these two joggers that might be able to come forward and help us with our inquiries," Insp Ainsworth said. 

"They [may] remember seeing a male person who looked unusual."
The attack occurred on a remote stretch of the path, near the back of WIN Stadium, under limited lighting when there were few people around. 
Insp Ainsworth described the attack as an isolated incident. 
"There's been no previous recorded incidents down there [but] it's something that we'd like to investigate and obviously bring the person who's committed these acts to justice." 

Contact Wollongong Police on 4226 7899 or call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 to assist with the investigation. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Brad Ainsworth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIN Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insp Ainsworth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Drive</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
