<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406601831562177</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/wallaroos-selected-for-world-cup-but-pay-remains-issue/8764342</url>
  <title>Wallaroos selected for Women's Rugby World Cup as donation provides welcome boost</title>
  <content>
The coveted green and gold Australian jersey has been presented to 28 female rugby union players ahead of the World Cup.
Of the 28 athletes heading to Ireland, just three, including Wallaroos captain Shannon Parry, are paid professionals with contracts with the Women's Sevens program.
For the 25 others, the World Cup means taking time off from their full time jobs.
But the group chosen to play for Australia say they are playing for the jersey, not money.
"We want to be known as professional amateurs, we want to be seen as a united squad, we want to be well respected at the World Cup," Parry said.
Veteran player Ash Husain is a prison guard at Sydney's Long Bay Jail.

External Link:

@pacificann: "@JosephineSukkar Women's rugby support by Buildcorp a game changer. #proud #Wallaroos  @WallaroosRugby"
The prisoners she works with follow her rugby career.
"When I got back from [a recent tournament in] New Zealand they had all the cut-outs from the newspapers, which they brought them to me to show me," she said.
"It was quite sweet because I work with guys with intellectual disabilities.
"They are quite excited when they see me in the paper and on the television."
Parry said giving up as much as three months' pay was an incredible sacrifice for players to make.
"They have to take leave without pay - and not many people in the economy that we're in would do that," she said.
"This jersey means a lot."
Business woman boosts player's pockets

While the Australian Rugby Union covers the cost of the Wallaroos' entire trip to the World Cup, the athletes are not paid match fees.
But thanks to businesswoman Josephine Sukkar they will get $1,000 each to help with extra costs.
"That will drop into their accounts, it will go a long way to paying for some of their strength and conditioning coaching, gym memberships et cetera. We're working on it," she said.
The so-called 'fairy godmother' of the Wallaroos recently donated $200,000 to the ARU from the Australian Rugby Foundation to help boost the women's game.
And she wants more corporates to jump on board.
"At the end of the day the ARU are like other sporting bodies, they're just not flush with cash," Ms Sukkar said.
"But at the end of the day there's a lot of money in corporate Australia that can be mobilised for this."
ARU boss Bill Pulver - currently in arbitration with Rugby WA over moves to cull a Super Rugby franchise - was unavailable for comment at the Wallaroos' farewell.
The Wallaroos face host nation Ireland in their first group match next week.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Parry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rugby Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josephine Sukkar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Rugby Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Pulver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Long Bay Jail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Sukkar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Rugby World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash Husain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WallaroosRugby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buildcorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Sevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JosephineSukkar Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
