<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407374925690644</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/kelly-flexes-white-house-muscle-first-day/news-story/97908542cccf10ae762e3713f1d4d735</url>
  <title>Kelly flexes White House muscle first day</title>
  <content>
Raised voices could be heard through the thick door to the Oval Office as John Kelly - then secretary of Homeland Security - offered some tough talk to President Donald Trump.
Kelly, a whip-cracking retired general who was sworn in as White House chief of staff on Monday, had demanded to speak to the president alone after Trump complained loudly the US was admitting travellers from Afghanistan, Iran and Haiti.
Kelly first tried to explain the admissions were standard - some people had legitimate reasons to visit - but the president insisted it was making him look bad, according to an official familiar with the exchange.
Kelly demanded other advisers leave the room so he could speak to the president frankly. Trump refused at first but agreed when Kelly insisted.
It was an early indication Kelly, a decorated retired Marine general who served three tours in Iraq, is not afraid to stand up to his commander-in-chief.
Tapped to bring order to a chaotic West Wing, Kelly began to make his mark immediately on Monday, ousting new communications director Anthony Scaramucci and revising a dysfunctional and factional command structure.
From now on, said White House press secretary Sarah Huckabee Sanders, all senior staffers - including son-in-law Jared Kushner and chief strategist Steve Bannon - will report to Kelly instead of the president.
Kelly "will bring new structure, discipline and strength" to the White House, Sanders said.
"It definitely has the fingerprints of a new sheriff in town," said Blain Rethmeier, who guided Kelly through the Senate confirmation process for the Homeland Security post.
Rethmeier said what stood out about Kelly during the time they worked together was the way he commanded respect and respected others.
Kelly fostered a reputation as an outspoken commander who didn't shy away from unpopular opinions during his military career.
Rethmeier said Kelly also respects authority deeply - "and that's something that Trump sort of smells out, if you respect him or not".
"If he disagrees with you, he'll disagree respectfully," Rethmeier said.
It was a point Kelly made clear during his confirmation hearing in January.
"I have never had a problem speaking truth to power and I firmly believe that those in power deserve full candor and my honest assessment and recommendations. I also value people that work for me speaking truth to power," he said.
Kelly's appointment is being celebrated beyond the White House.
Senator Bob Corker says he discussed it with Trump on Friday and hopes Kelly "will do everything possible to bring the appropriate discipline and focus that needs to be at the White House there".
Professor David B. Cohen, who is co-authoring a book on chiefs of staff, applauded Kelly for doing "things that should have been done on Day One of Reince Priebus's tenure".
But he wondered how long Trump would go before beginning to undermine him.
"President Trump is his own worst enemy. He instinctively likes to be his own chief of staff and he's a pretty awful one."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Bob Corker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeland Security</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haiti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor David B. Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rethmeier</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blain Rethmeier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day One of Reince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
