<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407121522615029</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4819647/ptsd-no-limit-for-lifter/?cs=305</url>
  <title>PTSD no limit for lifter</title>
  <content>
Determined: Rachel Kerrigan has used weightlifting to help in her battle with post traumatic stress disorder. Picture: Simone De Peak

Life hasn't been easy for Rachel Kerrigan since she left the armed forces.
After serving as an electrical engineer with the Royal Australian Air Force for seven years - which included time in Afghanistan - she has battled post traumatic stress disorder, fought cancer and been recovering from a stroke.
While Ms Kerrigan says she's still "not 100 per cent", weightlifting has proved a source of solace for the Wallsend mother. 

She will compete on the big stage this week, at the Australian Masters National Power Lifting Championships in Melbourne on Friday.

- Rachel Kerrigan.
Ms Kerrigan said she began training full-time in February, after trying her hand at para-power lifting at last year's Invictus Games.

"Basically, when you've got PTSD, your mind isn't quiet at all," she said. 

"It's really hard to be in the moment and to be focused because you're just on high alert all the time.
"When I'm lifting, my head is clear, I'm right there - just in that moment - and it just helps me release tension.

"If I'm angry or if I'm anxious, all of that just disappears."
In 2010, three years after Ms Kerrigan left the RAAF, signs of PTSD surfaced.

Ms Kerrigan will compete in the Australian Masters National Power Lifting Championships in Melbourne on Friday. Picture: Simone De Peak
She also suffered a stroke, which meant she had to learn how to use the left side of her body again. If that wasn't enough, she was also diagnosed with uterine cancer. 

But, after weighing in at 119kg a few years ago, Ms Kerrigan has worked her way to less than 60kg - and she can lift almost double her body weight. She has also beaten the cancer.
In that time, Ms Kerrigan has completed the Sandakan Death March trek in Borneo and the Kokoda Trail in Papua New Guinea.

Since she began to focus on exercise, Ms Kerrigan has been able to stop her 30-tablet-a-day PTSD medication regime periodically over the past two years.

Rachel Kerrigan trains in the makeshift gym at her Wallsend home. Picture: Simone De Peak
She credits her 13-year-old daughter, Kiara, as being her biggest motivation and her greatest supporter. 
In her makeshift home gym last Friday afternoon, Ms Kerrigan said weightlifting had given her a purpose again.

"If I'm having a really bad day, I can go to the gym and lift some weights," she said.
"Obviously it doesn't take the problems away, but there's lots of stuff in my life that I can't control.

"Lifting that weight is something I can control and it's something I do for me. 

"The only limit is what I can do."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Kerrigan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Borneo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian Air Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandakan Death March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Invictus Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAAF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PTSD</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kerrigan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kokoda Trail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallsend</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Masters National Power Lifting Championships</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone De Peak</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
