<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407374925690617</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4827358/saifiti-confident-win-a-pointer-to-the-future/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Saifiti confident win a pointer to the future</title>
  <content>
OH BROTHER: Daniel and Jacob Saifiti celebrate after the Knights' drought-breaking 21-14 win over the Dragons. Picture: Darren Pateman (AAP).

DANIEL Saifiti was happy that the Knights to "won ugly" against the Dragons.
He was even happier that twin brother Jacob scored a try and "got off the nudie" run.
"I didn't want to see that side of him at the end of the year," Saifiti joked.
Saifiti is also well aware the Knights will need to improve on their 21-14 triumph - just their third victory this season - if they are to overcome the Warriors at McDonald Jones Stadium on Saturday and win back-to-back games for the first time in almost two years.
"We won ugly," he said of the Dragons win. "In previous weeks against the Roosters, Broncos and Bulldogs we lost pretty. We would definitely rather win ugly. We toughed it out and I don't think we have done that in the past couple of years. It shows how much we have improved. We would have lost that game in the past. "
Indeed, the Knights have lost several games in which they have been in positions to win this season. 
"To be able to hang in and finish the game off with a win gives us confidence and belief," centre Dane Gagai said. "We have to take that into next week but also realise that the Dragons game is done now. We can't expect to think that will roll on and just happen again."
Nathan Brown has named an unchanged 17 for the Warriors. Chanel Mata'utia has recovered from a concussion and returns on an extended bench. 
The Saifiti brothers carried the ball an incredible 351 metres between them against the Dragon. Daniel, who started at prop, surged 153m and Jacob was even more damaging off the bench with a season-high 198m.
"That is my job," Daniel said down-playing his contribution. "Having Jacob make close to 200 metres. We play off the back of each other. That helps as well. I thought he was close to the best player on the field. Having him making runs like that inspires me. Sometimes it is the other way round. Physically I am starting to get stronger. I've played 30-odd games now. Everyone is getting that bit of experience and knowing what to do now to get that win."
The Warriors, who have lost halfback Shaun Johnson to a season-ending knee injury, have lost three games straight to drop out of contention for the top eight.
However, they beat the Knights 26-22 in round one and Saifiti and Gagai are preparing for the visitors to be at their best.
"They have close to the best spine in the competition," Saifiti said. "We have to stop their big fellas as well. We let a few offloads go on the weekend. If we can stop the Warriors' offloads, it will go a long way to helping us win."
It was the Warriors' power-packed outside backs which did the damage in the season opener.
Centre David Fusitua scored a first-half hatrick and Roger Tuivasa-Sheck (251m), Ken Maumalo (151m) and Solomone Kata (119m) made constant inroads. 
"They have some big ,strong backs who carry the ball well," Gagai said. "We have to play a smarter style of football. Make sure we finish our sets better. When they do get second-phase ball, we have to make sure we are all working together and not trying to solve it on our own."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centre David Fusitua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Pateman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanel Mata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Tuivasa-Sheck (251</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Gagai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DANIEL Saifiti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OH BROTHER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Maumalo (151</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Saifiti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solomone Kata (119</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald Jones Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saifiti</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gagai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
