<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407460825038509</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4827477/haynes-looks-to-net-ffa-cup-goal-in-final-shot-photos/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Haynes looks to net FFA Cup goal in final shot | photos</title>
  <content>
MAGIC MAN: Peter Haynes has played more than 250 games for Broadmeadow after stints with Adamstown, Lake Macquarie and Hamilton.

AFTER two league player of the year awards, a golden boot, a Newcastle Jets contract, five grand final wins and four minor premierships, there's not much Broadmeadow veteran Peter Haynes has left to achieve at state league level.

But as the 35-year-old comes to the end of his 19th and final season of first-grade football, there's at least one box left to tick - a round of 32 win in the FFA Cup.
Haynes was there when Broadmeadow finished with nine men in a 2-1 extra-time loss to Brisbane Strikers in 2015 and in 2016 when Heidelberg beat them 3-1.
On Wednesday night, Haynes gets his last chance to qualify for a round of 16 game when Broadmeadow take on Moreton Bay at Wolter Park in Albany Creek.

Haynes looks to net FFA Cup goal in final shot | photos

exit
"It's probably irked a few of the boys who have been there twice before," Haynes said of falling short on the FFA Cup national stage.

"The last game against Heidelberg, we probably got a bit of a touch up and they were probably a better side than us at the time, but the first game against Brisbane, that was the one that got away from us.

"Hopefully tomorrow we can make amends because I really think we deserve to be in the round of 16 at some point and hopefully I can be part of it this year."
And he believes the game against Moreton Bay is Magic's best chance yet.
"They are in a similar position to us in their league and they'll probably fancy their chances against a small team from Northern NSW, and we probably fancy ours against a mid-table team from Queensland," he said. "No disrespect to them, but this is probably the best draw we've had in the round of 32 so we're quietly confident and we'll be pretty disappointed if we don't get a result."
Haynes told teammates two months ago this would be his final season. At that point, Magic were long odds to make the finals and, on form, an FFA Cup run looked unlikely. However, the injection of Mitch Oxborrow sparked a sharp turnaround in fortunes and set Broadmeadow on a seven-game winning streak into fourth.

But with the departure of Oxborrow to Brisbane Roar, Haynes, who was rested last week in the 3-1 win over Maitland, looms as a key man against Moreton Bay.
"Mitch coming in didn't change the way we played, so it's not going to disrupt us too much now that he's gone - apart from the boys would rather have Mitch in there instead of an old guy like me trying to copy what he did," he laughed. "But I said to the boys the other night, these games don't come along too often so I'm probably more excited than most of the boys because I know hard it is to get to this stage and you don't know when the next one will come along. I'm like a kid in a candy shop at the moment."
Against Moreton Bay, Broadmeadow will be without Scott Robertson (broken foot), while captain Josh Piddington (knee) is in doubt.

On Sunday, Magic will honour Haynes on their Old Boys day when they take on the Newcastle Jets Youth in the penultimate NPL round. Magic then finish the regular season away against Hamilton the following Saturday.

Haynes, though, was keen to extend the swansong.
"Halfway through the season, I thought the game against Hamilton was probably going to be the last time I step out onto the field," he said.

"But now, I'd pretty disappointed if it is. Hopefully I get one more game at home in a semi-final, and then finish off with a grand final at McDonald Jones Stadium, that would be pretty special."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haynes</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Roar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolter Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Jets Youth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Jets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxborrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Haynes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Strikers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Boy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Piddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adamstown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Oxborrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald Jones Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
