<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406387083193137</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826343/meet-the-man-who-went-to-more-meetings-than-any-wollongong-councillor/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Meet the man who went to more meetings than any Wollongong councillor</title>
  <content>
Mr Erwin gave out parting gifts to councillors. Pictures: Adam McLean.

Otford resident Warwick Erwin attended more Wollongong council meetings than any councillor - Lord Mayor included - or any single council staffer over the past six years.
In the 110 meetings between September 2011 and this Monday, the civic-minded eccentric missed just two - one due to an infected finger and another because of "a minor heart condition".
But otherwise, he's been there, sitting at the back of the public gallery, keeping a watchful eye on the shenanigans of the 13 councillors.
Read more: 
This week, Mr Erwin - who started attending meetings to support his friend, Greg Petty and then just continued going "to make sure councillors kept doing the right thing" - took to the lectern of the public access forum to bid farewell.
- Warwick Erwin
"You didn't expect six years ago, when you were elected to represent the residents of Wollongong, that you would still be here," he said.
"You as councillors have made Wollongong as better place for us, and for the future residents of Wollongong to live in."
He reminded them of their early days, and what they had been elected to do - marking out some of his favourite points over the six year term.
"Council meetings - haven't they been interesting, hmm?" he said, to councillors.

"Off in an unknown direction at times, marathon nights - from my memory the longest ran to 11.30pm - and motions drafted on the floor of council."
He pointedly looked at outspoken Liberal councillor Bede Crasnich as he highlighted the "political jabs", and called out academic George Takacs for giving "science lessons".
"Words of wisdom" earned Labor's David Brown a nod, while "trumpet blowing, in some cases" was a reprimand for all.

"But you've all worked together, and been entertaining," he said.
"As the last public access forum speaker to this council, I wish to thank you for your service to the community of Wollongong."
At this point, Mr Erwin opened a box of gifts - mugs marked with the city's emblem and an "I heart Bald Hill slogan".
Mr Erwin told the Mercury he hoped to see more residents taking an interest in meetings during the next term of council.

"Unless we do take an interest, the council will become even more disconnected from the people," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Erwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bede Crasnich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's David Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Otford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bald Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Takacs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Petty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Erwin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
