<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406520227182025</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/almost-half-of-cdu-students-sexually-harassed-last-year/8764432</url>
  <title>Almost half of Charles Darwin University students surveyed by AHRC were sexually harassed last year</title>
  <content>
Almost half of surveyed students at Charles Darwin University (CDU) say they experienced sexual harassment last year, according to a new national survey.
The  into sexual harassment and assaults on campuses was released today.
It drew 30,000 responses nationally, including 362 from Charles Darwin University.
Forty-five per cent of the CDU students said they experienced sexual harassment in 2016, with 13 per cent of that group saying that the harassment happened at university.
Nationally 51 per cent of students surveyed said they were sexually harassed in 2016, with one in four sexually harassed at a university setting.
Sexual assault at university was reported by 1.3 per cent of Charles Darwin survey respondents, compared with 1.6 per cent nationally.
'Insufficient responses to be statistically relevant'

The vice-chancellor of Charles Darwin University, Professor Simon Maddocks, said the survey results did not provide a lot of detail, "because ... overall [Charles Darwin's] student numbers are relatively low".
"Put simply, in some areas there were insufficient responses to be statistically relevant," Professor Maddocks said.

Sexual assault support services:

National university support line: 1800 572 224 (until November 30, 2017)
1800 RESPECT: 1800 737 732
Lifeline: 131 114
Beyond Blue: 1300 224 636

"There is no reason to believe, however, that CDU is greatly different to the rest of the sector in terms of sexual assault and sexual harassment, which is why I have committed CDU to [Universities Australia]'s 10-point action plan."
The plan includes the establishment of an interim 24-hour support line to be operated by Rape and Domestic Violence Services Australia, the development of a respectful relationships program for university students and the extension of first responder training to more frontline university staff.
CDU 'continuing to develop systems'

Professor Maddocks said CDU had policies, trained staff and services to support victims of sexual harassment or assault, but would continue to develop its systems.
He said CDU was considering creating a university-side network of contact officers specifically trained to support students and staff affected by sexual violence.
A majority of those categorised that the nature of the harassment was inappropriate staring or leering, sexually suggestive comments or jokes, or intrusive and offensive questions about the victim's private life or physical appearance.
Fifty-one per cent of students who reported an experience of sexual assault said that the perpetrator was not someone they knew, but 66 per cent said it was a fellow student and 59 per cent said the perpetrator was male.
Only 2 per cent of those who reported experiencing sexual harassment sought support or assistance from the university.
Sixty-six per cent of those who did not report the harassment said they did not think it was serious enough, while 19 per cent said they did not want to get the perpetrator in trouble.
Just over one fifth of people who experienced sexual harassment said they did not report it because of confusion about cultural norms in Australia.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Simon Maddocks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RESPECT: 1800 737 732</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifty-one</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domestic Violence Services Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 30, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AHRC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Maddocks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue: 1300 224 636</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Darwin University</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CDU</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sixty-six</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
