<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407460825038507</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/crime/mother-of-satan-gas-may-have-been-involved-in-alleged-terror-plot/news-story/c5ae4f2ff8f6b57c070c9523fb4d0f54</url>
  <title>'Mother of Satan' gas may have been involved in alleged terror plot</title>
  <content>
Sydney Terror plot 'days away' from going off
9:08

Terror expert Greg Barton says the device found in Syd Terror raids may have been 'days away from going off'

July 31st 2017
a day ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

A terror expert says the toxic gas apparently included in the plot may have been the same one used in the Manchester and Paris attacks. Picture: Getty Images.

Share

THE alleged plot to bring down a commercial flight may have involved a toxic gas dubbed the "mother of Satan" that was used in the Manchester bombing and Paris attacks.
That's according to Deakin University terror expert Greg Barton who suggested the plan may have revolved around acetone peroxide - or TATP.
The gas has been given the terrifying "mother of Satan" nickname because it is unstable but powerful and can kill those handling it. It's also unlikely to give off the "tell-tale" chemical signs picked up by airport tests, Prof Barton told AAP.
"That makes it a candidate for using in this sort of attack," he said.
TATP, which needs a pressure vessel to be packed in, could be placed in a grinder so it was opaque through an X-ray machine and appeared innocuous upon visual inspection.
"It might just pass (security)," Prof Barton said.
He speculated while the plot could have succeeded it more likely would have failed because the bomb would have been detected, failed to detonate or not have detonated to its full potential.
"(Still) it's important to understand this clearly is the most sophisticated terror plot we've had, probably ever, in Australia," he added.

Police have four men in custody while they search homes following counter-terrorism raids across the city at the weekend. Picture: AFP PHOTO / WILLIAM WESTSource:AFP

Police have been combing rubbish for evidence of a plot, after US and UK authorities delivered a tip-off to Australian police after having picked up communications in Syria. Picture: AFP PHOTO / WILLIAM WEST.Source:AFP
The same chemical was found in the backpack of Manchester terrorist Salman Abedi and was also used in the Paris 2015 attacks and one in Brussels in March 2016.

The Chair of the US Homeland Security Committee, Mike McCaul has called it a "classic explosive" used by terrorists. It can be made using household chemicals but is unstable and unreliable, .
The common substance used in separate European attacks has fuelled speculation of a wider network.
Authorities have remained tight-lipped about how the alleged plot would have been carried out. However it's believed the plan was "" and may have involved concealing an explosive inside a meat grinder.
Etihad Airways has confirmed it is working with police on the investigation but the men had not purchased tickets for the flight.
"Etihad is complying fully with the enhanced security measures at airports in Australia and monitoring the situation closely," the airline said in a statement.

Manchester terrorist Salman Abedi reportedly returned from Libya just days before carrying out an attack that killed 22 people including seven children. Picture: AFP PHOTO / GREATER MANCHESTER POLICESource:AFP
Four men remain in police custody after raids at Sydney addresses over the weekend including Khaled Khayat and three others.
Khayat has no criminal history and was described by a man familiar with him as "very nice".
None have been charged yet and police have seven days in which to make inquiries.
"It should be noted that the presumption of innocence applies to these persons," AFP said in a statement.
"Investigations remain ongoing and further information will be provided at an appropriate time."
It's believed US and UK authorities tipped off Australian police as to the plot that was alleged to have been carried out "within days" after monitoring chatter in Syria.
Speaking to Reuters on condition of anonymity, US intelligence experts said the plans were "fairly well along". The UK Government would not confirm or deny its involvement.

Alleged terror plot suspects linked to IS
0:38

Four men arrested in Sydney over an alleged terror plot reportedly have clear links to IS figures overseas.

August 1st 2017
15 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Khaled Khayat is one of the men being held. He has not been charged.Source:Supplied
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull has hosed down speculation that Australian authorities missed signs a local terror plan was imminent, saying intelligence was a matter of co-operation between different countries.
Australian National University intelligence expert Professor John Blaxland says relying on international tip-offs shouldn't raise questions about the adequacy of Australia's intelligence services.
"What we know is that organisations like the AFP and ASIO have extensive networks of connections and liaisons arrangements with counterparts globally," Prof Blaxland told AAP.
"There's a mutual benefit - a mutual back-scratching exercise.
"That network is proving more and more useful and more and more important for countering potential terrorist acts."
- With Jamie McKinnell of AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Barton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie McKinnell of AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREATER MANCHESTER POLICESource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor John Blaxland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Libya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP PHOTO</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WILLIAM WESTSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Satan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syd Terror</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRUSSELS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Blaxland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WILLIAM WEST.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike McCaul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Airways</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Barton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chair of the US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TATP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salman Abedi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Terror</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
