<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406344133519048</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-life/win-tickets-to-see-placebo-at-ais-arena-in-canberra-20170731-gxmqey.html</url>
  <title>Win tickets to see Placebo at AIS Arena</title>
  <content>
Believe it or not, it's been 20 years since British alternative rock group Placebo burst onto the scene.
Their two decade career has produced seven albums with hit songs like Every You Every Me, Pure Morning and The Bitter End.Photo: Neon Black Communication
Even more impressively - the band is still touring, and they're heading to Australia this September.
You can live out your late-nineties fantasy and see the band live when they come to Canberra's AIS Arena on Thursday September 14, 2017.
While more recently Placebo has shunned playing their classic tracks, there's good news.
"Let's just say there will be songs in the set that I've sworn never to play again," said lead singer Brian Molko.

"I think it's time that we purposefully acknowledged what a lot of Placebo fans really want to hear. They've been very patient with us since we rarely play our most commercially successful material. A 20 year anniversary tour seems like the right time to do so."
They will be supported on tour by UK rockers Deaf Havana. Tickets are on sale now at .

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

WIN TICKETS
We have five double passes to give away to the Placebo concert at AIS Arena on September 14. To win, email your name and number to  and answer this question: Which year did Placebo release their debut self titled album?
Competition closes Monday August 7 at 5pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deaf Havana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Every You Every Me</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday September 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Molko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitter End.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIS Arena</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra's AIS Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neon Black Communication</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
