<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407374925690599</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/perth-stadium-gets-home-turf-advantage/news-story/4819798845263f3292de9af9afcbb46e</url>
  <title>Stadium gets 'home turf advantage'</title>
  <content>
IF FANS at Perth Stadium really want to be pedantic, they'll insist that any opening batsman or half back flank claiming a "home turf advantage" hails from Serpentine.
That's where 18,000sqm of grass was painstakingly planted, grown and harvested from yesterday for installation at the Burswood stadium ahead of its opening next year.
It was a big and complex operation that started at Greenacres Turf Group's farm, WA's biggest, about 77km south of Perth nearly two years ago.
In a state-of-the art turf system demanded by modern stadium operators and elite athletes for its evenness, stability and durability, fibres of artificial grass were infilled with sand where wintergreen, couch and rye seeds were planted.
The resulting hybrid system, 40mm thick and 10 per cent artificial grass, will be harvested from Greenacres in one-tonne, 10 metre-long strips over the next two to three weeks and rolled onto the playing surface at Burswood within 18 hours.
Greenacres Turf Group director Peter Pitsikas said the company was proud to be associated with what will become a significant WA venue, but despite also providing playing surfaces for both the Eagles' and Dockers' new training facilities, the local teams wouldn't necessarily have the edge at Perth Stadium.
"There won't be won't really be a home ground advantage because we've done AAMI Park, the MCG and ANZ Stadium," he said.
"If you looked at it you couldn't tell the difference (between 100 per cent natural grass), but it's a very durable, uniform consistent surface."
Hamish Sutherland, managing director of HG Sports Turf, which designed and constructed the sports field for Perth Stadium, said the stabilised turf system would provide durability for the venue's event's schedule which will include concerts as well as sports fixtures.
Five "grow lights" will be positioned on the northern side of the ground where about 7000sqm will be shaded during winter to provide light for photosynthesis and warmth to stimulate growth.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Pitsikas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HG Sports Turf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenacres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenacres Turf Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Stadium</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burswood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
