<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406395673128008</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/afghan-forces-lose-2531-troops-this-year/news-story/c6510e0c2163c0953517292efc19ca61</url>
  <title>Afghan forces lose 2531 troops this year</title>
  <content>
A total of 2531 Afghan security forces have been killed and 4238 wounded in the first four months of the year.
The figures released on Tuesday in a report compiled by the US Congress Special Inspector General for Afghanistan are consistent with those from the same period last year.
SIGAR said in February at least 6785 Afghan soldiers and police were killed in the first 10 months of 2016.
The figures, showing about 20 soldiers and police being killed every day, underline the challenge for the NATO-led training and advisory mission trying to build up Afghan security forces.
The United States is expected to send about 4000 troops to boost the mission but is yet to announce its long-awaited new strategy for the region.
US officials have warned repeatedly that Afghan forces have been suffering unsustainably high casualties against the Taliban partly because of tactics that include a heavy reliance on vulnerable checkpoints.
Last week 30 Afghan soldiers were killed in the southern province of Kandahar when their checkpoint was overrun by Taliban fighters.
US officers say troops defending checkpoints suffer as much as 10 times the level of casualties as they do during offensive operations.
However they have struggled to persuade Afghan commanders to cut their use, partly because local politicians say the checkpoints are needed as a visible sign of government presence in isolated areas.
The SIGAR report also quoted US commanders who assess the fighting between government and insurgent forces as a "stalemate", with government forces in control of 59.7 per cent of the country's 407 districts.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kandahar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taliban</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Congress Special Inspector General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATO-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIGAR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
