<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407422170332029</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/paddy-mccartin-should-wait-for-as-long-as-possible-to-make-return-says-justin-koschitzke/news-story/c1ad05d16e38dd4e943c4b6c3b591ed1</url>
  <title>Take your time, Paddy: Kosi</title>
  <content>
JUSTIN Koschitzke has urged luckless St Kilda forward Paddy McCartin to delay his return from a sixth concussion since 2014 for as long as possible, saying his own experience of head knocks still cause him short-term memory loss a decade on.
Koschitzke's cautionary warning comes as McCartin, 21, edges closer to a return in the VFL within the next fortnight having not playing since his latest concussion in late June. The Saints are insistent he won't be rushed in his comeback.
But the 34-year-old, who played 200 AFL games between 2001-2013, said the former No.1 draft pick needed to "listen" to his body and be completely honest with the medical staff.
COACH'S VIEW:
CALLING TIME:
"It is really hard (because) he is in the fishbowl of it all ... I do feel for him," Koschitzke said on this week's Talking Footy podcast.
"I've only met him a few times. He is a great kid ... (who) is a sponge for knowledge and wants to work hard."
"My advice is to go and make sure he is 100 per cent, and to be 100 per cent honest with the guys, the doctors, the neurologists and whoever it is he is talking to. Don't cloud over anything, listen to what your body is telling him."
Koschitzke sometimes struggles with short-term memory loss and worries about how his "horrendous (2006) year" might impact on him later in life.
"I feel like sometimes my short-term memory lets me down a little bit ... conversations that I've had yesterday or a couple of hours ago - if I don't write it down or take a note I can lose it pretty quick," he said on the podcast.
Asked about his concerns, he said: "Yeah it does (cause some worry) ... there's something in me that just doesn't want to know. You see stuff - you see Greg Williams come out and (say) he can't remember the middle name of his daughters."
Koschitzke was diagnosed with a fractured skull and burst ear drum after suffering a legal hip and shoulder from Western Bulldogs' Daniel Giansiracusa in a match in 2006.
Less than a month later he collapsed live on Channel Seven, with subsequent scans showing no abnormalities. On his return to football in a VFL reserves match later that year, he collided with an umpire, suffering yet another head knock.
He admitted he sometimes put his hand up to play when in hindsight he knows he wasn't in a fit state, mentally or physically.
Koschitzke went onto play in three AFL Grand Finals (for two losses and a draw) and he played his 200th game in the final round of 2013.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kosi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs' Daniel Giansiracusa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCartin, 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talking Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Grand Finals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JUSTIN Koschitzke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy McCartin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koschitzke</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
