<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406773630257208</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/18/25/demand-a-refund-gap-insurance</url>
  <title>How to get your money back for 'junk' insurance</title>
  <content>
If you've ever bought anything, you may have paid for added extras you don't need - without even realising it.
James Hensley admits when he bought a car, he was an easy target for the pushy salespeople who also convinced him to buy something called Gap Insurance for $1300.
"It was made out that you needed this Gap Insurance, you'd be a fool if you didn't get it," he told 9NEWS.
As it turns out, he didn't need the new policy at all - he was already covered by his comprehensive insurance. He's not the only one getting ripped off.
According to Susan Quinn of the Consumer Action Law Centre, consumers are paying half a billion dollars a year towards these junk products that include:
-Extended Warranties
-Consumer Credit Insurance

Related Articles

-Loan Protection Insurance
-Tyre and Rim Insurance
"Often people won't even realise they're being sold this add on insurance on warranties," Ms Quinn said.
But if you're a victim of this bad customer service, you can get your money back - and it's easy - through the Demand-A-Refund website.
James filled out the online form and received a full refund for his Gap Insurance.
Susan is urging everyone to check their policies, especially for car loans, insurance and credit cards.
"Australians have had enough of this junk insurance, it's profitable but it's not useful for the vast majority of people who buy it and it's being sold in ways that are not really ethical or fair," she said.
For more information go to: 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Quinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demand-A-Refund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Protection Insurance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gap Insurance</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Insurance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rim Insurance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Hensley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Quinn of the Consumer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Action Law Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
