<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407246076669269</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/television/top-of-the-lake-china-girl-stars-nicole-kidman-in-a-brutally-ugly-drama-you-cant-afford-to-miss/news-story/743cb6a30109f119006b87c2279be666</url>
  <title>Nicole's 'ugly' role you can't miss</title>
  <content>
****
FOR one of the most beautiful women in the world, Nicole Kidman is arguably at her best when she strips away the couture, the make-up and even her golden red locks and plays `ugly.'
Now, before the feminists beat me with her Academy Award, let me use her Oscar as exhibit A, won for her bulbous-nosed, emotionally-broken performance as author Virginia Woolf in the acclaimed 2003 biopic, The Hours.
It was a remarkable portrayal of the fragile literary figure, with Kidman disappearing into the role, which came with added intrigue as it did in the painful months after her divorce from first husband, Tom Cruise.
Back then, it was a prothetic nose that helped obscure the star's natural beauty.
In her latest incarnation -  - it's a shock of grey corkscrew curls and a face full of freckles, masking her famed red mane and porcelain skin - which focuses the audience's full attention on .
While hers is a supporting role - opposite lead actor Elisabeth Moss (wowing TV audiences now in A Handmaid's Tale) as damaged detective, Robin Griffin - these two women join forces to make this 'ugly' but unmissable TV and more proof, if any were needed, they are both actors truly in their prime.
Unlike her moving movie role in the recent Australian box office hit, Lion (when she played the adoptive mother of a lost Indian-born boy raised by a Tasmanian couple), Kidman's latest exploration of motherhood digs into darker territory, following her character's fractured and fractious relationship with her adopted daughter, Mary (Alice Englert, the real life daughter of the show's co-creator and director, Jane Campion).
The 17-year-old has been in search of her birth mum (Moss) since early adolescence, but it is only when the latter returns to Sydney from New Zealand (where the first season of TOPL was set) and agrees to meet the child she conceived in violence not love that this story gets even more dangerously tangled for all involved.
Mary - already acting out over her adoptive mother's decision to leave her husband (Ewen Leslie) for another woman - has her heart set on marrying a mysterious, older man, who raises parental suspicions when presenting himself as a university professor, who in reality is now an English tutor for Asian prostitutes at a local brothel.
It is one of their number who washes up on Bondi Beach, nameless but for a few DNA clues, which Moss must decipher to solve this tightly-woven murder mystery.
This is ugly, dark, oppressive stuff, and not a postcard of Sydney any tourism official will want going global (even if international critics who saw it at this year's Cannes Film Festival gave it - Moss and Kidman especially - rave reviews).
The women in this are all broken, in varying degrees; while the men are either misogynists, racists, impotent or brutally manipulative.
Sounds fun, huh?
Well, in the same way the show's first season and shows like Twin Peaks and True Detective drew such loyal audiences with their drip-drip-drip style of storytelling, this six-part psychological thriller seeps into you like the best book you can't put down.
With just two episodes teased to VIP guests and the media at its Sydney screening, its August 20 premiere, and the remaining four hour-long chapters, can't come quick enough.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moss</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Englert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twin Peaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TOPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Kidman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Handmaid's Tale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elisabeth Moss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>True Detective</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cannes Film Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ewen Leslie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Cruise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virginia Woolf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Campion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
