<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407460825038530</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/national/snake-found-wedged-in-toilet/news-story/273bc25973687a7723922c19881e137e</url>
  <title>Snake found wedged in loo</title>
  <content>
A SNAKE wedged in a toilet in a North Queensland home became so attached to the location it refused to leave.
Licenced snake catcher Leanne Colthup was last night called to a Charters Towers home where he found a carpet python in a toilet bowl.
When she arrived to capture the snake, it wedged itself up the s-bend in the toilet and refused to let go.
Mrs Colthup tried again later that night but was once again foiled.
She finally had success this morning after grabbing the python's head and yanking it loose before it had a chance to get a grip on the toilet.
The snake was later released into bushland as required by law.
Mrs Colthup said many snakes were adept at swimming.
She said the snake was quite strong and was frightened by humans.

"We think it came through the vent in the top of the toilet which is not covered in mesh - they're getting it covered today," she said.
Mrs Colthup said the snake was likely attracted to frogs and rodents in the area.
She said the elderly resident of the Southern Cross home was worried after finding the snake in the toilet.
"They've been there for 20 years and it's the first time there's been a snake in the home.
"Fortunately they had two toilets and were able to use the other one."
The ecologist, who teaches at All Souls St Gabriels School, said people should remain calm if a snake slithered into their home.
"Block off the exits and call a snake catcher. Keep an eye on it as it makes it easier to catch," she said.
It's the second time the volunteer snake catcher has wrangled a snake from a toilet.
"The last time was in Middlemount, a small mining town southwest of Mackay," she said.
"I found a pale-headed snake in the cistern."
She received a flood of messages after a photo of the snake in the toilet was posted on social media.
"There are lots of people freaking now out about using the toilet," Mrs Colthup said.
Continue the conversation in the comments below or with Andrew Backhouse on and .
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Backhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Cross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Souls St Gabriels School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leanne Colthup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Colthup</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charters Towers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middlemount</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
