<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407246076669193</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/university-harassment-must-end-say-sa-campuses/8764422</url>
  <title>SA unis vow to tackle 'culture of harassment' highlighted by Human Rights Commission</title>
  <content>
Adelaide's three major universities have expressed concern about sexual harassment findings in a landmark report and vowed to actively tackle the problem.
Survey results from campuses across the nation are  which found more than half of university students said they were sexually harassed at some time last year.
The major SA universities - Adelaide, Flinders and the University of South Australia - also released their individual reports as they committed themselves to changing a culture of harassment they conceded was a part of university life.
Across SA campuses, 2,114 students were surveyed.
Flinders' data, for example, indicated 25 per cent of the 73 students who said they were affected in 2016 cited a tutor or lecturer as the perpetrator.
Sixty three per cent pointed to another student.
Flinders vice-chancellor Colin Stirling said all sexual harassment reports would be investigated.
"[It is] wholly unacceptable and I would encourage students or staff to make a complaint, to register and report it with the necessary authorities," he said.
"These findings are of grave concern to me personally and I am committed to ensuring that we redouble our efforts to provide a safe and respectful environment for work and study for everyone at Flinders University.
"We've seen the majority of students at Flinders do know how to find support and register complaints [but] there are some who evidently don't."
Adelaide University interim vice-chancellor Mike Brooks agreed the data had pointed to under-reporting of concerns.
"We have improved online resources so students may more easily report incidents," he said.
"Extra counsellors have been engaged to provide additional support."
University of South Australia vice-chancellor David Lloyd also vowed to deal with the problem.
"No incidence of sexual harassment or assault is acceptable," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of South</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Stirling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Brooks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
