<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407465120005857</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/queensland-schools-failing-to-protect-students-from-sun-damage/news-story/aec878b70f6ed23ed1b62351aaaab608</url>
  <title>Schools failing to protect our kids</title>
  <content>
MOST Queensland schools are failing to ensure children are adequately protected from the sun, the Cancer Council has warned.
Cancer Council Queensland chief executive Chris McMillan said schools needed to do better, with a new survey finding less than half of all schools in the state provided sunscreen in every classroom.
The 2017 National Primary School SunSmart survey found while 92 per cent of schools promoted the use of sunscreen, fewer than half actually had it available in the every classroom.
And although 99 per cent of Queensland schools required children to wear hats, only four per cent also encouraged them to wear sunglasses.
Ms McMillan called on all schools to write and implement a sun protection policy, after the survey found less than two-thirds of the state's schools had done so.
She said children needed to be protected from skin cancer and eye damage, with 3650 melanomas diagnosed in Queensland every year.
"Sun-smart behaviours learned in childhood will help encourage sun safety well into their teenage and adult years," she said.
Junction Park State School students Gianni Seminara, 8, Edith O'Brien, 7, and Sam Windels, 7, are well trained in the art of sunscreen application, which their principal Christine Wood said was available in every classroom.
Mrs Wood said the school also enforced a "no hat, no play" policy on the oval and tried to keep students out of the sun during the hottest part of the day.
The Education Department was contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Windels, 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gianni Seminara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Junction Park State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edith O'Brien, 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris McMillan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McMillan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Primary School SunSmart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sun-smart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cancer Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
