<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406567471823073</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/rejuvenated-lion-daniel-rich-confident-of-derailing-dogs</url>
  <title>Rejuvenated Lion Daniel Rich confident of derailing Dogs</title>
  <content>
Daniel Rich believes the Lions are a good chance of knocking off the Bulldogs at the Gabba

DANIEL Rich is confident the Brisbane Lions can derail the Western Bulldogs' finals ambitions with an upset at the Gabba on Saturday.

While the Dogs are locked in a battle for the top eight, the Lions are waging their own war with North Melbourne and Carlton in a race to avoid the wooden spoon.

With Dayne Zorko to return from suspension, Dan McStay from a shoulder injury and youngsters Eric Hipwood, Hugh McCluggage and Jarrod Berry from a one-week rest, the Lions will be rejuvenated on their home ground.

Rich says despite a heavy loss to West Coast on Sunday, they believe their best football is good enough to cause surprises. 

"(In) matches in the past against very good teams, we've shown our footy can match it with any side in the competition," Rich said. 

"It's just a matter of playing that way for long enough.

"We back ourselves in every week."

When the teams met in round five at Etihad Stadium, the Lions shocked the Bulldogs by jumping to a six-goal lead before wilting in the final term.

"We probably played for three quarters in that game and a quality side like the Bulldogs, reigning premiers, overran us in the last quarter."

On a personal front, Rich is having his best year since rupturing his ACL early in 2014, capped by an equal career high 32-disposal performance despite close attention from the Eagles.

The 27-year-old said new coach Chris Fagan had changed his mindset. 

"When we spoke to 'Fages' earlier in the year before the season started, we spoke about having my best footy ahead of me and that's still the goal.

"I feel like I've got a lot of growth in me.

"The team playing better, it coincides with me being a bit more consistent and playing better footy."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gabba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan McStay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Rich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lion Daniel Rich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh McCluggage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Fagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Hipwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayne Zorko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fages</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
