<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406395673128056</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/business/breaking-news/govt-contract-losses-closures-hit-navitas/news-story/0dcbf03492a38dcd3bbeb3a71a84735b</url>
  <title>Govt contract losses, closures hit Navitas</title>
  <content>
Shares in education giant Navitas have fallen heavily after the company announced an 11 per cent drop in full year profit and said a decline in government-backed language training contracts had hurt the outlook for its English language training division.
The company's profit fell to $80.3 million in the year to June 30, while revenue dropped more than five per cent, largely on the back of the closure of two colleges in Sydney, Navitas said.
Underlying earnings before interest, tax, depreciation and amortisation were down 5.8 per cent at $155 million, in line with the company's guidance.
Chief executive Rod Jones said Navitas had experienced tighter market conditions in the US and the UK, and was streamlining the business' operating structure to deliver future growth.
"Despite delivering a result in line with our guidance, group revenue declined due to a number of factors including the final closures of two University Partnerships colleges," Mr Jones said.
The two Sydney colleges were ventures with Macquarie University and Curtin University.
Within Australia, Navitas has delivered government-contracted settlement services in English, education and employment pathways, focusing on migrants and refugees.
Navitas said its near-term earnings would be hit by a reduction in the size of contracts under the federal government-backed Adult Migrant Education Program (AMEP), and the shutdown of its two university partnership colleges.
"However, global demand for high quality education remains strong and is forecast to continue to grow in Navitas' key markets," the company said.
In April, Navitas said the latest round of AMEP contracts would result in a two-thirds reduction in contracted areas from the beginning of July.
Its shares dropped 50 cents, or 10 per cent, to $4.47.
NAVITAS HIT BY COLLEGE CLOSURES
* Full year net profit down 10.8pct to $80.3m
*Revenue down 5.5pct to $955.2m
* Final dividend up 0.2 cents to 10.1 cents, fully franked
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adult Migrant Education Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University Partnerships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAVITAS HIT BY COLLEGE CLOSURES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMEP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navitas</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
