<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407551019353472</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/entertainment/television/weather-conditions-wreak-havoc-as-kate-temby-is-sent-packing-on-australian-survivor/news-story/4a5dbac7ff03751cc85ddb8c348f9ab7</url>
  <title>Weak link sends Aussie Survivor packing</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE'S Kate's Temby has revealed dangerous cyclonic activity forced Australian Survivor contestants to stand up all night by the fire, brutal weather conditions that had an impact on the game.
Temby, 47, was the third person to be voted out on the show, after she couldn't build a strong enough rapport with some of her tribe members.
However much of the drama was a night before tribal council, where weather conditions in Samoa were so bad popular contestant Mark "Tarzan" Herlaar developed hypothermia.
'The weather was so tough," Temby said.
"We basically stood up around the fire all night one night, for twelves hours.
"It was intense.
"We wanted to keep that fire going, and we did."
Temby describe the whole experience as a bonding experience.
After her Samatau tribe lost the immunity challenge, which was nearly the unlosable after rival tribe member - Henry Nicholson - from the Asaga tribe, tried to through the challenge, Temby's name was always going to be on the chopping block.

After poker player Adam Park was voted out the vote before, it was always going to be her or Melbourne doctor Tessa O'Halloran.
In the end Temby received five votes, O'Halloran four, and Tara Pitt two.
Temby, and O'Halloran in particular, were furious at Pitt, who was formerly in their alliance.
Temby also couldn't understand why Herlaar ended up voting for her, with his vote ending up sending her home.
Despite going third, Temby said she loved every minute of her time on Australian Survivor.
"I was there for nine days and it was so intense, and I felt that I got a real flavour of the game, " she said.
"I was away from home for 25 days, and I got to reflect that to get on, and go through the whole process, was such a great thing.
"I always vowed to myself that when I was going to go to tribal, I would always vote how I said I was going to vote.
"I"m proud how I played, and you can't beat yourself up about it."
Australian Survivor will be back on Channel 10 next Sunday and Monday from 7.30pm.
It will now air for two nights a week, and not three, which was always going to be for the first week.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herlaar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Temby</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Survivor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarzans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tessa O'Halloran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie Survivor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Temby, 47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Kate Temby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Halloran</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samatau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
