<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406472982540772</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4827322/dangerous-surf-warning-issued-for-the-illawarra/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Dangerous surf warning issued for the Illawarra</title>
  <content>
Big surf at Sandon Point earlier this year. Photo: Sylvia Liber

Large and powerful waves are expected to slam the Illawarra coastline on Tuesday and Wednesday.

The Bureau of Meteorology has warned surf and swell conditions are expected to be hazardous for coastal activities such as rock fishing, boating and swimming.

Read more: 
The warning covers the Illawarra, Sydney, Hunter and Macquarie coastlines and is current until midnight, Wednesday.

The forecast for Wednesday is partly cloudy, with a slight chance of a shower along the coastal fringe.

Light winds are expected in the morning, with a top of 17 degrees and a low of 9 degrees predicted.
NSW Police Force, Marine Area Command advise that:

People should consider staying out of the water and avoid walking near surf-exposed areas.
Rock fishers should avoid coastal rock platforms exposed to the ocean and seek a safe location that is sheltered from the surf.
Boaters planning to cross shallow water and ocean bars should consider changing or delaying their voyage.
Boaters already on the water should carry the appropriate safety equipment and wear a lifejacket.
Boaters should remember to log on with their local Marine Rescue radio base, via VHF Radio or the Marine Rescue APP, and consider their safety management plan.
The next warning will be issued by 5pm Tuesday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Area Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VHF Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandon Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sylvia Liber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Rescue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Rescue APP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
