<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407503774712253</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/cricket/australian-test-captain-steve-smith-says-he-wishes-cricket-pay-dispute-was-kept-behind-closed-doors/news-story/5fedfbd1f7f13ff1dff63cbea06bb6f5</url>
  <title>Australian Test captain Steve Smith says he wishes cricket pay dispute was kept behind closed doors</title>
  <content>
'It's taken way too long'
7:04

Cricket: Former Australia coach John Buchanan talks to Fox Sports News about the closing days of the pay dispute.

August 1st 2017
10 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Cricket news and galleries/

Australian captain Steve Smith.

Steve Smith

Share

STEVE Smith has defended his decision not to be more outspoken in cricket's pay war and expressed disappointment that so much of the ugly battle has been played out in public.
The Australian captain confirmed that a final Heads of Agreement is close and gave a strong indication that although the players have had to make some compromises, the revenue share model will be retained.
In a candid interview on Fox Sports Back Page Live, Smith credited vice-captain David Warner for his forthright role as the public face of the players' fight, but argued that it was important for him as skipper to take a different path.
The 28-year-old has been criticised in some quarters for not presenting more prominently, but last night he detailed the active role he's played behind the scenes, even telling Cricket Australia head of team performance Pat Howard in one of their daily conversations that the players would not tour Bangladesh without an MOU in place.
With final details being worked through late into Tuesday night in the push for a joint announcement, Smith lamented the way elements of the saga have played out over the past nine months.
"I (would have) liked to see it more behind closed doors trying to get things done rather than out in public," Smith said.

Australian captain Steve Smith.Source:AAP
The skipper played down fears that irreversible damage has been done to the relationships between players and administrators, but admitted that he felt he had a tightrope to walk and chose to not enter into the public debate.
"First and foremost I'm supporting the players and the ACA. I think they've done a terrific job throughout this negotiation. But of course when this is all over with I have to deal with Pat Howard and the board and speak to James Sutherland, so I need to be careful with what sort of lines I tread," he said.
"Some guys have been really vocal on social media and the way for me to lead in this dispute is to be able to talk to the guys behind the scenes who are important, who are at the table, so I've been talking to them plenty and as I said, they've been making some really good progress and hopefully it's almost done.

"Obviously (David Warner) has been very vocal and he's supported the ACA through this whole thing and he's been great. I've chosen a different path."

Pay dispute all but over
1:02

Cricket: Robert Craddock has indicated the pay dispute is all but over between Cricket Australia and the Players Association.

August 1st 2017
12 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Cricket news and galleries/

As reported in The Daily Telegraph, Smith has been in regular contact with both Howard and ACA boss Alistair Nicholson in the countdown to the final deal.
"I told Pat Howard personally (we wouldn't tour) if there wasn't a deal done and the guys have worked extremely hard the last few days," he said.
"I know, I've had calls from Alistair Nicholson at midnight at the end of a day's work so they've been working incredibly hard and hopefully it's all coming to a head."
Asked what the deal looks like, Smith hinted that the revenue share model will be retained but with concessions made to suit Cricket Australia's desire for more financial flexibility.
"Yeah perhaps but we've said from ball one that the revenue share model for every player in Australia has been crucial for us," he said.
"That's something we've been incredibly strong on. And I must say the unity and strength the playing group have shown through this whole dispute has been outstanding.
"Particularly the Australia A guys to forgo that (South African) tour and an opportunity to put their foot forward for Australia, those guys showed some real courage and leadership. I've got to tip my hat off to them for what they did for the whole playing group in trying to get this resolved."
Meanwhile, Australia's Test tour of Bangladesh has been given a final security clearance as players await the finalisation of their new pay deal.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Buchanan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MoU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Former Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heads of Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Players' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Craddock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Warner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports Back Page Live</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair Nicholson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Smith</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Howard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
