<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407512364647025</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/hadouken-flamethrower-gloves-let-you-blast-street-fighter-fireballs-with-every-punch/</url>
  <title>Hadouken! Flamethrower Gloves Let You Blast Street Fighter Fireballs With Every Punch</title>
  <content>
Video: Hacker Allen Pan built a pair of custom gloves featuring a butane dispenser, parts from an electric arc lighter, and a motion sensor that automatically triggers a terrifying blast of fire with every detected punch.

Don't have billions of dollars at your disposal like Tony Stark or SHIELD do? You can still build some impressive superhero accessories like Iron Man's laser-blasting gauntlet or Captain America's boomeranging shield, using easily found electronics, a little ingenuity and some clever hacking.

Pan says he was inspired by Avatar: The Last Airbender and The Legend of Korra for this build, but to us these gloves are the perfect way to recreate Ryu's Street Fighter "hadouken!" fireballs in real life. If you want to build a pair for yourself (and we strongly advise against that for safety reasons) you can . Or you can try to master an ancient mystical fighting art that may or may not exist outside of a video game.

[]

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hacker Allen Pan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryu's Street Fighter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hadouken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Last Airbender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legend of Korra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
