<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406988378626309</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/private-health-insurance-forecast-to-become-more-unaffordable/8764756</url>
  <title>Private health cover forecast to become more unaffordable as insurers, doctors point finger</title>
  <content>
Do you have private health insurance? Are you considering cancelling or downgrading it because you can't afford it?
If you are, you're not alone.
According to Western Australia's biggest private health fund HBF -  - the number of its customers with top hospital cover halved in the past five years.
The body representing health insurance providers nationally, Private Healthcare Australia (PHA), warned that figure was only going to get worse.
PHA's chief executive Rachel David said private cover was forecast to become too expensive for many existing policy holders over the next five to six years.
"If premium rises occur at the same level they have over the last decade, about a fifth of people on our modelling are going to have serious issues with continuing to afford their private health insurance," she said.
Private cover has already become too much of a luxury for 64-year-old talkback radio caller Tony in Perth.
Tony this morning told ABC Radio Perth he had been looking for permanent work for two years and had been eating into his savings.
"I've been with private medical insurance for 30 years," he said.
"Last year I downgraded it from top hospital to base, and at $300 I just can't afford it anymore so I'm going to be binning it."
HBF executive Sasha Pendal said the industry had a responsibility to keep costs down.
"What we can't influence however are the prices set, for example, by private hospitals, by private specialists," she said.
We're not at fault: doctors

Australian Medical Association president Michael Gannon said it would be misleading to blame doctors.

"Because the moment a doctor charges one cent above the schedule that the insurer in their wisdom agrees to pay, they go all the way back to 75 per cent of the fee, so they actually pay less for those patients," he said.
"When it comes to egregious fee setting by my colleagues, the AMA, the College of Surgeons, other bodies stand against that.
"But the insurers cannot say that that's the problem because they do not pay when doctors charge above their scheduled fee."
Dr Gannon said the industry needed to stop signing customers up for things they did not need while excluding things they did.
"There are products available for male singles that include maternity cover, now that's simply silly," he said.
"Equally, maternity cover is a great example of an area where we need to see reforms.

"Pregnancies are normal, natural and physiological, and one of the things that the AMA is advocating for is that maternity cover is included in the so-called bronze products.
However, Ms David defended the insurance industry's maternity policies.
"Don't forget that people that are older are often on the highest levels of health fund cover because they know they're going to claim," she said.
"And they know those are the products that cover for things like hip and knee replacements as well, which are things that people need as they get older."
A senate committee looking into the value and affordability of private health insurance is due to publish its report in November.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>College of Surgeons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Gannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Healthcare Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasha Pendal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Gannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
