<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406902479278764</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/breaking-news/teen-dies-after-herding-bulls-on-wa-farm/news-story/8abb16a67352a4c9f0335b03baa0fb89</url>
  <title>Family mourns daughter after WA farm death</title>
  <content>
The devastated family of a 19-year-old West Australian woman have paid tribute to their "happy" daughter who died after being crushed by a bull at a farm
Alexandra Henderson, from Dalyup, was found unconscious on Monday morning and rushed by ambulance to Esperance Hospital in WA's south where she died from her injuries.
She was working at the farm at Dalyup herding the large bull when she was hit into a fence in a paddock.
The family said they were devastated by the sudden loss of their beautiful daughter Alexandra.
"We are consoled at this time by the fact that she was in a happy place at this time in her life," the family said in a statement.
Alexandra was working on a property she loved, with people she cared for and respected and who felt the same about her, they said.
While Alexandra was only young she had worked with animals her whole life, including cattle and was a competent horsewoman, breaking and training horses, they added.
"She was also a compassionate person who cared deeply about her world and the living things she shared it with," the family said.
"We are buoyed at this time by the fact that we have spent so much time with her, and that we live in a community which has supported us with an outpouring of love and support."
The family thanked paramedics and hospital staff for trying to save Alexandra.
Worksafe are investigating and a report is being prepared for the coroner.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esperance Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WorkSafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalyup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
