<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406391378160525</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826757/uow-responds-to-national-report-on-sexual-assault-and-harassment/?cs=300</url>
  <title>University of Wollongong welcomes national report into sexual assault and harassment at universities</title>
  <content>
REPORT: ​University of Wollongong chief administrative officer Melva Crouch talks about the new Australian Human Rights Commission report dealing with sexual assault and harassment at Australian universities. Picture: Adam McLean

Almost 50 per cent of University of Wollongong respondents to a national survey admitted to being sexually harassed in 2016.

UOW chief executive officer Melva Crouch said these numbers were horrible but important.

''It is important for us to know that number and to know that so much that happens is also unreported to us,'' she said.
Ms Crouch comments came as she addressed the media on Tuesday to give UOW's response to the damning findings of the new Australian Human Rights Commission report, which surveyed 31,000 students from all Australian universities.
''The University of Wollongong welcomes this report and accepts the key findings,'' she said.

''Sexual assault and sexual harassment are never okay. Even one incident is one incident too many.
- Melva Crouch
''We are determined to confront what is a difficult problem for universities, as it is for the wider community. That's why UOW fully supports the aims of the Respect. Now. Always. campaign.''

UOW's results, released by the university, are on par with the national reporting, which found more than a fifth of Australian students (21 per cent) were harassed on campus, and 1.6 in every 100 university students experienced sexual assault while at university in 2016.

But it also noted there was significant under reporting of these incidents to universities.

Students at the ​University of Wollongong. Picture: Adam McLean
''We are mildly encouraged by some of the results of this survey....UOW students who responded to the survey indicated an encouraging high report rate,'' Ms Crouch said.
''Sadly the vast majority of sexual assault and sexual harassment incidents still go unreported. We've been working hard to reverse this trend at UOW in recent years and will continue to try and streamline the process to make it easier.

- Melva Crouch
''We do need to pay more attention to encourage them to report. To make it easier to do so. To make it so a student doesn't have to bare their soul to four or five different people in order to get concessions on assignments and exams - all of that rolls into really trying to keep it to a one touch reporting process to minimise the angst that these students understandably feel.''

The university's response to sexual assault and sexual harassment is being similarly enhanced, with comprehensive education, support and policy improvements centred around its 'support first' approach to reported incidents, which aims to provide students the care and support they need as swiftly as possible.

UOW has conducted an initial policy and procedural review but will now undertake further reviews in light of the national report's recommendations.

''We're already working to prevent incidents, raise awareness, train students and staff and provide additional avenues of support for sexual assault and sexual harassment victims and survivors,'' Ms Crouch said.

A Sexual Assault and Sexual Harassment Support Hotline (1300 303 455) is available from 9am to 4.30pm weekdays.

A new 24/7 national universities support line, 1800 572 224, has also been established for anyone needing around-the-clock support and will be available until November 30.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexual Assault</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melva Crouch</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexual Harassment Support Hotline (1300 303 455</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Crouch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
