<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406606126529633</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65451/volkswagen-polo-runs-out-with-two-farewell-editions</url>
  <title>Volkswagen Polo Runs Out With Two Farewell Editions</title>
  <content>
As the current generation Volkswagen Polo comes to the end of its innings, Volkswagen has introduced a pair of swansong models to help send off its fifth-generation city car.
In place of the usual Trendline and Comfortline model variants, Volkswagen will instead offer the Polo in Urban and Urban+ trims until the sixth-generation Polo's arrival in March, 2018.
The Urban stakes the place of the previous entry-level Trendline with driveaway pricing that sees the five-speed manual version priced at $16,990 or the seven-speed dual-clutch DSG automatic at $19,490.

Compared to the Trendline, the Urban scores some extra equipment, with 15-inch alloy wheels, leather steering wheel, handbrake and gear shift knob, a multi-function dash display, illuminated vanity mirrors and Urban badging.
The Polo Comfortline bows out to make way for the Urban+ which costs $19,990 driveaway with a manual transmission or $22,490 driveaway when equipped with a DSG automatic.
Extra goodies included in the Urban+ package include 16-inch alloy wheels, front fog lights, tinted windows, auto headlights and wipers, driver fatigue monitoring and Urban+ badging.

The Urban+ also dresses up inside with Alcantara-trimmed heated front seats, auto-dimming rear-view mirror, climate control, footwell lighting, and chrome and silver cabin highlights. Buyers can also add Volkswagen's Drive Assistance Package to the Urban+ to add autonomous emergency braking, adaptive cruise control, front and rear parking sensors and satellite navigation.
Engines remain unchanged compared to the previous trim lines with a 1.2-litre turbocharged petrol engine producing 66kW and 160Nm in the Polo Urban or a more powerful 81kW and 175Nm version in the Urban+.

Pricing

Polo Urban manual - $16,990
Polo Urban DSG automatic - $19,490
Polo Urban+ manual - $19,990
Polo Urban+ DSG automatic - $22,490
Driver Assistance Package - $1800
Metallic paint - $500
Driveaway pricing including on-road costs.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comfortline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen's Drive Assistance Package</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polo Comfortline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistance Package - $1800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alcantara-trimmed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen Polo Runs Out With Two Farewell Editions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polo Urban DSG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polo Urban</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Driveaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volkswagen Polo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DSG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
