<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406734975550922</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/work/anthony-scaramucci-fired-after-just-11-days-by-donald-trump/news-story/06c31b6b6400bed4859d81c762f6ba52</url>
  <title>11 stunning disasters in 11 days</title>
  <content>
HE was spectacularly dumped as White House communications director after just 11 days in the job.
But that didn't mean Anthony Scaramucci's time wasn't filled with a lot of colour, a fair bit of swearing and a few personal sagas along the way.
Here's how the week and a half went down for the colourful and potty-mouthed wealthy financier.
1. HE IGNITED CIVIL WAR IN THE WEST WING
The brash Wall Street executive didn't waste any time in making it clear he wanted to completely up-end the West Wing. He targeted big names in Trump's team, and from the start questioned whether anyone was truly loyal to the President.
"The President and I would like to tell everybody we have a very, very good idea who the senior leakers are in the White House," he said.
"The fish stinks from the head down. But I can tell you two fish that don't stink, that's me and the President."
2. HE FORCED RESIGNATIONS
Before he was even officially hired, former White House spokesman Sean Spicer said he couldn't work with him, and told Trump he was walking. He probably made a wise decision, because as soon as he started, Scaramucci started his crusade against chief strategist Steve Bannon and then Chief of Staff Reince Priebus. Priebus in particular was targeted, most spectacularly in a foul-mouthed tirade in the New Yorker. He quit the next day.
3. HE SWORE ... A LOT
The New Yorker interview was extraordinary not only for the fact he openly declared war on his Chief of Staff - technically his boss - but the incredible attacking tone. In the phone call with the New Yorker's Ryan Lizza he said he was going to "f***ing kill all the leakers".
"Reince is a f***ing paranoid schizophrenic, a paranoiac," he said, referring to Mr Priebus.
"I'm not Steve Bannon, I'm not trying to suck my own c**k."
4. 'ALL OF THEM WILL BE FIRED BY ME'
Scaramucci seemed to be under the impression that he had much more power than a normal White House communications director. He was clearly out to fire a lot of people, including assistant press secretary Michael Short. In an interview with Politico he confirmed his plans.
But when , Mr Short didn't know anything about it and resigned before he was fired.
5. HIS WIFE FILED FOR DIVORCE
Scaramucci's personal life has also been in shambles. In the short period he was employed in the White House, he was also dumped by his wife Deidre Ball, reportedly because of his "naked political ambition."
According to the , she filed for divorce after three years of marriage, becoming fed up with his ruthless quest to get close to the President Trump.
A post told Page Six: "She is tired of his naked ambition, which is so enormous that it left her at her wits' end."
6. HE MISSED THE BIRTH OF HIS SON
The Mooch was already in the middle of a marriage breakdown when he took the White House job. But that wasn't all that was going on in his personal life. His wife had , the New York Post revealed.
When she gave birth a few days after he took the role, Scaramucci sent his wife a text saying: "Congratulations, I'll pray for our child" and didn't meet his son James until four days later.
7. HE SET RECORDS
Serving just 11 days in the job, July 21 to July 31, Scaramucci holds the shortest time in the post of any communications director in history, the reported.
He was ousted just hours after President Donald Trump's new chief of staff, John Kelly, was sworn into office.
8. HE DELETED EMBARRASSING TWEETS
Scaramucci was once a vocal critic of Mr Trump.
While hosting Wall Street Week in 2015, he called Mr Trump "another hack politician" who was "probably going to make (left-wing Democrat) Elizabeth Warren his vice-presidential nominee", the  reported.
Then on his second day in the White House, Scaramucci deleted a series of tweets where he took a swipe at Mr Trump in 2012, calling him an "odd guy with no judgment."
He later said his past views shouldn't serve as a distraction and he served the POTUS.

Full transparency: I'm deleting old tweets. Past views evolved & shouldn't be a distraction. I serve  agenda & that's all that matters
9. HE BACKTRACKED ON CRITICISM
During the 2016 election campaign, Scaramucci mocked Mr Trump's business judgments and called him "an inherited money dude from Queens County",  reported.
At his first question-and-answer session at the White House last week, Scaramucci was forced to take those comments back.
"I should have never said that about him," said. "I love the President."
10. HE LOST THE CONFIDENCE OF THE TRUMPS
It has been reported that initially key presidential advisers Jared Kushner and Ivanka Trump were keen to bring Scaramucci in, as a way to force out Mr Priebus. The New York Times reports that by the weekend, the President, along with his daughter and son-in-law, had changed their mind about the destructive nature of Scaramucci, seeing him as a political liability and potential embarrassment.
In addition, new Chief of Staff John Kelly called the Mooch's comments "abhorrent and embarrassing for the president". The Washington Post reported Trump believed removing him was crucial to getting the White House back in order.
And in the words of the White House announcement, Scaramucci said he was leaving because he "felt it was best to give Chief of Staff John Kelly a clean slate and the ability to build his own team."
11. HE WAS LISTED AS DEAD
To top off his rough week and a half, Scaramucci was also wrongly declared dead.
He was listed as deceased in the new Harvard Law School alumni directory, the  reported.
An asterisk by his name indicated he was reported dead since the last directory was published in 2011.
It was unclear whether it was a prank or typo, but the school told the Post it was an error and would be corrected in subsequent editions.

Harvard has apologised for listing ousted White House communications director Anthony Scaramucci as dead.

Harvard sorry for listing Scaramucci as dead
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DELETED EMBARRASSING TWEETS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BIRTH OF HIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SET RECORDS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Short</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CONFIDENCE OF THE TRUMPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Page Six</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard Law School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIFE FILED FOR DIVORCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IGNITED CIVIL WAR IN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Politico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker's Ryan Lizza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FORCED RESIGNATIONS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queens County</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Priebus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>POTUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Short</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanka Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BACKTRACKED ON CRITICISM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LISTED AS DEAD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deidre Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WILL BE FIRED BY ME</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
