<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407503774712244</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/entertainment/confidential/radio-star-mel-greig-says-she-wants-a-man-not-a-dk-pic-after-revealing-a-flurry-of-hot-sex/news-story/93292336c4e70748cb432a6912aafa2d</url>
  <title>Mel Greig wants man not d**k pic</title>
  <content>
SINGLE breakfast radio announcer Mel Greig has revealed she is "lonely" despite living a life of "a flurry of hot sex and fun encounters."
The 24-year-old opened up in her most recent blog for YahooBe in a column titled, .
Greig detailed her "testing week" where she felt lonely for the first time in a year.
"I'd love to say that single life is a flurry of hot sex and fun encounters, well it is, BUT it's also a life of feeling lonely," she wrote.
"I'm ready to love again. So, where is he? I thought he was just going to appear when I clicked my fingers. But these things take time and because of the heartache I went through, the screening process is a little bit more ruthless. To be honest I'm also sabotaging some opportunities before they've even blossomed because I can see that down the track, I might get hurt.
"Feeling lonely means that you want to share your vulnerable moments with someone, to feel safe in someone's arms, and know that after a tough day there is a hug there waiting for you if you need it. To keep you company when your own company isn't enough in that moment. That's what I miss and that's what I needed this week... not a d*ck pic."
Greig and ex husband Steven Pollock married in November 2014, with , while Pollock was on holidays with friends in Nepal.
Greig added in her blog post "to take some time off from social media" as her final piece of advice.
"It's not real. All you see on Instagram is the perfect and flawless lives of everyone, you don't see the flaws #guilty," she wrote.
"It's ok to be vulnerable but only if you understand why, and only if you shake away those negative vibes and pick yourself up and keep on going. Talk to your girlfriends about it BUT definitely don't go to a bar and crumble into a stranger's arms screaming "Why won't you love me?" Defs not a good idea, and neither is drunk texting #guilty #takeawaymyphone."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greig</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel Greig</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Pollock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YahooBe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pollock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nepal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
