<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406734975550952</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/wests-tigers-study-bulldogs-salary-worry-in-hope-of-retaining-skipper-aaron-woods-20170801-gxn6i0.html</url>
  <title>Wests Tigers study Bulldogs salary worry in hope of retaining skipper Aaron Woods</title>
  <content>
The Wests Tigers are keeping a close eye on the events unfolding at Canterbury and whether there may be a chance of hanging onto skipper Aaron Woods for next season.
It's no secret Canterbury have some massive salary cap issues for next season. They've already been told they have until the start of the 2018 season to be salary cap compliant or the most recently signed players won't be able to play. The Tigers know this and are watching on with interest.Photo: NRL Photos
What may come as a surprise is how happy Woods is at the Tigers after such a turbulent time during protracted contract negotiations that dominated the headlines for the first half of the season.
There was a time when Woods wanted the season to come to an end after being booed by his own supporters and feeling uncomfortable in a place that has long been home for him.
But there has been an obvious difference in Woods' demeanour around the place and he appears to be in a good frame of mind as his time draws to an end at his junior club.
That hasn't been lost on the Wests Tigers powerbrokers, who are wondering whether the Bulldogs' salary cap predicament might afford the NSW and Australian prop a small window of opportunity to rethink his future.

They took note when earlier this month Woods declared he might have stayed at the club had they signed coach Ivan Cleary sooner.
Woods is fond of Cleary's coaching philosophy and has grown to admire the new Tigers boss. 
As was  alluded to in this column a couple of months ago, Woods was so upset with the treatment from the Wests Tigers during the contract talks that he ignored chairwoman Marina Go in the sheds after one of their games.
That relationship now appears to be on the mend and judging by a tweet out by Go after the victory against the Titans on Sunday, Woods is still well respected by those that matter at the club.
"Try to captain @aaronwoods11 and @WestsTigers get a well-deserved win. #NRLTitansTigers," Go tweeted.
The Tigers still have some money in the salary cap after missing out on Connor Watson and they would be able to afford Woods if circumstances were to change in the near future.
If the salary cap is finalised at $9.2 million for next season, the Bulldogs will need to shed a number of players, given that it is understood they have close to $10 million worth of talent on their books for 2018.
It's unclear whether Woods would even want to remain at the Tigers if the opportunity presented itself, but at this stage the Bulldogs have not contemplated letting him go.
Woods' signature has been met with mixed reactions from Canterbury fans, although there is no denying the club values what he can bring both on and off the field, not to mention the influence he will have on good friend David Klemmer.
Brett Morris has attracted interest from the English Super League clubs, while the Bulldogs know they need to offload Greg Eastwood in order to get close to being salary cap compliant for next year.
Bulldogs officials have outlined a plan to the NRL about how they intend to become cap compliant, although rival clubs are well aware of how desperate Canterbury are to shed players and are holding off in a bid to bag players at a bargain price.
A Panther pads

At least Corey Harawira-Naera knows he can trust Penrith Panthers teammate Nathan Cleary. During his contract negotiations a couple of months ago, Harawira-Naera went out to the Cleary residence to meet with Ivan Cleary about the prospect of joining him at the Wests Tigers next season. There was Nathan, lurking in the background.
"It was pretty funny. We had a meeting with him at his place and Nathan was home," Harawira-Naera said. "He had to keep a quiet mouth around here. He couldn't really say anything. It was a bit weird. But Ivan is a nice guy. He did have me sold. It was hard to backdoor it on him, but I'm glad I did because I never wanted to leave. Ivan knew that I didn't want to leave, so when he found out Penrith placed an offer he knew my mind would have changed real quick.
"I was pretty close to going there. It was a bit hard because my mind was made up to go to the Tigers, but once they showed interest here, I wouldn't say I backflipped but it changed my mind. I didn't want to leave the Panthers. As soon as the opportunity came up to stay, I signed straight away. I'm really humbled and blessed the Panthers offered me a few more years. I owe them and I'm in debt to them for what they've done and the faith they've shown in me."
Kangaroos feel heat

The Kangaroos incumbents in the outside backs are under pressure to retain their spots ahead of this year's World Cup. Darius Boyd and Will Chambers are considered certainties to be included, but Josh Dugan and Blake Ferguson are no guarantees for selection. Cowboys centre Justin O'Neill has all but been scratched from contention, with Australian coach Mal Meninga looking at James Roberts, James Tedesco, Dylan Walker, Latrell Mitchell, Dane Gagai and Tom Trbojevic to fill the back-line positions. Billy Slater will also come into the mix after an impressive return to representative football for the Maroons, while forgotten man Josh Mansour will be given every chance to return to the fold after his 2016 Four Nations campaign was brought to a sudden halt by an anterior cruciate ligament injury. Cronulla fullback Valentine Holmes needs a strong finish to the year to cement his place in the team after making his Test debut last year.
Where's the sponsor?

How can the Parramatta Eels go 21 rounds and still not have a major sponsor in place? We're talking about arguably the biggest Sydney club, if not the biggest in the NRL, who are about to end an eight-year finals drought after enduring a season from hell last year. They are hugely popular with the television networks given the ratings they draw, they have a brand new stadium being built and are undergoing massive renovations at their Leagues Club. All looks well out Parramatta way, yet they still haven't landed a major sponsor. Shouldn't they be lining up out the door? They were asking for $1.2 million a season for the right to their front of jersey.
Green armband history

​Penrith players didn't wear the green RLPA arm bands designed to show the unity of the playing group against the Bulldogs last Thursday night. They intended to, but one Panthers player told us Phil Gould asked the group to take them off. It seems as though Gould and Wayne Bennett both felt the same in regards to the initiative from the RLPA.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Harawira-Naera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gould</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Cleary</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Eastwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harawira-Naera</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Woods</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Gagai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latrell Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin O'Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Trbojevic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL Photos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleary</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dugan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Gould</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Mansour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRLTitansTigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WestsTigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Eels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Klemmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentine Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RLPA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith Panthers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Chambers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Super League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mal Meninga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darius Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Cleary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leagues Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Tedesco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Go</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
