<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407503774712293</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/japans-asahi-kasei-homes-buys-40pc-of-mcdonald-jones-20170801-gxmvkt</url>
  <title>Japan's Asahi Kasei Homes buys 40pc of McDonald Jones</title>
  <content>
Japan's Asahi Kasei Homes has joined the wave of Japanese companies buying into the Australian housing boom after acquiring a 40 per cent stake in Newcastle-based McDonald Jones Homes, the country's sixth biggest detached home builder and biggest in NSW.
MJH Group, which includes Queensland builder Mojo Homes, Tasmania's Wilson Homes, Hayman Homes and medium-density builder MJH Multi, turns over almost $500 million a year and is one of the country's fastest growing residential builders, according to the HIA Housing 100 Report.
AKH joins the likes of Sekisui House (Central Park Sydney), Sumitomo Forestry Group (majority owner of home builders Wisdom Group and Henly Group), Obayashi Corporation and construction giant Kajima (majority owner of Melbourne builder and developer Icon) with big presences in the Australian residential building sector as they struggle for growth opportunities in the weaker Japanese economy.
AKH, a subsidiary of listed Japanese conglomerate Asahi Kasei Corporation, delivers over 8000 homes a year and has a target of reaching net sales of ¥1 trillion ($11.3 billion) by 2025.

AKH noted in a statement that the NSW market where MJH is ranked first "holds the greatest promise in Australia fuelled by a continuously growing population".

MJH Group is expected to generate $620 million in revenue in FY17, up from $486 million in FY16. Profits lifted 57 per cent to $10.5 million in FY16.
Top of the list

Founder Bill McDonald, chairman Peter Durbin and managing director Andrew Helmers will each retain 20 per cent shares in MJH Group with AKH to gain seats on the company board.
Mr Helmers said Australia, New Zealand and Canada were at the "top of the list" for investment by successful Japanese building businesses like AKH given the more limited opportunities at home due to "negative population growth and almost negative economic growth".

"The expansion into the Australian market by AKH enhances our already robust financial position, and provides new opportunities in research and development, home design and construction which will be of great benefit to our customers," Mr Helmers said.
"The housing market has come off it its peak, but there's an under-supply of homes in Australia and NSW so it will settle at a much higher level [than in the past]."
Mr Helmers said expanding into Victoria was "still on the agenda" but not something it would rush into.
MJH has built up a 15.9 per cent stake in Victorian building group Simonds Group and used it to block a buyout by the family of founder Gary Simonds in November. Mr Helmers said there were no plans at this stage to increase that stake though it was always "looking for opportunities".

"We bought a stake in Simonds because we thought it offered good value for money and still see it as good value for money given the growth potential in that business," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MJH Multi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIA Housing 100 Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sumitomo Forestry Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MJH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henly Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Helmers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayman Homes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Asahi Kasei Homes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Simonds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sekisui House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania's Wilson Homes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kajima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asahi Kasei Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle-based McDonald Jones Homes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MJH Group</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Park Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Durbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wisdom Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mojo Homes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obayashi Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FY17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FY16</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Helmers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AKH</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
