<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407503774712277</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/3330779/illawarra-dads-celebrate-special-day/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Illawarra dads celebrate special day</title>
  <content>
Michael Baker and Katherine Baker with baby Chloe Baker, who was born at Wollongong Hospital on Father's Day. Picture: ROBERT PEET

It was a day of new arrivals, heartfelt messages and top honours for dads across the Illawarra on Sunday.
In the northern suburbs, a team from Thirroul and Austinmer Anglican churches had organised a 'Message to Dad' campaign with local cafes and a newsagent.
Children enjoying breakfast or lunch with dad at a participating cafe wrote special messages and posted them on boards, while dad received a free coffee and newspaper.
Thirroul dad Jason Squires, who went for breakfast at Seafoam Cafe with wife Emily and his four sons, said it was a nice touch.
''It was really great getting a nice message from the boys and it was great to read the other kids' messages on the board too,'' he said. ''It made my day.''

Jack Squires, 8, Emily Squires, Charlie Squires, 5, Jason Squires and Oscar Squires, 2, enjoying Father's Day breakfast at Seafoam Cafe, Thirroul. Picture: ROBERT PEET
Anglican Reverend Steve Dinning said the campaign aimed to give dads something more than ''socks or jocks'' on Father's Day.
The aim is to inspire fathers, and grandfathers, to bear the challenge, carry the responsibility and enjoy the privilege, he said.
The church group even wrote to the Prime Minister's office for a message, with Tony Abbott sending them his ode to Father's Day.
''From the age of eight to 12, every weekday, I walked the couple of kilometres from home to the railway station with my dad before the train ride to school,'' Mr Abbott wrote.
''The haze of time has obscured most of our conversation, but I do clearly recall dad's insistence that it was better to be a good person than a successful one.''
Meantime more than 100 dads across the region vied for the top spot in the Lighthouse Best Dads Awards. 
Two dads stood out - Joshua Mitchell and Mark Netherclift, both of Albion Park Rail.
Awards founder Paul Bartlett said the two dads had both stepped up for their kids while supporting their wives through ill health, and the awards honour their efforts.
At Wollongong Hospital, new dads held their tiny offspring tight, with little Chloe Baker the perfect Father's Day present for Michael Baker of Cordeaux Heights.
It was an early start to the day for Mr Baker, rushing wife Katherine to hospital at 4am before Chloe's arrival at 8.23am. 
''Our first child, Felicity, was born on her due date, but Chloe waited for the day after her due date to come on a national day of celebration,'' Mrs Baker said.

''It'd be hard to top this Father's Day present,'' Mr Baker said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Squires, 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Netherclift</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Squires</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe Baker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felicity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar Squires, 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Squires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican Reverend Steve Dinning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBERT PEET</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Squires, 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joshua Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seafoam Cafe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austinmer Anglican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Baker of Cordeaux</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park Rail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Father's Day</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lighthouse Best Dads Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Baker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Bartlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
