<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406558881888304</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/jungle-edge-back-in-the-groove-for-missile-stakes/news-story/da21eedc311845d461e543a3d53b8737</url>
  <title>Jungle Edge back in business</title>
  <content>
CRANBOURNE trio Mick Bell, Kevin Forrester and Jungle Edge have developed a cult following after their heroics during the Sydney autumn carnival.
It extended further to Brisbane in winter before coming to an end on firming ground at Doomben in June when Jungle Edge beat one runner home in the Stradbroke Handicap.
WARWICK FARM:
GOOD TRIAL:
Bell has endured a tough six months after his wife Beverley died from breast cancer earlier in the year, but Jungle Edge has given the trainer his career highlights.
Two Group 3 wins and three Group 1 placings in Sydney and Brisbane have Bell looking for wet tracks during the spring.
Sent for a break following the Stradbroke, Jungle Edge makes his return in the Group 2 Missile Stakes (1200m) at Randwick on Saturday.
Bell has also nominated the gelding for Sunday's rescheduled Bletchingly Stakes at Sandown, but the predicted rain in Sydney has influenced Bell to look north.
"The entry for the Bletchingly was made just in case we got a power of rain but that doesn't look like happening, so I don't think I'll even accept," Bell said. "He'll probably be short of a run on the weekend but he's stripping nice and fit, however it would have been good to get a trial into him first."
Bell said Jungle Edge had freshened up at Aquis Farm in Queensland following the Stradbroke with work on the water walker and swimming.
It coincided with Bell taking his first trip overseas where he based himself in Greece and took the opportunity to travel to Newmarket in England and Chantilly in France.
"I even got an invite to the Greek Derby," Bell said. "I tried to be an ambassador for Australian racing as much as I could."
Jungle Edge has been in Sydney for two weeks and Bell said he worked well at Rosehill on Tuesday morning. The weather will dictate Jungle Edge's campaign going forward.
"I feel the tracks down here (Melbourne) drain too well," Bell said. "I'd be lucky to get something to suit and I think our best chances are in Sydney. I've been incredibly lucky with the weather at times so I have to learn to be patient."
Meanwhile, Clarry Conners has three nominations for the Missile Stakes but will just take one shot at it. The veteran trainer indicated only Bolero King would be given an opportunity on Saturday to bounce back from a difficult run at the same track on July 22, when the five-year-old over-raced early and was then blocked for a run.
"He never got a clear crack at them," Conners said. "He's a big horse and he was tightened up and couldn't stretch out where he was."
Bolero King needed a plate replaced at the barriers and then struggled to settle on several occasions after Kerrin McEvoy slipped him back to the rail.
"Last time we ended up where he shouldn't have been back on the fence," Conners said. "It went wrong the other day and Kerrin suggested we forget he went around. "He knows the horse now and he'll go well on him."
Conners was confident Bolero King would perform better if he stuck to his usual forward race pattern. Despite Bolero King's unfancied status in early markets, Conners said black-type was a viable target this preparation after he wrapped up his previous campaign with a third in the Listed Canberra Guineas (1400m) in March.
Bolero King was also nominated for a Benchmark 80 Handicap (1200m) while stablemates Dorf Star and He's A Given were also in the mix for a Benchmark 80 (1400m) before the fields were finalised on Wednesday.
With Randwick classified in the soft range on Tuesday, only He's A Given was likely to find the ground suitable and Dorf Star could be held in reserve for another week.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrin McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stradbroke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conner</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosehill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aquis Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Missile Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolero King</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bletchingly Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doomben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greece</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Forrester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benchmark 80 (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benchmark 80 Handicap (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chantilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newmarket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarry Conners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group 2 Missile Stakes (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jungle Edge</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beverley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stradbroke Handicap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorf Star</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek Derby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bletchingly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Listed Canberra Guineas (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
