<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406339838551656</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/art-and-design/sydneys-underwood-street-grows-a-tree-of-awe-and-wonder-20170728-gxkvis.html</url>
  <title>Tree of awe and wonder suspended over Sydney laneway</title>
  <content>
In literary circles trees, are often powerful symbols of perseverance, hope, beauty and wisdom.
In a CBD laneway, a tree has been tipped on its side and suspended 10 metres above ground as a tangible connection to Sydney's colonial and Indigenous past.Photo: Steven Siewert
The mature eucalypt with massive root ball attached has been trucked and craned into the CBD from a south coast timber yard, part of a unique collaboration between the National Art School and property developer Mirvac. 
The trunk is attached by cable and bracket to three land bridges. At one end the branches sit and at the other the root ball, conveying a sense of awe in nature among the soaring office towers.Photo: Steven Siewert
Underwood Ark, to be officially opened Thursday, is the work of visual artist and National Art School graduate Michael McIntyre, who was selected from a group of four student artists to develop an art installation that would enliven Underwood Street.
Each contender was given a small budget and a two to three-month time frame to develop an idea. Mr McIntyre's ark was awarded the public commission.    

The artist said his simple and poetic aim was to trigger reflection about the past, remind pedestrians of the natural landscape and connect with the cove's Indigenous guardians.
"It is a pretty unremarkable laneway but has a really remarkable history," Mr McIntyre said.
"Through the years since British settlement, the area has been a centre for ship building, commerce and trade but the image of the stream flowing through the site prior to British invasion was the strongest and most resounding: a pristine landscape full of trees, grasslands, mangroves, birds, animals and home to the Gadigal people of the Eora nation. The tree emerged as a possible symbol for all this."
The timber was selected by the artist for its strength, height and straight growing habit from a forest in Tomerong, three hours south of Sydney.
The tree was cut and stripped of its bark and leaves and the root ball cleaned and sculpted. As it ages and weathers, the blackbutt will develop a silvery grey colour.
The Underwood Ark is a "symbolic vessel that carries the history of this particular place, floating down the once existing stream," Mr McIntyre said. "Laying on its side, the tree becomes a boat, an ark floating down Underwood Street."
Underwood Ark is the first project realised through Mirvac's partnership with the art school, which began in 2014 and encourages emerging artists from the school to produce artwork for Mirvac developments.
National Art School director Steven Alderton said public art commissions were a way for students to build their careers post graduation.
"We are really interested in working with corporate entities and government and foundations to create an environment whereby we can bring the best out of our students and create opportunities for all artists, not only our graduates, and to make public spaces places for everyone to enjoy."
.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Alderton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomerong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McIntyre</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Art School</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Siewert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirvac</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael McIntyre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Underwood Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Underwood Ark</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gadigal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
