<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407121522614964</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/latest-news/kidman-sparkles-on-sydneys-red-carpet/news-story/c0588e1428f8c325c775e3939936a013</url>
  <title>Kidman sparkles on Sydney's red carpet</title>
  <content>
Oscar-winner Nicole Kidman confidently walked the red carpet for the Sydney premiere of Top of the Lake: China Girl, but admitted she had felt nervous about the role.
The actress, who is filming superhero movie Aquaman on the Gold Coast, came home on Tuesday to appear at the Sydney Opera House for the second-season premiere of Jane Campion's acclaimed TV series.
But, as a fan of the director and the first season of the show, Kidman admitted she was nervous going into this one.
"Jane said this will be a really bold character and that's what I'm interested in," Kidman said on the red carpet.
"This series, the first one was so good, I was nervous because I wanted to be able to deliver for her."
Kidman looks older in the series with a mop of grey hair and added sunspots; a different look for the glamorous actress who wore a champagne sparkly Zuhair Murad tulle gown.
But the actress loved the transformation and how she could lose herself in a role that attracted her for its "spicy and honest" dialogue.
"I got off that plane and I went straight to rehearsal and I felt so at ease and relaxed and at home, in a way. We have good food, good conversation and then we rehearse rigorously," she said.
Top of the Lake: China Girl was shot in Sydney last year and follows detective Robin Griffin, played by American actress Elisabeth Moss (The Handmaid's Tale), as she returns to Sydney from New Zealand and investigates the death of an Asian girl whose body has washed up on Bondi Beach.
Kidman plays Julia, the adopted mother of Mary, who is played by director Jane Campion's real-life daughter Alice Englert. Mary is the biological daughter of Robin, who has returned to Sydney to reconnect with her daughter.
Kidman has been working frequently at home, having filmed the Oscar-nominated film Lion in Australia, Top of the Lake and now Aquaman over the past few years.
"I love being here and I love being a part of this industry. I love being able to use my own accent," she said.
"I just used my accent again in an American film where they said to me, 'she was written American' and I said 'I think it would be better if she was Australian' and they went 'yeah OK'. It was with Kevin Hart and Bryan Cranston, The Upside, I play a supporting role in that but I'm an Aussie in that."
* Top of the Lake will air on BBC First from August 20 at 8.30pm
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Englert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin Griffin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar-nominated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aquaman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Handmaid's Tale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elisabeth Moss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zuhair Murad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidman</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Girl</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryan Cranston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC First</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Campion</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Opera House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Hart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top of the Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar-winner Nicole Kidman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
