<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406382788225709</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/17/03/mahmoud-hrouks-father-recalls-conversation-with-man-accused-of-murdering-his-son</url>
  <title>Mahmoud Hrouk's father recalls conversation with man accused of murdering his son</title>
  <content>
A Sydney father has recalled his conversation with the man now accused of murdering his son in Sydney's southwest.
Azzam Hrouk says he went to Aymen Terkmani's house in Fairfield East on the night his 16-year-old son disappeared.
He told the Supreme Court he asked the 24-year-old if he had seen Mahmoud Hrouk.

He alleged Terkmani replied "Mahmoud who? I don't know of any Mahmouds."
"I said to him 'Mahmoud Hrouk, that's my son and I am his father'."
"He raised his voice and said 'so what do you want?'
"I said to him 'my wife and my son had passed in front of your house at about 11 o'clock and saw my son's bicycle'

Related Articles

"He said 'I know nothing I have just returned home'."
Terkmani eventually claimed to have left the teenager at another friend's house earlier in the evening. 
But Mahmoud's bike was found outside a vacant home in Belmore Street.
His body was inside in a pool of blood, he had been strangled and beaten with a toaster.
His mother Maha Dania tearfully told the court of scouring the neighbourhood for her son after their final phone call cut out.
In that conversation she said, "Mahmoud don't worry about the bike I'm coming to pick you up. He said 'Mum', he was whispering and he said 'Mum I'm with Aymen, my friend Aymen and come pick me up from Mitchell Street'."
Crown Prosecutor Adrian Robertson alleges Terkmani killed the teenager in a vacant house he used to play pool and smoke cannabis.
He told the court yesterday a tiny spot of Mahmoud's blood was found on a five dollar note in his bumbag and bloody shoe prints at the scene matched his size.
But Terkmani has pleaded not guilty.
His barrister Mark Austin has told the jury "not only has the accused denied to police that he was even present at the scene where the deceased was alleged to have been killed, but his father says he was home."
He said his position will be "I had nothing to do with this killing."
The trial is expected to run for four weeks.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Azzam Hrouk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmore Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aymen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mum I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Austin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terkmani</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahmoud Hrouk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfield East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aymen Terkmani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maha Dania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Adrian Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
