<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407374925690604</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/bond-university-highest-rate-of-campus-sexual-assault-in-queensland-report-20170801-gxn9eq.html</url>
  <title>The Queensland university with the highest rate of campus sexual assault</title>
  <content>
Bond University had the fifth highest rate of sexual assault on campus in the country, and the highest among Queensland Universities, according to a new report.
Australian universities released their own data following the Australian Human Rights Commission's report, which found  were sexually harassed at university.Photo: Supplied
Of the students that responded, 2.7 per cent at Bond University said they had been sexually assaulted on campus in 2015 or 2016. The next highest rate of campus sexual assault in Queensland was at Queensland University of Technology, with 2 per cent of responders saying they had been assaulted at university. At James Cook University and Griffith University, the rate of campus assault was 1.8 per cent.
Bond University also topped the list of Queensland Universities when it came to sexual harassment on campus, followed by JCU, Griffith University, and the University of Queensland.

Bond University Vice-Chancellor and President, Professor Tim Brailsford said the results could not be ignored.

"Today is a wake-up call, and we understand that the issue of sexual harassment and assault is real and attitudes need to change, both in society and within the university sector," he said.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"One case is one case too many."
All eight of Queensland's universities have released their own data, and their responses to the results - which vary from more education for students and staff, to external policy reviews.
Below the table is a breakdown of all the Queensland university-based data, and the university responses.

Bond University

Topping the list for sexual assault and harassment on campus is Bond University.
36 per cent of responders said they had been sexually harassed at university in 2016, and 2.7 per cent said they had been sexually assaulted in a university setting in 2015 or 2016.
Bond also tops the list for percentage of responders who reported being sexually harassed by a staff member, at 5.1 per cent.
Professor Brailsford said the university already had initiatives in place supporting campus safety, but said the university needed to do more.
"We will also be undertaking a comprehensive review of our disciplinary processes and procedures to ensure that we have the power to deal with perpetrators quickly and effectively, including suspension and expulsion," he said.
The university has also introduced "respect and consent sessions" to residential students, and will have an educational campaign for all students.
James Cook University

A quarter of students at James Cook University reported being sexually harassed at university in 2016, with 95 per cent of responders saying the most recent instance of sexual harassment was from other university students.
JCU vice chancellor Professor Sandra Harding said the university has already taken steps to improve safety for students and staff, and has brought on former Sex Discrimination Commissioner Elizabeth Broderick to conduct a review of the university's policies.
""These results are confronting, and I understand they will be of great concern for staff and students at the University, as well as the wider community," she said.
"I want to assure the JCU community, and the wider community, that we have taken, and are taking, steps to make the University safer."
"We want staff and students to know that if you have been assaulted we will do all we can to support you."
The university has worked on making a number of changes which including revising its harassment and bullying policy, reviewing campus security, training staff and working with residential colleges on standards of conduct.
Queensland University of Technology

At QUT, 2 per cent of responders said they had been sexually assaulted on campus in 2015 or 2016, and 22 per cent said they had been sexually harassed in 2016.
QUT Vice-Chancellor Professor Peter Coaldrake said he recognised it was a serious issue within universities and the wider community.
"This issue has a very real impact on students as they go about their lives both on and off campus," he said.
"The only acceptable rate of sexual assault or sexual harassment is zero - anything above that means there's more work to do to prevent incidents and support those affected."
He said the university was educating students on the acceptable standards of behaviour as well as the consequences of their actions, and the university was also working to raise awareness of its support services.
University of Queensland

More than 1500 students from UQ responded to the survey. While the rate of sexual assault on campus was lower, at 1.1 per cent, 24 per cent of respondents said they had been sexually harassed at university.
UQ vice-chancellor and president Professor Peter Hoj said an "unacceptable number" of students across Australia had experienced sexual harassment or assault.
"As the report shows, this is a serious issue facing Australia's universities and society as a whole," Professor Hoj said.
He said there should be zero instances of sexual assault on university campuses around australia, but sexual harassment was also unacceptable.
"The incidence of sexual harassment, which encompasses a range of behaviours that can also have a devastating impact on the survivor, is disturbingly high and must also be eliminated," he said.
"At UQ, our response will centre on providing enhanced support for survivors and taking a strong stance on prevention."
Among other measures, he said the university was working on a number of measures including an awareness campaign, creating a specialist unit for student support and counselling, and an online training module on consent.
CQUniversity

CQUniversity had the lowest rates of campus sexual assault and sexual harassment among Queensland universities.
The percentage of campus sexual assaults was 0.5, while 12 per cent of responders reported being sexual harassed in 2016.
However CQUniversity vice-chancellor Professor Scott Bowman said the number was still concerning.
"Universities should be safe and respectful places to learn and interact with others, and largely this is the case," he said.
"That is why any instance of sexual harassment or assault, regardless of where it occurs is completely unacceptable."
Professor Bowman said the university had "long had" policies in place to address sexual assault and harassment, but they were committed to doing more.
"As a community and a university, we need to do much more to educate people and raise awareness around the seriousness of sexual harassment and assault, reinforce a zero tolerance approach and help to build a culture of harmony and respect."
Among a raft of measures, the university will will offer zero tolerance and first responder training to all staff, and establish a student-led advisory group to help the university develop policies relating to student safety and wellbeing.
University of Southern Queensland

USQ also had a lower rate of campus sexual assault, at 0.8 per cent. 16 per cent of responders said they had been sexually harassed in 2016.
Vice-chancellor Professor Janet Verbyla said the data suggested were more likely to be sexually assaulted or harassed outside the university's campus.
"The survey results suggest, as do USQ's own reports, quite low rates of sexual harassment and even lower instances of sexual assault," she said.
"Sexual harassment and assault is wrong at every level and in any location and USQ will continue to play its part in tackling head-on the circumstances and situations where such instances occur."
She said USQ was "well known" for its student support, and would continue to give students who experienced assault or harassment any assistance they can.
"We already have a number of comprehensive policies and procedures in place to ensure that any reported incidents of sexual harassment and assault within USQ are responded to fairly but firmly," Professor Verbyla said.
University of the Sunshine Coast

At USC, 1 per cent of student responders said they had been sexually assaulted on campus in 2015 or 2016, and 21 per cent said they had been sexually harassed last year. 3.24 per cent of all responders said they had been sexually harassed by a staff member.
USC Vice-Chancellor Professor Greg Hill said the University would adopt the Commission's recommendations, and further develop its codes of conduct for both staff and students.
"Students who participated in the survey have been assured that the results will be used by universities to guide further improvements in how to better prevent and respond to sexual assault and harassment," Professor Hill said.
Griffith University

Griffith University students reported the same rate of sexual assault as those at JCU, but a slightly lower rate of sexual harassment on campus at 23 per cent.
In a statement, the university said it had a range of support services in place for students and staff, including counselling, a security escort service and around the clock phone and text support.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Southern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffith University</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CQUniversity</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UQ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Brailsford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cook University</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Universities</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC, 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Peter Hoj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JCU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUT, 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USQ</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice-Chancellor Professor Janet Verbyla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bond University Vice-Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bond University</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Scott Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland University of Technology</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUT Vice-Chancellor Professor Peter Coaldrake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Sandra Harding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sex Discrimination Commissioner Elizabeth Broderick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Hoj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Verbyla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC Vice-Chancellor Professor Greg Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Bowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Tim Brailsford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
