<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407246076669208</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/roosters-battler-eloni-vunakece-gives-players-unique-voice-on-rlpa-board-20170801-gxn66b.html</url>
  <title>Roosters battler Eloni Vunakece gives players unique voice on RLPA board</title>
  <content>
Eloni Vunakece has three children and as many jobs. They provide him with a unique perspective that he will bring to his latest gig, as a director for the Rugby League Players' Association.
There are plenty of marquee men on the RLPA board. Cameron Smith, James Maloney, Tim Mannah and the other new addition, New Zealand captain Adam Blair, are now as influential off the field as on it.

Up Next

Dangerfield out of Brownlow running

01:30

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Plays of the Week

Nail-biting finishes, ripping yorkers and hat-trick heroes, these are the plays of the week.

Vunakece brings an altogether different insight to the plight of the players. The Roosters prop continues to work as a garbage collector, didn't make his NRL debut until 28 and has picked up a third job, as a personal trainer, to help make ends meet for a young family that includes wife Mel and their three children under five.
The game's elite will always be well remunerated, but Vunakece is the voice of the battler. He will represent those who strive to make the NRL but can't make a living from football alone.

"I don't know of anyone representing the second-tier guys and the Islander players, anyone fitting in that category. That's how I came to be involved," Vunakece said.
"I don't know of anyone in the NRL that works a second job."

Vunakece, having finally fulfilled his dream of playing first-grade last season, hasn't been able to add to his tally of nine appearances for the Roosters in 2017. He has been plying his trade for feeder side Wyong in the Intrust Super Premiership and taking on as many garbage runs and personal training sessions as his footy commitments allow.
Up until last year, Vunakece was working full time on the garbage run, starting work at 4.30am and finishing just in time to make training. He has scaled back those commitments to about two or three casual evening shifts per week and added a couple of client sessions as a personal trainer.Photo: David Stewart
"Work has been really accommodating for me, they understand the situation I'm in and were happy to give me shifts whenever I could come in," he said.
"I would have happily continued doing both, but when you've been waiting for a footy opportunity as long as I have, you can't pass up on it."
There's no such thing as a typical day in the Vunakece household but, suffice to say, they are busy.
"Mel is a nurse at the RPA, she's on a double shift today," he said on Tuesday.
"The eldest daughter is at school so I've got the other two kids. One is asleep now, we're about to watch a movie. Just juggling it all."
Another reason the RLPA approached Vunakece is his cultural background. The front rower is proud of his Fijian heritage and has represented the Pacific nation in the Test arena on nine occasions.
"It opens our eyes up to the opportunities the Islander boys have to become role models to our communities here and back home," he said. "It's pretty cool that our achievements can have an effect on people."
Vunakece and Blair will join the RLPA board after George Burgess and Dene Halatau stepped down as directors. The pair join the union in an executive capacity just as collective bargaining negotiations with the NRL ramp up.
"It's an important time for the RLPA given the ongoing CBA negotiations, and I have no doubt that Adam and Eloni will provide great assistance in navigating our way through this critical period," said RLPA chairman Russell Adams.
"The unity within the playing group is stronger than ever and I believe it speaks volumes of the association that we have the current captains of Australia and New Zealand sitting on our board.
"Not only that, but the diversity we have within our directors makes for powerful leadership and representation of the players going forward."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intrust Super Premiership</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eloni Vunakece</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vunakece</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fijian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RLPA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Players' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Mannah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dene Halatau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eloni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Maloney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
