<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407121522614977</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/regal-reservoir-house-inspired-by-classic-film-for-sale/news-story/7b889d0e92477c51798b3b60db1215ad</url>
  <title>Regal Reservoir house, inspired by classic film, for sale - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Dan Astuto at the ornate family house his parents built in the '70s in Reservoir. Photo: Tony Gough

A RETRO Reservoir palace with an ornate interior that's been preserved since the '70s is set to go under the hammer this month.
It took Dan Astuto's parents three years to build the opulent 13 Lawley St, based on a design they drew themselves that was inspired by their favourite film, Gone With the Wind.
BIGGER IS BETTER:
DESIGN DARLINGS:

The house took three years to build and features an impressive fountain out front. Photo: Tony Gough

Mr Astuto's late older brother also helped create the four-bedroom, two-level beauty, which features a sprawling staircase and ballroom that Scarlett O'Hara and Rhett Butler wouldn't look out of place in.
He said the house was well ahead of its time when it was erected four decades ago, due to its open-plan layout and underfloor heating, and hasn't been altered since.
It's now scheduled to be auctioned on August 26 with a $1.2 million price guide.

The house's open-plan layout was ahead of its time. Photo: Tony Gough

Many of the home's regal features were imported from Italy - where the Astutos migrated to Melbourne from in 1963 - including its custom-made doors, door handles and balustrades.
An imposing custom-made fountain also adorns the front yard - Mr Astuto said his father modelled it on the one at Carlton's Royal Exhibition Centre.
Mr Astuto spent his teen years and early 20s living in the remarkable home, becoming the envy of his friends: "No one else I knew had a house like that," he said.

The design was inspired by the film
Gone With the Wind.

His home wasn't easy to build - particularly the trailblazing open-plan living room, he said: "The architect wanted to put a wall in the middle. But my dad stuck to his guns, and they added steel beams in the roof to hold it up.
"It added a huge amount of cost, but it looks fantastic. My parents knew they wanted it to be their forever home."

It now has a price guide of $1.2 million and an August 26 auction date.

Mr Astuto made the emotional decision to sell the house after it became too much for his parents, who are now in their mid-80s.
"We're all so attached to it," he said.
"It needs a bit of TLC, but I hope whoever buys it loves it as much as we did."
Barry Plant Reservoir agent Marc Romeo said it would have been "the best house in the northern suburbs" during its heyday, offering 465sq m of living space and occupying a substantial 1200sq m block.
"It's one of a kind, made of solid brick and concrete - the workmanship is absolutely amazing," he said.
"I think it will be quite popular."

It features 465sq m of living space spread across two levels.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Royal Exhibition Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astutos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RETRO Reservoir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regal Reservoir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TLC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Astuto</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lawley St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarlett O'Hara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhett Butler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 26</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Gough</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Plant Reservoir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Astuto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Romeo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
