<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406348428486528</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coleborns-hopes-of-qualifying-for-world-tour-shake/3207598/</url>
  <title>Coleborn's hopes of qualifying for world tour shaken</title>
  <content>
SURFING: Mitch Coleborn's hopes of earning a berth on next year's world tour were seriously dented at California on Tuesday, when he made an early exit from a crucial qualifying series event.
The 30-year-old, who has been on the fringes of the globe's main circuit for years, was eliminated from the Vans US Open of Surfing at iconic Huntington Beach in round two.
It's one of the highest rated events on the schedule - with 10,000 points on offer - so the Wurtulla product missed a prime chance to improve on his 22nd ranking.
The top 10 on the season-ending QS standings, not including surfers who are also in the top 22 of the world tour, will claim spots on next year's championship roster.
There are three more 10,000-point events left.
Fellow Sunshine Coaster Keely Andrew was scheduled to resume her world tour campaign on Tuesday night, also at California.
It's the sixth stop on a 10-stop calendar.
Gofundme set up for better mobility equipment and ongoing costs
MOTORBIKE rider transported to hospital in a serious condition
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
KEN has more than a passing interest in the evolution of music.
And so BYTE - the Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence - was born.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>QS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vans US Open of Surfing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wurtulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coaster Keely Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Youth Theatre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Coleborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
