<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406563176855692</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/australian-businesses-unaware-of-slavery-in-supply-chains-inquiry-told-20170801-gxmvun.html</url>
  <title>Businesses unaware of slavery in supply chains, inquiry told</title>
  <content>
Australian businesses are not doing enough to tackle slavery in their supply chains, a federal inquiry has heard, but big companies have warned against "overly prescriptive" laws in a bid to stamp out the problem.
Submissions to the joint committee looking at establishing a Modern Slavery Act in Australia has backed introducing new laws to force big companies to report on modern slavery in their supply chains. The joint standing committee on foreign affairs and trade was asked to look at the issue by Attorney-General George Brandis, and is this week holding hearings in Melbourne.Photo: Felipe Dana
The 2016 Global Slavery Index estimated that 45.8 million people in 167 countries are victims of slavery. Two-thirds, or 30.4 million of these people, are in the Asia-Pacific region, with more than 4000 in Australia. 
Business lobbies and companies acknowledge that more needs to be done to address the problem, but remain concerned that Australia may end up with laws that place stricter requirements on companies than is the case in other nations such as Britain, which has a Modern Slavery Act.Photo: Andrew Meares
Business has no clue

Nestle said it was striving for better conditions for workers by using co-operatives for its cocoa supply chains in West Africa's Ivory Coast and seafood chains in Thailand. Its submission to the committee said the purpose of Australian legislation must be clear and "should not be overly prescriptive".  
Despite "strong rates of compliance, from time to time our responsible sourcing audits uncover incidents of forced labour and modern slavery", Nestle said. These were "managed on a case by case basis, and we work hard to ensure effective remediation is sought for all rights-holders impacted". 

"It is our view that even with the best endeavours, no company can confidently say that they do not have modern slavery or other serious human rights abuses in their domestic or global supply chains," Nestle's submission said.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Our observation, unsupported by data, is that in the UK, as in Australia, awareness of modern slavery in supply chains is generally low among businesses, and where it might be considered, it is generally viewed as an issue in developing countries, but without domestic implications," it said. "Even where awareness exists, capability within businesses to understand how to approach this issue is often lacking." Photo: Esther Han
Who gets captured?

It isn't clear which size companies the laws will apply to and division remains between businesses on whether reporting by companies on what they are doing to tackle the problem should be mandatory.
The Australian Council of Superannuation Investors (ACSI) suggests "mandatory reporting, with provision for board approval, public disclosure, independent oversight and civil penalties".Photo: Jesse Marlow
"The issue of slavery is present, endemic and global," ACSI chief executive Louise Davidson said. "It warrants urgent action by the Australian government."
But the Business Council of Australia warns against "overly prescriptive" laws. It said to minimise the risk of a regulatory burden on companies, or overlapping with existing laws, the legislation must clearly define which companies will be required to report and what part of their supply chains they will have to report on.
Even with the best endeavours, no company can confidently say that they do not have modern slavery or other serious human rights abuses in their domestic or global supply chains.
Nestle

Minimise compliance burden

Retailer David Jones said in its submission while "broadly supportive" of the introduction of a Modern Slavery Act in Australia, "any time and resources spent managing and reporting on compliance detracts resources from actual implementation". It urged the government to minimise the costs of compliance and guide companies in the implementation.
Woolworths also supports such an act but said similar to Britain, an appropriate threshold would need to be determined for mandatory reporting in Australia and that "this would need to be low enough to ensure adequate coverage of the Australian marketplace, yet high enough not to unduly burden smaller companies with excessive reporting requirements". Photo: Paul Jeffers
Qantas also supports the introduction of Australian laws to complement existing laws under Australia's Criminal Code which criminalise modern slavery, but said it was "concerned with the potential duplication of reports companies will be required to draft and publish to meet the requirements of these acts and potentially future parallel legislation around the world".
Miners and big banks have also backed new laws but also warn against red tape. NAB's general manager of group risk, appetite and analytics Nicky Parsons said in the bank's submission that an Australian act and accompanying guidance should give companies flexibility on how they respond. 
Support for a central registry

BHP's group sustainability and public policy officer Tony Cudmore said the government should "make it clear that a parent entity can report on behalf of its group entities". The miner would also support an official government registry of all statements as part of any Australian reporting regime.
The submission also notes that some interested parties would like to see a statutory due diligence requirement included in any anti-modern slavery legislation introduced in Australia, but there is no such provision in the British Modern Slavery Act.
"It can be a difficult, inefficient and potentially unreliable exercise for a company to undertake detailed investigations into the operations and activities of its suppliers, particularly in relation to Tier 2 and 3 suppliers," he said.
Fortescue Metals external relations director Tom Weaver said in the company's submission that all large businesses should be required to publish annual modern slavery statements.
Almost 10 per cent of Australia's top 100 ASX listed companies already report under Section 54 of the UK act. "Without mandatory reporting, those companies that voluntarily report on the identification of slavery within their supply chain may be unfairly disadvantaged," he said.
Follow Nassim Khadem on  and .​
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Section 54 of the UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACSI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Council of Superannuation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Marlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esther Han</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Modern Slavery Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Modern Slavery Act.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Criminal Code</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicky Parsons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tier 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Pacific</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nassim Khadem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Modern Slavery Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Africa's Ivory Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General George Brandis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Slavery Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Cudmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felipe Dana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Weaver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue Metals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nestle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
