<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407503774712257</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4827578/topics-the-chronicles-of-ljubo-a-cult-hero/?cs=308</url>
  <title>Topics: the chronicles of Ljubo, a cult hero</title>
  <content>
LOST IN TRANSLATION: Ljubo Milicevic at Fat As Butter in 2013. Picture: Simone De Peak

YOU know those listless days when you waste time online and suddenly you're down a rabbit hole?

For Topics, one such listless foray has yielded the surprising social media musings of former Newcastle Jets captain, Socceroo and cult figure Ljubo Milicevic.
Ljubo, who goes around with Dandenong City these days, recently detailed the Jets' weird build-up to their 2009 Asian Champions League game against Japan's Nagoya Grampus. It wasn't a game of two halves, nor did full credit go to the boys. Over to you, Ljubo.
"Sooo, after flying to Japan via the longest and cheapest route possible we were given our room keys, and no sh-t, I was at least two foot too big for the shower, toilet, doorway and bed," he says.
"I literally felt like the BFG in Roald Dahl's novel."
Ljubo threatened to check into the Hilton across the road, before he and teammate Sasho Petrovski were given bigger rooms. The next weirdness: game day. You couldn't make this up.
"I went off to get a tattoo in the morning, thinking to myself 'cool story', haha, Yakuza vibes!" continues Ljubo.
"Problem being, I forgot about the boring game day sh-t walks where we are supposed to pretend to be focused."

Somehow, coach Gary Van Egmond was displeased and wanted Ljubo on the next flight out of Nagoya's Chubu Centrair International Airport, before the team's then owner Con Constantine advised to "leave the kid alone".
Ljubo at this point goes into a grievance with Van Egmond that frankly sounds like a matter for the two of them, before this bizarro version of Lost in Translation reaches its climax.
"So as we rock into the change rooms I set up my DJ equipment, drop "Juicy" by Biggie Smalls and yell out 'anyone got a f---en problem with my tatt?' as I rip off the plastic to showcase the new artwork I got that morning!" 
There was silence, apparently. The Jets went out and drew one-all with a Nagoya line-up that presumably warmed up with nothing more than a boring game day sh-t walk.
"Oh well, nothing but love for Newy," said a philosophical Ljubo. Topics eagerly awaits the book.
DO WE STILL MAKE 'EM LIKE LES?

MR FOOTBALL: SBS broadcaster Les Murray, who died this week aged 71.
Gideon Haigh, the patron saint of cricket, business and, er, panel shows said something interesting this week after the sad passing of SBS football patriarch Les Murray. 
For viewers of a certain age the appearance of Les on the telly's blurriest, rudest channel meant a screen-lit vigil in your PJs to Montevideo or Tehran in the dead of night. There'd be tension from your parents, who didn't get it, and tension from the Socceroos, who'd stuff it up, and it was seldom worth it on a school night to see another wave of disappointment crease the features of Robbie Slater and Aurelio Vidmar.

But somehow Les, burring, unflappable, made you feel like coming back for that one, perfect school night the Socceroos would make it worth it. That, and he taught us that Italy's Serie A is pronounced like exhaling warm tea: "Sereeya Ahhhhh". 

THAT NIGHT: A baby-faced Harry Kewell at the MCG after that draw with Iran.
Speaking on Ten's The Project (told you), Haigh wondered if the Hungarian migrant born Laszlo was something of a broadcasting relic.
As the sharply-dressed Mr Football of the public broadcaster, he found his voice at a time when the audience didn't talk back. Says Haigh, in a way Les Murray was to soccer as Richie Benaud was to cricket.

Like we said, an interesting one; Topics counts cycling's Phil Liggett, sorely missed from this year's SBS Tour commentary team, among the broadcasters you can't replace. Any others jump to mind? Tell us.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BFG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nagoya's Chubu Centrair International Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ljubo Milicevic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tehran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Jets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nagoya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Con Constantine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy's Serie A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roald Dahl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gideon Haigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sereeya Ahhhhh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PJs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EM LIKE LES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haigh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Liggett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Van Egmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fat As Butter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laszlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasho Petrovski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STILL MAKE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montevideo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Kewell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurelio Vidmar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biggie Smalls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Van Egmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richie Benaud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone De Peak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ljubo</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Nagoya Grampus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
