<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407160177321613</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/martin-place-homeless-tent-city/8764814</url>
  <title>Sydney Mayor and NSW Government pass blame over tent city for the homeless in Martin Place</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A thriving tent city for the homeless in Sydney's busy Martin Place has turned into a political football for the City of Sydney and State Government, with neither side keen to take responsibility.
The two levels of government are accusing each other of not doing enough to move the group of homeless people and protesters from the front of the Reserve Bank building.
New South Wales Premier Gladys Berejiklian told Parliament her Government had tried to intervene but had been turned away.
"Our staff have been down there 41 times," she said.
"It concerns me that people who are sleeping in tents in Martin Place are refusing to get help, refusing to receive help and I frankly think that is unacceptable."

The Premier said it was now up to the local government to forcibly remove the camp.
"I call on [Sydney Lord Mayor] Clover Moore to get rid of that tent city. It should not be there," the Premier said.
"Anyone who wants to receive help in New South Wales will receive that and I call on her to act because that is the right thing to do."
But Cr Moore says that is not possible.
"We don't have the power to move people," she said.
"We have the power to move structures and make places safe. But we don't have the power to move people on.
"The police have the power to do that. We're not calling on the police to do that. But that's the reality."
Social Housing Minister Pru Goward had earlier tweeted her disapproval of the Lord Mayor, saying the State Government was "doing what we can" to provide support to the homeless.

External Link:

Pru Goward Tweet

External Link:

Pru Goward Tweet 2
The Lord Mayor said the State Government had not provided enough affordable housing and the problem could be solved if vacant homes in the Sirius building were opened up for the campers.
"The Government and the Premier are acting now because it's in their face," she said.
"They have to walk by to go to Parliament. The [Reserve Bank] has to walk by to go into their premises."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirius</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Housing Minister Pru Goward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pru Goward Tweet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pru Goward Tweet 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.17</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
