<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406382788225699</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/defence-sa-boss-andy-keough-quits-for-privatesector-job/news-story/af61b35f61b3f44ee5c744c8112e5a30</url>
  <title>Defence SA boss quits</title>
  <content>
DEFENCE SA chief Andy Keough has quit after about two years in the job - lured away into the private sector by defence technology giant SAAB.
Defence Industries Minister Martin Hamilton-Smith said he would be missed.
"He's going to be a big loss but Mr Keough has been made an offer he can't refuse," he said.
"Our loss is SAAB's gain."
When Mr Keough took up the job in 2015 he said his focus was creating as many defence jobs in SA as possible.
His resignation comes before the expected increase of jobs in submarine and shipbuilding, and on the same day as confirmation the $5 billion army vehicle project will not be based in SA.
Before becoming Defence SA's chief executive, the former submariner managed ASC's submarine maintenance program in WA.
His predecessor, Malcolm Jackman, left the position after less than a year in the job.
Before him was Andrew Fletcher, who left with some harsh words for the Government - he said federal and state ministers were surrounded by minders who knew nothing about the industry, hampering long-term decision-making.
Mr Hamilton-Smith went on to say that he was concerned that Naval Group would build the $50 billion Future Submarines - at this stage it has only been confirmed they will design them.
He is also concerned the three firms bidding for the $30 billion Future Frigates will be the builders.
"The Federal Government needs to provide clarity on the fundamental principle of whether contracts will specify that an Australian company will have prime carriage of building the submarines and frigates in partnership with the designer," he said.

French company DCNS won the contract to build Australia's next fleet of submarines, according to an announcement made by Australia's prime minister, Malcolm Turnbull, on Tuesday, April 26. Bids for the AU$50 billion (US$39 billion) contract also came from Germany and Japan. Turnbull said the submarines would be built in Australia with Australian steel and will employ locals in the production. He added that the submarines would be serviced in Adelaide and that the contract would generate 2,800 jobs. This video shows a pre-concept design submitted by DCNS for what they described as "the world's most advanced conventionally-powered submarine", and named the Shortfin Barracuda Block 1A. Credit: YouTube/DCNSgroup

AUSTRALIA: France's DCNS Wins Bid to Build New Fleet of Australian Submarines April 14
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Build New Fleet of Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shortfin Barracuda Block 1A. Credit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saab</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Jackman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future Submarine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence SA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube/DCNSgroup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France's DCNS Wins Bid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Keough</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy Keough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defence Industries Minister Martin Hamilton-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DCNS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AU$50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Submarines April 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future Frigates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hamilton-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naval Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US (39</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
