<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406515932214705</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-01/dan-murphys-backs-out-of-case-nt-alcohol-restrictions-case/8764378</url>
  <title>Dan Murphy's backs out of case against NT Government over alcohol restrictions</title>
  <content>
Liquor chain Dan Murphy's parent company, Woolworths, has announced it will end its legal proceedings against the Northern Territory Government over its regulations on store sizes.
The company said it was lodging a notice of discontinuance for the case while it waited for the Government's response to a review of the NT Liquor Act.
, arguing the floor size restriction was "arbitrary".
"We feel we have let down the people of Darwin who overwhelmingly wanted us to proceed and win this case," Dan Murphy's general manager for corporate services Shane Tremble said.
"But the pragmatic decision is to await the government response to recommendations from the Liquor Act review before considering our options."
In December the NT Government introduced new laws restricting liquor store sizes to 400 square metres, setting back the liquor chain's plans to open a 1,800-square-metre store on Darwin airport land.
Mr Tremble said the decision was made after the Government introduced legislation that would replace the contested law.
"Our initial view that the regulation was invalid was largely confirmed after the Government decided to rush through legislation to replace the regulation after it received the timetable for discovery," he said.
"Their actions effectively voided our legal challenge against the regulation."
Mr Tremble said despite the new legislation having the same effect, the company would have to mount a "totally new and different legal case".
"Which would then be subject to further uncertainty while we awaited the outcome of the Liquor Act review and the Government's response," he said.
"We will consider our options, including potential further legal avenues, after the Government provides its response to Justice Riley's Liquor Act review."
The NT Government has been contacted for comment.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Liquor Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Murphy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Tremble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tremble</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liquor Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Riley's Liquor Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
