<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406945428952574</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/markets/the-rba-signals-its-discomfort-with-the-rising-australian-dollar-20170801-gxn0et</url>
  <title>The RBA signals its discomfort with the rising Australian dollar</title>
  <content>
Reserve Bank governor Philip Lowe has taken aim at the , warning that it could scupper expectations for growth to remain relatively robust and for inflation to gradually climb back into the central bank's target range.
In his statement released after yesterday's RBA board meeting, Dr Lowe said that the bank's central forecast was still for the economy to grow at an annual rate of around 3 per cent over the next couple of years, and for inflation to "pick up gradually as the economy strengthens".
But he warned that recent rise in the Australian dollar "is expected to contribute to subdued price pressures in the economy" as well as "weighing on the outlook for output and employment".
A strengthening exchange rate, Dr Lowe warned, "would be expected to result in a slower pick-up in economic activity and inflation than currently forecast".

AMP chief economist Shane Oliver said Reserve Bank officials were "clearly stepping up their efforts to try to jawbone the Australian dollar lower."

He said Dr Lowe's statement "effectively says that a stronger Australian dollar amounts to a de facto monetary policy tightening which threatens the RBA's growth forecasts. It implies they're a long way from raising interest rates."
The  which means that the cash rate has been at the record low level of 1.5 per cent for a full year. And even though the , traders quickly shrugged off the jawboning attempt and pushed the currency to US80.2¢ in late trading.
But HSBC Australia chief economist Paul Bloxham - who is expecting a cash rate hike early in 2018 - disagreed that the currency's strength would stay the RBA's hand. He pointed out that the bank's forecasts had not been blown off track despite the stronger currency.
"With the Australian dollar having rallied by 4¢ against the US dollar since the last board meeting, the central bank could easily have shifted to more aggressively jawboning the currency if they were worried".

Instead, he said, "the post-meeting statement reported that the forecasts were largely unchanged and that growth was still expected to pick up to around 3 per cent."
All the same, about his discomfort with the Australian dollar's rise, particularly against the weakening US dollar.
After the July board meeting, he confined his comments to pointing out that the fall in the Australian dollar since 2013 had helped the economy in its transition following the mining investment boom, and adding that "an appreciating exchange rate would complicate this adjustment."
But last week, Dr Lowe was much more forthright, telling a . It would help generate more jobs, it would help push inflation a bit closer to target."

The greenback has come under downward pressure this year as investors have become increasingly sceptical that US President Donald Trump will deliver on his promised massive tax cuts or a major infrastructure spending program that would lift US economic activity.
More recently, the US dollar has lost ground as investors have concluded that the US central bank won't raise rates again this year because of feeble US inflation.
One way to alleviate the upward pressure on the Aussie dollar, would be to cut interest rates even further. But the RBA is reluctant to take this step, for fear of re-igniting in the Sydney and Melbourne property markets.
The Reserve Bank remains hopeful that tighter prudential rules are beginning to bite. In his statement yesterday, Dr Lowe noted that "housing prices have been rising briskly in some markets", and said that "there are some signs these conditions are starting to ease."

And he did point to the disturbing trend that "growth in housing debt has been outpacing the slow growth in household incomes."
But monthly house price data yesterday from Corelogic showed that prices in Melbourne had risen by 3.1 per cent in July while Sydney prices jumped 1.4 per cent and Canberra was up 2.4 per cent. Brisbane prices fell but the average capital city price rise for the month was 1.5 per cent.
Meanwhile, the outlook for consumer spending remains clouded. Although jobs growth is picking up and the unemployment rate is expected to edge lower over the next couple of years, wages growth remains feeble.
In his statement, Dr Lowe said that although retail sales had picked up recently, "slow growth in real wages and high levels of household debt are likely to constrain growth in spending."

One bright spot for the economy is the prospect of recovery in business investment spending. With business conditions improving, and capacity utilisation increasing, "some pick-up in non-mining business investment is expected."
There is also likely to be a short-term pick up in inflation, as measured by the consumer price index, as higher electricity and tobacco prices flow through. But Dr Lowe noted that "a factor working in the other direction is increased competition from new entrants in the retail industry."
The Australian economy is benefiting from a more benign global backdrop, as stronger growth in a number of major economies is helping to buoy commodity prices.
Dr Lowe said that Chinese economic growth has strengthened, bolstered by stronger spending on infrastructure and property construction, although he noted that high debt levels continued to present a medium-term risk.
And while commodity prices have risen recently, he warned that "Australia's terms of trade are still expected to decline over the period ahead."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lowe</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSBC Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Bloxham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
