<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406554586920977</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/01/17/26/australia-smashes-national-record-for-warmest-july</url>
  <title>Winter heat: Australia records its hottest July in history</title>
  <content>
Australia has had its warmest July on record, as the nation struggled through one of the driest months in a decade.
Last month was dominated by unusually strong high pressure systems over the country, following a similar trend to June.
This pattern limited the amount of cloud and rainfall across many parts of the country and produced the highest nationally averaged July maximum temperature the country has ever recorded.
Australia's average maximum temperature for July was 2.62C above average,  the highest in 108 years of records.
The nation's average rainfall last month was just 13.5mm, which was close to 40 percent lower than usual and lowest for July since 2007.
While minimums were below average in some parts of southern and western Australia, the national average was still one degree warmer than usual and the equal 13th warmest on record.
Historically speaking, July was a dry and warm month for Australia as a whole.

Related Articles

Looking around the country, there was a notable contrast from north to south in terms of rainfall and minimum temperatures, although maximums were notably warm for almost everyone.
Here's a wrap of the capital cities and noteworthy state-wide achievements:
Sydney had the driest July in 22 years (12.6mm) and the second warmest on record in terms of average maximum temperature (19.1C).
NSW as a state registered its lowest rainfall, warmest days and coldest nights for July in 15 years.

Melbourne did okay with rainfall and ended up with 30.4mm in the gauge, about twice as much as June and the driest for July in only three years. 
The city's average minimum temperature of 8.6C was the coldest for July in 19 years, while days were about a degree above average.
Most of Victoria had a fairly dry month, helping the state record its second driest June-July period on record.
Brisbane enjoyed warm days, the second warmest on record when averaged throughout the month (22.8C). The city's 47mm of rain was the highest July total in five years.
State-wide, Queensland had its hottest July on record in terms of both maximum and mean (combined minimum and maximum) temperatures, while the average July minimum was the 10th warmest on record.
Perth finally came through with a decent month of rain. The city's 172.9mm was the wettest, and first wetter-than-average, July in nine years.
Perth's daytime temperatures were fairly normal, although the July average monthly minimum temperature (10.2C) was the highest in 17 years.
Western Australia notched up its warmest July on record based on maximum temperatures and just finished its fourth driest June-July period on record.

Adelaide experienced its warmest July in 15 years in terms of maximum temperatures and registered 91mm of rain, which is 13mm more than the July monthly average.
South Australia had its warmest July on record as a state for both maximum and mean temperatures.
Hobart shivered through notably cold nights last month, producing the city's lowest average July minimum temperature (3.5C) in 35 years. For Tasmania, it was the coldest July in nine years in terms of minimum temperatures.
Canberra's driest July (17mm) in three years rounded out the city's driest June-July period since 1982. The city's average minimum temperature for the month was a numbing -2.3 degrees, which is the lowest for July in 46 years when looking at observations from the current and old airport sites.
Darwin was warm in July. The average maximum temperature of 32.6C was the city's highest on record for July and the average minimum of 21.1C was its highest in seven years. No rain made it Darwin's third consecutive dry month, ending the first completely dry May-to-July period in nine years. 
In the absence of any strong influence from climate drivers in the Indian or Pacific Oceans in the near future, the end of winter and early spring will most likely continue the recent trend of above average temperatures and below average rainfall for most of the country.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State-wide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June-July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific Ocean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May-to-July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>24</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
