<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407331976016676</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/no-sign-of-bus-strikes-stopping-wednesday-strike-to-go-ahead-20170801-gxn85g.html</url>
  <title>No sign of bus strikes stopping: Wednesday strike to go ahead</title>
  <content>
Brisbane City Council bus drivers could continue planning strike action and disrupting commuters until an agreement is reached on safety, pay and rostering.
On Wednesday,. Photo: Glenn Hunt
On Tuesday Opposition councillor Jared Cassidy asked Public and Active Transport chairman Adrian Schrinner how much longer the council's deliberation over a new Enterprise Bargaining Agreement (EBA), and the associated bus drive strike action, could go on for.
"We hope for the best, not aim for the worst," Cr Schrinner said.
The council's EBA, that covers all council employees, expired in October, 2016, but a new agreement is yet to be reached.
Several unions have taken this opportunity to fight for workplace improvements like safety, pay and rostering improvements.

The council has put an offer on the table of a 2.5 per cent pay rise each year for three years, plus a $400 signing bonus, but this has not been widely accepted.
The Rail, Tram and Bus Union have asked for 3.5 per cent, while other unions have simply knocked back the offer without making a counter offer. 

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Cr Schrinner said there had been no consolidated counter-offer response from all of the unions.
"There's one thing to be kicking and screaming, but they actually need to put a counter position on the table, that is how negotiations work."
It was understood a new EBA would be agreed on sometime in August when every council employee would be given an opportunity to vote yes or no on the 2.5 per cent offer.
Until then, strike action could continue.
On Tuesday evening the RTBU released a statement that said despite having another meeting with the council, an agreement on driver safety, rostering or pay rates could not be reached.
"As a result the RTBU will be taking further protected industrial action this week," the statement said. 
Cr Schrinner said going forward, it was anyone's guess what would happen in terms of strike action.
"Obviously prior to the first strike we met with the RTBU to see if we could come to an agreement which was mutually satisfactory, I thought that we would get there," he said.
"As time has gone I'm losing confidence that they will come to an agreement which is also an appropriate agreement for the rate payers of Brisbane.
"Ultimately, there are thing we can work with them on, safety has always been one of those things."
Cr Schrinner said the new EBA wasn't trying to take anything away from anyone.
"Yet, there has been this ugly situation...we expect if we were taking something away from staff, if they were losing pay or conditions, by all means there would be strike action happening," he said.
"But, that's not happening, we haven't done that.
"It's simply continuation of the existing EBA that they signed up to three years ago, plus we're giving them a pay rise.
"You've actually got to ask yourself, why is this happening.
"We all know this is about the state election coming up, the timing of that election and the fact the unions are activating their membership in the lead up to the state election - that is all this is about."
Cr Schrinner said the council was still waiting for state government's Bus Safety Review
"Because the state hasn't acted we've stepped up," he said.
While waiting for the review, the council, in response to request for improved safety by the RTBU, funded 50 senior network officers for the network.
"We expected this would all be resolved long ago. The state's review was due in March we are now into August and there is still no review.
"Council has committed to doubling our investment in security because we just don't know what the state is doing and how much longer we're going to have to wait.
"We're trying to be reasonable, we're trying to do what we can, but we don't have the authority to employ more Translink officers, only the state can do that.
"We're doing what we can, but it's not the ultimate solution and the union and council are on the same page here."
A spokeswoman for Deputy Premier and Transport Minister Jackie Trad said the Bus Safety Review had been conducted and the Government would release its full response shortly.  
"We've already introduced several of the recommendations of the review including a trial of shatter-resistant window film on buses in Cairns and on the Gold Coast and increasing the frequency of Bus Safety Forum meetings from two to six per year," she said.
Information on Wednesday's industrial action can be found on the  or by calling 13 12 30.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enterprise Bargaining Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TransLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Schrinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Safety Review</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Safety Forum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Schrinner</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Active Transport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Cassidy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
