<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407890321777373</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/miners-told-to-draw-on-big-tobaccos-lessons-20170801-gxn5hs</url>
  <title>Why miners should have taken a long smoko through the super cycle</title>
  <content>
If the  announces anything usefully systemic, it is crisis of confidence among long investors institutional in the capacity of big mining to allocate capital focus, discipline or wealth creating effect.
And if you needed more evidence of the state of distrust, just try getting hold of a fabulously interesting discussion paper that Citi's London resources research team sent to clients about a week ago.
The Citi report aims to assess big mining's investment return over the past decade through the slightly jarring comparative lens of very big tobacco. Needless to say, the way Citi sees it, the miners may as well have stopped digging in preference for a very long smoko.
"The  has massively outperformed the mining sector over the past 10 years, despite the two sectors tracking closely (on most value and returns metrics) in the 1990s and early 2000 period," Citi opined.

Peter Braig

"Tobacco has achieved this outperformance despite the miners being in a 'super cycle' for growth, driven by China, over this period.

"Arguably the tobacco sector came to terms with a declining end-use market, shrunk excess capacity to increase utilisation rates and returned cash to shareholders. The tobacco industry has maintained capex well below depreciation for an extended period with capex to sales of less than 5 per cent versus the miners at (circa) 15 per cent. This has led to the tobacco companies delivering superior ROE (return on equity). We think this presents a decent case example for the miners over the coming decade to follow suit.
"The revenue growth of the tobacco companies has lagged that of the mining companies over the past 20 years. Despite this, the tobacco sector has delivered higher ROE, resulting in higher dividend payments and delivered a massive outperformance of tobacco relative to the market.
"The tobacco companies have held the capex below depreciation and R&D in the last 15 years whereas the miners have always been running capex higher than D&A (and) they have only brought below D&A in 2016. In our view this fits with a shrink-to-grow mentality," Citi finished.
Patently the Citi thesis is a fairly blunt instrument built to ignore the essentially very different challenges that faced the miners through what investors regard, fairly or not, as a decade of capital dissipation.

Nic Walker

The biggest of the obvious flaws in the Citi comparison is that the past decade has seen the tobacco and mining sectors shaped by profoundly different market pressures.
The post-2006 boom in demand and prices for a host of bulk and metals commodities that is given such passing acknowledgement by Citi created a set of capital allocations challenges that were unique to the mining sector and its super-cycle.
China's arrival in the seaborne markets for bulk materials like coal and iron ore was, and continues to be, a total game-changer for the resources business. The volume of iron ore sailing around the world, for example, has more than doubled to 1.6 billion tonnes annually with China now routinely importing better than two thirds of that volume.
Big mining had two choices to make from the moment the shape-shifting of China's raw materials market became apparent. The companies could invest against new capacity or surrender market share to the newcomers invited by the potential of wild pricing. Over the longer term, by accepting stasis the existing operators would effectively have been accepting an erosion of value of their assets.

Vincent Mundy

Most, including Glencore's canny cousins at Xstratra, chose to defend their place in the market and opted to grow their mine fleets to meet what was assumed, correctly in most circumstances, to be a secular shift in patterns of demand.
Given the fact that the cheapest source of growth capital is internally generated free cash flow and given that the miners' cash coffers were so historically flush, a whole lot of that new capacity was financed by what was at hand.
Towards the back end of the boom, the desire of incumbents to self-fund expansions and the sheer weight of the capital spending programs that were being baked in by management teams who would subsequently be accused of excessive exuberance began to seriously irritate a family of active investors in the resources sector.
The most public of the critics through the back end of the boom was the western world's biggest investor in the mining business, Blackrock. It argued consistently the miners were spending too aggressively and that shareholders had not enjoyed a fair share of the boom-time spoils.

Nic Walker

From the moment the income boom (but not the structural shift in demand that inspired it) began its long retreat in 2012, the Blackrock proposition became industry orthodoxy.
Now, the story for big tobacco through the mining industry heady decade of investment was quite different and is pithily captured by the Citi note. Big tobacco responded to further retreat in its traditional western markets by pursuing a thoroughly conventional strategy that aimed, essentially, to harvest its legacy assets and markets in the most capital efficient way possible.
That is what happens when you find that fewer and fewer people seem to want to buy what you make. And that brings us, pretty neatly, to the other core flaws in the Citi thesis.
Resources companies cannot afford to simply harvest their legacy. What you dig up needs to be replaced so, at very least, the miners needs to maintain a comparatively rare level of sustaining capital to ensure that shareholders have a legacy to be harvested.

Robert Rough

And then there is the issue of growth. Raw materials demand is not ex-growth. Demand for iron ore is expected to continue to grow at better than 1 per cent annually for a while yet. Demand for copper and light metals is expected to grow at better rates than through the next decade. And the growth outlook for the raw materials of our battery driven future looms even more exciting.
There is, in short, a lot of growing to do yet in the mining business. And that, in the end, is why it is so important for the boards and executives who run big mining to reflect on the mood that invites Citi's "musing" and that sustains .
The word is that Blackrock invited Citi's interesting little note. That is telling, first because of the position of seniority the funds manager holds on a slate mining industry registers.
But there is a broader message here. Earlier this week we talked here about the challenge big mining now faces in recovering the standing necessary to pursue growth options. And Citi's little thought bubble offers a timely if flawed pointer to the reportedly entrenched scepticism that is abroad, most particularly in the London markets. Put very simply, big mining's big owners reckon they can deploy capital more effectively than the extractors.
While we are talking bulk minerals, what on earth has happened to the  that was supposed to see the price of the Australian economy's bellwether range-bound somewhere under $US50 through most of calendar 2017?
Well, give or take a couple of million tonnes here or there, that wave has duly arrived. But its dampening impact has been constrained - at least at the top end of the iron ore food chain - by surging steel demand, production and pricing and by a set of structural and cyclical shifts in the way China is making its steel.
High steel prices continue to encourage Chinese steel mills to chase maximum productivity from their blast furnaces. The path to peak output is paved by the highest possible quality inputs.
As a result, demand for 62 per cent (and better) grades of iron ore is unexpectedly strong and small undershoots in forecast production by both Rio and Vale have had an overweight impact on a market that is now received as being short quality supply.

Rio's issues revolved around an unexpected need to replace rail tracks while Vale's issues are said to revolve around weather and operational issues caused by the need to blend southern and northern system ores.
Just last week at a Perth forum, Wood Mackenzie people warned that the 62 per cent market was under-supplied though the seaborne system remained in structurally over-supply.
That is why C while 58 per cent product was changing hands at $US47 a tonne. We have been talking to the delta between the index benchmarks for months now and Fortescue reported last week that it expected the trend to continue through this calendar year.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Walker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vincent Mundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi's London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xstratra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Braig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Rough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlackRock</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wood Mackenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortescue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citi</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
