<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407890321777415</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/paul-keating-accuses-bcas-westacott-of-peddling-falsehoods-over-company-tax-cuts-20170801-gxmrfd</url>
  <title>Keating accuses BCA of peddling falsehoods over company tax cuts</title>
  <content>
Former Labor prime minister Paul Keating has accused the Business Council of Australia's Jennifer Westacott of peddling falsehoods over company tax cuts, saying her "limited and jaundiced view" ignored how benefits would flow solely to foreign investors.
A day after the BCA chief executive  for claiming company tax cuts would impede growth, Mr Keating accused her of blackguarding the Opposition Leader.
Mr Keating told The Australian Financial Review "the principal peddler of untruths in respect of the economic impact of company tax cuts is Westacott herself".
"Westacott talks about incentives to invest coming from company tax cuts but has failed to acknowledge the elephant in the room - dividend imputation."

Louise Kennerley

Mr Keating argued that domestic shareholders do not benefit from  because they pay the same amount of tax on a dollar of company profit no matter what the company tax rate. This is because franked credits account for company tax already paid and domestic investors then pay the difference between that and their personal rate.

Foreign investors, however, receive dividends after the company has paid tax so the lower the tax rate the greater the dividends.
"The key point is if shareholders do not pay the company tax because it is returned to them, how can any nominal reduction in that rate make any difference to them?" Mr Keating said.
"It is hard to give a company tax cut to somebody who doesn't pay company tax. And this is the great majority of companies and their shareholders.
"Westacott, in her obfuscation, hides this central fact.

Peter Morris/Lowy Institute

"The fact is, Westacott, in her stewardship of the BCA, is essentially barracking for foreign investors, but she will not admit to it. Because it is foreign investors, and only foreign investors, who would benefit from a gratuitous company tax cut."
Mr Keating also took issue with Ms Westacott's assertion that a lower company tax rate would encourage greater investment.
"Companies invest when economic conditions are propitious to invest. Australia's primary mineral and petroleum industries increased investment by 6 per cent of GDP a year, roughly $100 billion per annum, for six consecutive years up to 2012," he said.
"And they did this with a company tax rate of 30 per cent. They did it to meet the enhanced demands of Chinese urbanisation.

"It is preposterous to claim, as Westacott claims, that companies will only invest if the corporate rate is lower, irrespective of commercial prospects at the time."
Mr Keating said the BCA has become "highly ideological and partisan under Jennifer Westacott".
" And it will remain so while ever her limited and jaundiced view remains currency," he said.
Ms Westacott returned fire, saying "the sizeable permanent economic boost (of the government's proposed company tax cuts), equivalent to $17 billion a year, modelled by the Treasury fully factors in the impact of dividend imputation".

"Domestic shareholders will gain over time from stronger investment and a more buoyant economy."
The BCA noted Mr Keating lowered the tax rate from 39 per cent to 33 per cent.
"The reasons for further reductions in the company tax rate are the same as those that have driven earlier reductions - that is the need to keep Australia competitive in the global contest for investment.
"As Ken Henry has said, the principal beneficiaries of a company tax cut would be workers, who benefit through higher wages. This is because increased investment makes workplaces more productive and their labour more valuable," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Westacott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Keating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westacott</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Westacott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Kennerley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Keating</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Morris/Lowy Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
