<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407800127462280</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/soccer/western-sydney-wanderers-marquee-oriol-riera-grabs-late-winner-in-ffa-cup-20170801-gxndr1.html</url>
  <title>Plenty of drama but no magic in Wanderers' cup win</title>
  <content>
If there ever was an example of why the FFA Cup round of 32 should not be fixed to force A-League teams against one another, then this was it.
Western Sydney Wanderers beat Wellington Phoenix 1-0 with the last touch of the game but despite the late drama, it was hardly a cup game that held any "magic".Photo: Michele Mossop
Marquee striker Oriol Riera scored on debut seconds before the game was set to go into penalties to send the Wanderers into the round of 16, masking an otherwise lacklustre and sluggish affair. 
The Spaniard struck a powerful header from a corner as all hope seemed to be lost for two teams that failed to pull the match out of the doldrums over 120 minutes of football. He leaped the highest over a lethargic, exhausted defence to snatch the vital winner.

The Wanderers started five new signings in their first competitive match of the season with Josh Risdon, Michael Thwaite, Chris Herd, Roly Bonevacia and marquee Oriol Riera making their debuts. 
They were understandably disjointed in attack, while disciplined and well-structured in defence but chances were few and far between. Wellington, under the tenure of new coach Darije Kalezic, were no better and save for a few pot shots from distance, never looked like threatening. 

Riera attempted to pull the game out of the doldrums with a clever, sweeping through-ball to Roly Bonevacia. It split the defence but unfortunately the Dutchman couldn't finish from close range. 
Riera looked the most dangerous and came close with a header late in the first half while Wanderers' Brendan Hamill was fortunate to remain on the park by the break.
He earned himself a yellow card for a rugby tackle on Roy Krishna, while an off-the-ball elbow later in the match went unsighted by the officials. 
The left-back escaped a caution but could face further disciplinary action if cited by the match review panel. 
Wanderers captain Robert Cornthwaite had the best chance of the game nine minutes after the restart when he volleyed off a corner from close-range, forcing new Wellington first-choice goalkeeper, Lewis Italian, pulled off a a superb reflex save. 
That was about as close as regular time came to providing a goal as a game that nobody wanted to watch more of went into extra-time.
There were few spells of intricate possession for either side and less chances. Only the arrival of Brendon Santalab in the last 15 minutes of extra-time piqued the fans' interest who had otherwise resorted to singing songs about past heroes, such as Shinji Ono, out of sheer boredom. 
A crude challenge by Josh Risdon in extra-time was lucky to have only been met with a yellow and a sickening one by Tom Doyle on Abraham Majok was somehow not followed-up with a red card.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roly Bonevacia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spaniards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shinji Ono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney Wanderers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Herd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riera</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanderers' Brendan Hamill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darije Kalezic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oriol Riera</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanderers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Krishna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Santalab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Thwaite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Risdon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abraham Majok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MICHELE MOSSOP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutchman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Cornthwaite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
