<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407808717396961</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/draft-gayles-law-bill-to-ensure-safety-of-outback-nurses-responding-to-emergencies/news-story/efce41d6de69b6177c6d87612fd8348b</url>
  <title>Gayle's Law a step closer for Outback nurses</title>
  <content>
A COLLEAGUE or escort will have to be within earshot of Outback nurses attending after-hours patient call-outs, under a landmark law to be introduced in response to the murder of Gayle Woodford.
The State Government has issued a draft version of "Gayle's Law", which will require remote health professionals to be accompanied by a second person to appointments or emergencies at night and on weekends.
Nurses lobbied for the introduction of the law after their colleague Ms Woodford was murdered near her home at Fregon on the APY lands in March, 2016.
The law would ensure that remote health professionals could not be sued or face professional disciplinary action for refusing to attend after-hours call-outs without a "second responder".
The Bill states that health professionals who refused to attend call-outs on their own: "Cannot be held to have breached any code of professional etiquette or ethics, or to have departed from any accepted from of professional conduct."
A second-responder would have to be physically present during after-hours patient consultations, unless the health professional decided this was inappropriate for privacy reasons. When this occurred, the second-responder would be required to remain within the hearing of the health professional.

Keith Woodford, flanked by his children, talks about the jailing of Dudley Davey for at least 32 years for the rape and murder of his wife and outback nurse Gayle Woodford. Davey, 35, pleaded guilty to both the rape and murder of the 56-year-old who was found buried in a shallow grave three days after she went missing from her home in Fregon, in SA's north, in March last year. (AAP Video/Tim Dornin)

Keith Woodford speaks after wife's murderer is jailed
Under the draft Gayle's Law Bill circulated to health groups by State Health Minister Jack Snelling, remote health services which failed to provide second-responders would be banned from entering contracts and agreements with the Government.
Nick Xenophon Team Senator Skye Kakoschke-Moore was concerned the Bill might not go far enough. "For example, the fact it will only apply out of hours, yet we know remote area nurses are attending dangerous call-outs at any time of the day,'' she said.
When it comes to accountability and enforcement, the legislation seems to be a toothless tiger, only resulting in a report to the parliament for ongoing failure to meet the requirements. Mr Snelling's office will brief Senator Kakoschke-Moore on the details of the Bill.
The Federal Government confirmed it would continue to provide the APY health service Ms Woodford worked for with funding to ensure nurses were escorted on call-outs.
In response to a question-on-notice from Senator Kakoschke-Moore, the Federal Health Department said the Nganampa Health Council would receive an additional $895,000 in funding in 2017/18.
In June, Dudley David Davey was sentenced to life in prison with a 32-year non-parole period for the rape and murder of Ms Woodford and the theft of an ambulance.
Ms Woodford's death sparked a national campaign by remote health workers for the abolition of single-nurse posts and for after-hours escorts. The campaign was backed by Ms Woodford's husband Keith Woodford.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Health Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davey, 35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dudley David Davey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dudley Davey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Woodford</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon Team Senator Skye Kakoschke-Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nganampa Health Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fregon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP Video/Tim Dornin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Snelling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gayle Woodford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Kakoschke-Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Woodford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Health Minister Jack Snelling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APY</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gayle's Law</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gayle's Law Bill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
