<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408070710407933</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/opinion/columnists/how-can-ir-reform-help-fix-the-low-wage-problem-20170801-gxmvie</url>
  <title>How can IR reform help fix the low wage problem?</title>
  <content>
by
Graeme Watson

High-level skills, innovation and technology help create more valuable employees who deserve higher rewards. The  is widely noted, but where is the plan to fix it? The obvious starting point is Australia's outmoded workplace relations system.
At some time during the next parliamentary session, the government is expected to announce its response to the . The report, commissioned in 2014, is  - failing to grapple with the full extent of problems across the economy and to propose meaningful solutions.
The delay in a government response is a further disappointment. But for the sake of the economy, the nature of the government's response should not complete a dismaying hat-trick.
When the PC report was commissioned, it was intended to be an important vehicle to drive economic reform. The terms of reference sought "recommendations about how the laws can be improved to maximise outcomes for Australian employers, employees and the economy, bearing in mind the need to ensure workers are protected, the need for business to be able to grow, prosper and employ, and the need to reduce unnecessary and excessive regulation".

A government with a focus on jobs and growth should have used the past 18 months to prepare a case for substantive changes. The problems of low wage growth, persistently high youth unemployment, the transforming economy and the changing nature of work have made the job more urgent.

Some fundamental points should be noted. Industrial relations laws are multi-faceted - that is, they affect different employers in different ways. Hence, piecemeal changes will not have a broad impact. Bolstering the rule of law for registered organisations is vital, but has limited significance outside the construction and maritime industries. Award compliance issues are mainly relevant to small businesses in industries that struggle to be profitable. Bargaining complications are relevant to the decreasing proportion of employers involved in formal bargaining.
Nature of the safety net

But more uniform award compliance and restrictions in the bargaining process bring the nature of the safety net more into focus. The safety net is on the rise from its internationally high base. The combined effect raises the spectre that awards and arbitration will return to greater prominence. When actions of regulators lead to more restrictive regulation it is obvious that there is a major problem.
An understanding of wage levels paid to Australian employees requires an appreciation of the segmentation of the workforce and the economy. Mainly for economic reasons, some employers seek to reduce labour costs to the minimum and cut the number of employees performing routine jobs. Count the employees in an Aldi store. And labour intensity is even lower in e-commerce. Staff-less retail outlets have arrived in China.

Employers who have the freedom to reward well for high performance operate on a different plane. Successful businesses use leadership, culture, values and employee engagement to drive innovation and higher productivity. Fairness, safety and accountability are embraced enthusiastically by all. Mutual discretionary effort flourishes. Many Australian businesses have successfully moved into this space, but too many others are caught in the Fair Work conflict trap.
Well paid jobs in aligned businesses is what Australia needs. And the last thing these businesses need is a regulatory system that institutionalises conflict.
Returning the rule of law to the construction industry will have obvious economic advantages. Construction is now Australia's second largest contributor to GDP and employs 9.1 per cent of total employees. However, in June, the ABS revealed that the construction industry accounted for 40 per cent of total working days lost due to industrial action. The Australian Building and Construction Commission has 50 proceedings before the courts, 47 against the CFMEU, in which there are 2307 alleged breaches of the law. The mind boggles at the impact on productivity from this type of workplace culture.
But the prize from a general reduction in adversarial relationships is much higher. As the McLeod report in the UK has noted, employee engagement, going to the heart of the working relationship, can be the key to unlocking productivity and transforming working lives. It is well established that putting smart people together will give rise to innovation and improvement. But they need a working environment that encourages their efforts. We should be asking why Wellington is succeeding in attracting technology talent at the expense of Sydney and Melbourne, and why an Australian bicycle designer is manufacturing his bikes for the Asian market on 3D printers in New Zealand.

Providing, indeed encouraging, a pathway towards a collaborative and productive business with their high performing, better paid jobs should be a fundamental element of a modern Australian workplace relations system. The government's response to the Productivity Commission report should start with such obvious objectives and incorporate meaningful changes that provide the kick-start we clearly need. Wasting political capital through inaction is a ludicrous alternative.
Graeme Watson is a former vice-president of the Fair Work Commission.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Productivity Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Watson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aldi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Construction Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLeod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Building</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
