<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407636918701161</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/heidelberg-united-beat-perth-glory-in-ffa-cup-clash/news-story/9ae51ea27c361701f874e13e17175189</url>
  <title>Heidelberg send Glory crashing out of Cup</title>
  <content>
IT was another one for the little guys.
IN the first FFA Cup giant killing of 2017, local Victorian outfit Heidelberg United toppled the A-League's Perth Glory 1-0 at a raucous Olympic Village on Tuesday night.
And didn't it deserve it?
Kenny Athiu put his name up in lights with a powerful 48th minute strike, but there were heroes aplenty for George Katsakis' side, with the Sean Ellis starring in a forward role, Harry Noon dominating midfield and Steven Pace and Luke Byles providing rock solid defence.
It was a night where former Perth player Adrian Zahra got one over his old side, with Zahra's words in Tuesday's Herald Sun proving prophetic - that good National Premier League teams can match it with A-League clubs.
Heidelberg, as it proved on Tuesday night, is just that.
Victoria's is regarded as the best state competition in the country and Heidelberg sits on top of the tree with three matches to play.
Perth on the other hand is just starting its pre-season and actually lost a friendly to state opposition two weeks ago.
On Tuesday night it was without Johnny Warren Medalist Diego Castro, star No.10 Mitch Nichols and midfield enforcer Rostyn Griffiths, while Jake Brimmer, 19, got a start despite only signing from Liverpool on Monday.

Football: A moving moment ahead of the FFA Cup match between Perth and Heidelberg.

FFA's Les Murray tribute
Despite Perth being a two-time FFA Cup finalist and having never been bundled out of the competition this early, the Glory was ripe for the picking.
But that should not dampen the achievement one bit, as the manner of the win was just so impressive.
Joining Adelaide City, Redlands United and fellow Victorians Green Gully as NPL sides to defeat A-League opposition in the Cup's four-year history, this was not a win built on a sucker punch goal and a park-the-bus attitude.
Heidelberg was the dominant team for much of the night against a Perth side that was clearly wanting to win if coach Kenny Lowe's usual sideline theatrics were anything to go by.
But the visitors were not allowed into the contest.
Stats can be misleading, but the fact Heidelberg shaded the possession share and had 16 shots to six shows it was unwilling to take a backwards step.
The result was also symbolic in this week of mourning for Australian football.
The first game Les Murray commentated on was the 1980 National Soccer League grand final between Heidelberg United and Sydney City in Canberra.
Heidelberg won 4-0 that day.
So it was fitting that in the first game broadcast nationally since the death of "Mr Football", Heidelberg would score a famous victory.
You'd suspect, watching on from above, he'd have been happy with the result.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Nichols</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zahra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny Athiu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Noon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren Medalist Diego Castro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorians Green Gully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Katsakis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Football</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA's Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redlands United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glory</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Zahra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Soccer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Byles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rostyn Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Pace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday's Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Brimmer, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
