<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407954746288405</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:24</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/nabs-head-of-retirement-says-product-is-part-of-the-conversation-20170801-gxn6u9</url>
  <title>NAB's head of retirement Brian Long says 'product is part of the conversation'</title>
  <content>
National Australia Bank's head of retirement Brian Long says the bank has no plans to stop manufacturing its own wealth products and insists they will remain "part of the conversation" staff will have with customers.
Mr Long, who joined NAB's asset management business in January this year, told The Australian Financial Review he is the bank's first "voice of retirement" and is keenly interested in the ways new investment products can be used to make up shortfalls in the superannuation savings of Australians.
"Where product comes in is that where you haven't got enough [retirement savings] - and people don't have enough - the industry has got to find a way of meeting your needs," he said.
"We've got to get our thinking caps on and think about how do we give a client more growth assets ... and that has to be a product discussion. How to do we create products that are better for retirees."

In 2016, NAB offloaded 80 per cent of its life insurance business to Japanese giant Nippon Life. But Mr Long, a veteran of Colonial First State, Mercer and former head of distribution at van Eyk, said exiting the creation of other wealth products was not on the cards for NAB.

"Product is part of the conversation. We as an organisation, we offer our own package solutions, we'll bring out products that are better account-based pensions, we'll put products on our investment platforms for direct access," he said.
"We'll provide that help and guidance to use those products appropriately. That skill we have in asset allocation... you can add a lot of value to clients by being in and out of asset classes at the right time."
Rivals change emphasis

This comes as other big institutions reduce the emphasis of product to the business or look to exit product manufacturing all together.

ANZ has said that it made little sense for it to use its capital to manufacture wealth products and would
Suncorp is also mulling the sale of its life insurance arm and is
But Mr Long said with less than half of Australians feeling prepared for retirement, NAB is focused on the different objectives Australians have in retirement, with "engagement" being equally as important as a "product solution".
"There is too much focus in the industry on the amount and it's really what standard of living you want in retirement," said Mr Long.

"People have different objectives in retirement. [Those with] lower balances [may say] 'why should I bother? Why shouldn't I give up?' There is actually a lot we can tell them to do to improve their lives."
Mining data to help customers

NAB is now investing an undeclared amount of money into mining the data of its customers, in a move designed to help then make the right retirement planning decisions.
"We're doing a lot of data mining. We know what their spending is, we know their assets, we know their liabilities, we know their super. With some powerful optimisation tools we can put their financial lives together for them in a way that's never been done," said Mr Long.

"We're going to invest in [financial modelling] and change their financial lives ...  Unlike accumulation where you can shoehorn people into very narrow ranges of risk, everyone [in retirement] sits in a different place. That's spurring the product innovation and more than one solution."
AFRthat product sales will form a smaller part of the remuneration equation for NAB's frontline staff when a new incentive plan is rolled out from October 1
"Their reward now will not be as focused on product sales but rather on this balanced scorecard which includes outcomes, customer outcomes, risk outcomes and financial outcomes," NAB's chief customer officer, Andrew Haggar, said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nippon Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Long</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Long</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Haggar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eyk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFRthat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colonial First State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
