<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407804422429584</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/utah-jazz-star-joe-ingles-says-preseason-nba-games-in-us-will-pave-the-way-for-a-match-in-australia/news-story/78117528020a553036c07f170589e49a</url>
  <title>Could an NBA game come to Australia?</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN Utah Jazz star Joe Ingles says he will do whatever it takes to enhance the chances of an NBA game being played Down Under.
On a day when the NBL announced a historic agreement to play a pre-season triple-header against NBA teams in America this October, Ingles had his sights set on the bigger picture.
The veteran Boomer and former NBL Rookie of the Year believes the new partnership with the NBA will pave the way for a game on Australian soil.
NBL boss Larry Kestelman has had preliminary discussions about an NBA match in Sydney or Melbourne in 2019 in the lead-up to the World Cup in China.
The National Basketball Players' Association in America would have to give any match in Australia the green light for it to go ahead.
It's why Ingles insists player support and campaigning will be crucial in getting an NBA fixture in cities like Sydney or Melbourne over the line.
"For sure and I'll be advocating for it," Ingles said about the prospect of an NBA game in Australia.
"Hopefully one day and I know I will be pushing for it.
"There are obviously steps to get there. We started with Basketball Without Borders and Larry (Kestelman) and his team did unreal with that.
"And to do this (pre-season NBA games) is the next step."
The NBL has already signalled their intentions for the 2017 pre-season matches to become part of the NBA and NBL's annual calendars.
Ingles agrees and says he'd like to see more players given the opportunity to test themselves against the NBA's finest.
"I think every NBL team should get the chance to be a part of this," he said.
"Obviously the first one is to get some teams over there to compete to make it a good event and worthwhile.
"Why not send Wollongong and let the other five teams have a crack too.
"I think if it is a good event it will just continue building and then obviously the next step is to bring a game out here.
"Larry is probably having those conversations already, but there are a lot of moving parts that have to happen with the players as well."
For Ingles, the historic clash against the Sydney Kings on October 3 (AEST) will be more than just a basketball game.
On top of the match being played on his 30th birthday, he'll take on fellow Adelaide product and former school friend - Kings swingman Brad Newley.
Friendships aside, Ingles says the NBA's high respect for Australian basketball will ensure the Jazz won't take the Kings for granted.
"For us it's a serious game," he said.
"Our pre-season is cut in half, so I think we play four or five games instead of nine or 10.
"So we've got to take it as seriously as we would in game 82. They (the Kings) will be the same because it is part of their pre-season.
"It won't be taken lightly. Anyone that knows our coach (Quin Snyder) knows he won't be taking it lightly.
"I think it will take a while for the (Kings) guys to adjust to the NBA rules and the three-point line.
"For us in Utah there is also the altitude - the first quarter they might be struggling a bit.
"But I'm hoping we win, but if they play well there is every chance of an upset."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Newley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Basketball Players' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quin Snyder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL Rookie of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basketball Without Borders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
