<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407641213668520</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/simon-sinek-key-to-starting-successful-business-leadership-2017-7</url>
  <title>A leadership expert reveals the one question to ask yourself when starting a business</title>
  <content>
Simon Sinek is the author of four books, including his latest, "Leaders Eat Last." He sat down with Business Insider to discuss how to start a successful business. Following is a transcript of the video.

So, there are many ways. A "why" is an origin story. It is the reason why we get out of bed in the morning. It's the reason why we started the business in the first place. The best businesses are usually formed out of personal experience where I personally suffered a problem or somebody I love or care about suffered something and the solution that I found became the business that we built.

The weaker businesses tend to be ones where I looked in a magazine, I saw there was an opportunity, and I decided to start a business.

And the reason is because people aren't really passionate about that. We're passionate for the things we actually do in our lives. Take a look at Airbnb. Airbnb was started because a bunch of people came for a conference and they opened up their home and had people stay in this air bed and breakfast.

Because they set up all these air beds. That's literally how it started. It was a real solution to a real problem. And because it worked so well they did it again, and again, and again. And before you know it, a business was formed. Those are the best ones. But that still doesn't capture the why.

The why really is based on the founder or founders. It's who you are as people. And the business you form, you form in your own image. Virgin is Richard Branson. Apple is Steve Jobs. It's the same thing.

So you really want to go through your own life and you look at the peaks and valleys in your own life, and you'll find that there's a pattern in all of your experiences that you absolutely loved being a part of. That pattern is your why - it's the thing that inspires you the most and the thing that drives your passion.

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Sinek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Jobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Branson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leaders Eat Last</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
