<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407765767722995</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/chanticleer/ahmed-fahours-bcg-move-is-a-reversal-of-the-talent-flow-20170801-gxn98w</url>
  <title>Why do Australian boards employ so many consultants?</title>
  <content>
When Ahmed Fahour moved seamlessly from chief executive of Australia Post to the digital arm of Boston Consulting Group he confirmed the powerful nexus between Australian business and management consulting.
after a 20-year absence that included
He is reversing the normal flow of talented people from consulting firm to various high-level roles in business.
Before exploring why Fahour's move is a clever strategic one that should enhance his career it is worth exploring a pressing question: Why there is such a high level of trust placed in management consultants by Australian boards?

Josh Robenstone

A separate but not unrelated question is: Why do so many boards approve the expenditure of tens of millions of dollars on external management consultants on the advice of the CEO?

To back up the proposition that Australian business is enamoured with consultants run your finger down the list of the top 100 companies.
The first two companies are, of course, run by former management consultants., is CEO of the Commonwealth Bank of Australia and Brian Hartzer, a former management consultant at First Manhattan, is CEO of Westpac Banking Corp.
Within the ranks of Westpac, the CEO of the consumer bank, George Frazis, is a former BCG consultant.
His chairman, Gordon Cairns is a former McKinsey consultant.

Josh Robenstone

Alumni swell executive ranks

The McKinsey alumni is pretty extensive and includes Matt Bekier, who is CEO of Star Entertainment Group, and Alison Watkins, who is CEO of Coca-Cola Amatil. Former CEO of the ASX, Elmer Funke Kupper is a former McKinsey consultant who managed to work in banking, wagering and the securities industry.
Jayne Hrdlicka, who is CEO of Jetstar Group, is a former Bain consultant.
One observation about this cohort is that all have high IQs and proven emotional intelligence. That distinguishes them from many of their former colleagues in consulting who failed the emotional IQ test and did not make the transition to business.

Peter Rae

Boards are attracted to management consultants because of the depth and breadth of the work they have done. More importantly, consultants tend to have been forced to make rapid decisions about threats to business, particularly from digital disrupters.
A management consultant's job is to shake up companies. In doing so they have to put forward a difficult hypothesis and solve it.
Of course, 80 per cent of management consultants end up leaving the firm to find a real job in business. McKinsey's business model relies upon these former partners to continuing supplying the firm with work from the other side of the fence.
It is common for former consultants to call in the people they used to work with, either to fill senior executive positions or to work on projects requiring rapid change.

Ben Rushton

BCG's work on a roll

It is no surprise that the. In his case it is BCG.
BCG is obviously on a roll considering it is doing work with ANZ, National Australia Bank and AMP at the same time. It is assumed they are all being given unique advice on how to attack the country's tight-knit financial services market and respond to threats from fintech competitors.
This is the obvious segue into the BCG diversification into digital ventures. By adding digital services to its range of services BCG is ensuring it can get two bites of the consulting revenue dispersed by major companies.

Australia is said to be one of the most lucrative markets in the world for consultants and that is really a tribute to the lack of tough conversations at board level about the role of highly-paid managers.
It is one thing to hire a former management consultant for his or her breadth and depth of experience across different industries and his or her high IQ and EQ and another thing altogether to squib the critical issue of internal talent management.
Boards are too ready to approve the employment ofwithout pressing CEOs to employ their own digital transformation staff.
Australia Post is a prime example of this. While Fahour was successful in executing a transformation strategy that is unmatched in the global postal industry
BCG was employed in 2014 to carry out a project called "a deep dive on reform", which reviewed the letters business and made recommendations for change.
An Australia Post spokesman said BCG was selected by shareholder departments of the government following a competitive tender process.
"Australia Post was not involved in assessing the tender," the spokesman said.
Keeping distance from decisions

Chanticleer understands that Fahour ensured he was excused from all decision making in relation to BCG at Australia Post.
This distancing of himself was sensible and it happened again in 2015 when Australia Post examined the idea of a "Digital Identity Solution", which cost $3.9 million.
A spokesman said this involved a "robust market analysis to determine a suitable business partner with proven experience to develop a digital identity solution".
"This process included interviews, immersion sessions and site visits to a number of organisations.
"BCG was assessed as having a unique and superior perspective and proposition around how to start up a new business in the context of a large corporate.
"They had a strong appreciation and understanding of the limits and constraints around such areas as governance, funding, branding and decision making. Other incubators tended to focus on the start-up space and the sourcing of venture capital funding.
"Mr Fahour was kept at arm's-length through the process of engaging BCG DV for this piece of work. The executive in charge of making the recommendations to proceed with BCG DV was Mr Andrew Walduck, executive general manager Trusted eCommerce Services."
Mentoring and advice

When he left Australia Post Fahour discussed with the Post chairman John Stanhope his decision to be non-executive chairman of BCG Digital Ventures.
Stanhope told Chanticleer he did not see any conflict of interest and the job "passed the smell test".
He said that it was not a full-time job and Fahour would really be providing mentoring and advice about his views on digital disruption to the BCG staff.
Fahour made clear that he would be working for BCG Digital Ventures for only about two or three days a month.
But the move is clever because he will be able to travel to all of the BCG Digital Venture offices in Shanghai, Singapore and the United States to absorb its intellectual capital.
He is in a prime position to enjoy the flow of information about the latest developments in digital disruption as he prepares for his next CEO role.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCG</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Frazis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Rushton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elmer Funke Kupper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cola Amatil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fahour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston Consulting Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IQS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Bekier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrew Walduck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post Fahour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayne Hrdlicka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of the ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanhope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Identity Solution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fahour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Robenstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of the Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCG DV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banking Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Fahour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chanticleer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Hartzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Stanhope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCG Digital Ventures</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Coca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alison Watkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEOs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKinsey</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trusted eCommerce Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Rae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
