<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408019170799228</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4827615/former-staffer-squares-up-against-lambie/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Former staffer squares up against Lambie</title>
  <content>
Tasmanian senator Jacqui Lambie

Jacqui Lambie's former chief of staff Rob Messenger is seeking damages from the North-West senator over non-payment of a ghostwritten autobiography.
In documents lodged with the Burnie Magistrates Court last month, Mr Messenger claims he is still owed $4000 for the delivered manuscript.
The documents allege the agreement was that Mr Messenger would receive $12,000 in three installations of the $20,000 that publishers Allen & Unwin had offered Senator Lambie for the book of between 80 to 90,000 words.
It is claimed timelines to deliver the book were changed by verbal agreement due to issues around the double-dissolution election in 2016, and that the deadline would be extended to June 1.
The documents state that Mr Messenger's professional relationship with Senator Lambie deteriorated in March.

Still, it was agreed to the following month that the arrangements for the book would remain.

Publishing director Tom Gillett said by email in April that Senator Lambie was happy to continue with the book though he was unsure of what changes she would want to make to the final chapters.
Mr Messenger and his wife Fern, who worked as Senator Lambie's office manager, were sacked on May 3 but the final chapters of the book were delivered five days later.
The pages were rejected by both the publisher and Senator Lambie several days after that, and the writing arrangement was also terminated.
Senator Lambie was contacted for comment on the matter on Tuesday.
"My lawyer is onto this and has told me it would be inappropriate to comment," she said.

Mr Messenger also lodged an unfair dismissal claim in the Federal Court on Monday against Ms Lambie and the federal government.

The two separate court actions follow the explosive leaking of a letter written by Mr Messenger in which he complained of Senator Lambie's unpredictable behaviour, vile language, and complaints about her sex life. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lambie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui Lambie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Messenger</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Lambie</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Messenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Gillett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnie Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
