<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407641213668593</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/yougov-poll-leave-voters-happy-for-relatives-to-lose-jobs-over-brexit-2017-8</url>
  <title>Leave voters are happy for family members to lose their jobs over Brexit</title>
  <content>
LONDON - Brexit voters are willing for the British economy to take "significant damage" from leaving the EU, even if it means their own family members losing their jobs, a new poll has found.

61% of all Brexit-backers believe that significant damage to the British economy would be a "price worth paying for Brexit," according to the new

A further 39% of all Leave voters would also be willing for their own family members to lose their jobs as a price for Brexit, with just 38% opposed.

Among all those expressing a preference, the proportion of Brexit voters who are content for relatives to be made unemployed rises to 51%.

Older Leave voters are the most relaxed about family members losing their jobs due to Brexit. Among Brexit-backers over 65 years age, 50% say it would be a price worth paying with 22% unsure.

The poll also found around one-in-five Remain voters would also be willing for serious damage to take place to the economy and for relatives to lose their jobs in order to "teach Leave politicians and Leave voters a lesson."

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit-backers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
