<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407765767723057</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/theres-an-easter-egg-hidden-in-the-ready-player-one-movie-logo/</url>
  <title>There's An Easter Egg Hidden In The Ready Player One Movie Logo</title>
  <content>
Steven Spielberg's adaptation of Ready Player One looks like it's going to be one of those movies we keep finding secrets and Easter eggs in years after its release. But it turns out one of the first has been hiding in the film's official logo since it was released a few weeks ago. Do you see it?

Created by a graphic designer named  working at design studio , the logo perfectly balances near-future aesthetics and '80s nostalgia. But if you look even closer you'll notice many of the logo's letters are connected because the entire graphic is actually a functional maze connecting the first 'R' to an egg hidden inside the "O" on "One".

The maze is an homage to a 1979 Atari 2600 video game called Adventure, which, appropriately enough, first introduced the world to the concept of Easter eggs as the game's creator, Warren Robinett, gave himself a secret hidden credit inside it. In the original Ready Player One book, the video game Adventure is what inspires OASIS creator James Halliday to create the contest for his fortune and control of Gregarious Simulation Systems, the company that runs the virtual world.

Solving this maze isn't quite as rewarding, unless you thrive on revealing secrets and hidden surprises to your friends.

[]

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Spielberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ready Player One Movie Logo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Halliday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atari 2600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Robinett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregarious Simulation Systems</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easter Egg Hidden In</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ready Player One</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
