<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408066415440577</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/accounting/aicd-clause-prevents-ceo-pay-disclosure-20170607-gwmnl1</url>
  <title>Australian Institute of Company Directors clause prevents CEO pay disclosure</title>
  <content>
The nation's largest professional body for company directors has revealed it cannot legally divulge the salary of its past two CEOs because of a confidentially clause within their contracts.
The terms of the contracts mean the Australian Institute of Company Directors, which has the core mission of corporate governance and governance education, cannot tell its 40,000-strong membership how much was paid to John Brogden, who was CEO between 2015 and earlier this year, and John Colvin, who was CEO between 2008 and 2015.
Chairman Elizabeth Proust said the confidentiality clause will be eliminated from the contract of the next CEO, with a decision on the position to be made in the coming weeks.
"The confidentiality is around the remuneration of the CEO. [There's] a draft contract awaiting the appointment of a new CEO. That clause is not repeated and we will, when announcing the name of the CEO, announce the remuneration of the CEO," Ms Proust said.

Asked if the existence of the clause was an illustration of good governance, she replied: "No it's not. But it's history and we're not repeating it in the contract that I'll be responsible for signing."

Disclosing the remuneration of CEOs and key personnel has become a key test of governance at member bodies after the implosion at CPA Australia, which was fuelled in part by an initial lack of disclosure over  and the amount paid to senior management.
Expert criticises contract

The confidentiality clause for CEO pay at the AICD was slammed by governance expert Peter Swan of the UNSW Business School.
"A confidentiality clause like that promotes opacity and denies the right of members to know how much key executives are paid. This is particularly so for the AICD because they teach governance rules for listed companies and one of the requirements for all listed companies is that the pay of executives has to be fully revealed," he said.

Ms Proust said the AICD had not yet decided if the body would break out the pay of key management personnel as is done in the reports of listed companies.
"The issue is we're not a listed company and the governance and the constitution of an organisation needs to be fit for purpose. The question [of pay disclosure] is being discussed in the next period of time by the HR committee and the audit committee of the AICD in relation to just that question," she said.
The AICD's last annual report showed that key management personnel, including then-CEO John Brogden, earned a collective $3.74 million.
Ms Proust said "our salaries are nothing like the salaries paid at CPA" but said events at the CPA will be a factor that "obviously you take into account".

Courses 'reasonably priced'

She also said the body's courses were reasonably priced given the length of the courses and the cost and quality of the facilitators, adding that the body had 150 not-for-profit scholarships on offer at the moment. The AICD's flagship seven-day company directors course costs members $7235 and non-members $10,189.
Ms Proust said the , introduced by , to compel companies covered by the Corporations Act to collect email addresses of their members, but its submission calls for a policy that is a more holistic solution.
"These concerns include the need for further consideration of privacy and cyber-crime risks, the practicalities of imposing the obligation on companies as a strict liability offence, and the desire to consider the implementation of technology neutrality across the Corporations Act in a holistic way," she said.

Professor Swan said that while some of the AICD's concerns are valid, the body should have gone into the benefits of the changes.
"Instead of attacking the proposed legislation, why not praise it for saving organisations millions in postal charges once members are required to provide email addresses, as they do postal addresses?"

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Proust</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Brogden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman Elizabeth Proust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporations Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute of Company</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Swan of the UNSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Swan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO John Brogden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AICD</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEOs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
