<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407963336223277</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:26</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/retail/surfstitch-shareholders-told-to-reject-puzzling-crown-proposal-20170801-gxn8ds</url>
  <title>SurfStitch shareholders advised to reject 'puzzling' Crown proposal </title>
  <content>
Proxy advisers have denounced attempts by SurfStitch's second largest shareholder and thwarted suitor, Crown Financial,  as "puzzling" and not in the interests of minority investors.
Long-suffering SurfStitch shareholders will meet in Sydney on Wednesday to consider a proposal from Crown, which owns 10.3 per cent of the embattled online surf wear retailer, to remove Mr Weiss from the board.
Crown, l and his tenure has been marked by board dysfunction, inconsistent strategy, ongoing losses, the sale of assets at significant losses and the decimation of the share price.
However, proxy adviser CGI Glass Lewis has rejected Crown's claims, questioned the publishing group's motivation in calling for the removal of Mr Weiss, and advised shareholders to vote against the Crown proposal.

Crown's case against Mr Weiss was "demonstrably inadequate" and the group had failed to clearly establish Mr Weiss' culpability for SurfStitch's operational and legal problems.

"Just as importantly, Crown appears to offer no alternative candidates for chairman and fails to describe any value-maximising alternatives which, when combined with a recently failed takeover attempt by a Crown affiliate, causes us to view the current dissident campaign rather sceptically," CGI Glass Lewis said.
The Crown group launched  over a failed content deal agreed with former chief executive Justin Cameron. SurfStitch has countersued, alleging Crown affiliates were involved in .
"Whether these counter-claims ultimately prove to be legally supportable is presently unknown," CGI Glass Lewis said.
"We nevertheless believe it is important to acknowledge Crown's historical exposure to the company clearly expands substantially beyond its position as a shareholder, and, as a result, the dissident may have interests and intentions that diverge substantially from those of otherwise unaffiliated investors."

The SurfStitch board has also advised shareholders to vote against the Crown proposal and has defended Mr Weiss and other directors and senior management, saying they were all appointed after the events associated with the contested content deals and an ASIC investigation.
"In the view of the board, Mr Weiss' skills and accumulated knowledge are important for the task of turning the company around and addressing the various challenges that the company is facing," SurfStitch said last week.
after losing two-thirds of their value in 12 months, falling to 6.8¢, a fraction of their December 2014 issue price of $1.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Weiss</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CGI Glass Lewis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SurfStitch</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Financial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
