<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408019170799221</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/accounting/deloitte-ey-kpmg-and-pwc-split-on-diversity-targets-20170724-gxhyju</url>
  <title>PwC splits with Deloitte, EY and KPMG on diversity targets</title>
  <content>
More than 95 per cent of EY partners identify as being from an English, Irish, Scottish or "Australian" background but only 73 per cent were born in one of those countries.
At the staff level, the contrast is even bigger, with 90 per cent from this background but only 56 per cent born in one of those countries.
The wide variation in results for the big four accounting and consulting firm highlights the issues that arise when measuring cultural diversity and is one of the reasons EY does not have specific diversity targets.
"What this data reflects is the inherent difficulty in collecting these types of data - when you ask our staff what cultural background they belong to, they're most likely to tell us that they're Australian," said Tony Johnson, the Oceania managing partner and CEO of EY.

Pat Scala

The big four firms differ on both the way they measure cultural diversity and the use of targets.

EY, KPMG and PwC all use some form of survey to determine the background of their staff, while Deloitte . Only PwC has set targets, around the cultural diversity for new partner admissions, while EY, KPMG and Deloitte do not have specific diversity targets.
All the firms have other goals around increasing diversity at their respective workplaces.
The partner in charge of Deloitte's cultural diversity efforts, Leon Doyle, said targets based on cultural background were ineffective "."
PwC chief diversity and inclusion officer Julie McKay disagrees. "You can't change what you're not measuring, and we measure what's important to us," she said.

Les Hewitt

'Targets send a signal'

The Race Discrimination Commissioner Tim Soutphommasane has stated he wants to see better collection of cultural diversity data and believes "".
Both EY's Mr Johnson and PwC CEO Luke Sayers, along with six other corporate leaders, are on Dr Soutphommasane's Leadership Council on Cultural Diversity.
Mr Johnson said EY uses a regular internal census that collects a wide variety of data for each staff member.

Les Hewitt

"This data covers each individual's place of birth, international experience, citizenship and language skills to help create a comprehensive understanding of their cultural experience," he said.
"With our employee's permission, we then securely record this data against their personnel files - much like their gender - which provides us with much richer analytics on the experience of cultural diversity at our firm."
'Targets not appropriate'

Mr Johnson said his firm was focusing on other initiatives to attract and retain culturally diverse employees instead of specific targets.

"It's important to remember that while we've been talking about gender diversity for some time now, the national discussion on cultural diversity is relatively recent in comparison," he said.
"Because of this, targets and goals aren't appropriate at this stage for increasing cultural diversity - we're not yet at the point where we can accurately set a firm-wide target for cultural diversity, as we still don't have the right knowledge to understand the right numbers to aim for."
KPMG uses a voluntary annual people survey to measure the cultural diversity of its partners and staff but does not have targets, said Barbara Taylor, the head of talent, inclusion and diversity at the firm.
"Survey responses tell us our people come from a wide range of cultural backgrounds. We know that cultural diversity is greatest in our people below manager, and we have revised the questions for our next survey to provide better information and understanding on the cultural diversity of our people at all career stages."

Ms Taylor said the firm had a strong focus on inclusion and diversity, and this includes diversity of cultural backgrounds.
Partner diversity targets

PwC uses an annual survey which asks staff to self-identify if they come from a diverse cultural background, said Ms McKay.
Based on the May 2017 survey, 18 per cent of partners and 45 per cent of employees identify as coming from a diverse cultural background.
The firm also has a strong emphasis on targets. In 2016 the target was that 20 per cent of new partners would be from a diverse cultural background, rising to 30 per cent in 2020. The firm has previously said its diversity targets aim to have the partnership .
Ms McKay said the use of targets meant "the need to foster diversity and inclusion at all levels" was front of mind for decision at the firm.
"We want to ensure our leadership is reflective of top talent in our firm and in Australia, and we recognise that our historical processes haven't delivered us that in our partnership For us at PwC, this is about shining a spotlight on talented people from diverse cultural backgrounds and addressing any barriers that may exist to their progression into partnership," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EY</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EY's Mr Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race Discrimination Commissioner Tim Soutphommasane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oceania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PwC CEO Luke Sayers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbara Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PwC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of EY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Soutphommasane's Leadership Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cultural Diversity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Scala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPMG</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Hewitt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie McKay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McKay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
