<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408075005375333</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/economy/employment/male-earnings-going-backwards-while-multiple-jobs-play-greater-role-20170801-gxmwzt</url>
  <title>Lack of real wage growth 'insidious': RBA</title>
  <content>
Men's weekly earnings have flatlined and even fallen in recent years while women have experienced strong wage growth, potentially reducing the long-standing gender pay gap.
The overall soft wage figures from the coincide with more employees working multiple part-time jobs to achieve full-time hours and with a broad deterioration in labour market conditions for recent university graduates.
The data, which involves detailed responses from individual employees up to 2015, is expected to add fuel to the  and .
The report showed there had been little growth in full-time male employees' average and median weekly earnings since 2012, with average earnings rising from $1667 to just $1691 in the two years to 2014.

Between 2014 and 2015, their earnings went backwards by 1 per cent to $1673 - lower than what it had been in 2013.

In contrast, female earnings grew "quite strongly" between 2014 and 2015, rising 3.6 per cent from $1284 a week to $1330. However, the jump came off two years of "almost unchanged" average earnings.
University of Melbourne Professor Roger Wilkins, who authored the HILDA report, said the data showed "very tentative" signs that the gap between male and female pay may be closing.
"If this continues that might suggest we're making some inroads into the incredibly persistent gender pay gap."
Women were also less likely to leave the labour market, with the female exit rate from the labour force between 2014 and 2015 the lowest ever recorded.

More workers combining part-time jobs

The report found the proportion of employees  at about its 2009 average of 7.5 per cent.
However, the proportion of those multiple job holders who combined part-time jobs to achieve full-time hours had climbed dramatically from 18 per cent in 2001 to 26 per cent in 2015.
"Multiple-job holding is therefore playing a greater role in delivering full-time employment to those who want full-time work," the report concluded.

Mr Wilkins said this "is a natural response to high underemployment if you can't get enough hours".
New graduates were also increasingly likely to find themselves in part-time employment, with the part-time rate rising from 17.1 per cent of those who graduated from 2001 to 2005 to 25.2 per cent of graduates in 2012 or 2013.
Consistent with the part-time rise, graduates' average pay two years out of university had fallen by a third, from $1468 a week in 2005 to $1023 in 2013.
Lack of real wage growth 'insidious': RBA

The declining incomes and push to create full-time work from part-time jobs comes a week after RBA governor Philip Lowe said an increase in aggregate wage growth would be a "positive development" and warned if 2 per cent increases continued, incomes would decline.
"If workers are getting no real wage growth year after year that is insidious," he said.
Dr Lowe also  that showed about 25 per cent of part-timers wanted more hours while just under 10 per cent said they worked part-time because they could not find full-time jobs.
The RBA is looking , which measure the additional hours sought by workers, as a potential reason for low wage growth.

The minutes from its July 4 monetary policy meeting noted that the underemployment rate "remained elevated" despite the lowest unemployment rate since early 2013.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
