<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407868846940313</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/adam-warlocks-cocoon-from-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2-is-even-creepier-up-close/</url>
  <title>Adam Warlock's Cocoon From Guardians Of The Galaxy Vol. 2 Is Even Creepier Up Close</title>
  <content>
Versions of Adam Warlock's cocoon have appeared in both Guardians of the Galaxy films, and every time I've seen them my skin has crawled, even though the pods are only on the screen for the briefest of moments. Imagine my horror, then, as I gazed upon the high-definition concept art for the monstrosities.

Image: Marvel Studios

Over the weekend, freelance artist Ian Joyner posted a 3D model of his take on Adam's Cocoon to his , and while his work is absolutely phenomenal, it's also kind of disgusting to look at. Even though it's fashioned out of highly-advanced Sovereign technology, the thing still looks like a horrifying cross between an , a cockroach's carapace, and the underside of a horseshoe crab.

Image: Ian Joyner

We already know that the thing inside the cocoon will look human enough (assuming the MCU's Adam Warlock looks anything like his comics counterpart), but it's going to be nearly impossible to forget that he crawled out of that thing like an insect.

[]

WATCH MORE: Entertainment News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardians Of The Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam's Cocoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Joyner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Warlock's Cocoon From Guardians Of The Galaxy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Studios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Warlock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCU's Adam Warlock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
