<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407959041255813</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:25</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/telecommunications/vodafone-halves-loss-despite-2b-tech-spend-20170801-gxn3wu</url>
  <title>Vodafone halves loss despite $2b tech spend</title>
  <content>
The country's third largest telco, Vodafone Hutchison Australia (VHA), halved its loss in the first half of 2017 despite flagging a $2 billion spend on its mobile network for this calendar year, as it seeks to consign its "" days to history.
The loss of $81.5 million for the six months to June 30, 2017, represented a 50.3 per cent decrease year-on-year, with most of the loss due to depreciation from heavy investments to fix VHA's mobile network in the first half of this decade, according to chief financial officer James Marsh.
VHA's total revenue increased 3 per cent year-on-year to $1.65 million, meaning the $2 billion technology spend flagged for 2017 is around 60 per cent of annualised revenue.
Mr Marsh admitted the spend was high, but pointed out much of it had gone on a new fibre rollout to VHA's 1800 base stations around the country, via a .

Vodaphone

"It means that as we upgrade the network we are not curtailed by transmission issues, and it sets us up for the  in the future," he told an analyst call on Tuesday.

Like every mobile network provider, VHA is having to continually invest to keep up with customer demand for mobile data downloads. Mr Marsh said the average amount of data downloaded each month by its customers had increased from 3.2 gigabytes to 4.8 gigabytes over the past year.
VHA has historical reasons to be more conscious than most telcos of providing a seamless experience to its customer base, which grew by 190,000 to 5.7 million over the first half of 2017.
Mr Marsh revealed VHA's "net promoter score" - a measure of the willingness of customers to recommend a company's products or services to others - had turned positive 18 months ago for the first time since the .
Prepared to keep investing

VHA has provided no forecast for when it expects to turn a profit, but Mr Marsh said the company's two shareholders - CK Hutchison Holdings and Vodafone Group - were prepared to keep investing to shore up its long-term position.
VHA will enter the fixed broadband market for the first time in the second half of 2017, and Mr Marsh revealed the company was building its own " to plug directly into the National Broadband Network's 121 points of interconnect, and would buy capacity directly from the government-backed telco.
"We know that many Australians are unhappy with their current internet service provider," he said.
"We plan to change the game by offering a service that is simple to understand and gives customers what they are paying for."

Mr Marsh would not comment on , despite analysts enthusing that it would bolster its hopes as an NBN reseller.
Average revenue per user for the six months to June 30 grew 2 per cent to $45.89 on a gross basis, with Mr Marsh crediting the higher data downloads and the popularity of new products like a $5 international roaming package, revenue for which increased 19.7 per cent year-on-year.
Revenue from the mobile virtual network operator channel (where other telcos use VHA's network to deliver mobile services) was also up 20 per cent over the six months, with Mr Marsh revealing most of that revenue and the uplift came from , in a field which also includes Lebara and TPG.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>VHA's 1800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodafone Hutchison Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TPG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VHA</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodaphone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Marsh</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CK Hutchison Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodafone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Broadband Network's 121</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodafone Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
