<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651406863824572256</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/tasmanian-basketballer-tanner-krebs-keen-to-pull-on-green-and-gold-at-world-university-games/news-story/c0bb3fb9424a2eaf7fd86672a17368aa</url>
  <title>Krebs keen to pull on gold and green</title>
  <content>
IT has been a two-year wait to pull on the green and gold jersey for Tanner Krebs and the Tasmanian talent hopes the World University Games is just the first step onto more national representation.
Krebs, who plays for St Mary's - the American college which produced the likes of NBA stars Patty Mills and Matthew Dellavedova - is part of a 12-strong squad Australian squad which will hit the courts in Taipei from August 19.
The under-19 2015 FIBA World Championships was the last tournament where Krebs featured in Australian colours, but the 21-year-old knows a strong showing at the 29th Summer Universiade, which reflects an Olympic atmosphere with as many as eight games played in a 10-day period, will go a long way towards reaching his Boomers dream.

"Any time you get to put on the green and gold it is a huge honour, having the opportunity to do it again means a lot," Krebs told the Mercury on a quick visit home from the US.
"A lot of current Boomers have gone through this pathway of the World Uni Games. I think it is definitely a huge opportunity for me to put my name out there as a potential Boomer in the future.
"I know head coach Andrej Lemanis really follows the junior level up to these Games - he looks at those to see who is performing well.
"If I'm able to perform it gives me a big chance to put my name in that group of players to play for the Boomers one day."
Krebs will enter his sophomore season at St Mary's eager to build on the momentum he gathered towards the end of his freshman year, which saw him score 12 points off the bench in both of the Gaels matches in the March Madness Tournament.
He has been working out in three sessions a day, three days a week during summer school and is confident the team can better its 2016-17 campaign.
"I would like to improve and have a more consistent year throughout the whole season," he said.
"At the beginning of the year I struggled a little bit trying to adapt to college basketball. But towards the end of the year I really found my feet and was able to contribute.
"We are looking really strong, we have a lot of guys returning, we lost a couple of key pieces but we have a lot of young guys, including myself, who can definitely fill that void."
Krebs heads to Cairns on Friday to see his Dad - former women's Chargers coach Dan - before flying to Taiwan.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World University Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Dellavedova</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taiwan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taipei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gaels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrej Lemanis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Marys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Krebs</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patty Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Summer Universiade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanner Krebs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March Madness Tournament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIBA World Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Uni Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
