<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408148019821168</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/editorial-unis-must-be-made-safer/news-story/037cff52b7484108a30d11a8db5d450e</url>
  <title>Unis must be made safer</title>
  <content>
THE shockwaves have been felt in universities across Australia. A new report, published by the Australian Human Rights Commission, found 51 per cent of students had reported being sexually harassed and 6.9 per cent had been sexually assaulted in the past two years. The report is based on a national survey of more than 30,000 students attending 39 institutions.
In Tasmania, which had a smaller sample size, the rate of sexual harassment was 54 per cent and the sexual assault rate 6.1 per cent. But overall, these figures are damning. They are shocking. And they demand swift and strong responses.
Described as "heartbreaking" by National Union of Students president Sophie Johnston, the report showed significantly more women than men were assaulted and harassed, and a disproportionate amount of LGBTI students affected.
"A significant proportion of students who were sexually assaulted or sexually harassed knew the perpetrator, who was most likely to be a fellow student from their university," the report stated.
"It is clear from the survey that women experience sexual assault and sexual harassment at disproportionately higher rates than men. They were almost twice as likely to be harassed in 2016 and more than three times as likely to be sexually assaulted in 2015 or 2016."

UTAS has announced it will install Professor Margaret Otlowski, the current law Dean, as pro vice-chancellor (culture and wellbeing) as a direct response to the survey results.
Vice-chancellor Peter Rathjen vowed to ensure the university would use the report to build on its commitment "to the creation of a safe and just society." Meanwhile, universities across the country have acknowledged they must do more to protect students from sexual assault and harassment.
Part of Universities Australia's initial response to the report was to announce a 10-point plan to help prevent assault and harassment.
This included developing a respectful relationships education program tailored for university students, providing specialist training to academic and student-residence staff and a 24-hour support line to give students access to specialist counsellors from Rape and Domestic Violence Services Australia.
The universities will then do a follow-up survey to monitor progress - to determine whether real change has been made. But it also needs a response as a society and a community.
Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins said simply: "Sexual assault and sexual harassment are far too prevalent in university settings, as they are in the broader community."
Universities and their communities must confront these issues, tackle them head on and never, ever seek to sweep them under the carpet.
This is a serious social issue which has been laying in plain sight across our universities for years.
Without this landmark report, many of us would be none the wiser.
That cannot be allowed to ever happen again.
As University of Queensland vice-chancellor Professor Peter Joj said: "There is only one acceptable number and that is zero."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Peter Joj</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Union of Students</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice-chancellor Peter Rathjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domestic Violence Services Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UTAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Margaret Otlowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sophie Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
