<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408156609755953</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/flaskback-1990s-pivot-point-coast-development/3204796/</url>
  <title>FLASHBACK 1990s: A pivot point for Coast development</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIA had won the Auckland Commonwealth Games and Bob Hawke was ousted as Prime Minister.   

Princess Diana's death shot Elton John's Candle in the Wind back into the number one spot for six weeks and Queensland was welcoming a rapid population growth.   

The 1990s were a time of change, celebration, tragedy and growth, and for the Sunshine Coast it was boom time.   

To celebrate the Coast's 50th anniversary, we're looking back through the decades and exploring the industries that defined the region over the past 50 years.   

The 90s was all about economic growth, development and catering for a multiplying population and who better to remind us what that looked like than top Coast developer and founder of FKP Property Group Rod Forrester.   

The late 80s saw the worst recession since The Great Depression and it leaked into the start of the next decade. But by about 1992, things took a turn for the better.   

Australians were beckoned to the Sunshine State, particularly South-East Queensland, by its buoyant economy and affordable property market.   

Mr Forrester said the 90s marked the end of a development freeze on the Sunshine Coast and the start of a new era.   

"There was a whole lot of development in the early 80s so we found ourselves with an oversupply and for the rest of that decade we had to try and absorb it," he said. 

"But by the 90s, people were moving to the region and the market started to get going and development started happening again."  

Caloundra was on the up, and Mooloolaba and Noosa were the growth hotspots.   

"More older money went to Caloundra and people hung onto their properties so there was a more steady and stable growth there," he said.

"Mooloolaba was a real growth area and there was development happening around Cotton Tree.  

"Noosa was the number one spot, but opportunities became less and less with most of Noosa getting built out so there were less opportunities to develop there."   

Mr Forrester said while apartment-living was no new beast, its popularity on the Coast began to grow in the 90s.    And in the Sunshine Coast Daily on September 17, 1996, Mr Forrester said exactly that.   

"We now have the single-parent family, not requiring the traditional 40-perch block of land, which has created an opportunity for high density living with less maintenance and more free time with their children," the article reads.   

"We also have the acceptance of investment property by a greater proportion of Australians through tax incentives and investment advisers."  

He predicted the baby-boomer population would join investors and small families as the occupiers of apartments and we'd continue to see rapid growth well into the future. 

Looking back now, from 2017, he wasn't wrong. 

"We used to have about 20% of Australians living in apartments, now it's 50/50 and I think in time that's going to look more like 70/30," he said.   

"It's all about catering for the baby-boomers who are looking to downsize, they want ease-of-living and all the perks that come with it, and be able to live right in the heart of it."  

This Flashback series is brought to you by Yaroomba Beach, a world-class destination for all. 
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elton John's Candle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FKP Property Group Rod Forrester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Forrester</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yaroomba Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South East Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Depression</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
