<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408160904723353</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/talking-point-a-chance-meeting-an-astonishing-legacy/news-story/0a1fecd38f363d133c6252f1c9edf4b6</url>
  <title>A chance meeting, an astonishing legacy</title>
  <content>
GALA and I met along the Channel Highway in Tasmania. She was hitchhiking to her caravan at Eggs and Bacon Bay south of Hobart as I was driving home to nearby Randalls Bay. Some months later she was by the road again and I had the pleasure of offering her another lift home.
In these days of almost universal car ownership, in this wealthiest country on Earth, it is unusual to see hitchers, let alone female hitchers, with a thumb out by the road. An older woman hitching is extraordinary and so, it turned out, was Gala.
In her two trips from the local centre of Cygnet to Eggs and Bacon Bay, Gala occupied the front-passenger seat of my car for a total of just 20 minutes. My recollection of exactly what was said in those 20 minutes is as patchy as the impression she left is complete.
She grabbed my attention from the moment the car door closed. Gala told me she was from Wales and loved the beautiful country of her origin as much as Tasmania, her newfoundland in the Antipodes. She enjoyed sailing and had bought a cheap backblock at Eggs and Bacon Bay, close enough to the beach to hear the waves breaking on the white, sandy beach. At night she lit her small second-hand caravan with candles.
Unlike continental Australia, where feral foxes are everywhere and have eradicated most of the small marsupials, the island of Tasmania is fox-free and most of the marsupials (including bettongs, wallabies and potoroos) remain.
Part of the picture of the strength and practicality of Gala is that she would take fresh roadkill home to cook for a protein-rich meal, much like those the Tasmanian Aborigines have enjoyed over the last 30,000 years.
I told Gala about my environmental foundation, set up after I left the Australian Senate in 2012, and about our energetic determination to save the 500,000 hectares of Tarkine (takayna) wilderness in North-West Tasmania from the onrush of clear-fell logging and mining as well as the desecration that off-road vehicles wreak on Aboriginal heritage sites along its coast.
The Tarkine has Australia's largest temperate rainforest, pristine rivers which are home to the world's largest freshwater crayfish, and endangered species like the Tasmanian devil, wedge-tailed eagle and masked owl. Earth's cleanest air blows across the Tarkine's wild western shore.
Gala and I were of one mind on the need for the comfortable wealthy masses of the world to get out of our armchairs, step off our kerbsides and take action to turn around the accelerating degradation of the biosphere. Cataclysmic human-induced problems, including extinctions, global warming, ocean acidification, social inequity and the diversion of massive resources into armaments instead of alleviating poverty and overpopulation, demand human-induced remedies. There will be no divine intervention.
Our chance get-togethers ended with cheery goodbyes and Gala walking across the lea towards her caravan under the trees. For me, these were uplifting moments from the infinite universe of chance meetings. There was the happy prospect of seeing her again because Gala had invited me and my partner Paul to visit her in Wales. So I was very saddened when I heard last November that Gala had died. I am glad she did not suffer greatly in her final days.
The news that she had bequeathed my foundation $160,000, plus a share of the caravan sale money, has left me amazed and inspired. Gala was a genuine citizen of our Earth.
She saw the need to foster both the planet's natural plenitude and the potential of the human soul to soar. She lived way in advance of the petty (and very often macho) personalities and divisions which hold back human society and its right to a secure common destiny.
She believed in taking peaceful action and her final gift is testimony to her optimism that her ideals would not die with her.
The Bob Brown Foundation will use Gala's bequest to lift our campaign for the Tarkine to greater national and international attention.
We are convinced that if enough Australians, and people beyond, get to know about this wonderful wild area they will join the campaign until it is saved. Our aim is to work with the Palawa (Tasmanian Aboriginal) community to achieve national park and World Heritage status for the Tarkine and to have it returned to that community.
From a chance roadside meeting, Gala has become a hero for those of us 'down-under' charting the road ahead in this unpredictable campaign.
One thing is for sure though: on the day the Tarkine is saved we will be raising a special glass to Gala from Wales.
Environmentalist Dr Bob Brown is a former senator for Tasmania and federal leader of the Australian Greens.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Greens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Aborigines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Brown Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bacon Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North-West Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wales</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarkine</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cygnet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Bob Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randalls Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Heritage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
