<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407847372103317</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/preseason-matches-against-nba-teams-proof-of-the-nbls-resurrection/news-story/16537595ae77de08346de7a1ad14bbaa</url>
  <title>NBA clashes proof of NBL's resurrection</title>
  <content>
IT was not that long ago that the National Basketball League was jokingly referred to by some as the RBL - the Regional Basketball League.
Once the hottest ticket in towns all over the country, the competition was on its knees.
In the 2009-10 season there was no team from either Brisbane or Sydney.
In 2012-13 there was no team between Townsville and Sydney.
At the end of the 2007-2008 season, three teams handed in their licences.
You had to be a complete fanatic or incurable insomniac to find a game on TV. It was sad.
For all the popularity that the game enjoyed in junior club and school competitions, under-age national and international levels, as well as the high world ranking for both the Boomers and Opals, the sport's shop window - the NBL - was hanging on for dear life.
That's what makes yesterday's announcement that three NBL teams will play three NBA teams in the US in October so significant.
In two short years since he took control, NBL owner Larry Kestelman and his team have worked wonders.
The NBL is relevant again. And on a global level. NBA teams wouldn't be wasting a pre-season game out of the goodness of their heart.
Due to the new CBA in the NBA, the number of pre-season games has been reduced.
Superstars like Russell Westbrook and Paul George will line-up for OKC against Melbourne.
Aussie stars Joe Ingles and Dante Exum will suit up for the Jazz against the Sydney Kings and young gun Devin Booker - who hit 70 points in one game last year - will play for the Suns against the Bullets.

Basketball: The NBL is set to announce exhibition games for the Sydney Kings and Brisbane Bullets to be played against the Utah Jazz and Oklahoma City.

NBL set for NBA action
Kestelman gets stuff done.
He got a TV deal with Fox Sports, brought the Bullets back and restored credibility to the NBL to the extent that both the NBA and the rapidly-growing Chinese market have sat up and taken serious notice.
The internet and property mogul was bouncing around Sydney's Circular Quay yesterday like a proud father in a delivery room handing out cigars.
So he should. The NBL is back, baby.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OKC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dante Exum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Basketball League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devin Booker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OKLAHOMA CITY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Basketball League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Westbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kestelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Circular Quay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
