<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408156609755932</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/talking-point-corruption-fight-should-be-carried-out-in-broad-daylight/news-story/d72e7810d179d5eb926319da30f739a9</url>
  <title>Corruption fight must be in broad daylight</title>
  <content>
TASMANIA'S Integrity Commission must become more transparent if it is to fulfil its purpose of exposing and tackling corruption.
Why does corruption happen?
Because deals are made behind closed doors. Money changes hands, mates give favours, decisions are made, and the public is kept in the dark.
When politicians and officials are not held to account in public, undue influence can operate in private.
Tasmania's anti-corruption investigations would be more effective if the doors were flung open to the public and the media.
What can change this? Anti-corruption investigations with public hearings shed light on shady decisions of government and the public sector.
Public hearings allow the community to hold their representatives to account.
They expose corruption and misconduct, and give the public confidence that investigations are carried out fairly and in the public interest.
The very act of bringing corruption into the public view diminishes its power.
Holding anti-corruption investigations solely in private continues the culture of opaque decision making.
Private hearings are important in the beginning of investigations, but as the investigation progresses a commissioner should have the option to open the doors in the public interest.
The Tasmanian Commissioner has this option but has never used it.
The Tasmanian Integrity Commission has not held any public hearings since its inception in 2010.
It has only referred two people for prosecution for corruption or misconduct.
It does not have the power to prosecute misconduct in public office.
It hasn't exposed corruption or misconduct involving members of parliament or ministers.
In contrast, NSW ICAC holds regular public hearings as part of its investigations. Public hearings have been critical in its successful exposure of systemic corruption, including the investigations of Eddie Obeid, Ian Macdonald and other corrupt politicians and ministers.
In these public hearings hundreds of witnesses came forward with valuable information that was vital to progressing investigations.
The NSW ICAC commissioner who oversaw the investigations, David Ipp QC, has said that "the stark fact is that Operations Jasper and Acacia could not have been undertaken without public hearings".
Another former ICAC commissioner, Anthony Whealy QC, has said "One of the advantages of a public hearing, not only does it shine a spotlight on possible corrupt behaviour, it means the public know what's going on.
"And there are many people out there in the public arena who will have information that's very important to the investigation.
"If you conduct the investigation behind closed doors, they never hear of it and the valuable information they have will be lost."
Research from The Australia Institute revealed that public hearings are critical to an anti-corruption commission's success. Comparing the track record of anti-corruption commissions around Australia shows that NSW ICAC held 28 public hearings, made 123 corrupt conduct findings and referred 76 people to the Director of Public Prosecutions.
Its investigations have made findings against 12 MPs and ministers.
The Australia Institute's Shining a Light on Corruption report finds that commissions that do not hold regular public hearings, including the Tasmanian Integrity Commission, had fewer successes.
Without public hearings, the only way that a commission can expose corruption is through its final investigation report.
These reports are often hundreds of pages long and can come out months or even years after an investigation finishes.
Sadly, media outlets these days have fewer journalists, with more deadlines, and rarely have the resources to trawl through these reports full of legalese.
The majority of Tasmanians are likely unaware of many cases that the Tasmanian Integrity Commission has investigated.
Even if charges are laid, the lack of media and public knowledge diminishes the deterrence effect of anti-corruption commissions.
So if experts agree that public hearings are required to expose corruption in the highest level of power, why are some politicians against them?
Currently there is a Senate committee inquiry underway into setting up a federal integrity commission.
It will report shortly before the Australia Institute's Accountability and the Law conference, which will discuss the weaknesses in the current accountability system and suggest mechanisms for reform.
It's time to get serious on tackling federal corruption and set up a federal commission with public hearings, a wide jurisdiction and the investigative powers of a Royal Commission.
Tasmania could improve its Integrity Commission by doing the same. The 2016 review of the commission was a missed opportunity to strengthen Tasmania's watchdog, and worse still, limited its jurisdiction and investigative powers.
Murray Kellam, the integrity commissioner in 2015, said public servants that would be prosecuted in other states will get away with misconduct in Tasmania.
Corruption happens in backroom deals behind closed doors. Anti-corruption investigations in Tasmania must open these doors and let the public in.
Hannah Aulby is the Accountability and the Law Conference director at the Australia Institute. The Accountability and the Law 2017 conference will be held on August 17 at Parliament House. www.accountabilityconference.org.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acacia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law (2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Corruption</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Institute's Accountability</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operations Jasper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TASMANIA'S Integrity Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Integrity Commission</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian MacDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah Aulby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Ipp QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Integrity Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Law Conference</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW ICAC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Institute</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Institute's Shining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Obeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Whealy QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Kellam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parliament House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
