<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408156609755999</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/liberal-mps-gear-up-for-ugly-internal-brawl-over-samesex-marriage/news-story/438726293278f4b72e49f31ba1f292d4</url>
  <title>Lib MPs threatened as gay marriage erupts</title>
  <content>
CONSERVATIVE Liberal MPs have warned moderates they could inflict irreparable damage on the Government by crossing the floor to vote for same-sex marriage when federal Parliament resumes.
Pro and anti-same sex marriage government MPs privately traded insults on Tuesday ahead of a potentially ugly battle over the issue next week.
Supporters of same-sex marriage - including Queensland MP Trevor Evans and Victorian Tim Wilson - are being threatened with preselection challenges if they defy the party and vote with Labor to change the Marriage Act.
A majority of Liberal MPs continue to support the Government's policy of holding a plebiscite on same-sex marriage but under party rules, backbench MPs have the right to cross the floor. Senior conservatives said moderates should drop their threats to vote with the opposition.
"I think it could get pretty ugly next week if the Left keeps pushing this the way they are at the moment,'' one leading conservative MP said.
Former minister Eric Abetz said it would be "an exceptionally grave matter" if the Government lost a vote on gay marriage on the floor of the House of Representatives.
Liberal MPs Waren Entsch and Trent Zimmerman Senator Dean Smith are also pushing for a conscience vote on marriage equality.

Gay Liberal MPs could face a preselection threat if they cross the floor on same-sex marriage.

MPs may face preselection threat on marriage
Despite endorsing the right of backbenchers to cross the floor, Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull said the Government was committed to letting voters settle the same-sex marriage issue at a plebiscite.
"Our government's policy position on this issue is very, very clear and it has not changed,'' Mr Turnbull said.
"The only reason that plebiscite or vote has not been held, the only reason every Australian has not been given the opportunity to vote on this is because of Bill Shorten's opposition."

Immigration Minister Peter Dutton publicly ruled out challenging Mr Turnbull for the Liberal leadership if the Prime Minister fails to prevent pro-gay marriage MPs from crossing the floor.
"I'm a Cabinet Minister in Malcolm Turnbull's Government and I've accepted that commission,'' Mr Dutton told FIVEaa.
"I said to Malcolm at the time that I would be completely loyal to him - I have been and I remain so."
The Government doesn't have the numbers in the Senate it needs to get parliamentary approval for a plebiscite.
Some Coalition MPs are backing a previous suggestion by Mr Dutton that the Government organise a national postal vote on same-sex marriage. The postal vote could go ahead without a vote in the Parliament. Victorian Senator Bridget McKenzie said the idea was worthy of consideration.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland MP Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lib MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull's Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs Waren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CONSERVATIVE Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dutton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIVEaa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immigration Minister Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabinet Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Senator Bridget McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
