<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408190969495313</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/gasvalpo-back-in-front-of-australian-tyrekickers-bell-potter-swoops-20170731-gxmot4</url>
  <title>GasValpo back in front of Australian tyrekickers; Bell Potter swoops</title>
  <content>
Could it be the third Australian owner in ten years for Chile's oldest gas distribution business GasValpo?
Street Talk can reveal GasValpo's owner - Challenger Ltd-backed infrastructure fund manager Whitehelm Capital - and adviser Bank of America Merrill Lynch have kicked off a search for interested buyers, sending a teaser document to tyrekickers ahead of an auction.
It's understood the sellers have targeted Australian infrastructure fund managers with an appetite for investing offshore such as IFM Investors and QIC Ltd and even the utility players as part of the process, as well as big investors offshore.
The up-for-sale business was pitched as Chile's oldest gas distributor, serving about 100,000 clients in the country's second largest city, Valparaiso.

It is the country's third largest distribution company by gas volume and second largest in terms of revenue and network length.

GasValpo is expected to be worth about $200 million.
Whitehelm bought GasValpo in 2008, taking the business off Australian utility AGL Energy as part of a clean-out by then new chief executive officer Michael Fraser. The manager has since retained a 92 per cent stake on behalf of its clients.
It seems likely to go to an offshore buyer although given the history, you can't blame the sellers for testing local appetite.
Meanwhile, Bell Potter has swooped on three members of Canaccord's corporate finance team,

Bell's staff were told of the hires on Tuesday. They have picked up Canaccord's executive director investment banking Matt Storey and ECM execution and advisory staff Leon Dowman and William Hughes.
The trio - which represent about half of Canaccord's local corporate finance team - will start at Bell after a period of gardening leave.
A memo to Bell staff, obtained by Street Talk, said: "It's exciting for the Bell Potter business and no doubt will add significantly to our overall origination and broader corporate capability.
"It is also in keeping with Colin Bell and Alastair Provan's philosophy that Bell Potter is a growth business and we are always open to the idea of adding quality people throughout the organisation when the opportunity presents."

Storey joined Canaccord five years ago after a stint at Patersons Securities and has worked on deals including capital raisings for BigAir Group, now owned by Superloop, and NetComm Wireless.
Dowman joined Canaccord two years ago from CIMB where he was an associate across investment banking and equities, while Hughes started at the firm at a similar time after a stint as an accountant at KPMG.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valparaiso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canaccord</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehelm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IFM Investors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QIC Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Storey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Challenger Ltd-backed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GasValpo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehelm Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chile</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Dowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patersons Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BigAir Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPMG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superloop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>storEy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alastair Provan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NetComm Wireless</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrill Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell Potter</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dowman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CIMB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
