<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408319818517136</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/small-business/trends/the-big-idea/why-arent-more-businesswomen-in-politics-20170801-gxmqzh.html</url>
  <title>Why aren't more businesswomen in politics?</title>
  <content>
In my opinion, this garbage about people holding dual citizenship being ineligible for election to Parliament demonstrates exactly why so few women in this country want to be involved in politics.
That such a side issue should dominate public debate is appalling. I wish we paid more attention to what we could do to improve Australia, rather than focus so much on such a small matter.Photo: Jacky Ghossein
No wonder women in business don't want to get involved. What a waste of time.
It might be a stereotype, but I think males in business see an association with a local political party as part of doing business, and building their networks and influence. And I assume that few women feel the same.Photo: Supplied
Which is such a shame, as women in small business have a lot to add to the political debate as well as a responsibility to make a contribution.
Jennifer Morris is the founder of advocacy group  (WFEA), which is dedicated to increasing the number of women in Parliament and supporting them once they're there. It is organising a  for women wanting to make a difference by taking part in public life.

Morris says there is no simple answer for why more women are not involved in politics.
"It has nothing to do with the number of highly experienced and credentialled women who could do the job, and absolutely nothing to do with merit," she says.
At the federal level, after the 2016 general election, 29 per cent of the House of Representatives was female, as was 39 per cent of the Senate.
The major political parties vary in their representation of women. The Greens are about gender equal; about 40 per cent of the ALP's members are women; in the the Liberal Party, they account for about 30 per cent.
"Women won the right to vote and to be elected to Parliament in 1902, but it took more than 40 years for the first woman to take her seat," says Morris.
"Thereafter, women have been determined to make progress but the pace of change is glacial. We did not have our first female governor-general until 2009 and first female prime minister until 2010."  
Women in small business have a lot to add to the political debate and a responsibility to make a contribution.

Several states and territories have had women premiers or first ministers, and it's a select, highly impressive group that includes Gladys Berejiklian, Anna Bligh, Lara Giddings, Kristina Keneally, Joan Kirner and Annastacia Palaszczuk.
"The lack of women in politics has an impact on decision making and diversity of opinion," Morris says.  
WFEA researched why women do - and don't - enter politics for its report, .
"The results were both obvious and depressing," she says.  
Cash and career were among the main reasons. It's expensive to run a campaign and at the same time potentially lose employment certainty and seniority.
Childcare, the requirement to travel and long hours were other factors keeping women out of politics. Women also said they didn't jell culturally with the political sphere, and were turned off by what they saw as a bullying and at times aggressive environment.
Intense competition for key positions and subsequent undermining of trust and a perceived boys' club approach are other reasons. Distaste for the double standards inherent in political life also keep women out of the game.
City of Sydney independent councillor and , knows how hard it is to juggle business and politics.
"I live in a world that has absolutely no balance. Five years ago when I was first elected, I didn't think it would be that much different. I just thought I was taking on another project and it would fit in with my life. I was very wrong," says Vithoulkas.
"Business is very black and white for me; it's safe and comfortable. Politics is grey, dirty and full of Machiavellian scenarios. So I'm not surprised more businesswomen don't take up the political mantel."
In fact, Vithoulkas says she's not sure she would have taken this path had she known how tough it would be.
"But I feel compelled to stay because, despite some disappointing aspects, there are so many people in our community who need someone to fight for them, and who cares more for them than votes," she adds. 
Vithoulkas is the exception that proves the rule. I think for most women in small business, being involved in politics is simply unrealistic given the demands on their time from other spheres.
As a group, we have an opportunity to participate more in the political sphere. There are ways of becoming involved that don't require the commitment required to sit in Parliament.
For instance, becoming part of the local chamber of commerce or joining groups like WFEA are ways to have a say about political issues that affect business without too much of a time commitment.
I think it's important to get involved. Otherwise, we can't complain when political decisions affect the way we run our businesses.  
What do you think? Why are more women business owners not involved in politics?
Follow MySmallBusiness on ,  and . 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joan Kirner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Bligh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WFEA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Machiavellian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristina Keneally</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MySmallBusiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara Giddings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacky Ghossein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vithoulkas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morris</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
