<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408165199690845</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/heidelberg-west-cake-manufacturer-sweet-by-nature-wins-gold-at-australian-food-awards/news-story/bcf2a0ae9be54f5cd956b53496eb66a1</url>
  <title>Sweet taste of success</title>
  <content>
A HEIDELBERG West cake manufacturer is enjoying the sweet taste of success.
Sweet by Nature, in Bamfield Rd, claimed two gold medals at the Australian Food Awards for its rum and raisin brownies and its delicious coffee walnut cake.
It also collected silver for its fruit and nut biscuit, and lime and coconut cheesecake plus three bronze medals for its lemon drizzle cake, let-it-snow cheesecake and apple hokey pokey crumble.
The gourmet bakery has operated for more than 27 years, supplying Victoria, NSW, Queensland, South Australia and Tasmania.
And it all began in founder Megan Misso's suburban kitchen.
"I became obsessed cooking with choc chip cookies and a friend suggested I should try and get them into David Jones," Ms Misso said.
The department store took the entire line and continues to sell them today.
The Vermont South woman's business has doubled in the past six years and projections show there is no slowing down.
"We have 120 dedicated employees who've helped our business thrive - these awards reinforce it and I couldn't be more proud," she said.
For more details, click .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bamfield Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Misso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HEIDELBERG West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vermont South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Food Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Misso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
