<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408169494658209</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/doggie-tales-a-hit-with-pupils-and-pooches-at-yarra-plenty-libraries/news-story/3126f06a4afbb3795738330d39301e0a</url>
  <title>Kids and dogs team up to chase tales</title>
  <content>
A PROGRAM that encourages primary school students to improve their literacy skills by reading to a dog has been expanded across eight of the Yarra Plenty Regional Library branches.
Doggie Tales provides an easygoing, non-judgemental canine audience for readers at Lalor, Mill Park, Thomastown and Whittlesea libraries by pairing students up with a
Library spokeswoman, Marieclaire Baird, said the program began three years ago with a single dog at Diamond Valley library in Greensborough and has grown to eight dog listeners.
Since it began, more than 1200 children have read to the program dogs in the various library branches.
"Doggie Tales develops children's verbal communication skills and offers a joyful experience," Ms Baird said.
"It's an innovative way for children to practise their reading with a non-judgmental and safe canine audience," Ms Baird said.
"Potential dogs are assessed by a qualified dog trainer for suitability and a volunteer co-ordinator trains the handler. We're always on the lookout for new recruits."
If you're interested in being a fill-in or regular doggie volunteer, email ypmail@yprl.vic.gov.au.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marieclaire Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Plenty Regional Library</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomastown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mill Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Baird</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lalor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREENSBOROUGH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
