<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408375653093080</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/indonesia-not-closing-door-to-australian-agricultural-exports-despite-selfsufficiency-drive-20170801-gxn5fm.html</url>
  <title>Indonesia "not closing door" to Australian agricultural exports despite self-sufficiency drive</title>
  <content>
Jakarta: A senior trade official insists Indonesia is not "closing the doors" to Australian agricultural products despite its drive towards food self-sufficiency as the two countries enter the eighth round of free trade negotiations in Canberra this week.
In an exclusive interview with Fairfax Media, Indonesia's Director-General for International Trade, Iman Pambagyo, compared Indonesia's desire to be self-sufficient in some areas with President Donald Trump's "Buy American" policy.

Up Next

Smelly water oozes into Niagara Falls

01:16

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Cattle farming in Indonesia

A partnership between Indonesian and Australian research institutes hoping to increase cattle productivity, through improved cow nutrition, is beginning to show results in eastern Indonesia.

"It's just prioritising your own products, it doesn't necessarily mean we close our doors," Mr Iman said.
The comments come as Indonesia announced on Friday it would import 75,000 tons of salt from Australia in August, although the trade ministry stressed it hoped its domestic supply would gradually return to normal.

Analysts have expressed scepticism the Comprehensive Economic Partnership Agreement (CEPA) - which both countries have pledged to finalise by the end of the year - will address long standing barriers to market access for Australian products into Indonesia.
Indonesia has self sufficiency goals for a number of key commodities including beef, sugar, rice and soybeans.

"Indonesia uses import restrictions, including bans and quotas, to support local producers while negatively impacting Australia's exporters," the Australian Department of Agriculture and Water Resources said in a submission to a parliamentary inquiry on the trade relationship. Unexpected changes to import conditions also led to a lack of certainty for Australian exporters.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

However, the submission acknowledged that more recently Indonesia's pursuit of self-sufficiency goals had been balanced by sensitivity about high retail food prices and better recognition of the role imports played in maintaining price stability.Photo: Tatan Syuflana
Mr Iman told Fairfax Media that Indonesia would like to see Australia help promote its palm oil industry. "Perhaps palm oil based biofuel could be used in Australia more and more. This is one simple example," he said.
Indonesia is chafing over the European Parliament's call for the EU to phase out by 2020 the use of vegetable oils in biodiesels - including palm oil - that are produced in an unsustainable way leading to deforestation.
"I don't think palm oil is the most destructive vegetable oil in that context - even their own parliament I think in 2006 or 2007 or 2005 came out with a report that soybeans are the most destructive vegetable oil in terms of deforestation."
Mr Iman said Indonesia was doing a lot of things around sustainable palm oil and hoped to work with Australia to improve the sector.
"So in the spirit of partnership perhaps we could include these issues into the CEPA agreement and for the two countries to work together ... even a joint venture to enter a third market."
Mr Iman said the Australian government's decision in April toon A4 paper from Indonesia "creates issues for Indonesia" but "personally speaking" should not hold up the free trade deal.
"We have conveyed our concerns, well this is not a great development against the backdrop that we're rushing to conclude this CEPA negotiation, but on the other hand we understand that every World Trade Organisation member has the right to take trade remedy measures."
However, Mr Iman said palm oil, pulp and paper were key sectors for Indonesia. "More than 12 million people depend their livelihood on these three sectors. So we have to seek some cooperation with Australia."
Mr Iman said economic cooperation and capacity building along with economic liberalisation were key pillars of the CEPA negotiations.
Australia had provided a lot of capacity building in the cattle sector - such as the cattle breeding program in East Kalimantan - but he would like to see initiatives converged into one big program so "we could see the tangible progress in this cooperation".
Mr Iman said ministers had met several times to check the progress of negotiations.
He believed "at least the meat of the agreement should be concluded by the end of the year", but acknowledged it was an ambitious timetable.
 Two more negotiating rounds are scheduled in September and December, but working groups could meet in between sessions to accelerate the process.
CEPA negotiations have been underway since 2010 but stalled in 2013 amid diplomatic tensions and a climate of economic protectionism.
They re-started in early 2016 but some analysts have questioned whether a meaningful agreement can be reached.
"I would say that in the face of Australian demands for agricultural export and mining investment, notions of self-sufficiency and economic sovereignty would prevail," said Rocky Intan, of the Jakarta-based Centre for Strategic and International Studies.
"The administration would be loath to make new enemies among the powerful agricultural and mineral interests."
Former Australia Indonesia Business Council president Debnath Guharoy said that in comparison to Indonesia Australia had very few tariffs.
"We have very little to give as a country to Indonesia because we are an open economy relatively speaking. In that sense, Indonesia will be asked for much more than we will be giving to them if you compare tariffs," he said.
"The emphasis from the Indonesia Australia Business Partnership Group has always been to look for a partnership agreement which will go beyond tariff line comparisons."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Niagara Falls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iman Pambagyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Department of Agriculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia Australia Business Partnership Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Indonesia Business Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatan Syuflana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Kalimantan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia's Director-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Iman</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rocky Intan, of the Jakarta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Trade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jakarta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comprehensive Economic Partnership Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEPA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Trade Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Studies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debnath Guharoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
