<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408238214136717</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/sprint-stock-price-popping-earnings-beat-profit-2017-7</url>
  <title>Sprint is popping after its first positive earnings report in three years</title>
  <content>
Shares of  opened almost 7% higher on Tuesday after the telecom company reported a quarterly profit for the first time in three years.

The fourth-largest carrier in the US, controlled by Japan's SoftBank, reported a net income of $US206 million, or 5 cents per share, for the first quarter of this fiscal year. Analysts had expected a loss of 1 cent per share.

The profit is largely a result of thousands of job cuts last year, which trimmed $US4 billion from the Kansas-based company's operating costs.

Aggressive new promotions to court new subscribers led to 61,000 new connections during the quarter, Sprint said, including 88,000 new post-paid subscribers - it's most lucrative segment.

"Sprint reached an important milestone this quarter by returning to profitability for the first time in three years," CEO Marcelo Claure said . "This represents the progress of a turnaround journey that has delivered improvements in postpaid phone and prepaid customer growth, a return to top-line growth, and a significantly transformed cost structure."

Sprint's stock price is up 36% over the last 12 months.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kansas-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Marcelo Claure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's SoftBank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$206</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
