<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408173789625681</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/chipmunks-cafe-cranbourne-caught-up-in-false-facebook-storm/news-story/8f340bd81b4b32e5706f40c4b7bcb324</url>
  <title>Cafe stung by 'drugged toddler' claim</title>
  <content>
A FAMILY-FRIENDLY cafe in Cranbourne has said it is "saddened and disgusted" at social media accusations that a toddler's safety was endangered at its premises.
Chipmunks Cranbourne put up a post on Facebook last week denying a claim by an anonymous poster that a two-year-old child was drugged and almost abducted from its centre, saying the claims were "100 per cent false".

Victoria Police said there had not been any reports of an incident where a child was endangered at the centre.
Owner Mark Ollier said the store had faced vexatious claims being made against it before, sometimes by business rivals, but he said the fact that the latest claim involved a child made it particularly volatile.
He said the business had to shut down its Facebook ratings in response to a bombardment of low star ratings from the poster's friends.
He said such posts could seriously affect businesses if people didn't question what they read online.
He said the claims were hurtful as he had worked with children for decades.
"We spoke to the police about it and they said (if a child was drugged and potentially abducted) it would have made the news," he said.
"I am here seven days per week and 100 per cent it didn't happen - there was no lockdown and no lost baby.
"The rumours going around are phenomenal.
"At the supermarket this morning the girls were saying, 'geez, what happened?'
"To say a two-year-old was drugged, that is way, way crossing the line."
Mr Ollier said each child and carer were given matching security bands which were checked when children left. Adults were not allowed in through locked gates without being questioned.
Mr Ollier said the owners knew who had made the post and were considering their legal options.
Justin Quill, litigation and dispute resolution principal, Macpherson Kelley said: "People need to realise that when they post something on Facebook or Twitter in the eyes of the law that is a publication just like the front page of Cranbourne Leader or tonight's 6pm Nine News bulletin."
"They are liable for defamation or malicious falsehood just like they were a major media organisation," he said.

Do children's digital fluency allow them to distinguish between fake news and real news online? WSJ's Sue Shellenbarger has surprising results of a study of nearly 8,000 students (from grammar school through college) that tested their ability to tell news from ads and to discern websites from hate groups and mainstream professional organizations. Photo: Getty

STUDY: MOST STUDENTS CANNOT DISTINGUISH FAKE AND REAL NEWS
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WSJ's Sue Shellenbarger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macpherson Kelley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Quill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Friendly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Ollier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ollier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STUDENTS CANNOT DISTINGUISH FAKE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
