<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407950451320931</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:23</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/home-ownership-in-queensland-on-the-slide-as-survey-finds-17-fall-since-2002/news-story/8de30e891c4f9cb9fed1bedfdb9ce57b</url>
  <title>Home ownership in Queensland on the slide as survey finds 17% fall since 2002 - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
HILDA report author Prof Roger Wilkins says: "We've seen a precipitous decline in the rate of home ownership for adults aged under 40." Picture: Paul Burston

THE great Australian dream is becoming a nightmare with an astonishing collapse in the number of young Queenslanders who have bought their own home.
Ownership rates for adults under 40 in cities and towns outside of Brisbane plummeted from about 38 per cent in 2002 to just 21.1 per cent in 2014, while mortgage debt practically doubled, the Household, Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia (HILDA) study found.
The only place in the country with lower ownership rates was Sydney.
"We've seen a precipitous decline in the rate of home ownership for adults aged under 40," report author Professor Roger Wilkins said.
The ownership rate in greater Brisbane, including Logan, Beaudesert, Ipswich and Moreton Bay, was just 29.8 per cent.
Average mortgage debt had jumped from $169,201 to $336,586 nationally.
"In real terms, home debt of adults aged under 40 who own their home has nearly doubled, certainly well outpacing wages growth over that period."
Debt-laden homeowners received some relief yesterday when the Reserve Bank left cash rates parked at 1.5 per cent, marking 12 straight months of no change.
The latest HILDA focused on family relationships, household finances, employment, retirement, attitudes and gambling.
Other significant findings showed almost 40 per cent of adults gambled at least once a month, with about 2 per cent of those identifying as problem gamblers; up to a quarter of children in single-parent families lacked basic essentials; childcare costs had skyrocketed by 74 per cent in real terms over the lifetime of the study; and incomes had flatlined.
HILDA is the longest running survey of Australia's population and has followed the same people from right across the country since 2001 to assess how their lives are changing.
The survey has tracked more than 17,000 people in 9500 households and will continue to grow as families expand.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Burston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaudesert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
