<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407628328766389</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/are-your-children-fussy-eaters-heres-how-to-help-them-eat-their-food/news-story/9d8e58ba74946f074029e962d6149cb0</url>
  <title>How to get fussy kids to eat their food</title>
  <content>
FUSSY eaters: it's the stuff of parental nightmares.
And with experts predicting there are more than 90,000 fussy eating children in South Australia, the nightmare is an all-too-common reality for frustrated parents.
Torrensville mother, Amy Brett, was one of those: mealtimes with her daughters Jemima, 7, and Maisie, 5, had become a stressful battleground.
"The girls didn't like the smell and texture of lots of different foods and would only eat things like sausage rolls or chicken nuggets and other bland food ... it was very stressful," she said.
So Ms Brett called on the professionals, enrolling her children in a specialist program for picky eaters offered through sensory support service, Can: Do 4 Kids.
Can: Do 4 Kids occupational therapist, Molly Moloney, said managing a fussy eater could be an all-consuming problem.
"Mealtimes should be an enjoyable experience, but when you have a child that is experiencing difficulty eating this can become incredibly stressful," she said.
"Eating is a learned behaviour just like walking and talking.
"It is important to model mealtime behaviours positively in front of children to help them develop skills for eating and a healthy relationship with food.
"Of course this isn't always as straight forward or easy as it sounds."
The organisation's Mealtime and Feeding Service uses speech pathologists and occupational therapists to give fussy eaters gentle encouragement to develop skills for eating including chewing and biting and how to discover different foods through taste, smell, touch, sound and texture.
Therapists also determine the variety and intake of food groups that a picky eater is currently eating and compare that with dietary guidelines.
"The therapists will engage with dietetics support regarding the child's nutrition and growth," Ms Moloney said.
"During feeding sessions, the therapists will encourage children to interact with foods from all food groups, including fruits, vegetables, proteins, grains and dairy."
Ms Brett said therapists helped desensitise her girls to new foods by giving them time to touch them, smell them and even peel vegetables.
Jemima and Maisie - who both have Albinism and associated vision impairment, which could contribute to their fussy eating - underwent a 12-week, one-on-one, in-home program with two occupational therapists followed by group sessions on-site.
"Now, the children are not so afraid to try new things," Ms Brett said.
"They are willing to try a bigger variety of fruit and they are now eating roast chicken and spaghetti bolognaise.
"They'll still have chicken nuggets, but will eat sweet corn and peas with them."
Foods that they don't want to eat at meal times now go on a "learning plate" where the sisters can look at it, smell it and touch it rather than being forced to eat it.
The feeding service is available to all South Australian children aged 0-18.
Contact on 8100 8200 for more information.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maisie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrensville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moloney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maisie, 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jemima</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feeding Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Brett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Brett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molly Moloney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
