<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408117955049117</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/sofia-vergara-underwear-startup-eby-2017-8</url>
  <title>'Modern Family' actress Sofia Vergara is launching an underwear startup</title>
  <content>
Sofia Vergara may be famous for her role in "Modern Family," but she also wants to be known as a businesswoman.

Vergara is the highest-paid actress on TV, pulling in $US41.5 million over the past year alone, according to .

But Vergara has learned not to rely only on her acting - she has been endorsing brands like Pepsi and Head & Shoulders since she started out as an actress, and she has her own perfume that's sold in Kohl's and on Amazon.

She's become a successful businesswoman in her own right, and in her latest venture, she's helping other women to do the same.

Vergara is partnering with  to relaunch a women's underwear brand called EBY (formerly "Empowered by You"). Black, who is also the founder of
, a non-profit that provides women with micro-financing to enable them to grow their own businesses, originally created the company in 2012 with the goal of spreading the message of women's empowerment.

10% of EBY's sales will go to the Seven Bar Foundation.

"It's about driving profits with purpose," Vergara told Business Insider.

The new underwear collection has been reimagined with Vergara's input. Underwear is sold directly to consumers via an online subscription, rather than wholesale to stores.

Customers can decide whether they want to receive shipments monthly, every other month, or quarterly.

"It's a little gift you give yourself every month," Vergara said.

The new collection comes in six different styles, in various colours and patterns, and from sizes XS to 4XL. Each pair will cost between $US20 and $US27. There will also be bundle pricing and discounts for customers who buy more frequently.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kohl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US41.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pepsi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Bar Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sofia Vergara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBY</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vergara</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
