<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408242509104057</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/ps4-playstation-4-sales-june-2017-8</url>
  <title>Sony's PlayStation 4 continues to dominate as the world's most popular game console</title>
  <content>
Sony's PlayStation 4  Microsoft's Xbox One and Nintendo's Switch. As of June 30, the PlayStation 4 reached 63.3 million consoles sold. That puts Sony in the lead by a mile.

More specifically, Sony's PlayStation 4 sales are more than double that of the closest competition - the "closest competition," of course, being Microsoft's Xbox One. Though Microsoft no longer reports sales numbers for its Xbox One console, the best estimates put the Xbox One somewhere in the realm of 30 million units sold.

In just Sony's last financial quarter, from April 1 to June 30, the company sold 3.3 million PlayStation 4 consoles. Doesn't sound like a lot? Nintendo's Switch, by comparison, has sold a total of 4.7 million units in its lifespan - from March 1 to June 30. Nintendo estimates it will sell around 10 million Switch consoles in its first year, while Sony's expecting to move a whopping 18 million PlayStation 4 consoles in the same amount of time.

The continued success of the PlayStation 4 is due to several different factors:

The PlayStation 4 was the less expensive console when it launched in 2013, coming in at $US100 less than Microsoft's Xbox One.

The PlayStation 4 is an attractive box that easily fits into your home, and using it as more than a game console is a snap.

A lineup of killer blockbuster games, from "Uncharted 4: A Thief's End" to "Horizon Zero Dawn" to "Bloodborne," made the PlayStation 4 a must-have console. All three of those games are only playable on PS4.

Success begets success - the PlayStation 4 has overtaken the zeitgeist as "the" game console to own if you're going to buy a game console.

Though Sony's exclusive game lineup isn't full of bangers in the back half of 2017, an impressive array of major exclusives are currently in the works. And if you're looking for a way to enjoy more 4K content on your new 4K TV, the PlayStation 4 Pro offers an upgrade path to even prettier games. All of which is to say one thing: Sony's PlayStation 4 isn't showing any signs of slowing down.

Get the latest Microsoft stock price

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thief's End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PlayStation 4</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PlayStation 4 Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PS4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horizon Zero Dawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo Switch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uncharted 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloodborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony PlayStation 4</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xbox One</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft's Xbox One</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
