<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408156609756001</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/real-estate/tasmania/tasmanias-housing-market-heads-for-record-heights-and-could-reach-4-billion-by-years-end/news-story/f51437e5fd67eb4e049f418c814747b4</url>
  <title>Tasmania's housing market heads for record heights and could reach $4 billion by year's end - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Homeowner Michelle Cogan outside her new home in Glenorchy. Picture: MATT THOMPSON

THE hot Tasmanian real estate market is on track to reach $4 billion worth of home sales this year, eclipsing last year's record of $3.1 billion.
In the first half of this year 5782 sales were recorded, setting Tasmania on a path toward 11,000 housing transactions, a result not achieved in more than a decade.
The Real Estate Institute of Tasmania's June quarter report shows that strong results have spread outside of Hobart.
There were 2896 sales in the three months to June, with a gross value of $989,629,768, up 10 sales on the previous quarter.
Median prices increased across all regions with Hobart at $430,000 (up 4.9 per cent for the quarter), Launceston $292,000 (up 4.3 per cent), and the North-West $249,000 (up 4.2 per cent).
In the six months to June 30, first home buyers bought 426 houses, 73 units/townhouses and 120 blocks of land.
That was up 1.1 per cent on last year but below 2014 levels.

REIT president Tony Collidge.

REIT said 1272 interstate buyers acquired property in Tasmania this year and almost half (46.3 per cent) were investors buying at a median price of $262,600 while the rest purchased property to live in at a median price of $310,000.
REIT president Tony Collidge said a shortage of rental properties had seen upward pressure placed on rents and a growing interest in investment.
Mr Collidge said the West Tamar, Meander Valley, Northern Midlands, Circular Head, Derwent Valley, Central Highlands and Southern Midlands all had increased sales.
He said the transformation in Tasmania's market had occurred as a result of a shortage of properties for sale and rent coupled with an increase in population and positive economic conditions.
Mick and Michelle Cogan moved from South Australia last month after snapping up a property in the busy Glenorchy market.
After missing out on properties despite months of looking, Mr Cogan showed his wife the listing online and they put in an offer.
"We wanted flat ground, three bedrooms minimum, with wardrobes and a dishwasher," Mrs Cogan said.
"If we decide in the future that it is too small, we feel good about its potential as a rental property."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Cogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Midlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIT</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate Institute of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Collidge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North-West $249,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derwent Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Tamar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Circular Head</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Midlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston $292,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Highlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Collidge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Cogan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenorchy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
