<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407675573407925</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/football/a-league/teams/melbourne-city/stefan-mauk-scores-on-return-for-melbourne-city-in-20-ffa-cup-win-over-penninsula-power/news-story/5052df82066c616a801bffe92aae8771</url>
  <title>Mauk stars as City down Power</title>
  <content>
STEFAN Mauk has made a telling return to Melbourne City as the FFA Cup holders progressed to the round-of-16 with a 2-0 win over Brisbane Premier League club Peninsula Power.
Midfielder Mauk, who has rejoined City on loan from Dutch club NEC Nijmegen, scored the game's opening goal in first-half stoppage time at Dolphin Oval.
City skipper Bruno Fornaroli sealed his side's win in second-half stoppage time before tempers flared seconds later in a fiery end to the contest.
However, calm was soon restored by referee Lara Lee, with City ending the Power's dream of a Cup upset in front of 4017 fans.
City coach Warren Joyce praised the Power for making life hard for his side.
"It was a tough game," Joyce said.
"I thought the opposition were good, well-organised and had two or three people who were giving us a threat as well.
"We're just pleased we're in the next round because they made a really good account of themselves tonight."
Power coach Aaron Philip lamented his side's failure to make the most of their few opportunities.
"We probably had to take them half chances today," Philip said.
"You're not to get too many chances against an A-League team, so your half chances probably need to go in.
"All the boys put in. Obviously they were going to create chances but I thought we were good in dealing with most of it. I think it was a pretty good performance."
The plucky Power fought hard throughout the contest, and should have gone ahead in the 16th minute when striker Charles Mendy got the better of a dozing City defence.
But with only goalkeeper Dean Bouzanis to beat, Mendy couldn't hit the target, with his shot hitting the side netting.
City created very little in opening 30 minute despite having the lion's share of possession.
Their first genuine chance of the contest came in the 36th minute when midfielder Neil Kilkenny unleashed with a powerful strike that skimmed the top of the crossbar.
But soon after Kilkenny turned supplier as City took the lead on the stroke of halftime.
Kilkenny produced a sublime chip, with the brave Mauk getting his head to the ball ahead of advancing Power keeper Jake Reesby.
Mauk copped the brunt of the collision with Reesby, and didn't return for the second half, with former Brisbane Roar midfielder Luke Brattan replacing him.
Fornaroli should have doubled his side's lead five minutes into the second half but couldn't get the better of Reesby from close range.
The Power's Dean Briggs came close to equalising in the 78th minute, hitting the crossbar with a strike from distance.
With Power pushing forward, City capitalised, with Fornaroli's late goal settling the contest.
For City, Bouzanis started ahead of the recently signed former Adelaide United goalkeeper Eugene Galekovic.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Roar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kilkenny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Bouzanis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Philip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mauk</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Brattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Mendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Power's Dean Briggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eugene Galekovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dolphin Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bouzanis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fornaroli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reesby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Kilkenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruno Fornaroli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEC Nijmegen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STEFAN Mauk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Reesby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
