<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408152314788546</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/blanchfield-jazzed-up-for-nba-clash/news-story/364df3a54913cb92ca78da6efd33a099</url>
  <title>Blanchfield Jazzed up for NBA clash</title>
  <content>
IT'S never too late. Just look at Joe Ingles.
That's the attitude Todd Blanchfield is taking as he looks to enhance his childhood dream of cracking the NBA when Sydney Kings play Ingles' Utah Jazz in a pre-season clash in Salt Lake City on October 3.
The NBL has struck an agreement for the Kings, Melbourne United and the Brisbane Bullets to take on NBA teams in pre-season clashes in the US in October.
Former Townsville Crocodile Blanchfield left Melbourne United to join the Kings on a two year deal and said the one-off game is "an unbelievable opportunity".
Ingles had a successful career in Europe before joining the Jazz in 2014 as a 27-year-old.
Fellow Australian Dante Exum is also on the Jazz roster and Blanchfield, who will travel to Lebanon with Australia's Asia Cup team today, wants to make his mark.
"I'm only 25 years old and it's still my dream, and always will be, to play in the NBA," Blanchfield said.
"It's something I've dreamt of since I was 12 years old shooting in the front yard.
"To get to the NBA has always been my dream and always will be until I finish playing. "Whether it happens is another story but everyone's got to have goals and something to work towards."
Blanchfield said the pre-season fixtures are a chance for the NBL to earn the respect of the basketball world.
"The Boomers at the Olympics have really put Australian basketball on the map and this is another good stepping stone to put the rest of the world on notice that the NBL is a really good league," he said.
"You're playing against the best players in the world and it's going to be great to see where I'm at an individual level and give you something to work toward.
"It's an unbelievable opportunity. Because it's only one game, you have to put your best foot forward.
"You've got to leave everything on the floor. You can't go out there and be hesitant or ease your way into it.
"I've got to back myself and not second guess everything I do. I have to believe in myself and trust my basketball skills to get me through."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Kings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blanchfield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebanon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles' Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd Blanchfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salt Lake City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Asia Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Crocodile Blanchfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Dante Exum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blanchfield Jazzed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
