<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407628328766407</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/real-life/news-life/british-student-brutally-bashed-in-nightclub-toilet-ruining-new-nose-job/news-story/b765f0cad315dfa1268f66535339da11</url>
  <title>British student brutally bashed in nightclub toilet, ruining new nose job</title>
  <content>
Holly Ellis has been left with her recent nose job ruined, after allegedly being bashed in a nightclub toilet. Picture: Facebook

Share

WARNING: GRAPHIC CONTENT
A student - who had just spent more than $8200 on a nose job - claims she was brutally attacked by a former friend, who has ruined her face.
Holly Ellis, 23, that an old school mate "kicked the s***" out of her face while wearing high heels, as she sat on a toilet in a nightclub.
Holly, who had the surgery in London after she received an inheritance from her grandfather - believes the attacker knew of her operation.
"I'm still in shock and completely devastated with the state of my nose," Ms Ellis told The Mirror.
"After waiting for years to have surgery to take the lump away, for this to happen just a month after my op."

Holly Ellis had just spent $8200 on a new nose procedure. Picture: Mirrorpix/australscopeSource:australscope
Ms Ellis claims she'd been out with her cousin and friend when the abuse occurred. The 23-year-old student alleged that they'd run in to the attacker around 2.30am, and were simply "catching up".
"She mentioned she is a mother. I said that's nice and she didn't like the fact I'd said that's nice," Ms Ellis explained.
"She mentioned that me and a friend had been a bit of a b**** to her in school. I said to her to stop being silly, that girls can be b**** and that it was 12 years ago.

Holly, who is a 23-year-old student, thinks the attacker knew about her recent nose surgery. Picture: FacebookSource:Supplied
Going to the bathroom with her friends and the attacker, Ms Ellis claims she left the door of her cubicle open so she continue with the conversation.
"I'm sat on the toilet and talking normally," she explained.
"Then she just came in and started kicking me in the face with her heels on.
"I was sat on the toilet and tried to protect my face. Because I just had my nose done I was protecting it. I went to the floor.
"She knew I had always hated my nose. It has been all over my social media that I had the job done.
"Then the girl she was with said something like, 'that's enough, lets go'. I was covered in blood.
The attack left Ms Ellis with a broken nose, which she hopes will heal and not ruin her recent surgery.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Ellis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GRAPHIC CONTENT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FacebookSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Ellis, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirrorpix/australscopeSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ellis</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
