<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408148019821141</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/mortgage-childcare-costs-hurting-young-australian-families/8763058</url>
  <title>Mortgage debt, childcare cost rises see families doing it tough</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Australian mortgage debt and childcare costs have dramatically increased, according to the latest long-term economic and lifestyle study by the University of Melbourne.
The annual Household, Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia (HILDA) report sees the same cohort of 17,000 people surveyed each year on issues including relationships, education, employment and health issues.
The latest report reveals mortgage debt for 18 to 39-year-olds had almost doubled since 2002, with the average debt on owner-occupied homes rising from $169,201 to $336,586.
"What I think was interesting about this finding was that it's not simply because people are borrowing more to purchase their homes," report author Roger Wilkins said.
"It seems that many young people are using the increased equity in their homes that's coming about through the rise in house prices to meet their living expenses."
The researchers believe more people are using their home loans to buy other big ticket items such as cars instead of taking out more expensive personal loans.
Homeowners vulnerable to changes in interest rates

The HILDA report noted the growth in debt meant the economic wellbeing of young homeowners was now more sensitive to interest rate changes than it was in 2002.
"Even small changes in interest rates will have substantial impacts on the effective income situation of many home owners," the report said.
Previous surveys revealed home ownership had been declining, but the latest results suggested the drop was particularly concentrated in the same age group.
In 2002, 36 per cent of 18 to 39-year-olds had a mortgage. That fell to 25 per cent, with the sharpest falls among couples with dependent children.
"The single stand-out factor is house prices," Professor Wilkins said.
"For example, in Sydney fewer than 20 per cent of people aged under 40 are home owners, whereas in non-urban Australia it's [35.7 per cent]."
Home ownership rates (per cent) of people 18-39 by region

City2002 2014 change
Sydney29.219.7-9.5
Other urban NSW4224.6-17.4
Melbourne35.721.3-14.4
Other urban Vic36.624.7-11.9
Brisbane35.329.8-5.5
Other urban Qld38.221.1-17.1
Adelaide35.425.4-10.0
Other urban SA38.725.4-13.3
Perth37.230.9-6.3
Other urban WA3525.2-9.8
Urban Tasmania40.930.4-10.5
ACT and urban NT37.437.7-10.5
Non-urban Australia39.235.7-3.5
The report showed large declines in home ownership for male and female clerical and administrative workers, for male community and sales workers and female technicians and tradies.
Professionals and male machinery operators and drivers appeared to fare relatively well.
People in Sydney, Melbourne and urban Queensland outside Brisbane recorded the lowest home ownership rates, while the Australian Capital Territory and Northern Territory had some of the highest.
Not surprisingly, the study showed young adults were living with their parents longer.
In 2015, 60 per cent of men and 48 per cent of women aged 22-25 were living in their parents' home, up from 43 per cent and 27 per cent respectively in 2001.
Super used to pay mortgages

The HILDA survey raised concerns about the declining home ownership rate affecting the living standards of retirees who bought a home later in life.
Professor Wilkins said many retirees may have to use a significant part of their superannuation to pay off their outstanding home loan.
"Even if house price growth was to moderate and many of these young home owners ultimately do buy a home, they'll be buying it much later in life," he said.
"So it's likely they'll have significantly more mortgage debt when they retire.
"We may be finding that reliance on the aged pension for future generations is higher than we might have expected."
Childcare costs skyrocket

The HILDA survey also found a drastic increase in the cost of child care since 2002.
Average incomes have not grown for five years, but the median weekly expenditure on child care for children not yet at school has risen 75 per cent in real terms for couples and more than doubled for single-parent families.
Approximately 1.2 million children have parents who are separated.
The survey found about 59 per cent of parents who care for their children most of the time do not receive regular child support from the other parent.
And for those who do receive payments, only about one quarter continued to receive support after five years.
The report concluded low rates of home ownership, a high cost of child care and a lack of child support had led to high poverty rates among single-parent families, with 20 to 25 per cent of those children lacking basic essentials.
The study is conducted by the Melbourne Institute on behalf of the Federal Government.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Wilkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City2002 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Capital Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
