<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408156609755976</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/news/call-for-100000-social-housing-boost-across-australia-to-help-people-experiencing-homelessness/news-story/4ffa6244fa3ecc41fb492c3e32689560</url>
  <title>The hidden faces of homelessness</title>
  <content>
CHRISTINE Thirkell would go to work with a brave face and the story that she was "staying with friends" to mask a reality she had never imagined for herself - she was homeless.
After a relationship breakdown the then Footscray primary school teacher grabbed her daughter, packed the car and fled her Sunshine home.
They wound up sleeping at a friend's house in the children's play room. She had no bed or any belongings.
"My friend was very good to me but I felt like I was imposing. You are interrupting someone else's life and you have no space of your own," she said.
"I continued my work and tried to keep things together, making sure I got my daughter to school, but it's not easy living in someone else's home.
She suffered further blows when her father became terminally ill and she injured her back while caring for him and had to quit her job.
"I was in shock - I hid from the world for a year." Ms Thirkell said.
"Not only was I homeless but I lost my father, my mother's health deteriorated and I was severely depressed."
She felt shut out of the rental market and didn't know where she could find any help.
"Renting is so tough because there are so many people out there vying for the same affordable places that you are," Ms Thirkell said.
"Any decent, property for an affordable price will be fought over."
Unable to afford a place on her own she teamed up with her ageing mother to rent a house, which belonged to her sister and brother-in-law.
But even with a roof over their heads, things are still tough.
They brave winter chills without a heater to save money on electricity bills and don't eat meat because it is too costly.
She also volunteers with the Council to Homeless Persons (CHP) and is studying to be a counsellor.
Ms Thirkell is leading a petition for 100,000 new public housing properties across Australia to ensure families and individuals facing homelessness don't suffer as she did.
"Homelessness is not a choice and it is not your fault," Ms Thirkell said.
There are more than 35,000 people on the Victorian public housing register.
Last financial year 21,400 Victorians - an average of 59 per day - were turned away from homelessness services, and about a third of them could not be helped due to a lack of both short and long-term accommodation.
CHP acting chief executive Kate Colvin and Launch Housing chief executive Tony Keenan echoed the call for large scale investment in social housing.
According to the Australian Institute of Health and Wellbeing, 105,000 Victorians sought help from specialist homelessness services in 2015-16 and more than 60 per cent of them were women.
Ms Colvin said the number of women becoming homeless was growing, particularly single, older women who had often retired with a lot less superannuation than men.
"The way that the pension is set up there is an assumption that you own your home and are not renting," Ms Colvin said.
"And for people who are on Newstart it is completely inadequate."
Mr Keenan said it was also important to prevent intergenerational homelessness.
"We've got families facing homelessness, because they have been moved from pillar to post, it is difficult to keep their children engaged in education," he said.
"We've seen children whose schooling has been disrupted because they've had to move five or six times a year."
Mr Keenan said there had been some significant investment in social housing made by the State Government, but that it was an issue that had gone largely unaddressed for decades.
"If we can get people into long-term housing and back them with support, that is much more effective than putting them in crisis accommodation or a motel room temporarily."
State Housing Minister Martin Foley said government funding and initiatives would deliver more than 6000 social housing properties and help more than 19,000 people find housing.
"The initiatives not only provide bricks and mortar but include interventions such as private rental assistance to sustain at risk tenancies, as well has medium and long-term subsidies," Mr Foley said.
Ms Thirkell's petition is at endthehousingcrisis.org.au
WALK IN THEIR SHOES
THEY say you can never truly understand what someone is going through unless you take a walk in their shoes.
As part of Homelessness Week, from August 7-13, the Council to Homeless Persons is inviting people to take part in a "Walk in my Shoes" tour on August 7 to provide insights into how people become homeless and the challenges they face every day.
The tour will be led by someone who has experienced homelessness and will explore sites of personal significance for them in Melbourne's CBD and inner-city suburbs.
It aims to counter stereotypes and give a human face to the homelessness crisis. For more information visit
Other events during Homelessness Week include:
Ringwood: August 1, 11am - 1pm
A Walk to End Homelessness. Kevin Andrews, Federal member for Menzies; Greens Senator, Sam Dunn and Maroondah Mayor, Prue Cutts, will meet with homelessness workers and clients from eastern homelessness services and walk around Ringwood Lake
Glenroy: August 9, noon - 1.30pm
VincentCare, 175 Glenroy Rd, Glenroy will host a BBQ lunch, at which a financial counsellor and employment consultant will be available to give advice to people struggling with rent and bills.
Epping, South Morang, Whittlesea: August 7-13
Plenty Valley Community Health Services, Show your support by donating blankets to the Plenty Valley Blanket Drive.
North Melbourne: August 9, 10am - noon
Wombat Housing & Support Service, 191 Melrose Street, North Melbourne - inviting donations of myki cards, gift cards, mobile phones and blankets.
Laverton: August 11, 10am - 3pm
Latitude Directions for Young People are running a free BBQ at the Laverton Community Hub, 95-105 Railway Ave.
Sunshine: August 11, 8.30am - 10am
Salvation Army Social Housing & Support holding a breakfast for clients at 6/147 Harvester Rd, Sunshine. Members of the community are welcome to drop off donations any time during the day.
Werribee: August 12, 10.30am - 1pm
UnitingCare Werribee are running a festival, Corner Duncans Rd and Synnot Street, Werribee Federal MP Joanna Ryan will be joining UnitingCare Werribee at this event.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Thirkell</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1, 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Keenan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroondah Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHRISTINE Thirkell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werribee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army Social Housing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laverton Community Hub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncans Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werribee Federal MP Joanna Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plenty Valley Blanket Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homelessness Week</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VincentCare, 175 Glenroy Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvester Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Colvin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footscray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeless Persons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12, 10.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newstart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Synnot Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>End Homelessness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dunn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launch Housing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringwood Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Morang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenroy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens Senator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Support Service, 191 Melrose Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UnitingCare Werribee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wombat Housing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Epping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prue Cutts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellbeing, 105,000 Victorians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley Community Health Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11, 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Railway Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whittlesea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young People</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laverton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Colvin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Housing Minister Martin Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
