<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408156609755908</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/maroondah-bizweek-celebrates-businesswomen-in-photo-exhibition/news-story/5e42687f18f458a43b87bfc530659150</url>
  <title>Exhibition celebrates businesswomen</title>
  <content>
BUSINESSWOMEN are being celebrated in a photo exhibition as part of Maroondah BizWeek.
More than 60 per cent of new businesses in Maroondah have been established by women and this exhibition celebrates the story of 19 of them.
The annual celebration is a week of business , workshops and free mentoring clinics from August 7 to 11.
Croydon business owner Sharee Potter, who is included in the exhibition, said it was a great way to acknowledge the success of women in Maroondah.
"I love the idea of supporting small businesses and women and the council has definitely been supportive of new businesses," Ms Potter said.
Ms Potter quit her 20 year career as a paediatric nurse to start up her shop .
The shop offers unique homeware, art, fashion and accessories sourced from local artists and overseas fair trade dealers.
"I try to have pieces in the shop that you're not going to find in your mainstream shopping centres," Ms Potter said.
"I definitely think my location in Maroondah has been a big part of my success because the women here appreciate the quality."
Maroondah councillor Kylie Spears, who attended the exhibition launch, said it was encouraging to see the entrepreneurial spirit of diverse business owners.
"I would encourage both men and women to go along to the Women in Business Photographic Exhibition," Cr Spears said.
"There are many women in business from a diverse range of working backgrounds who are achieving great things and who have demonstrated courageous and successful leadership."
The Maroondah BizWeek Women in Business Photographic Exhibition is on display at Eastland Shopping Centre (near Rebel and JB HiFi).
It will move to the Realm Activity Space, 179 Maroondah Highway from Monday, August 7 until Friday, August 11.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroondah Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Potter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroondah</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Croydon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroondah BizWeek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Spears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharee Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB HIFI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Spears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realm Activity Space</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Photographic Exhibition</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastland Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroondah BizWeek Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
