<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408152314788557</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/real-estate/tasmania/hobart/dennes-point-modern-stylish-coastal-living/news-story/e5555f8f2794d4294bdbab75521613de</url>
  <title>Dennes Point: Modern stylish coastal living - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Dennes Point at Bruny Island. 47 Cox Drive. Picture: SUPPLIED

THIS is a modern, craftsman-built holiday home with the finishing touches only completed early this year.
The home has open-plan kitchen/living/dining areas with timber joinery, polished hardwood flooring and vaulted ceilings.
Full-height glass sliders open on to an extensive west-facing covered deck, overlooking the D'Entrecasteaux Channel.

Take in the view

An efficient freestanding wood heater warms the home throughout, and all windows are double-glazed.
There are three good-sized bedrooms, a kitchen fitted with quality appliances, a bathroom, and separate toilet and laundry.
Adjacent to the main dwelling is an outbuilding with a garage and office space below, and a large workshop area above.

Perfectly positioned

Timber features

The upper part of this building has its own toilet, small bathroom, kitchenette and wood heater.
There are just five houses currently on the market for sale in Dennes Point.
The variety is broad with houses priced between offers over $400,000 and low $900,000s.
CoreLogic figures show only six houses were sold in the 12 months to April.
Fall Real Estate has this property listed at early $600,000s.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruny Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entrecasteaux Channel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennes Point</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
