<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408165199690792</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/diamond-valley-streetwatch-crooks-grab-cash-and-trucks-from-hurstbridge-garden-store/news-story/4f5fa23cf9ac89ef1904e5fe095c26a0</url>
  <title>Crooks roll off in stolen trucks</title>
  <content>
CUNNING crooks targeted a Hurstbridge garden supply store and drove off with a thousand dollars and four vehicles.
The Heidelberg-Kinglake Rd store was broken into when a group of thieves climbed a cyclone fence and entered the office building sometime between 5pm on July 26 and 5am on July 27.
Investigators believe once inside, the intruders turned the power off to stop the sensored lights going off, then they stole $1,000 from the till and keys to four vehicles parked on site, which included three tipper trucks and an excavator.
Anyone with information is urged to phone Banyule Criminal Investigation Unit on 9450 8000.
ARTHURS CREEK
A man is expected to be charged after he was bust by police for allegedly driving dangerously. The 28-year-old Meadow Heights man was first spotted by officers driving at an excessively slow speed north along Plenty Rd in Mill Park. He then turned onto Arthurs Creek Rd allegedly veering into oncoming traffic before almost collecting a cyclist. The man was pulled over by police and when searched, a firearm was found in the car. He refused to be tested for drugs and alcohol and is expected to be charge.
GREENSBOROUGH
City-bound trains on two busy lines were at a standstill after a person walked onto the tracks at Jolimont train station. There were major delays for Hurstbridge and South Morang line commuters after the incident took place at 9.05am on July 26. Trains stopped at Jolimont Station, with passengers told to take the tram if they wanted to get to Flinders St. Victoria Police said one person had been removed from the tracks and was in custody. Metro said passengers experienced delays up to 55 minutes. A commuter told News Corp passengers were growing frustrated on board the stopped trains. "They can't hear the (train driver) announcements, they are all broken," she said. "We have to go into the other carriages and ask passengers what was said."
WATSONIA
A number of police descended on a Watsonia home after fears an armed man was holding a woman hostage. Emergency services rushed to the Richards Avenue home about 2.15pm on July 25. Police blocked off the area and tried to negotiate with the man. The 26-year-old man eventually walked out onto the driveway before he was arrested by police. He is expected to be charged with a string of offences.
ELTHAM
A tablet computer plugged into a car's cigarette lighter, to charge its battery, was pinched from Eltham. The car was parked on Heacham Rd when the thieves struck sometime between 11.30pm on June 26 and 8.30am on 27 July. Anyone with information is urged to phone Crime Stoppers.
ELTHAM
Four distinctive wheels from a classic MG car were pinched from Eltham. The 15 inch wheels, which were painted red, were stored in the garage of a 10 acre property in Mount Pleasant Rd. Investigators believe the thieves took the wheels sometime between June 30 and July 20 from an unlocked shed 50m away from the house. Anyone with information is urged to phone Crime Stoppers.
BUNDOORA
A thief broke into an empty Bundoora house. The owner had just bought the property before flying to Sydney on business. However when he returned to the Stellar Pl home, on July 10, the rear sliding door has been smashed. There was nothing for the offender to grab from inside.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hurstbridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plenty Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Pleasant Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jolimont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eltham</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundoora</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meadow Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARTHURS CREEK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders St. Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heacham Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stellar Pl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jolimont Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthurs Creek Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Morang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banyule Criminal Investigation Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mill Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATSONIA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg-Kinglake Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREENSBOROUGH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richards Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
