<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408152314788580</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/compensation-wanted-for-people-living-near-electrical-substation-eyesore-in-ivanhoe/news-story/921a45d6628a38e2c22337a245a4b72c</url>
  <title>People with no power</title>
  <content>
RESIDENTS living near an "eyesore" electrical substation due to be built in Ivanhoe say they want compensation as their property values will fall.
The substation is being built along the Hurstbridge rail line in Sherwood Rd, Ivanhoe, to cope with power upgrades for the rail duplication between Heidelberg and Rosanna railway stations and the level crossing removal in Rosanna.
It is on VicTrack land.
Peter Camilleri, who has lived at 33 Sherwood Rd - directly opposite the proposed site - for more than 25 years, said the lack of consultation had baffled residents.
Residents learned about the plans for the building only on July 17.
The substation will be 35m long, 5.2m wide, 3.5m tall and will be surrounded by 20m of fencing and bollards. Several trees will be removed before construction starts in -September.
Mr Camilleri said residents had no objection to the substation but that it could have been built somewhere with less "visual -impact".
"It will be a blank canvas for graffiti," he said.
He said properties directly affected included 25 to 35 Sherwood Rd, but that other nearby residents were also concerned.
Those concerns were raised in two community meetings on July 20 and 26, but Mr Camilleri said discussions went "around in circles" and that there was no "two-way consultation".
"It was an information meeting telling the residents that the construction was going ahead and there was no way anything could alter that fact," he said
He said the planned large industrial building would be an eyesore out of keeping with the neighbourhood with its many heritage homes dating back to the early 1900s.
"This is a large industrial building that has been dumped in a residential area, which is out of keeping with neighbourhood character and will have longstanding implications for the affected residents for many years to come," Mr Camilleri said.
He said it was "a given" that property values would be affected and that residents should be compensated -accordingly.
Mr Camilleri said they wanted to know how often "inevitable graffiti" would be removed.
Banyule Mayor Tom Melican said the council had only recently become aware of the proposal for the substation, on VicTrack land.
He said the Level Crossing Removal Authority indicated it was vital infrastructure but there may be opportunities for residents to influence the design and screening.
Council would work with the authority to ensure the best outcome for residents.
Level Crossing Removing Authority director Steve Brown said electrical substations were essential to the rail network and the authority would continue to work closely with the community as construction progressed.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hurstbridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosanna</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanhoe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Level Crossing Removal Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherwood Rd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Camilleri</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicTrack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Camilleri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banyule Mayor Tom Melican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crossing Removing Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
