<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408148019821153</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4797918/dont-despair-the-only-way-is-up-for-us-all/?cs=308</url>
  <title>Don't despair, the only way is up for us all</title>
  <content>
SUPPORT: A proposal for the Wests Group to take ownership of the Knights has been well received by many, with one contributor saying the deal is a "no brainer".

IN response to comments by Howard Bridgman (Letters, 31/7) and Dale Allen (Short Takes, 1/8), please don't be concerned about the impact on members with this takeover.

Dale, you obviously spend a lot of dollars at the club and if you would like to take those food, drink, entertainment and pokie dollars elsewhere, that's your choice. Howard, the way can only be up for the Wests Group, Newcastle Knights and Newcastle City as a whole. Phil Gardner is no fool and the dollars injected into local sports groups will continue. As a member I'm not too concerned as "what's in it for me".

My city of Newcastle needs this boost and I'm with it all the way. Maybe it would be nice if co-members of the Wests Group and the Newcastle Knights were offered a larger discount on food and drinks at the club. It would boost both their memberships. As I said, it's a no brainer.
Kathy Wilson, Lambton

Renewal, not race track

IN response to the letter by John Beach (Letters, 1/8), Newcastle City Council's investment in what is known as the Supercars works program is for the delivery of planned renewal works in the east end.
I appreciate a three-day Supercars event is not every resident's cup of tea, but it's important the debate be based on facts. Newcastle City Council is not spending ratepayers' money to build a race track.
Rather, Watt Street, as Newcastle's oldest street, was in desperate need of an overhaul long before the Supercars race was even considered. The race itself will attract 150,000 people to the city and act as a televised postcard to an international audience in the many millions.
The works will repair a patchwork of footpaths, replace unreliable 100-year-old water pipes and see the installation of telecommunication cables for the NBN.
Desperately needed stormwater pits will be built and new street lighting installed. Smart poles will provide the street with Wi-Fi along with speakers for emergency announcements and cameras for real-time traffic analysis. LED lighting will be dimmable by remote to reduce the brightness for Watt Street residents in the wee hours.
Council is listening to reasonable requests from residents by addressing their parking needs, and minimising disturbances as much as possible.
As for the ratepayers in our western suburbs, they're regularly thanking me for helping bring an international sporting event that will inject tens of millions of dollars into the local economy.
Jeremy Bath,  Newcastle City Council interim chief executive

Cutting Monarch ties

BILL Shorten is proposing to introduce a national vote on becoming a republic with an Australian head of state within the first term of a future Labor government. He empathises the ugly duel citizenship saga for not renouncing allegiance to a foreign power. And laws in parliament are passed in the name of someone who will never be an Australian citizen. 
Turnbull believes change would not be supported during the Queen's reign and is terrified of further unsettling the conservative right monarchists. Can you imagine the stink that monarchist Abbott will kick up over this treasonous act?
Mr Shorten said he had "tremendous regard for the Queen" and her service. "But I am not an Elizabethan ... I'm an Australian".  "And I believe our head of state should be an Australian too - and we should start now." 
How will Malcolm Turnbull try to weasel out of anything except condoning this move? Just wait for more of Turnbull's hypocrisy to try and deny a push for a republic. 
How is it that the head of Australia is a foreigner and never will be an Australian citizen and her overseer can remove our elected prime minister? 

Sound like we need to stand on our own feet and cut the chains that bind us.
John Undery, Kotara South

He was never a hero

I HAVE just finished reading about an organisation putting up National Socialist posters in universities including the University of Newcastle's Callaghan campus ('Police called in over uni poster strike', Herald, 29/7). This group believes Adolf Hitler has been misrepresented. I doubt its members have read widely on the subject for if they had they would not be so quick to idolise the man. Yes, Hitler did want the elevation of Germany, but he also wanted to rule the world. And he wanted to rid it of Jews.
Gradually he took away all the rights and freedoms of Jewish people so that they became impoverished in every way. He then arranged for them to be tortured, beaten, starved and those that were left were either shot or gassed. Few escaped.
So never ever make Hitler into a hero. He was an unhinged, racist, drug-taking dictator who eventually took his own life rather than face justice.
Julie Kay Robinson, Cardiff

Discounts worth the call

I CANNOT believe the main story in a lot of papers on Friday and on radio talk back was that electricity suppliers dare to give employees a discount on their bills. Why would anyone complain  about this when it is available to us all, and has been for a long time? If you are not getting a discount from your supplier for paying your bills on time then for goodness sake ring them.

I have been getting this discount now for at least 10 years. My current rate is 18 per cent from electricity and 11 per cent from gas. Not a lot of money with my bill but a family would make a big difference.

I say if you are missing out then get off your backsides, stop complaining and ring your supplier. As a side do you think major retail stores don't give their employees a discount on their groceries?
Kerry Redman, Waratah

Keep the facade

WHY is it so hard to retain the facade of The Store? Engineers have apparently deemed it too hard but engineers also have the ability to suggest ways to save it. After WWII, the city fathers of Paris declared that no facade was to be demolished. Developers had to keep the facade and any parts of the building able to be retained. We can now visit Paris in all is glory and with all the history and flavour. They were able to succeed after all the ravages of a world war. Our city fathers seem not to have the same vision and instead see lots of steel and concrete painted in various shades of grey. Sad.

Annette Gillies, The Junction

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald, 29/7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Knights</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAN'T</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kotara South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Socialist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Bridgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watt Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Undery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jewish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerry Redman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annette Gillies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardiff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adolf Hitler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabethan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Bath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hitler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Kay Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWII</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callaghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Short Takes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Group</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
