<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408156609756032</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/boost-for-macedon-ranges-regional-sports-hub-push/news-story/22ffbe7f428ce965a600e7226fc56b3d</url>
  <title>Search on for $18 million sports hub site</title>
  <content>
A LONG imagined indoor sports hub in the Macedon Ranges will take further shape with a $100,000 business study about to kick off.
The $18 million Macedon Ranges Regional Sports Hub is the vision of a range of sports clubs and associations frustrated at increasingly having to turn juniors away because of bursting competitions.
Last year the then federal Liberal candidate for Bendigo Megan Purcell declared her support for a $100,000 study following a concerted community campaign.

spokeswoman Megan Condron said that funding had now been confirmed and allocated to Macedon Ranges Council with Otium Planning Group to conduct the study.
Macedon Ranges Council will manage the project set to explore potential locations and compositions of the centre, while also looking into present and future demand for facilities.
"It is a really exciting landmark for us," Ms Condron said.
"It's clear we need facilities, but as a community we now have the opportunity to articulate a vision from user groups needing space to grow to families detailing they're needs."
Ms Condron said there are 60 junior basketball teams from Riddells Creek, Gisborne and Woodend travelling each week to play in Sunbury, while other juniors simply missed out if they registered too late for a season.
"It is heartbreaking to turn kids away as you want them to be active."
Ms Condron said finding a location easy to access and close to public transport should be a priority of the study, while it was also an opportunity to recognise how sports tourism could build the local economy.
"Sports tourism is something which regional cities like Shepparton has embraced, they estimated a three day tournament bringing in $2.3 million," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedon Ranges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Condron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Condron</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shepparton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Otium Planning Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bendigo Megan Purcell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedon Ranges Regional Sports Hub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riddells Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gisborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MACEDON RANGES Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
