<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408276868843292</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/00/32/cruel-paradox-in-repeat-child-abuse-cases</url>
  <title>Cruel paradox in repeat child abuse cases</title>
  <content>
It is unacceptable that children who have suffered the most extensive sexual abuse may be less able to receive justice in the criminal courts, the child abuse royal commission says.
Commission chair Justice Peter McClellan says it is increasingly apparent that changes to the process of, and evidence admitted at, a criminal trial may be necessary to ensure the response of the criminal justice system achieves justice not only for the accused but also for victims.
"There is a risk that if young children and children with disability are unable to give evidence in criminal proceedings, perpetrators of sexual abuse will be able to offend against some of the most vulnerable members of society with impunity," he said.
Justice McClellan said the requirement for the prosecution to provide particulars of the offences creates a difficulty for child sexual abuse survivors, who often find it difficult to provide adequate or accurate details of the offending.
The challenges in relation to particularising a series of repeated events that occurred some time ago are obvious, he said in a speech to an Office of the Director of Public Prosecutions NSW conference in Sydney on Wednesday.
"The result is a cruel paradox: the greater the regularity with which a child is offended against, the more difficult it can become to charge and prosecute the offender."
Each state and territory has a persistent sexual abuse offence, which in most jurisdictions requires proof of the occurrence of three or more unlawful sexual acts.

Related Articles

But the offence is rarely charged except in Queensland, where it has been reframed so the key element of the crime is the unlawful sexual relationship, not particular unlawful acts.
The royal commission will likely recommend changes to persistent sexual offences legislation as part of its major criminal justice report, to be released this month.
"It is unacceptable, in our view, that the criminal justice system should accept a situation in which children who have suffered the most extensive abuse may be those who are less able to receive justice in the criminal courts," Justice McClellan said.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Prosecutions NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice McClellan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of the Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Peter McClellan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
