<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408448667538829</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/2653363/hawks-star-ervin-hopeful-for-cats-clash-after-suffering-back-injury/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Ervin treating bad back suffered in loss to Breakers</title>
  <content>
Hawks star Gary Ervin sat out training on Monday with a back injury but hopes to be right for Friday's critical home clash with champions Perth.

The Wollongong Hawks will sweat on the fitness of guard Gary Ervin for Friday's must-win home stand against Perth Wildcats.

The American import had to be taken off shortly after half-time in Sunday's clutch 79-77 loss to New Zealand Breakers after suffering back spasms.
He failed to participate in Monday's recovery session and underwent physio treatment.
He is expected to receive continued treatment for the injury in the next 48-hours in a bid to be fit for Friday's clash.
With the Hawks' record currently sitting at 1-5, it will be crucial for all hands to be on deck at WIN Entertainment Centre.
Ervin was hopeful he'd recover in time for the critical stoush. 
''Obviously today is Monday and I have about five days to get it right. Me hoping and praying, I don't think I will be out on Friday,'' he said.
''It is too close to think about saying I am out but we will see the stuff I need to take to get better.''
Ervin had to be taken off less than a minute into the second half of Sunday's loss after numerous attempts to return to the court.
''I am one of those guys who can play through anything but that pain right there is difficult to play because you don't have any lift in you and you can't really move like that,'' Ervin said.
''That was the hard thing. I tried to give it a shot a couple of times but it wouldn't work.''
Ervin's absence saw the Hawks slide from five points down at the half to 13 points at three quarter time.
They'd recover to trail by just four with five minutes remaining but would ultimately fall short at the death.
Ervin said it was difficult to watch things unfold from the bench. 
''My mindset going into the game was that it was a big game and I was going to step up to the challenge but due to things I can't control it was tough,'' he said.
''I think the guys fought hard in the forth quarter and like I said before it was the third quarter which hurt us.''
Fellow guard Jahii Carson also spent time on the bench over the weekend as he battled illness, but said he was back to 100% on Monday. 

The Hawks follow up Friday's home match against the Wildcats just two days later with a trip to Melbourne United.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIN Entertainment Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ervin</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Ervin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Hawks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Breakers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jahii Carson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Wildcats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildcats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
