<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408457257473495</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>ABN Newswire</source>
  <url>http://www.abnnewswire.net/press/en/89411/Moxian-Inc-(NASDAQ-MOXC)-Offers-Investors-Access-to-Growth-of-Worlds-Largest-Economy-89411.html</url>
  <title>Moxian, Inc. (NASDAQ:MOXC) Offers Investors Access to Growth of World's Largest Economy</title>
  <content>
China is now the world's largest economy and on the brink of incredible growth

Moxian is targeting owners of 75 million small- and medium-sized businesses in China with O2O tools to engage and convert online viewers to brick and mortar purchasers

Social gaming, loyalty rewards and messaging allow Moxian to mine consumer data for clients' benefit while driving revenue
New York, New York, 08:30 EDT August 01, 2017 (NetworkNewsWire) - Moxian, Inc. (NASDAQ:MOXC) is offering investors a unique opportunity to benefit from the growth of what is now the world's largest economy. Moxian, a digital marketing company based in Shenzhen, China, is on the leading edge of e-commerce in China's newly emerging private-based economy, offering merchants a way to convert online views into retail purchases at brick and mortar locations.

China became the world's largest exporter in 2010, and, in 2014, surpassed the U.S. to become the largest economy in the world, according to Forbes (). The country is on the brink of incredible growth as it transitions into a consumer-based economy, according to Stephen Roach, former chairman of Morgan Stanley Asia (). Moxian is well-positioned to both drive the transition and benefit from it.

Moxian uses social media, entertainment and business intelligence to focus on the online-to-offline market (O2O). The company is targeting China's 75 million small- and medium-sized businesses to help offline merchants reach more digitally-oriented customers using promotions such as games, rewards, loyalty programs and social events.

Moxian is in the process of converting more than 31,000 small market enterprises (SMEs) to paid clients with its Moxian+ Business app. The app allows businesses to interact with new and existing customers and uses a client's consumer list to mine valuable data analytics and drive retail traffic into brick and mortar locations. Clients can create, manage and promote customized loyalty programs, ad campaigns and promotions.

For the 300,000 consumer users, the Moxian+ User app offers games, social loyalty programs and shopping, along with Mo-Talk, a proprietary voice chat service which helps clients and merchants interact.

Moxian projects its mobile advertising revenue in China to reach $3 million in 2017 and $6 million in 2018 - 24% of company sales. Spending on digital advertising in China has jumped to 57.2% of total ad dollars. SeeThruEquity () has projected that Moxian will reach $24.1 million in sales by fiscal year 2018.

For more information, visit the company's website at

More from NetworkNewsWire

NASDAQ:NETE) Lets Merchants Accept Both Online and Offline Payments
OTCMKTS:LXRP) Technology Set to Benefit as Study Shows More Benefits of Cannabidiol
NASDAQ:MBRX) is "One to Watch"

About NetworkNewsWire

NetworkNewsWire (NNW) is an information service that provides (1) access to our news aggregation and syndication servers, (2) NetworkNewsBreaks that summarize corporate news and information, (3) enhanced press release services, (4) social media distribution and optimization services, and (5) a full array of corporate communication solutions. As a multifaceted financial news and content distribution company with an extensive team of contributing journalists and writers, NNW is uniquely positioned to best serve private and public companies that desire to reach a wide audience of investors, consumers, journalists and the general public. NNW has an ever-growing distribution network of more than 5,000 key syndication outlets across the country. By cutting through the overload of information in today's market, NNW brings its clients unparalleled visibility, recognition and brand awareness. NNW is where news, content and information converge.

For more information please visit

Please see full terms of use and disclaimers on the NetworkNewsWire website applicable to all content provided by NNW, wherever published or re-published:

NetworkNewsWire (NNW)
New York, New York

212.418.1217 Office

Source:NetworkNewsWire

Contact:NetworkNewsWire (NNW)
New York, New York
www.NetworkNewsWire.com
212.418.1217 Office
Editor@NetworkNewsWire.com
Related Companies

Social Media
Share this Article

ABN Newswire
This Page Viewed:  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>O2O</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Study Shows More Benefits of Cannabidiol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOXC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SeeThruEquity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NNW</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NetworkNewsBreaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MBRX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN Newswire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shenzhen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LXRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Offline Payments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merchants Accept Both Online</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Roach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMEs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York, 08:30 EDT August 01, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's 75</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mo-Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OTCMKTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Page Viewed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moxian</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Technology Set</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NetworkNewsWire</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NETE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
