<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408448667538837</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/south-west/ipswichs-oldest-twostorey-home-going-to-auction/news-story/e4017e59b86ee679d8510c7dcd4989ae</url>
  <title>Ipswich's oldest two-storey home going to auction - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Booval House at 14-16 Cothill Rd, Booval, is going under the hammer.

A grand old Ipswich home that has been a country estate, convent and family home is going under the hammer after a 20-year, million dollar restoration.
The property at 14-16 Cothill Rd, Booval, known as Booval House, is the oldest two-storey house in Ipswich and the third oldest remaining home in the area.
Local banker George Faircloth had the property built between 1857 and 1859 on what was then a 310-acre farm.

Booval House in 1931.

The property passed to two different families before becoming a convent in 1931.
Today Booval House includes a two-storey, five bedroom main house and a two-storey annex on a 4,818 sqm block.
Dr John and Helen Jackson bought the home in 1997 and invested more than $1 million restoring the property.
"It was a major conservation job," Dr Jackson said.
"The property was essentially an unoccupied convent when we bought it.

Booval House in 1997.

"All the internal fittings had been removed and replaced in a very austere fashion for the nuns. All the verandas were totally enclosed with louvres and aluminium cladding and the timber veranda post had been replaced by brick.
"There was also a chapel that was built in 1969 that wasn't compatible with the main house."
The couple spent years returning Booval House to its original state.
They restumped and re-floored the ground level, opened up the verandas, rewired the property, re-roofed the main house and repainted inside and out.

One of the restored rooms at
Booval House.

The ground floor of the chapel annex was converted into a function space and the whole annex was remodelled to be more in keeping with the period of the original home.
Mrs Jackson, who has a keen interest in gardening, landscaped the grounds with the help of a heritage landscape architect.
"We know that we haven't cut any the corners even though people will not see a lot of the work that we have done," Dr Jackson said.
"We really wanted to make sure that (Booval House) last another 160 years."

The ground floor of
Booval House.

The Jacksons' hard work was acknowledged with the John Herbert Memorial Award for Excellence in Conservation - National Trust Queensland's top award.
And in May more than 1800 people visited Booval House during a Heritage Trust open day.
"The feedback we received was humbling and somewhat embarrassing, but it was lovely," Dr Jackson said.

The view from the wraparound veranda of
Booval House.

Dr Jackson said now he had retired and the conservation work was complete, it was time for the home to pass to its next custodians. "It would be a tremendous house for an extended multi-generational family and it has also been approved for significant business use," he said.
"It is the only place like it in Ipswich with large grounds and commercial potential."

One of the five bedrooms at
Booval House.

The property has five bedrooms, four bathroom, original cedar architraves and doors, hoop pine timber floors, six fireplaces, music parlour, cellar and library.
The two-storey annex includes a function area, kitchenette and bathroom downstairs and an open plan bedroom and living area upstairs.
Booval House is being marketed by Warren Ramsay of Ray White Ipswich and will be auctioned on Friday, August 25 at 10.30am at Ray White Corporate office, 111 Eagle St, Brisbane.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Jackson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Ramsay of Ray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cothill Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Herbert Memorial Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Booval</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Trust Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Booval House</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Faircloth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heritage Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Corporate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagle St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
