<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407950451320925</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:23</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/retail/david-jones-takes-lid-off-first-new-foodie-emporium-20170731-gxmeqs</url>
  <title>David Jones takes lid off first new foodie emporium </title>
  <content>
Marble counters, granite floors and leather banquettes - David Jones' new food emporium at Bondi Junction is clearly not your average supermarket.
After filling their trolleys and baskets with dry-aged beef from Cape Grim in Tasmania, cave-aged cheddar from Dorset in Britain, bottled water from Iceland, Italian-made pasta and olive oil, Serendipity icecream, Godiva chocolates, Sonoma bread and Dom Perignon champagne, David Jones shoppers will be able to sit down for a meal or a drink at Neil Perry's 270-seat Rockpool-style brasserie restaurant or one of several cocktail, coffee or sushi bars.
"The fitout is in keeping with what we're trying to achieve, which is a premium food offering the likes of which haven't been seen in Australia," David Jones chief executive John Dixon said on Tuesday after unveiling a five-month, multimillion-dollar renovation of the Bondi Junction food hall.
"It's an integrated and inspirational range of instore dining options developed with Neil Perry combined with a new food retail offer - what we're trying to do is connect and inspire people who really love food."

David Jones plans to spend at least $100 million in the next three years building a world-class retail food business aimed at restoring its reputation for gourmet food, differentiating the retailer from rivals such as Myer and protecting it from new competitors such as Amazon.

Mr Dixon is confident the food strategy will boost foot traffic, shopping frequency and "dwell time", lifting sales across the chain, which have come under pressure in recent months.
"There is a halo [effect] - I saw it in my old business and Woolworths [David Jones' South African owner] has seen it in their stores," said Mr Dixon, who ran British department store Marks & Spencer's food business for five years before taking the helm of David Jones last year.
"It's safe to say we know if you have got a differentiated food proposition it can absolutely have a positive halo effect on the rest of your business because people tend to buy food more frequently than they do apparel. Customers are increasingly looking for more of an experience when they go shopping."
Blueprint for revamps

The 2000-square metre Bondi Junction food hall, which reopens on Thursday, provides a blueprint for the revamp of David Jones' existing food emporiums in Market Street in Sydney, Bourke Street in Melbourne and new stores such as Wollongong, which opens in about four months.
David Jones also plans to open smaller 500- to 800-square-metre, small-format food halls in suburban and regional stores and 300 to 500-square-metre, standalone stores in high-density locations.
The flagship food halls will have restaurants, butcher shops, bakeries, oyster bars, seafood and sushi counters, and will sell a carefully curated range of about 6000 private label and branded products - one-third of the range in Woolworths or Coles - including chilled meals, salads and sandwiches, cheese and dairy products, fruit and vegetables and packaged groceries, with about 85 per cent of products sourced from Australian suppliers.
The Bondi Junction range also includes a small number of household essentials, such as dishwashing liquid and garbage bags, and non-gourmet groceries such as Vegemite and Weetbix, so David Jones' most well-heeled customers will be able to do their full grocery shop.

"We just have to make sure we're competitively priced on those," added David Jones food group director, Pieter de Wet.
David Jones has released no sales targets but JPMorgan's South African retail analyst, Stephen Carrott, estimates the food business will generate sales of $700 million within five years.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godiva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian-made</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi Junction</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weetbix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Grim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonoma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockpool-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorset</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pieter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iceland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Carrott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dixon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Market Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Perignon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vegemite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Dixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan's South African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Jones' South African</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
