<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408495912179976</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/r-kelly-hires-crisis-team-amid-sex-cult-accusations/news-story/5f32750487046a773aa95ed97b24ec69</url>
  <title>R. Kelly hires PR team over 'sex cult'</title>
  <content>
R. KELLY'S message to his fans about a report that he is allegedly holding women in a "sex cult" is: "It's a bunch of crap" - but he has hired a crisis team to fight the claims, which, sources tell the New York Post, have some truth to them.
Kelly was responding to multiple families' claims that he is housing their daughters in Chicago and Atlanta, where he brainwashes them and "records" them in sexual encounters.
His ticket sales have suffered since the families  with the allegations. Concert dates in Dallas, New Orleans and Baton Rouge, Louisiana, were cancelled due to low ticket sales - as fallout from the controversy.
A source  , "The promoter sent an e-mail to R. Kelly's team and told them they were set to lose $US400,000 ($658,000) if sales didn't pick up fast. They cancelled."
His booking agency, Monterey International, plans to cut ties with him this week, according to sources. A spokesman from the agency said, "No comment," when we reached out on Monday.
"Despite all of the crap y'all hearing, I will be coming to the East Coast to do my show, and believe me, y'all, it's a bunch of crap," Kelly said in a video.
The New York Post said the R & B crooner and his publicist Trevian Kutti, who is also Regina King's stylist, are plotting to undermine the families' accusations that he's holding their girls hostage.
One of the alleged captives, Jocelyn Savage, told TMZ that she's happy living with Kelly, and slammed her father's allegations.
After the video emerged, a source said, "They're working on a plan to portray Jocelyn's father as having ... encouraged the relationship with R. Kelly. They want to make it look like Kelly rescued her from her father."
Meanwhile, Kelly retained Bill Cosby's former lawyer Monique Pressley to manage the crisis, and is paying her $50,000 for 30 days. "She signed on to do damage control," the source said.
Mr Kutti told us in a statement, "Mr. Robert Kelly is both alarmed and disturbed by the recent revelations attributed to him. Mr. Kelly unequivocally denies such accusations and will work diligently and forcibly to pursue his accusers and clear his name."
This article was
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jocelyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monique Pressley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kutti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monterey International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TMZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regina King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BATON ROUGE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louisiana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Robert Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US400,000 ($658,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R. Kelly</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Orleans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevian Kutti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jocelyn Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlanta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Cosby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
