<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407804422429600</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/west-beaches/graeme-denton-sets-world-record-for-largest-bubble/news-story/430d535f3a0fe0ab4c30439033ae6912</url>
  <title>Big bubbles are no trouble for record breaker</title>
  <content>
DRESSED as his alter-ego Marty McBubble, Graeme Denton wasn't clowning about when he set about bursting a Guinness World Record.
Sporting a rainbow tie, glasses and colourful cap - the Fulham Gardens bubble expert used a supersized wand in his world record attempt to create the largest indoor, free floating transparent soap sud at Lockleys Primary School.
Mr Denton, 48, an educational performer who takes his show The ScientifiBubble Show to schools, not only succeeded, but his bubble of about 19.8m easily smashed the previous record of 8.5m.
"I've been performing in educational theatre shows in schools for about 10 years now and I've started mucking around with bubbles," said Mr Denton.
"There's a lot of science you can explain to children through the use of bubbles."
He teamed up with Professor Matt Roughan, of The University of Adelaide, who measured the bubble to ensure it passed the record.
Giant rulers and scales were placed on the floor of the sports hall to measure the bubble, which had been mixed with a secret soap mixture in the early morning when humidity was at its highest.
"The air was also very cool and slowed down the evaporation of the bubble, which ultimately leads to the popping," Mr Denton said.
"It was a real achievement because it had been twelve months or so since I made some sort of decision to do it."
Professor Roughan said bubbles were "mathematically interesting" because they are a "minimal shape" and they have a "minimum surface area because of the surface tension."

The Meaning of Money: Here's why some markets burst.

A Bubbles Artist Explains Economic Bubbles
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Denton, 48</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bubbles Artist Explains Economic Bubbles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guinness World Record</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockleys Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meaning of Money</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marty McBubble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Denton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ScientifiBubble Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Roughan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fulham Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Matt Roughan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
