<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408255394006276</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:34</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/life/columnists/glynis-traill-nash/paris-wanderings-turn-up-jewellery-inspired-by-literature-and-lingerie/news-story/d839e61eed90e3e8ffcb6a1e993570eb</url>
  <title>Jewels to flaunt, lingerie to feel</title>
  <content>
Following a four-week whirlwind of work then play in the French capital, Buzz is firmly ensconced behind her desk once more. And while the haute couture shows were as spectacular as expected, mooching about the side streets also threw up some unexpected discoveries.
One last-minute diversion down the rue Thorigny in the Marais offered up jewellery studio Beautiful Accident - like catnip to Buzz, who has a penchant for words and design. The studio specialises in delicate filigree designs, many based on passages and phrases from literature, but they also will make up custom pieces to your own specifications. Buzz plumped for an undulating flower ring made up of a passage from Le Petit Prince. Alas, they don't have an online store but they do have a Facebook page and Bruno Caby and his small team are very responsive to requests.
Buzz also always has one eye out for interesting lingerie stores, and two caused a detour. Yasmine Eslami trained in fashion in Paris before working for Vivienne Westwood for 10 years, which apparently sparked her passion for corsetry and underpinnings. She has a store near the Palais Royale but also an online store at yasmine-eslami.com that will offer some introduction to her sheer somethings. Second, swimwear label Naelie added lingerie to its line-up a few years ago, and some of its designs have a slightly sporty feel, particularly its black-trimmed designs (naelie.com).
Collaborations are the new black, apparently, but every now and then Buzz stumbles across one that makes sense, even in a slightly perverse kind of way. New Zealand accessories label Deadly Ponies, known for its practical and stylish leather goods (Buzz's crossbody bag is an off-duty essential), has partnered with Hasbro on a My Little Pony collection, launching tomorrow (deadlyponies.com). For sure, the two aesthetics seem worlds apart, even if the names collide on a single word, but Liam Bowden and Steve Boyd are nothing if not clever and have put together a collection that speaks to both brands.
The duo originally approached Hasbro in 2015 regarding another of their franchises but came to an agreement to work on a bigger collaboration around My Little Pony. "The inherent idea of this collaboration was to play on nostalgic feelings of childhood," Bowden tells Buzz. "After all, My Little Pony is universal and loved by millions of people for over three decades. For anyone who has experienced My Little Pony at some stage in their life, then this collection is for them."
There were, however, some guidelines to be followed. "The collection was designed in just over six months with our team leading discussions around new concepts, and Hasbro guiding us in what we could, should and couldn't do with their characters. For example, you can't ride them - they don't have a harness on them. If a Pony was shown to be flying in Equestria but our interpretation of that Pony didn't have wings, then that had to be addressed. It was a challenging but hugely rewarding design project for us and one that will prepare us for many future projects of this size, should we ever embark on them."
The International Woolmark Prize has been picking its regional winners of late in anticipation of the grand final early next year. The latest recipients are Bodice by Ruchika Sachdeva and Antar-Agni by Ujjawal Dubey, in the women's and men's divisions respectively, from India and the Middle East. Of his collection, Dubey says: "We wanted to play with the idea of creating comfort clothing for the new-age man who juggles several roles. Think banker by day, traveller by the weekend." Sachdeva, meanwhile, offered a collection that was equally influenced by the 18th-century costumes of the nautch dancing girls and men's tailoring. They join finalists from the US, Asia, British Isles and Europe. That just leaves Australia and New Zealand, whose winners will be announced at an event on August 14 in Sydney.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruchika Sachdeva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Isles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Petit Prince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Woolmark Prize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antar-Agni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yasmine Eslami</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naelie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sachdeva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beautiful Accident</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruno Caby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ujjawal Dubey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Equestria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Bowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thorigny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palais Royale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marais</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Pony</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vivienne Westwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasbro</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deadly Ponies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
