<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407761472755633</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/real-estate/commercial/sales/blackstone-bid-for-11bn-astro-japan-20170801-gxmtio</url>
  <title>Blackstone bid for $1.1b Astro Japan </title>
  <content>
Private equity giant Blackstone has launched a $436 million takeover bid for the ASX-listed
The offer at $7.18 per security values Astro's portfolio of 27 Japanese retail, office and residential properties at $1.1 billion - a 2.4 per cent premium to their most recent valuations - and at an attractive 13 per cent premium to the price securities last traded on Monday prior to the trust being placed in a trading halt on Tuesday morning.
Astro Japan security holders will vote on the proposal, which has been unanimously recommended by the Astro Group board in the absence of a superior proposal, on September 13. Fort Street are advising Astro.
Its the second approach made for the trust this year after Astro rejected an offer in March from private equity company Lone Star Funds to acquire all its assets at their book value.

The trust had also been eyeing up selling its securities into a Japanese REIT as the ASX-listed Galileo Japan Trust did last year, prior to delisting in November.

"We are pleased to be able to put this proposal to our security holders. The Blackstone proposal delivers Astro security holders with an asset premium that reflects the quality and scarcity of our underlying real estate portfolio, and net proceeds that provide cash liquidity at a material premium to recent trading levels" said Astro chairman Allan McDonald.
Security holders, which include Ellerston Capital, led by Ashok Jacob, the former boss of James Packer's private company, Consolidated Press Holdings, will receive the normal 21¢ per security half-year distribution as well as a 14¢ per security final distribution upon winding up of the trust by January 2018.
The offer from Blackstone, (advised by Macquarie), for Astro (advised by Fort Street) comes as global private equity groups like KKR, Carlyle and Blackstone circle opportunities in the Japanese market with its economy expected to begin growing this year.
"Japan had a relatively good year in 2016 and we see the momentum carrying into 2017 with growth projected at about 1.3 per cent. This is largely driven by a favourable external environment, which for Japan means higher exports. The benefits of the temporary fiscal support package, which was passed in August 2016, are also starting to play out and have helped economic growth," noted the IMF's Todd Schneider.

Astro Japan, the former Babcock & Brown Japan Property Trust, is the last of the ASX-listed trusts with a Japanese portfolio after the Galileo Japan Trust delisted in November last year following the sale of its portfolio to a new Japanese REIT.
The trust is managed by Japan- based Spring Investment Co with former global head of real estate at Babcock & Brown, Eric Lucas, its executive chairman.
It reported a statutory loss for the six months to December of $22.4 million, compared with a profit of $54.2 million in the prior corresponding period.
This loss was almost solely due to non-cash foreign exchange rate losses, with the yen falling against the Australian dollar between June 30 and December 31.

However, the underlying profit, which reflects the trading performance, rose 6.4 per cent to $18.3 million as it conversely benefited from a 9 per cent strengthening of the yen against the dollar compared with the previous reporting period to December 2015.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellerston Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMF's Todd Schneider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astro Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown Japan Property Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KKR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consolidated Press Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Investment Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Babcock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Lucas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashok Jacob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fort Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Packer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lone Star Funds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese REIT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astros</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackstone</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galileo Japan Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astro Japan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January, 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed Galileo Japan Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
