<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408160904723380</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/lifestyle-choice-key-to-micklehams-booming-property-prices/news-story/4cf0ac5fca44671858e73c0fa6c1685b</url>
  <title>Mickleham property prices booming</title>
  <content>
MICKLEHAM'S housing boom is paying off with the suburb leading the property price growth in Hume.
Newly released Victorian Valuer-General statistics show the suburb's median house price increased 18 per cent from $380,000 to $447,500 last year.
Ray White Glenroy director Ziya Koksal said buyers were turning to Mickleham because they could secure big blocks of land at affordable prices.
"It comes down to the lifestyle it offers and a lot of builders and tradies are moving up that way because of the land size," he said.
"People are seeing the value for money."
Mr Koksal said prices would continue to rise with five estates being developed in Mickleham with more schools, a city centre and a business park in the pipeline.
Gladstone Park's median property value jumped 14 per cent to $525,000.
Barry Plant Gladstone Park sales agent Daniel Fahd said f amilies and first-home buyers were flocking to the suburb, with the latter group's confidence on the rise after the July 1 axing of stamp duty for first-home purchases up to $600,000 and reductions for homes up to $750,000.
"Around 65 per cent of our homebuyers are first-home buyers," Mr Fahd said.
"We just sold a Gladstone Park property at 11 Leura Court to a first-home buyer for $627,000.
"We'd been dealing with them for three to four months and they had 100 per cent more confidence after July 1, outbidding an investor for this house."
Tracking close behind Gladstone Park were Broadmeadows and Tullamarine, where the median house price has soared 100 per cent over the past decade, capped off with a 12 per cent rise last year to $413,500 and $530,000 respectively.
Coolaroo, Jacana and Campbellfield were all up 12 per cent to $340,000, $419,500, and $420,000 respectively. The most expensive suburb was Attwood with a $655,000 median asking price, with Coolaroo the cheapest.
Mr Koksal said even he was surprised by the amount of growth across Hume in such a short period of time.
"We never expected that growth but it was a long time coming," he said.
Victorian Valuer-General Robert Marsh said the state's median house value had risent 73 per cent - from $300,000 to $520,000 - between 2006 and 2016.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leura Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Glenroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tullamarine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Plant Gladstone Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolaroo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hume</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Fahd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mickleham</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fahd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Valuer-General Robert Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Valuer-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbellfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ziya Koksal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Koksal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
