<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408233919169326</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/heritagelisted-bells-plumbers-shop-gutted-by-suspicious-fire/news-story/aa34112106e9aa2148a90afbb48f1f90</url>
  <title>Heritage-listed building gutted by fire</title>
  <content>
A HERITAGE-LISTED derelict building has been extensively damaged by a fire that's thought to have been deliberately lit inside the ageing structure.
Emergency services were called to the site of the 133-year-old Bells
Plumbers Shop at College Park about 9.15pm on Tuesday after a neighbour reported seeing smoke and flames from the empty building.
Staff at a hotel across the road from the shop said they could see flames coming from the roof as the fire moved through the vacant building.
MFS station officer Scott Baxter said crews were initially hampered because the floor of the building had been torn up for renovations.
Making their way across the exposed beams MFS personnel wearing breathing apparatus established the building was vacant and contained the fire to the structure.
The heavily graffitied external walls of the building contained the fire with little external damage obvious.
Initial reports indicate the fire was started with floor boards torn up and set alight.
Crime scene units and detectives attended the scene of the fire after it had been contained.
The MFS estimate $15,000 worth of damage had been caused in the fire, which took under half an hour to fully extinguish.
Last year the building was the subject of athat saw former racing car champion Philip Leslie March charged and found guilty of neglecting a heritage-listed building.
He was the first person to be charged under the Heritage Places Act.
Built by former premier John Colton in 1883, Bells Plumber Shop was granted the highest level of heritage protection in 1985 and is recognised as an example of Victorian-era shop front and dwelling.
Mr March and Hamilton Hill bought the building from the Bell family in 1997.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Colton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heritage-listed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bells Plumber Shop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>College Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Leslie March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Baxter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heritage Places Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian-era</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
