<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408405717864841</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4825704/putting-gold-in-the-cellar/?cs=2373</url>
  <title>Putting gold in the cellar</title>
  <content>
GOLDEN WIN: Tyrrell's managing director Bruce Tyrrell and daughter Jane with the 2011 Stevens Semillon.

OF the Hunter producers' wines that last week won three 2017 KPMG Sydney Royal Wine Show trophies and 15 gold medals, 13 are currently available.
The show attracted 2100 entries from 352 producers from NSW, Victoria, South Australia, Western Australia, the ACT and Tasmania. In four days of judging by a panel headed by former Hunter winemaker Samantha Connew, more than 11,000 glasses of wine were poured and assessed.
The Tyrrell's family wine company's $80-a-bottle 2011 Stevens Semillon won the Lindeman Trophy for the best mature white and the David Clarke Trophy for the best semillon. It also notched up a 97-point top gold medal in the 2015 and older semillon class and is currently available only at the Broke Rd, Pokolbin, cellar door and on tyrrells.com.au.
The wine comes from prized vineyards first planted in 1911 by the Stevens family, Pokolbin neighbours of the Tyrrells, who since 1993 have taken the grapes under a handshake deal.
The Tyrrell's 2012 Vat 47 Chardonnay was awarded the James Busby Trophy for the best NSW wine, winning the trophy for the third consecutive year.
The 2013 Vat 47 Chardonnay took the 96-point top gold in the 2014 and older chardonnay class and both wines can be bought for $70 a bottle at tyrrells.com.au, the cellar door and some bottle shops.
Tyrrell's won a fourth gold medal with the $80 2017 Vat 1 Semillon, which is only available at cellar door and tyrrells.com.au.
Brokenwood also claimed four Sydney gold medals with its flagship 2007 and 2011 ILR Reserve Semillon whites (2015 and older semillon class), the Beechworth-sourced 2016 Indigo Vineyard Chardonnay and 2016 Beechworth Sangiovese.
The 2007 ILR only exists in museum stocks but the 2011 IRL will soon be available at $75 a bottle in wine stores, at the McDonalds Rd, Pokolbin, cellar door and on brokenwood.com.au.
The $55 2016 Indigo chardonnay (2016 chardonnay class), reviewed below, and the $36 2016 sangiovese (2016 other red varietals class) are both available at cellar door and on brokenwood.com.au.
Richard Friend and John Hindman's wonderful little Pokolbin Estate vineyard, in McDonalds Rd, Pokolbin, once again confounded the nay-sayers by winning a Sydney gold medal with its 2007 Riesling. It is the only Hunter planting of riesling - a variety deemed unsuited to the Hunter.
The wine, made by long-time contract winemaker Andrew Thomas, won gold in the 2015 and older riesling class and is available in limited quantities at the cellar door and pokolbinestate.com.au.
Grapes from Pokolbin Estate also produced the $40 Andrew Thomas 2015 Dam Block Shiraz that won gold in the 2015 shiraz class.
Andrew also won 2015 shiraz class gold with his $35 2015 Sweetwater Shiraz and both reds are at the cellar door at Tuscany Wine Estate on the corner of Hermitage Rd and Mistletoe Lane, Pokolbin, and on thomaswines.com.au.
Bimbadgen Estate and the iconic Tulloch brand each won two Sydney gold medals.
The $30 Tulloch 2017 Julia Limited Release Semillon (2017 semillon class) and the $26 2016 Cellar Release Hilltops Barbera (2016 other red varieties class) can be bought at the Tulloch cellar door on the corner of De Beyers and McDonalds roads, Pokolbin, on tulloch.com.au and in wine stores.
The Bimbadgen gold medals were won by the as-yet unreleased 2014 Hunter Valley Signature Semillon (2015 and older semillon class) and the 2013 Hunter Valley Signature Chardonnay (2014 and older chardonnay class), which is available at $60 on bimbadgen.com.au, at the 790 McDonalds Road, Pokolbin, winery and in bottle shops.
The star of the Sydney show was the Rieslingfreak 2017 No 3 Clare Valley, which won a remarkable five trophies - the best wine of the show, the best wine exhibited in capital city wine shows in the past 12 months and trophies for the best white wine, best riesling and best young white.
It is rare for one wine to take out so many trophies and the last time a riesling was Sydney Wine Show's best wine was in 2003.
The wines was made by South Australian winemaker John Hughes, who suffers from cerebral palsy and gained wide public esteem in 2011 after he exited the Masterchef TEN network television cooking show in spectacular and despairing fashion.
John Hughes only established his small Rieslingfreak operation in 2009 and the brand originated from the nickname his fellow Adelaide University winemaking course classmates gave him because of his passion for riesling.

"My love for riesling comes from its variety and diversity, being able to go from sparkling to fortified and dry to sweet," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrrell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beechworth-sourced 2016 Indigo Vineyard Chardonnay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bimbadgen Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beechworth Sangiovese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tulloch 2017 Julia Limited Release Semillon (2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ILR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Friend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonalds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brokenwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hindman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuscany Wine Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweetwater Shiraz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vat 1 Semillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tulloch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broke Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hermitage Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hughes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bimbadgen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonalds Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Tyrrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Beyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Valley Signature Chardonnay (2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Wine Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Valley Signature Semillon (2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterchef TEN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mistletoe Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindeman Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Thomas 2015 Dam Block Shiraz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cellar Release Hilltops Barbera (2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pokolbin</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ILR Reserve Semillon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GOLDEN WIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vat 47 Chardonnay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stevens Semillon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Clarke Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrrell's 2012 Vat 47 Chardonnay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rieslingfreak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPMG Sydney Royal Wine Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riesling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Busby Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonalds Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Connew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rieslingfreak 2017 No 3 Clare Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pokolbin Estate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
