<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408410012832213</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/china-df-31ag-icbm-rollout-parade-2017-7</url>
  <title>Watch China debut an ICBM that can hit the US with multiple nuclear warheads</title>
  <content>
At a parade touting  on the 90th anniversary of the founding of the People's Liberation Army, China rolled out it's newest intercontinental ballistic missile, the DF-31AG.

Unlike the DF-31 before it, the DF-31AG boasts a range extended to above 6,800 miles, which means that most of the continental US is in range, .

Additionally, the DF-31AG can carry multiple nuclear warheads, or even a conventional warhead.

As Zhou Chenming, a military observer based in Beijing, : "We're not in the cold war anymore, extremely powerful weapons like nuclear missiles are no longer the mainstream. We'll still keep our nuclear strength, but when we face some regular threats we don't need to use nuclear warheads to attack, but will resort to some conventional warheads instead."

Another upgrade to the survivability and lethality of the missile comes from the truck that carries it. Like the DF-31, it's mobile and therefore can evade attacking forces, hide, and fire from surprising locations. But unlike the previous model, the DF-31AG can actually go off road, further complicating any plans to neutralise China's nuclear might.

Watch the rollout of the DF-31AG below:

China's new DF-31AG intercontinental missiles make public debut at military parade in Zhurihe base in Inner Mongolia
- People's Daily,China (@PDChina)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhou Chenming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DF-31AG</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People's Liberation Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DF-31</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watch China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhurihe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PDChina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inner Mongolia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICBM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
