<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407937566418793</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/jb-hifi-anchored-asset-key-test-for-market-20170801-gxn5rt</url>
  <title>JB HI-Fi anchored asset key test for market  </title>
  <content>
The Zone Oxley in Brisbane's south, once owned by the failed WOW Sight and Sound, will be offered for sale in what will be a key test of confidence in its anchor retail tenant JB Hi-Fi.
Market observers expect the property could fetch anywhere between $30 million to $40 million given comparable transactions.
Large format retail has seen some significant trades this year with the listed Aventus Property Group testing its investors' faith, paying $436 million  representing a record yield for the bulky goods sector of 5.6 per cent.
Local private owners of The Zone have appointed JLL directors of retail investments Jacob Swan and Sam Hatcher to market the property.

In a statement JLL said: "The majority of the tenants within the centre are on their second-lease terms, highlighting their long-term support, performance and commitment to the centre."

The Zone Oxley is anchored by a 1958sq m JB Hi-Fi and a 1980sq m lease to US clothing company TK Maxx as well as five mini-majors and parking for 226 cars.
The property sits within the prime, metro-Brisbane Large Format Retail precinct, which includes The Good Guys, Bunnings Warehouse, Harvey Norman, Officeworks, Super Amart Furniture, Super Cheap Auto and First Choice Liquor.
"Large-format retail market fundamentals have been well supported by a strong rebound in household goods spending and very limited supply of floor space in recent years," JLL's Sam Hatcher said.
"Large-format retail has been re-rated in 2016 and 2017 reflecting the improvement in leasing conditions and the attractive yield spread relative to more traditional shopping centres - such as sub-regional shopping and neighbourhood - which have recorded significant yield compression."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Large Format Retail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JLL's Sam Hatcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Officeworks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Good Guys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zone Oxley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JLL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aventus Property Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Cheap Auto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WOW Sight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Hatcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Hi-Fi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Swan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey Norman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TK Maxx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Amart Furniture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings Warehouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Choice Liquor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
