<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408173789625761</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/wells-st-revamp-cost-55m-more-than-2m-over-budget/news-story/e1b828ed5d98440ae3fe4dcffca66db8</url>
  <title>Council faces $2m works blowout</title>
  <content>
THE Wells St redevelopment project blew its budget by more than $2 million.
Council figures, seen by Leader, show the $3.4 million revamp ballooned to almost $5.5 million.
Frankston chief executive Dennis Hovenden said the extra money was spent on "necessary remedial works and an increased project scope".

HAVE YOUR SAY: What do you think about the Wells St redevelopment? Tell us below.
Significant changes including tearing up pavers and replacing them during to the project added to the blowout.
Mr Hovenden said the extra money was sourced by "reprioritising the capital works budget".
Veteran Cr Glenn Aitken, who oversaw the redevelopment, said nightworks done to minimise disruption, changes to the project scope and issues due to services being in unexpected locations, were behind the cost overrun. He said the project still represented good value for money for ratepayers.
"Council changed the scope of the works. It's not a blowout. It's a decision (of the council)," he said.
Leader revealed last October that street furniture for the project alone cost $680,000.
There are 50 pieces of street furniture consisting of 18 stainless-steel planter boxes at $8670 each, 11 public seats at $14,000 each, four circular seats at $12,820 and 17 street lights at $19,000 each.
Council officials told Leader they would not be making public an audit of the project, which was marked by delays that infuriated traders.
Frankston Labor MP Paul Edbrooke said not releasing the report made it look like the council had "something to hide".
"Frankston ratepayers voted these councillors in on promises of transparency and while they refuse to make this audit public their credibility is in question," he said.
Mr Hovenden said the Wells St project had transformed the heart of Frankston into a unique tree-lined avenue with sculptural furniture to admire.
"A recent business occupancy survey in Frankston's city centre found vacancy rates have decreased from 14.06 per cent in 2014 prior to the Wells St redevelopment to a current low of 6.25 per cent with works completed," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hovenden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Hovenden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Glenn Aitken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston Labor MP Paul Edbrooke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wells St</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
