<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408500207147341</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/under-armour-stock-price-is-plunging-after-disappointing-earnings-2017-8</url>
  <title>Under Armour is plunging after disappointing earnings</title>
  <content>
is tanking after its earnings report.

The clothing company , or $US0.03 per share. That's an improvement over last year, when the company announced a loss of $US0.12 per share.

Under Armour Class C shares are down 6.29% in early trading on Tuesday after releasing earnings before the bell. The company's revenue rose 8.7% to $US1.09 billion, which is

Increased competition from Nike and Adidas are hurting sales at Under Armour. The company is  with changing customer demands.

During the earnings release, Under Armour detailed its plan to restructure its business.

"As we stand up our category management structure within a consumer-led approach, we intend to meaningfully increase our go-to-market speed and amplify our digital capabilities," .

The company hopes to shift from a primarily US-based apparel company to a global apparel, footwear, and accessories brand.

However, not all investors are pessimistic about the stock despite its fall.

"We did not expect a great quarter, and what we got was a mixed bag," Randal Konik, an analyst at Jefferies, said in a note to clients. "We see minimal downside from here and much more significant upside potential, esp. as compares ease and Curry 4, int'l growth kicks in."

Konik set a price target of $US28.00, 63% higher than the current price of the stock.

"UAA is one of the few brands that matter in the athletic space. It has significant oppty to scale N.A., footwear, int'l, women's, and lifestyle LT. With valuation compressed and overly-negative sentiment, we see a buying oppty with significant upside," Konik said.

Under Armour is down 33.46% this year.  and .

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curry 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US28.00</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UAA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US0.12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US0.03</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jefferies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Konik</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.09</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adidas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randal Konik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armour Class C</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
