<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407671278440596</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/sport/soccer/arsenal-owner-launches-biggame-hunting-channel-motv-in-australia-20170801-gxn2w3.html</url>
  <title>Arsenal owner launches big-game hunting channel MOTV in Australia</title>
  <content>
Barely a fortnight after Premier League giants Arsenal won over Australian fans on their tour down under, the Gunners' owner is about to deliver something far less palatable to these shores. 
American billionaire and Arsenal owner Stan Kroenke is planning to go global with his US-based My Outdoor TV channel, which can be viewed online via an app. The channel features, among other things, the hunting of big game in Africa and Kroenke plans to market it to an international audience, specifically earmarking Australia, alongside Britain, New Zealand and South Africa.

Up Next

Plays of the Week

01:59

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Arsenal too good for Sydney FC

New signing Alexandre Lacazette scored on his Arsenal debut as the north London club completed a 2-0 win over Sydney FC at ANZ Stadium.

The channel has caused outrage among conservationists and animal-welfare groups  due to the programs devoted to "trophy hunts" for safari animals, such as elephant and lions.  
A spokesman for the MOTV channel, Simon Barr, told the BBC it would only screen "ethical hunts" but warned it would not censor what could be graphic footage of animals being killed for sport. 

"MOTV will present ethical, fair-chase hunting and as long as it's legal it will be on there," Barr said. "If you like hunting elephants, there will be legal elephant hunts, ethical elephant hunts, shown in that context."
"I'm sure people won't like all the content on MOTV, but it won't be censored. On every film, there's an explanation of what hunting does for conservation and the local community."

British-based animal welfare group, League Against Cruel Sports, said Kroenke was "out of touch" with public opinion, with spokesman Chris Pitt telling the BBC:

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"We're not in the old days when hunters went out to bag an elephant and put its head on the wall. So for someone in a position like Mr Kroenke to launch a channel that's so out of touch with what people want is an own goal to say the least.
"The reality of trophy hunting is that a lot, if not most, of these animals will not be killed cleanly, they will suffer long painful deaths - and so on the welfare argument alone, hunting like this should be banned."
The impending launch of MOTV comes two years after Australian Test cricketer Glenn McGrath was embroiled in controversy around big-game hunting when photographs emerged of him in Zimbabwe . 
Kroenke's web channel is part of a huge sporting empire, owned by the Denver-based Kroenke Sports and Entertainment, which also owns Arsenal, MLS franchise Colorado Rapids and NFL team Los Angeles Rams.
There have been calls for boycotts of those sporting franchises due to the links with MOTV.    
Arsenal toured Australia last month, playing games against Sydney FC and Western Sydney Wanderers. They attracted a combined attendance of more than 160,000 over the two games in what was the Gunners' first tour of Australia in more than 40 years. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Barr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colorado Rapids</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MLS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver-based Kroenke Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MOTV</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Pitts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsenal</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandre Lacazette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stan Kroenke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based My Outdoor TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney Wanderers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kroenke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kroenke</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League Against Cruel Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Rams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zimbabwe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
