<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407804422429637</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/a-league/western-sydney-wanderers-striker-oriol-riera-scores-ffa-cup-winner-against-wellington-phoenix/news-story/eb5d38a422751bed604dee8dc458e3b5</url>
  <title>Marquee man ensures Wanderers progress</title>
  <content>
AFTER 119 minutes of pain came a moment from Spain that sent the Wanderers into the last 16 of the FFA Cup.
A header from marquee striker Oriol Riera in the last seconds of extra time edged Wellington Phoenix, just as a dour, lumpen cup tie had seemed certain to go the lottery of a penalty shoot out.
Indisputably Western Sydney were the better side, but threw away what chances they had until Riera's dramatic late intervention. Roley Bonevacia's corner was met with an almost apologetic jump from the Spaniard, but his header went in off the post to win the tie.
It's fair to say that the all-A-League ties in the FFA Cup lack the romance of the smaller teams through the competition, and in August they also often lack finesse. It might be understandable rustiness, more than two months out from the start of the season proper, but as in this game it also can make for a laboured contest.
For Wellington that was amplified by the lack of half a dozen first teamers through injury, and Wanderers had an undoubted edge in terms of quality. They were helped by the inclusion of new faces expected to play big roles this season, from Bonevacia and Chris Herd to Michael Thwaite. Though Spanish winger Alvaro Cejudo is a few weeks off his first action, compatriot striker Riera's second appearance reinforced initial impressions that he has excellent technique and awareness, and twice he set up Bonevacia for chances before halftime.
The first was the most elegant, dropping deep then lifting a perfectly weighted pass over the Phoenix defence for his teammate, but Bonevacia's finish on the run went wide. Then the same player struck a powerful shot too high after Oriol's chest-down, as the Wanderers failed to capitalise on their superiority.
Kearyn Baccus followed suit, scuffing his shot from inside the box after surging into it with a powerful run, though Baccus's influence on the game generally was assured. Alongside Herd, who brings EPL experience, it will be a strong midfield base for the Wanderers this season.
The one hangover from last season was a profligacy with the chances they created. Captain Robert Cornthwaite was denied the first goal of the season thanks a reflex save from Lewis Italiano in the Phoenix goal, tipping away the defender's volley, but Steven Lustica shot over when played in by the substitute Abraham Majok.
From Wellington there had been industry and organisation, but little sense of a threat - until the second last minute, when Alex Rufer drove an inviting chance over the bar from Tinashe Marowa's lay-off.
Tom Doyle was lucky not to see red for an ungly, scything challenge on Majok, and the only downside for Wanderers was an ankle injury that left Brendon Hamill limping heavily.
But for all the lack of inspiration, the Wanderers are off to a winning start. The quality, presumably, will rise quickly from here.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spaniards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Rufer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kearyn Baccus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Lustica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alvaro Cejudo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Italiano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Herd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riera</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oriol Riera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinashe Marowa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington Phoenix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanderers</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonevacia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roley Bonevacia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Thwaite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baccus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Majok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abraham Majok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oriol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Hamill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Cornthwaite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
