<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408190969495292</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/cbd/the-biggest-loser-from-network-tens-political-donations-last-year-was--ten-20170801-gxmr13.html</url>
  <title>The biggest loser from Network Ten's political donations last year was - Ten </title>
  <content>
﻿It's good to know that, with financial collapse looming, the political priorities of Paul Anderson's Network Ten were as incoherent as its TV programming. 
The latest amendment to its political donations disclosure reveals that the failed broadcaster did not actually waste $25,000 in May last year donating to the Labor Party's federal division. 

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

There's trouble with trusts

While Labor wants to crack down on tax dodging through trusts, the government says they're a legitimate way to structure a business.

This disclosure was an administrative error, CBD was told.
And as Anderson made clear, one of the financial torpedoes that could (and did) sink the network, was the broadcast licence fees.Photo: Andrew Meares
Only Malcolm Turnbull's Liberals could fix that. And they did, belatedly, lifting its bottom line to the tune of $22 million last financial year.
Unfortunately, the amendments to Ten's political donations reveal that the broadcaster's $40,000 donation to the Liberals was not actually made to Turnbull's team. It was made to the party's NSW division. 

And as far as CBD can tell, not a cent was donated to the party which is holding up Australia's media merger orgy: Pauline Hanson's One Nation. 

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But that may have been a conscious decision by Ten's management to ensure that it does not end up in the hands of former executive chairman, Lachlan Murdoch, and the man who has now lost more money on television networks than Alan Bond - WIN's Bruce Gordon. The Biggest LoserPhoto: Ten
D Rex

Ten was not the only corporate which has been fiddling with its donations disclosures.
Rural airline operator Regional Express updated its donations register recently - erasing $50,000 donations to each of the federal Labor, Liberal and National parties last year. Photo: Andrew Taylor
Nothing untoward here, either.
REX, which features John Sharp - the former National Party MP and John Howard's transport minister - as its deputy chairman, was merely updating the register on which parties had actually used the $50,000of airline services it offered them, gratis.
Labor and the Nationals made a decent dent on the free fares while Turnbull's Liberals were too busy fighting with each other to use so much as a cent of the free travel in regional Australia. ﻿﻿
Falling Findex 

Legendary US private equity group Kohlberg Kravis Roberts (KKR) is reportedly trying to sell out of its troubled investment in Aussie financial group, the Spiro Paule-founded Findex. 
Unfortunately, it looks like the for sale sign is up just as Findex's troubles with ASIC are growing. 
Last October ASIC pinged Findex with a $21,600 fine for potentially misleading advertising.
On Monday ASIC came back with another serve, getting an enforceable undertaking from group subsidiary Financial Index Australia (FIA) after the regulator found it had moved clients into a more expensive FIA branded product "without sufficient explanation or justification".
"ASIC will intervene where it finds the quality of advice provided by advisers, and the supervision of those advisers by the licensee to be lacking," said ASIC's deputy chairman Peter Kell.
The only question is whether even more trouble is on the way given Paule's court action last month seeking access to documents from a former employee. ASIC intervened in the dispute, claiming "public interest immunity" in relation to documents seized from the ex-employee.
It's the sort of publicity that you can't buy, or, sell in the case of KKR. 
Isentia 

Isentia, the company previously known as Media Monitors, torched a lot of dough on its advertorial gamble, King Content.
Less than two years after buying the commercial content provider Isentia wrote off the entire $38 million it ended up paying for the business. It also closed the brand, along with two of its overseas offices.  
What CBD wanted to know is, where does this leave King Content's boss - Bauer Media's former CEO, Matt Stanton - who joined in February this year.  
CBD was told that any disclosure on Matt's future is part of the media blackout until the announcement of Isentia's financial results in a few weeks ... which doesn't sound promising for Stanton. 
Runs on board 

Departing Wesfarmers boss, Richard James Barr Goyder, took his seat on the Woodside Petroleum board on Tuesday, ahead of taking the chair from fellow Wesfarmers alumni, Michael Chaney, next year. 
And it's good to see Goyder has not wasted time picking up shares in his new shop. 
His initial director's interest notice reported he already has more than 8000 shares to his name. Let's hope he acquired the stock recently, and not at its $33 peaks in April and May. 
Energy stocks have not fared well since Malcolm Turnbull announced the quasi-nationalisation of our natural gas resources and the stock is now below the $30 mark. 
Follow CBD on . Got a tip? 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spiro Paule-founded Findex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodside Petroleum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Content</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Chaney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Media Monitors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Network Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kohlberg Kravis Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D Rex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WIN's Bruce Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isentia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biggest LoserPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KKR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paule</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Express</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull's Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Kell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Bond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull's Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson's One Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Stanton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wesfarmers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday ASIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Anderson's Network Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard James Barr Goyder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Sharp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Index Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Findex</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bauer Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October ASIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goyder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
