<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408362768191005</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/anthony-scaramucci-blasted-reince-priebus-in-an-email-but-he-was-actually-replying-to-an-internet-troll/news-story/fc637526ffda627b13d6fb972010070c</url>
  <title>Mooch caught out in email blast</title>
  <content>
US PRESIDENT Donald Trump's ousted communications director had an epic email clash with someone he thought was arch-enemy Reince Priebus - but it was just some internet troll.
The reports that Anthony Scaramucci received an email from the fake Priebus on Saturday - one day after the real White House chief of staff resigned, according to CNN.
"At no stage have you acted in a way that's even remotely classy, yet you believe that's the standard by which everyone should behave towards you?" read the email to Scaramucci from a "mail.com" account.
Scaramucci, apparently unaware the email was a hoax, responded with indignation.
"You know what you did. We all do. Even today. But rest assured we were prepared. A Man would apologise," Scaramucci wrote.
The prankster, now aware that he had deceived the beleaguered Scaramucci, went in for the kill.
"I can't believe you are questioning my ethics! The so called 'Mooch', who can't even manage his first week in the White House without leaving upset in his wake," the fake Priebus wrote. "I have nothing to apologise for."

Scaramucci shot back with a veiled threat to destroy Priebus Shakespearean-style.
"Read Shakespeare. Particularly Othello. You are right there. My family is fine by the way and will thrive. I know what you did. No more replies from me," the actual Scaramucci.
Othello is a tragedy in which the main character is tricked into killing his wife Desdemona after his confidante convinces him that she has been unfaithful.
Also fooled by the email prank was Homeland Security Adviser Tom Bossert, former Utah governor Jon Huntsman, and Eric Trump.
This article originally appeared in the
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homeland Security Adviser Tom Bossert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desdemona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Huntsman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Othello</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus Shakespearean-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
