<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408796559897121</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/microsoft-surface-plus-payment-plan-2017-8</url>
  <title>Microsoft is borrowing an idea from Apple to get more people on its Surface PCs</title>
  <content>
Today, Microsoft unveils  - a new payment plan program for purchasers of the Microsoft Surface line of laptops and desktop PCs.

The gist of the program is that, when you buy any Surface, you'll have the option to enroll in a 24-month repayment plan at 0% interest. Every 18 months, you'll have the option to trade in your Surface for the latest and greatest model. Microsoft is hyping the plan as perfect for back-to-school PC buyers.

The plan encompasses , including the , the , the  high-end laptop, and the new student-focused .

You can enroll in Surface Plus from Microsoft's online store, or at the physical Microsoft Stores. As an added benefit, Surface Plus will also get you a 30-day, no-questions-asked return policy on your Surface, as well as a year of free in-store technical support.

It's very similar to the , which Apple has been operating since 2015. It's also much like AT&T Next or .

Notably, Microsoft is also extending the Surface Plus program into businesses: In addition to the Surface laptops and desktops, business customers will also have the option to finance the . For an extra $US8.25 per device per month, Surface Plus business buyers will also get the Office 365 suite.

Microsoft's Surface laptops are extremely choice, but they also carry a premium. With , Microsoft is getting creative in ways to make the Surface more affordable - and to make students and individual buyers pause before buying a new Apple Mac.

Get the latest Microsoft stock price

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US8.25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office 365</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft's Surface</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple's Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surface Plus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T Next</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft Store</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surface PCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
