<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409183106961001</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/nintendo-snes-classic-edition-preorders-2017-8</url>
  <title>You can finally buy Nintendo's new $80 mini Super Nintendo later this month</title>
  <content>
Ever since Nintendo announced the SNES Classic Edition, fans have been frantically looking for a chance to reserve one.

It's easy to understand why:  that works with modern televisions, yet it costs just $US80 and comes with 21 games packed in. Better yet: One of those games is the never-before-released "Star Fox 2." When the console launches in September, demand is expected to be very high.

Thus, potential buyers have been anxiously anticipating the ability to pre-order the system. It looks like they will have the chance come late August, when Nintendo says various retailers will open up pre-orders. Nintendo announced as much :

"We appreciate the incredible anticipation that exists for the Super Nintendo Entertainment System: Super NES Classic Edition system, and can confirm that it will be made available for pre-order by various retailers late this month. A significant amount of additional systems will be shipped to stores for launch day, and throughout the balance of the calendar year."

It's not clear which retailers that will be just yet, but we expect the usual suspects like Amazon, Walmart, Best Buy, and GameStop.

Of note, Nintendo says the console will be shipped "throughout the balance of the calendar year." That means the SNES Classic Edition is already a limited-edition product; it will end its production run when 2017 ends, just like the NES Classic Edition before it.

The SNES Classic Edition otherwise launches on September 29, and will be available through the end of the year - if you can find one.

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Fox™ 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Nintendo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NES Classic Edition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super NES Classic Edition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Nintendo Entertainment System</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walmart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SNES Classic Edition</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Buy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gamestop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
