<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408019170799200</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/venezuelan-opposition-leaders-taken-into-custody-amid-fears-of-wider-crackdowns-20170801-gxnf7f.html</url>
  <title>Venezuelan opposition leaders taken into custody amid fears of wider crackdowns</title>
  <content>
Caracas: Masked security forces staged midnight raids on Tuesday to haul away two leading Venezuelan opposition leaders already under house arrest, possibly signalling an expanded crackdown on dissent after widely denounced elections to boost the authoritarian government.
The moves against Leopoldo Lopez and Antonio Ledezma could intensify the international fallout after Sunday's election that created a new super congress stocked with backers of the government of President Nicolas Maduro.Photo: AP
The vote was decried as fraud by the opposition and prompted the Trump administration on Monday to slap sanctions on Maduro. In a video posted online by Ledezma's wife, security forces are shown apparently dragging the opposition leader from the glass doors of a building.
"They're taking Ledezma!" another voice shouts in the background. A woman screams: "dictatorship! dictatorship!"

Both men were taken to Ramo Verde military prison south-west of Caracas, aides and family members said.
After the election results were announced on Sunday, Maduro gave a bellicose victory speech on national television that included threats to jail political leaders encouraging protests. Maduro also said a "truth commission" would be created to "take parliamentary immunity from the legislators who shouldn't have it."

Authorities only last month released Lopez, 46, into house arrest after nearly three-and-a-half years behind bars. At the time, the government called the decision a humanitarian gesture, citing his poor health, though supporters saw the move as an attempt to reduce international pressure.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In a video posted on Twitter by Lilian Tintori, Lopez's wife, masked security forces in riot gear can be seen in front of what appears to be the family's house, leading a man from the door and putting him in an official car.Photo: AP
"They just took Leopoldo from home," Tintori tweeted. "We don't know where he is or where they took him. Maduro is responsible if something happens."
Venezuela's most prominent political prisoner and former mayor of a district in Caracas, Lopez was arrested in early 2014 and handed a 13-year jail term. He became a symbol of resistance for opponents of the government, his portrait printed in bright colours on the T-shirts and flags of protesters who chant "Free Leopoldo!"
Roland Carreno, a senior member of Lopez's party, confirmed on Twitter that Lopez had been taken to the Ramo Verde prison.
Also taken into government custody early on Tuesday was Ledezma, former mayor of Caracas. His wife, Mitzy Capriles de Ledezma, posted a video on Twitter showing a dramatic melee as authorities entered their home and hustling him away.

Mitzy. Por la fuerza a golpes y empujones se llevan a Antonio de nuestra casa. Hacemos responsable al regimen por su vida e integridad!!!

"What's happening, my friend," a woman in her pyjamas asks a squad of masked, uninformed men in her house. The men appear to be from the government's Bolivarian Intelligence Service.
Ledezma's wife said her husband had posted a Twitter video on Monday, despite being under house arrest, and suggested that may one reason he was hauled away.

Former mayor Antonio Ledezma has also been seized.  Photo: AP

In the video, Ledezma, 62, with a Venezuelan flag in the background, called the constituent assembly vote a fraud, criticised the armed forces and rejected the government-controlled supreme court. He also critiqued the opposition for its lack of strategy.
Lopez last week had also released a video on Twitter, encouraging people to keep fighting and reject Sunday's vote.
"One more time Nicolas Maduro shows off his dictator-like qualities," said Mitzy Capriles de Ledezma. She insisted the move smacked of desperation, saying "the fact that Antonio is again in prison means Maduro knows he's on his way out."
Early on Tuesday, Ledezma's daughter, Oriette Ledezma, issued a video statement saying her father was "kidnapped" by Maduro's forces.

Mitzy. Nuestra hija Oriette denuncia otra cobardia contra Antonio. Se lo llevaron y no sabemos donde esta. Responsabilizamos al regimen.

"He was in his pyjamas," she said. "We don't now where they took him. A group of masked men in camouflage took him. We make the regime responsible for his life and physical integrity."
She added, "this is for Venezuela and the rest of the world because they keep violating the human rights."
She said that Ledezma was also taken to the Ramo Verde prison.
"I can say his morale is intact," Oriette Ledezma said. "But we don't know about his physical state. We're not scared. It's more indignation."
Ledezma was previously arrested in December 2015. Maduro at the time said he was part of a conspiracy to overthrow the government. In May of that year, he was remitted to house arrest after receiving surgery for a hernia.
In 2013, Ledezma, from the Alianza Bravo Pueblo party, was re-elected as mayor. In January 2017, Maduro created a higher executive post in the city, "Chief the greater state of Caracas", and named a pro-government official to the job.
Washington Post
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oriette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alianza Bravo Pueblo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nuestra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Ledezma</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Nicolas Maduro.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramo Verde</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledezma</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leopoldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roland Carreno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Responsabilizamos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hacemos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Free Leopoldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lilian Tintori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oriette Ledezma</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledezma, 62</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitzy Capriles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lopez</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitzy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leopoldo Lopez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolivarian Intelligence Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tintori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
