<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408276868843289</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4827479/cultural-change-gets-down-to-respect/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Cultural change gets down to respect</title>
  <content>
THERE are traditions that are worth saving, and traditions that need to be looked at with fresh eyes and different perspectives.

That is the key message that needs to be taken from a video about a University of Newcastle student residence party.

Teds is Edwards Hall, the university's oldest residence and home to 383 students.

No doubt it has been traditional for students in the past to drink until they pass out, and while the worst some students might experience is a hangover the next day, for others such events might end with much more serious consequences.

The ubiquitous nature of cameras allows us to view this tradition with fresh eyes.

In the cold light of day film of a young woman so drunk she doesn't respond gives a perspective that's probably not seen by many as the event actually happens - and that is how very vulnerable she is.

Apparently that view was missed by whoever posted that video as a form of advertisement to a party, which is why the Human Rights Commission report on a survey of 31,000 students across 39 Australian universities is important.

If students on campus have no insight that using the vulnerability of a drunk young woman as a selling point sends appalling mixed messages, then much work still needs to be done about the institutional culture that contributes to sexual harassment and abuse.

Responses to a young woman in that situation can cover a broad range, from concern for her welfare, to indifference, to seeing her as an object of derision, and on to seeing her as someone who can be taken advantage of while she is powerless to protect herself.

There are many in the community who would view such a young woman as having abandoned responsibility for her own well-being by drinking to excess.

That view is just a short step from deciding she "asked for it", potentially leading others at the party to commit a sexual crime, and others in the community to blame the victim if it ends up in court.

University of Newcastle Vice-Chancellor Caroline McMillen says the aim in 2017 is to "shift the dial on this culture as far as we can away from events that are based on alcohol to have a good time".
The issue is about respect, for self and for others, and being willing to have respectful conversations about necessary cultural change.

Issue: 38,560.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice-Chancellor Caroline McMillen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
