<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651407641213668484</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/television/former-a-country-practice-star-penny-cook-would-love-more-tv-work-after-small-role-in-pulse/news-story/9c1035982326f304ce1ecc192b298bfa</url>
  <title>Australian TV needs more of this</title>
  <content>
"WRITE in very big print that 'she's ready and able'." That is former star Penny Cook's instruction after snagging a small role in Pulse.
Cook, just turned 60, would love to have more television work after playing nurse unit manager Carol Little in the ABC medical drama.
Cook worked alongside young stars including Claire van der Boom, Andrea Demetriades, and Liam McIntyre.
Too often, Little hovers around the edges of the frame. It is a far cry from the days when Cook was front and centre as veterinarian Vicky Dean Bowen on Seven's beloved rural drama.
"There's not a bucket load of jobs for old ladies on television," Cook says. "It would be lovely to see more people my age (on the screen) but I doubt that is ever going to happen.
"I was given some of the best lines I've ever had in my career on Pulse (but) it is pretty much my elbows and hand and the back of my head (viewers see) a lot of the time.
"But I had fun with it. I was joyous working with people I'd never met before and some that I'd watched before and admired their work.
"It (being on Pulse) was good for my confidence. I hadn't done drama for a couple of years. I'd done a few plays but not a lot of telly.
"When you realise you can still find your mark and make the crew laugh and enjoy the day ... it is pretty exciting."
It is just over 30 years since Cook ended her time on A Country Practice. Cook first appeared on The Restless Years. Later she starred as Dr Elly Fielding in E Street. In the mid-1990s Cook was a presenter on The Great Outdoors. She also appeared in Neighbours and All Saints.
"A Country Practice stays with me constantly because I keep coming across people who adored it," Cook says.
"We were so lucky on that show. We were treated so well. We all grew up together and we're all still friends.
"I had a birthday the other day, a surprise party, and my colleagues (from A Country Practice) were there. That's not bad when you still have them in your life after all this time."
So does Cook think the time is right for a remake of A Country Practice? Nine is thinking of kickstarting another version of McLeod's Daughters. Foxtel has made a killing with its Prisoner reboot Wentworth?
"People keep saying it (a reboot) would (be popular) but would it," Cook says. "It was country people loving it and city people loving it which is a hard thing to achieve.
"I think Doctor Doctor (starring Rodger Corser) is pretty close to achieving that quirkiness and appeal.
"A lesson in life is 'you can't go back' because does it ruin the dream? Sometimes it is better to keep it in our hearts."
WATCH PULSE, ABC, THURSDAY, 8.30PM
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Elly Fielding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wentworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THURSDAY, 8.30PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam McIntyre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodger Corser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Restless Years</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH PULSE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREAT OUTDOORS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLeod's Daughters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Practice</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vicky Dean Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doctor Doctor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Demetriades</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol Little</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
