<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409067142841976</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/03/34/business-sa-welcomes-revised-energy-plan</url>
  <title>Business SA welcomes revised energy plan</title>
  <content>
South Australia's plan to install nine new generators to overcome any shortfalls in electricity over the next two summers is a flexible option that supports locals consumers, Business SA says.
The government says the state-of-the-art generators will be installed at two temporary locations before being moved to one permanent site.
They have the capacity to provide up to 276 megawatts but will only dispatch energy to the grid if there are shortfalls in electricity supply that could result in load shedding.
They replace the government's original proposal to build a new gas-fired power station and to put temporary diesel generators in key locations across SA.
Business SA spokesman Anthony Penney says the generators are a better option than construction of a new power plant.
"Business SA commends the state government for listening to industry and not committing to purchase an expensive permanent back-up generator while going with a flexible option," he said.
Premier Jay Weatherill says the generators will be funded within the existing $550 million energy plan, with the bill to be lower than the previous options.

Related Articles

The plan also includes construction of the world's biggest battery in SA's mid-north by tech billionaire Elon Musk and was developed following the statewide blackout in September 2016 and major load shedding in February.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Penney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Jay Weatherill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
