<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409062847874640</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/03/34/vic-firies-bullying-review-fight-in-court</url>
  <title>Vic firies bullying review fight in court</title>
  <content>
Victoria's firefighters union is expected back in court to continue its bid to stop a review of bullying and sexual harassment within the state's fire services being released.
The United Firefighters Union launched an urgent court bid in June to stop the Equity and Diversity Review into Fire Services being released, weeks before the findings were due.
The case is due for a directions hearing in the Supreme Court of Victoria on Wednesday.
When the matter was called in June, the parties requested an adjournment and it's understood the union was in talks with the commission.
The union wants an order preventing the Victorian Equal Opportunity and Human Rights Commission from "continuing to conduct the review or taking any steps whatsoever in the conduct of the review", according to court documents.
But the VEOHRC has said it will push on.
"We will continue with the review and are working with all stakeholders to ensure that this important work gets done and can benefit the agencies into the future," VEOHRC commissioner Kristen Hilton said in a statement in June.

Related Articles

The government maintains the review must go ahead to deal with "serious cultural issues" within the MFB and CFA.
The review began in July 2016 and is examining sexual harassment and discrimination, including bullying of employees and volunteers of the CFA and MFB.
The union ordered its members not to take part in the independent review, which was launched after concerns were raised in the Fire Services Report.
The report found relationships between volunteer and paid firefighters were strained, bullying was not dealt with properly, and there were many instances of sexual harassment and threatening behaviour against women.
The union also wanted a court-ordered declaration that the review goes beyond VEOHRC's powers.
It says the review's methodology is "seriously flawed" because anyone can complete the online survey, which "deprives its results of any credibility".
The review's findings were due to be released in August.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristen Hilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diversity Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire Services Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Firefighters Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VEOHRC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Equal Opportunity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
