<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408659120940772</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/labor-rightly-puts-trusts-under-spotlight-but-should-go-further-20170801-gxn0m7.html</url>
  <title>Labor rightly puts trusts under spotlight</title>
  <content>
The best and most remarkable thing about Bill Shorten's weekend announcement of a 30 per cent tax floor on discretionary trusts is that it puts trusts back on the political agenda where they belong.
Trust reform appeared to have been expunged from Australian political debate after then treasurer Peter Costello's Coalition colleagues quashed his push for reform in the early 2000s.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Want to save thousands on your tax bill?

Ken and Martha are using a family trust to knock thousands and thousands of dollars off their tax bill. This is how do they do it.

Six years ago, then assistant treasurer Bill Shorten ruled out action on trusts, insisting they were "legitimate business vehicles for farmers the like".
And as recently as April, a series of stories about family trusts - and the extent of tax minimisation through them - there was an uncomfortable silence from all sides, even from the Greens, who actually had a half-cooked reform policy, and from usually vocal-about-everything independents, such as Nick Xenophon.

Yet such is the fluidity of politics that only a few months later Labor believes prodding a sleeping giant like family trusts is not only worthwhile in terms of tax revenue, but politically as well.
The Coalition and business groups are fighting back with accusations that Shorten has abandoned the bipartisan market economics championed by Bob Hawke and Paul Keating, opting instead for envy-driven populism. Shorten's trust policy is part of what Scott Morrison describes as Labor leader's "dark economic vision".

There's no doubt that political change domestically and internationally has made trust reform palatable when only months ago it remained a political unmentionable. That does not make it wrong.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

All politics have an element of fashionability about them - 30 years of blind faith in markets and privatisation springs to mind. The question is whether there is a problem with trusts that needs addressing.
The answer is undoubtedly yes. Discretionary trusts are, for the most part, an inequitable tax rort costing public coffers and other taxpayers billions of dollars a year. Everyone who knows about trusts knows this to be true.
Currently, discretionary trusts allow high and middle income breadwinners to split their income and distribute it to family members on lower tax rates - adult children at university or retired parents, for example.Photo: AAP
So a rich miner or manufacturer with the right tax agent is able to minimise or even extinguish their tax bill by promising money to his kids and his parents.
And the tax savings tend to advantage the wealthy. Australian Bureau of Statistics data indicates that while discretionary trusts are often used for small and medium businesses, trust wealth is heavily skewed to the richest Australians. Almost 90 per cent of trust assets - almost $600 billion worth - are held by the wealthiest 20 per cent of income earners.
Does Labor's policy address the problem? Yes, sort of.
Trust and trust-tax laws are a centuries-old tangle of state, federal and case law that only a handful of top-shelf tax accountants and lawyers fully understand.
The default position for those proposing reform - from Costello and the Greens and welfare lobby ACOSS - has been to tax trusts in the same way as companies. Increasingly, this alternative has been criticised for failing to address the core problem of income splitting.
Labor's approach is innovative and surprising in its simplicity: everyone who gets a distribution from a discretionary trust will have to pay at least 30 per cent tax. It addresses the income-splitting question while avoiding the potential quagmire of a more structural rewrite of trust regulation.
But Shorten and treasury spokesman Chris Bowen have squibbed it on some fronts.
For reasons of pure political expediency - there is no policy rationale here - Labor has exempted farm (discretionary) trusts. Yet again, the rural lobby's political clout means farmers are off the hook. The Greens also exempted farmers in the trust reform policy it took to the 2016 election.
Labor's policy of a flat 30 per cent minimum tax on trust distributions does allow those on the top marginal tax rate of 47 per cent to reduce their tax liability.
The reality, however, is that wealthy trust users in particular who don't have children or pensioner parents to act as beneficiaries, already have the capacity to cut their tax bill to 30 per cent by making distributions to companies - what is know as the "bucket company" option.
This is one of a slew of issues that appear outstanding from Labor's plan.
Despite the weaknesses, Shorten's initiative puts pressure on all parties and MPs, and the wider community to address, and wrestle with, important challenges in tax and revenue.
For its part thein response. It wants to paint Shorten's plan as radical and Corbynesque. Yet it was its own favourite son and star treasurer Costello who declared in 1998 that trusts were being exploited by the rich so that "the community subsidises the wealthy taxpayer".
Rather than imposing a "dark economic vision" Shorten and Bowen have dragged trusts out of a dark corner of Australian politics and put them under a spotlight they have too long avoided.
Royce Millar is a Fairfax senior writer.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corbynesque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Keating</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACOSS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costello</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royce Millar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Costello's Coalition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
