<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408925408918533</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/muji-hotel-japan-china-2017-7</url>
  <title>Japan's coolest design company is opening an ultra-minimalist hotel</title>
  <content>
Muji - the retailer known for its minimalist home goods - is opening a hotel in Yokyo's Ginza district.

Set to be completed in spring 2019, the first six floors of the 10-story development will be dedicated to a Muji flagship store,  Spoon & Tamago. The top four floors will house the new hotel.

Like the store, the hotel will feature lots of Muji goods. The project calls for 79 rooms, outfitted with Muji furniture and accessories, many of which will be made from recycled wood.

The company also  in early 2017 that it plans to launch another hotel in Shenzhen, China.

The miniature model below shows what rooms in both hotels could look like. The bare-bones design mirrors that of , which it plans to start selling in August 2017.

The new hotels could be a smart strategy to market Muji's products. If a guest enjoys sleeping on a Muji bed, they might want to buy one for their own home.

The move follows the trend of other retailers that have opened hotels in recent years. The Portrait Firenze, which Salvatore Ferragamo  in 2014, offers 34 luxe suites designed in the style of the brand's clothing. The Americana clothing company Tommy Hilfiger has , while the home goods chain West Elm will open  starting in 2018.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvatore Ferragamo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tommy Hilfiger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Elm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shenzhen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portrait Firenze</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yokyo's Ginza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muji</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
