<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409350610688595</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/before-the-bell/asx-poised-to-drift-lower-as-commodities-retreat-20170801-gxnfv4</url>
  <title>ASX poised to drift lower as commodities retreat</title>
  <content>
by
Timothy Moore

Iron ore, oil and base metals drifted lower overnight setting the stage for a modestly lower local open. ASX futures were down 5 points or 0.1%. The Australian dollar slipped 0.3%.
Overseas sentiment was mostly positive, with strong gains across Europe. Optimism was somewhat more contained on Wall Street ahead of Apple's results after the closing bell.
In addition, the latest US economic data continues to be mixed. While July proved to be another solid month for US manufacturers, June proved another challenging one for consumers with a third consecutive easing in nominal spending.
The mostly strong second-quarter US reporting season hasn't yet quieted red flags on valuations for some market watchers.

JPMorgan's chief US equity strategist Dubravkos Lakos-Bujas sees the S&P 500 finishing the year at 2550; in contrast, Marko Kolanovic, JPMorgan's global head of quantitative and derivatives strategy, is bearish, according to Business Insider. 

Robert W. Baird's chief portfolio strategist, Brian Rauscher, recently boosted his S&P 500 year-end target to 2570.  Oppenheimer's chief investment strategist John Stoltzfus lifted his target to 2650, making him the second-most-bullish analyst on Wall Street, trailing only Mike Wilson of Morgan Stanley, according to Business Insider.
In the wake of yesterday's RBA rate meeting, the Aussie has drifted lower.
"The higher AUD got some focus in the RBA statement ... but does not appear to have pushed them off track yet," said Paul Bloxham, chief economist for Australia, New Zealand and global commodities at HSBC. 
"Better global growth, higher commodity prices and an improving local economy seem to be making the RBA more comfortable with the higher currency," Mr Bloxham also said.

Today's Agenda

Local data: Building approvals June; NZ unemployment rate
Capital Economics on the NZ jobs data: "Leading labour market indicators suggest that New Zealand employment is likely to have grown by 1.0 per cent q/q in Q2, after rising by 1.2 per cent q/q in the first quarter. We suspect that the unemployment rate edged down only slightly from 4.9 per cent to 4.8 per cent, as strong migration and a growing working age population continued to bolster the labour supply."
Overseas data: UK Markit/CIPS construction PMI June; US ADP employment report July

Market Highlights

SPI futures down 5 points or 0.1% to 5709
AUD -0.3% to 79.81 US cents (Overnight range: 0.7961 - 0.8043)
On Wall St, Dow +0.4%, S&P 500 +0.3%. Nasdaq +0.2%

In New York, BHP -0.6%, Rio -0.6%
In Europe, Stoxx 50 +0.8%, FTSE +0.7%, CAC +0.7%, DAX +1.1%
Spot gold +0.3% to $US1272.96 an ounce
Brent crude -2.2% to $US51.55 a barrel

US oil -2.5% to $US48.94 a barrel
Iron ore slips 14 cents to $US73.56 a tonne
Dalian iron ore -1.3% to 542 yuan
LME aluminium -0.6% to $US1907 a tonne
LME copper -0.4% to $US6345 a tonne
10-year bond yield: US 2.25%, Germany 0.49%, Australia 2.71%
From Today's 
Financial Review
: Why there is such a high level of trust placed in management consultants by Australian boards?

: The typical household had less real disposable income in 2015 than in 2009, which explains why Bill Shorten's inequality crusade resonates.
: RBA governor Philip Lowe has warned the strengthening Australian dollar could scupper growth expectations.
United States

The Dow came within spitting distance of the 22,000 mark and the S&P 500 was also higher, powered by strong corporate earnings.
The Nasdaq Composite, however, was kept in check by losses in healthcare shares, led by Regeneron. The drugmaker's shares were down 3.8 per cent after a rating downgrade.
All eyes will now be on the quarterly performance of Dow-component Apple, which reports after the closing bell. The iPhone maker's shares were up 0.1 per cent.
Investors have been counting on earnings to support high valuations for equities. The S&P 500 is trading at about 18 times earnings estimates for the next 12 months, above its long-term average of 15 times.
S&P 500 earnings are expected on average to have grown 10.8 per cent in the second quarter, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S.

Europe

European shares rose on Tuesday, looking to recover after two straight months of losses, with corporate earnings reports spurring brisk trading ahead of a what is typically a sleepy summer period for markets.
The pan-European STOXX 600 index, nursing two straight months of losses, rose 0.6 per cent. Blue chips closed 0.9 per cent higher, their best one-day gains in three weeks.
Germany's DAX advanced 1.1 per cent while Britain's commodities-heavy FTSE 100 gained 0.7 per cent as oil stocks rose.
Earnings updates dominated the action, with oil heavyweight BP rising 2.8 per cent and boosting the oil & gas sector after beating forecasts as new projects supported production.
"BP has covered the cash component of the dividend with free cash flow for the second straight quarter and the Upstream business is performing well," analysts at Jefferies said in a note. "Valuation is not challenging, but the company's ability to de-lever the balance sheet remains a concern."
The European second-quarter earnings season is nearing the halfway mark and so far 60 per cent of MSCI Europe firms have met or beaten analysts' expectations, according to Thomson Reuters data.
Earnings per share growth in Europe was tracking at about 13 per cent, including a significant boost from energy firms, according to the latest data from JPMorgan.

"You have seen some signs of (the) green shoots of recovery within the European economy and that, of course, is good for companies," Laith Khalaf, senior analyst at Hargreaves Lansdown, said.
Morgan Stanley analysts said the euro's surge this year could weigh on European corporate profits, however, joining the chorus of big brokers warning the currency could dent earnings growth.
Asia

Hong Kong stocks ended at a 26-month high, aided by strong gains in state-backed mainland firms, as investors cheered a private survey showing China's factory activity accelerated in July.
The benchmark Hang Seng index rose 0.8 per cent, to 27,540.23 points, its highest close since June 2015. The China Enterprises Index, an index tracking major state-owned mainland firms, gained 1.8 per cent to finish at 11,024.13 points, a two-year high.
China blue chips ended at a 19-month high on Tuesday, led by strong gains in heavyweight financial firms, as investors cheered a private survey showing the country's factory activity accelerated in July.
China's blue-chip CSI300 index rose 0.9 per cent to finish at 3770.38 points, its highest close since December 2015. The Shanghai Composite Index added 0.6 per cent to 3292.64 points. In July, the CSI300 advanced 2.0 per cent, while the SSEC gained 2.5 per cent.
Japan's Nikkei share average rose on Tuesday, buoyed by companies such as Nitto Denko and Mitsui Sumitomo Financial Group reporting strong earnings, though gains were tempered by a stronger yen.

The Nikkei ended 0.3 per cent higher at 19,985.79 points. On Monday, the Nikkei fell 0.2 per cent to its lowest close since June 15. For July, it shed 0.5 per cent, snapping a three-month winning streak.
The broader Topix gained 0.6 per cent to 1628.50.
Currencies

The US dollar briefly touched a 15-month low against a basket of major currencies overnight on political turmoil in Washington and weak US economic data that kept the Federal Reserve's policy outlook uncertain.
Economic data showed US consumer spending barely rose in June as income failed to increase for the first time in seven months.
The core PCE numbers - the Federal Reserve's preferred metric to gauge inflation - for June edged up 0.1 per cent following a similar increase in May.
The US dollar fell below 110 yen for the first time in more than six weeks, touching 109.94 yen. The dollar was last at 110.22 yen.
The US dollar index fell in July, its fifth consecutive monthly decline, the longest such stretch since December 2010 through April 2011. On a monthly basis, it was the biggest drop since March 2016.

Goldman Sachs CFO Marty Chavez said overnight that the market for fixed income trading has not improved much since the second quarter. Chavez said on a call with fixed income investors that low volatility - which caused a slump in trading revenue for Goldman during the second quarter - had "essentially continued into this quarter".
Goldman's trading performance during the second quarter was worse than peers including JPMorgan Chase & Co, Bank of America and Morgan Stanley.
Many of Goldman's clients are active asset managers, like hedge funds, that have broadly been struggling to post strong returns. Those clients have been trading less, representing less revenue to Goldman.
Commodities

Trading activity in the seaborne iron ore market slowed down on Tuesday, with prices softening after soaring by some $US5 per tonne a day earlier.
China's iron ore futures trended was weaker during the day, after closing at the upper limit just a day earlier, according to Metal Bulletin. January is now the most-traded contract, instead of September. Few deals involving seaborne cargoes of the steelmaking raw material were reported, with offers on trading platforms generating relatively few bids.
Copper prices held near two-year highs, supported by expectations of stronger demand from China. Benchmark copper on the London Metal Exchange closed down 0.4 per cent at $US6345 a tonne. The metal widely used in power and construction hit $US6430 on Monday, its highest since May 2015.
"China data shows things humming along in manufacturing and construction. That's the positive," a copper trader said. "The weak dollar also makes things easier for base metals, though there is some profit-taking going on."

Three-month tin closed down 0.6 per cent at $US20,525 a tonne, but close to the $US20,905 a tonne hit last week, its highest since the middle of January on worries about supplies from China.
LME nickel finished 0.8 per cent higher at $US10,290 a tonne, bolstered by supply concerns and expectations of stronger demand from Chinese stainless steel mills.
Aluminium ended down 0.6 per cent at $US1907, zinc closed down 0.5 per cent at $US2780 and lead finished 0.2 per cent higher at $US2338 a tonne.
Australian Sharemarket

The benchmark S&P/ASX 200 index closed up 0.9 per cent to 5772 points and the broader All Ordinaries Index lifted 0.8 per cent to 5820 points.​
Street Talk

with Reuters, Bloomberg, AAP
Comments? Questions? Let us know what you think of Before the Bell. You can reach Timothy Moore at  timothy.moore@fairfaxmedia.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Enterprises Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMI June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Metal Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Stoltzfus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC +0.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US73.56</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSI300</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LME</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP -0.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oppenheimer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK Markit/CIPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European STOXX 600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hang Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany's DAX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs CFO Marty Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Nikkei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX +1.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metal Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US20,525</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSCI Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sharemarket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dubravkos Lakos-Bujas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Topix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow +0.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US ADP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2338</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jefferies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio -0.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 2.71</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Bloxham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US48.94</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD -0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SSEC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2780</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitsui Sumitomo Financial Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikkei</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regeneron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Ordinaries Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Moore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10,290</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq Composite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500 +0.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US20,905</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasdaq +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany 0.49</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Wilson of Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2.25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6430</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1272.96</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bloxham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laith Khalaf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai Composite Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6345</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 50 +0.8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nitto Denko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marko Kolanovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US51.55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE +0.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow-component Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Rauscher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan Chase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1907</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert W. Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hargreaves Lansdown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
