<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409058552907224</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/retailers-that-investors-hate-more-than-under-armour-2017-8</url>
  <title>3 retailers investors hate more than Under Armour</title>
  <content>
shares have been hammered harder than almost any other retail company this year.

The company's stock price took a beating Tuesday,
, its most important market.

Since the beginning of the year, Under Armour's shares have dropped more than 33%, making it the ninth worst-performing stock in the S&P 500 this year.

Under Armour's fall from glory has been swift and brutal. It was only two years ago that the company was touted as a top investment pick after notching 26 straight quarters of at least 20% sales growth. Shares grew nearly 20% that year.

Despite its recent troubles, however, Under Armour has still outperformed a few other retailers in the S&P 500.

, , and  - which operates Kay Jewellers, Zales, Jared The Galleria Of Jewellery, and other jewellery stores - have all seen their share prices drop even further than Under Armour's.

Foot Locker and Macy's shares have dropped 34% in 2017 and Signet Jewellers shares have dropped 35%.

Foot Locker has been suffering from a shift in shoe manufacturers' preferences toward selling to online-only channels over brick-and-mortar stores, according to Credit Suisse.

"Ultimately, we believe the best-in-class execution by Foot Locker may no longer be enough to offset two-fronts of structural industry change," Credit Suisse analysts wrote in a recent note.

Macy's and Signet Jewellers are both under intense pressure from years of falling traffic to malls, where their stores are primarily located.

Macy's is also reeling from consumers' .

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Signet Jewellers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galleria Of Jewellery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foot Locker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kay Jewellers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
