<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409612603698057</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/mark-carrolls-blueprint-for-rabbitohs-trim-the-burgess-twins-and-trash-the-old-school-game-plan/news-story/cef4aec22b2fa135162ea64e0f7c20df</url>
  <title>Spud: Souths need to get with times</title>
  <content>
SOUTH Sydney legend Mark Carroll is as old school as they come in the NRL, but even he believes the struggling Burgess twins need to get with the times.
With the Rabbitohs out of contention for this year's finals, Carroll believes Tom and George Burgess must drop their playing weight over the summer to re- invigorate their NRL careers.
The pair have come under heavy scrutiny for another lacklustre season at Redfern Oval this year, however Carroll insists they can still be part of the team's future - but only if they scale down from their current 120 kilograms.
"Personally, I wish they'd get down in size a bit. I reckon they should get down to about 115," Carroll told AAP at Fox League's Retro Round launch in Sydney. "They're just massive humans. They don't have to do weights and they'd still keep weight on.
"But the game these days is about pace, mobility, working on the inside. They're still 25, so they're young boys, They'll get better at that.
"They're not the only ones Souths fans need to be having a go at though." Carroll is adamant coach Michael Maguire needs an overhaul of his current roster, and adjust his playing style to the up-tempo game plans in vogue across the league.
The former NSW and Australian prop said the Rabbitohs hadn't changed from their forwards-oriented approach that led to a breakthrough premiership triumph in 2014.
"I think Michael Maguire's a fabulous coach. He's had the grounding of Craig Bellamy. He just needs a clean-out, get rid of some players who are underperforming," Carroll said.
"But I reckon attack-wise, Souths are poor. They work five plays for a cross- kick.
"Look at the Melbourne Storm these days, they've changed their game this year to have a lot more inside-ball work. Your game's got to evolve at some capacity. And I don't reckon Souths has changed over the past three years."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redfern Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carroll</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Maguire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox League's Retro Round</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
