<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409449394938116</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/i-picked-a-fight-with-the-school-sissy-and-lost/3206081/</url>
  <title>I picked a fight with the school sissy ... and lost</title>
  <content>
I RODE my pushbike to school on day one of Grade 1 at Eudlo Primary School.
It was a mile and a bit and I was just six years old.
I remember riding into the schoolyard and all the kids on the veranda waving at me.
There were only 50 kids at the school.
On day one, I had a fight - my very first day at school.
I put a kid called David Johnson's head through the fence and wrapped the wire around his neck.
So day one before lunch, I'm in the principal's office getting a lecture about the cane and what can happen to kids who fight.
I never got into too much trouble after that.
I don't know what happened to David Johnson. I think he joined the Navy.
By Grade 3, I was a bit of a bully and decided to have a fight with the school sissy, who was also the teacher's son and I despised him immensely.
I decided to fight him one day and got bashed up by the school sissy so I decided in Grade 3 that being a bully wasn't my game and I never got into another fight after that - from Grade 3 right through to Grade 12.
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 3</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eudlo Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
