<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409492344611845</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/coast-woman-permanently-injured-after-cricket-acci/3207537/</url>
  <title>Coast woman permanently injured after cricket accident</title>
  <content>
AN UNIMAGINABLE sequence of events has left a Coast woman permanently injured and in hospital for four months.

Antonia Drury, 67, called the Sunshine Coast University Hospital home for the better part of this year - her room in the rehab wing was filled with flowers and balloons willing her better and her husband Vic never left her side.

Mrs Drury was playing family cricket at the Noosa River for her son's 30th birthday when a fall from a hard swing left her with a fractured hip.

In the ambulance on the way to hospital she suffered a heart attack and would go on to suffer two more and a stroke in the following months.

Her husband, 72, was by her bedside throughout surgery and rehab, but the left side of her body remains partially paralysed.

"We've (the family) worked as a team and we bring in food and everything she likes... anything we could think of to feel like she's at home," Mr Drury said.

She finally returned home yesterday afternoon, much to her family's delight.

Intense rehab has afforded Mrs Drury some movement in her left hand, but it's "never going to be 100%", according to her husband.

Mr Drury said before the accident he and his wife were out every day enjoying a life full of shopping and cooking, but they would still strive to do those things despite her disability.

"We'll be doing all those things now, just in a wheelchair," he said.

A strong family unit has been invaluable to Mrs Drury who said she received visits from her four children and two grandchildren on weekends while she was in hospital.

"They're my life, my family," she said.

"They're wonderful, I love them."

Renovations have been made to the couple's home to accommodate a sling and wheelchair which Mrs Drury will have to use for the rest of her life.

"We've knocked a small bedroom out and put a shower and toilet in there," Mr Drury said.

"We've extended our bedroom to make it a bigger bedroom so we can manoeuvre the hoist.

"I've worked tirelessly over the last few weeks to get that complete."

Although the hospital has provided a temporary hoist, Mr Drury's broken collarbone makes manoeuvring it difficult and he said he aimed to purchase one on a pivot.

A Gofundme has been set up to raise funds for better mobility equipment and ongoing medical costs.

Despite the enormity of the situation, Mrs Drury said she "takes everything as it comes" and her family were "dealing with it very well".

You can help the Drury family reach their $20,000 goal at .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Drury</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoFundMe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonia Drury, 67</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Drury</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
