<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409569654024494</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/federal-government-poised-for-2m-funding-pledge-for-cairns-aquarium-research-centre/news-story/2a7f8237b59f0f9eed59e3e2ad26af8a</url>
  <title>Chasing millions for reef centre</title>
  <content>
THE Cairns Aquarium is in line for about $2 million funding for a research centre that could evolve into a new outpost of the Great Barrier Reef Marine Park Authority.
Leichhardt MP Warren Entsch expected to hear from Regional Development Minister Fiona Nash by Thursday on whether the funding application had been approved.
GBRMPA's current research operations are close to outgrowing their Townsville home, meaning the Federal Government will have to construct a new purpose-built research station or piggyback on the Cairns Aquarium's existing world-class facility.
The National Stronger Regions Fund application was lodged by the Reef and Rainforest Research Centre to conduct testing from the aquarium.
Mr Entsch said GBRMPA's own expansion needs gave the proposal extra leverage.
"The options are that we're going to have to rebuild a whole new aquarium or they can use some elements up here," Mr Entsch said.
"There's no reason why we can't share the love.
"I've been working with the minister on this for some time and I hope to get a resolution later this week."
The aquarium's opening date has been pushed back to September following building delays, with the 1.7 million litre main tank due to start filling with water today.
Cairns Aquarium general manager Julie Cullen said she was not privy to the intricacies of the bid but confirmed she had been in talks with several groups about possible collaborations.
"If it all makes sense for all parties, we would be interested in hearing about it," Ms Cullen said.
Mr Entsch said the plan made more sense than spending $50 million or more to build a new aquarium from scratch.
"In my view it really strengthens our commitment to the reef in that we will have two research facilities, one in Cairns and one in Townsville," he said.
"It's not just about the amount of money, it's about the message it sends about building further capacity on a public-private partnership. I'm very strongly pushing it."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rainforest Research Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Development Minister Fiona Nash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leichhardt MP Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Cullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Cullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GBRMPA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Barrier Reef Marine Park Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Aquarium</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Stronger Regions Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
