<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409393560362231</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/ato-reveals-more-website-outages-as-calls-for-compensation-grow/8765186</url>
  <title>Tax office reveals more website outages as calls for compensation grow</title>
  <content>
The tax office has revealed another 10 website outages in recent months, stopping businesses and individuals from lodging their returns online.
The incident log does not include  and July, and adds to .
Some of the 10 outages recorded between January and June lasted for up to two days, while others lasted just eight minutes.
The ATO's acting chief operations officer Frances Cawthra told the ABC that more than $5 billion has already been returned to Australians - more than at this stage last year - despite the technical glitches.
"The systems are working; however we are certainly not trying to make light of the frustration our stakeholders have experienced over the last few months," she said.
Tax commissioner  in the industry.

The Tax Institute's chief executive Noel Rowland said the frequency of IT problems at the ATO was concerning and accountants are entitled to compensation for lost productivity.
"I can understand the calls for compensation given the disruption to practices, what's critically important is that no-one is any worse off as a result of the outage," he said.
"Agents rely very heavily on access to that system to lodge returns, to make queries, to look up balances; and so when they're down, it's really disruptive to their work."
Labor raising concerns about staffing cuts

The tax office has already said it will waive some late penalties for those unable to lodge their tax returns.
Ms Cawthra said she understands the frustrations and the ATO will consider compensation claims.
"We do have a Commonwealth scheme and details of that are available on our website - we do understand the impact," she said.

The additional outages were reported to a Senate estimates committee with the ATO stating that it managed "a large and complex IT environment and given this complexity, we will occasionally encounter unplanned issues with our systems".
Mr Cawthra said the tax office had only received 18 official complaints about the outages, despite many Australians and accountants voicing frustration online.
Labor frontbenchers Andrew Leigh and Ed Husic are calling for an investigation into the IT problems, raising concerns about staffing cuts.
"The ATO is trying as hard as it can, but it's been left struggling thanks to staffing cuts by the Coalition," Mr Leigh said.
Financial Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer was contacted for comment.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Minister Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Leigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cawthra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frances Cawthra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Rowland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Leigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Cawthra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Husic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tax Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATO</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
