<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409178811993589</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/3099855/proposal-for-bulli-twilight-market-lodged/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Proposal lodged for twilight market at Bulli showground</title>
  <content>
Crown Street Mall's Eat Street and Bulli's Foragers market organiser Kirrily Sinclair. Picture: ADAM McLEAN
The woman behind two of Wollongong's most successful markets - Crown Street Mall's Eat Street and Bulli's Foragers - has lodged plans for another weekly food set-up.
Thirroul businesswoman Kirrily Sinclair has submitted a proposal with Wollongong City Council to modify the operating hours of her Sunday market at Bulli showground to allow a new Saturday evening operation.
According to the plans, the "twilight food market" would have about 10 stalls, with a maximum of 60 stalls.
Ms Sinclair said the idea for the extra market had come from Foragers' patrons, who have been asking for a night food market for some time.
"The twilight market we held at Christmas was a huge success, but we want to make this more of a low-key local hangout where people can come together and eat some food and maybe hear some music," she said.
"We're thinking about putting out ping-pong tables and just making it a small scale event for the community. I think people really want a place to have that social connection these days, because so much of what happens in our lives now is online."
Market stallholders would begin setting up from about 3pm, the application says, and would be gone by 11pm at the latest.
The plan is on exhibition on the council's website until May 27.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Sinclair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirrily Sinclair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Street Mall's Eat Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulli's Foragers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
