<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409466574807721</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/the-students-make-it-all-worthwhile/3206095/</url>
  <title>The students make it all worthwhile</title>
  <content>
EDUCATION and schools have come a long way in the 50 years since the Sunshine Coast was given its new name.
I have spent the past 29 of those years at Mooloolaba Primary School and have seen many changes take place both at the school and in our local community.
While the apartment buildings and resorts started to tower around us, our charming school has stayed relatively the same over the years.
I started teaching in an old wooden demountable that had been trucked on to the school oval, as it was done in those times when a school ran out of classrooms. I had a class of 33 Year 6 students and we shared with a Year 7 class of 34.
Although you can still see many of the original classrooms if you take a walk around the school, you will certainly see efforts to keep everything looking good. The whole school has received many coats of paint over my years here.
Happily now, we also have a great new hall, a fabulous dedicated library block, and our wonderful P&C has just finished air-conditioning the final classroom. We also have smaller classes and much nicer working spaces.
In my first year, we had only chalkboards and very old wooden desks, and teachers went through many wrist watches as they filled up constantly with the chalk dust.
The only real "technology" we had were cassette players and the infamous overhead projectors. Not long after this, we graduated from the purple-ink gestetners that were used to run off student worksheets, to the very latest in technology - the new-fangled photocopiers. That has certainly made life easier.
Now, of course, our classrooms are bursting with smartboards, touch-screen TVs, laptops and electronic tablets.
We also now have robotics equipment and coding apps that students from Prep through to Year 6 eagerly use.
It really is an exciting time to be a teacher. Sometimes the teachers feel they are learning right along with the students, who are very quick to pick up on these skills.
Across from the school has always been a changing face.
The main strip facing the ocean at Mooloolaba has been upgraded beautifully since I first walked across to the bank to deposit my pay cheque.
Yes, we had to physically deposit our cheques and then get our money! Lunchtimes on Wednesdays always saw a long line-up of teachers waiting at the bank.
We now have many great coffee shops, cafes and a supermarket right across from the oval.
One thing that hasn't changed, however, are the students and their families who make our school a really wonderful place to work.
Just as we have now, there has always been a great sense of community and always a friendly face.
Over all these years, supply teachers and contract teachers who have worked at our school have always commented on what a warm and welcoming place it is. Our staff have always been a team and have really supported each other and enjoyed working together.
I have seen many past students come back as parents themselves and entrust their children to us and I believe there is no higher praise than that.
They always stop and say "hi" and remind me of when they were in my class. I am getting a little worried, however, that one day I might have to face a grandparent who says, "Oh are you still here? I was in your class!".
Both Mooloolaba itself and the school have certainly changed over the past 30 years, but I for one am happy with the changes and grateful that I get to live and work in such a wonderful place.
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 6</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
