<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409457984872833</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/tafe-has-come-a-long-way-on-the-coast/3206128/</url>
  <title>TAFE has come a long way on the Coast</title>
  <content>
TAFE's history is rich and our achievements are many and we aren't shy of saying that we've made great things happen for more than seven million students for over 130 years.
We've come a long way since our humble beginnings. In 1882 on September 4, when we started with only a dozen students in the North Brisbane School of Arts for a class in mechanical drawing.
In the same year, we expanded our course offering to include geology, bookkeeping, French, German and the history of the British Empire.
Prior to this, post-school education was expensive and generally reserved for the wealthy. Technical colleges gave a greater number of individuals access to the skills they needed to participate in the workforce.
By the 1900s, we had expanded our footprint within the greater Brisbane region - founding the South Brisbane Technical College when the South Brisbane Municipality took over the Mechanics Institute and began operations in Townsville, Maryborough, Normanton, Hughenden and Rockhampton.
During the 1900s, a number of significant changes impacted on technical education in Queensland, including the creation of the Board of Technical Education, which held responsibility for technical education (and the then Technical Colleges).
In response to a number of economic factors, we saw a number of smaller campuses in regional areas close, while larger ones such as Mackay and Warwick flourished.
The Depression caused a downturn in the trades and the number of apprenticeships required. However, as the 1930s progressed, the economy began to improve and we worked with industry to offer new courses such as waitressing.
In 1940, our Rockhampton, Ipswich and Central Technical Colleges began training men and women as munitions workers and technicians for the Army and the Air Force under the Commonwealth Technical (War Time) Training Scheme.
Five years later, the Brisbane Technical Correspondence School opened, offering 38 courses targeted at serving and discharged members of the armed forces.
It wasn't until 1974 that all Technical Colleges became known as Technical and Further Education (TAFE) Colleges.
It was 1979 before TAFE training became available to the Sunshine Coast, with the first full-time course in Office Education offered from the old Maroochy Shire Council Chambers in Nambour. One year later, it was decided a TAFE campus should be developed in the heart of Nambour, with construction starting in 1981.
TAFE training on the Sunshine Coast has continued to develop, offering training to thousands of students at campus locations including Mooloolaba, Maroochydore and Nambour and as far north as Gympie, Fraser Coast and Bundaberg.
TAFE Queensland East Coast - the result of an amalgamation between Sunshine Coast TAFE and Wide Bay TAFE in 2014 - is the premier provider of vocational education and training and the largest in the Sunshine Coast and Wide Bay region, with eight campuses and more than 20,000 enrolments annually.
As part of the TAFE Queensland network, we are able to draw upon the vast experience and resources of Queensland's largest training organisation.
Our programs have been designed in close consultation with business and industry and our modern facilities combined with highly-qualified and experienced staff means students gain the skills and knowledge that will give them a competitive advantage when entering the workforce, moving on to further education or even training staff.
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Shire Council Chambers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundaberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wide Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Normanton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>War-time</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Brisbane Municipality</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mechanics Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Technical Colleges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Empire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Brisbane Technical College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Technical Correspondence School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Further Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Technical College</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wide Bay TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Technical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Training Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Brisbane School of Arts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE Queensland East Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughenden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Board of Technical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
