<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409445099970745</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/music/alanis-morissettes-shock-new-look-as-she-books-her-first-concerts-in-australia-since-1999/news-story/7fbeec04b478f6de089fe502b18a5cee</url>
  <title>Alanis Morissette's shock new look</title>
  <content>
SHE was one of the defining voices of the '90s but is now almost unrecognisable more than 20 years after releasing one of the biggest selling albums of all time.
Alanis Morissette has been enjoying life as a blonde this year as she returns to the concert stage for rare shows in the US this year and Australia next January.
The 43-year-old singer whosealbum has sold more than 33 million copies since it exploded on the airwaves in 1995 will perform two shows only here.
The greatest hits sets performed with an acoustic trio will be at the Palais Theatre in Melbourne on January 23 and ICC Sydney Theatre on January 24.
They will be her first concerts here since 1999.
Morissette became one of the biggest female artists in history with her third record, dominating the charts for months courtesy of the controversial single You Oughta Know and its successors All I Really Want, Hand In My Pocket and Ironic.
Since then she has released five records and featured in several film roles including famously playing God in the controversial Kevin Smith comedy Dogma. She also had a recurring role in the hit series Weeds.
Her other hits in the intervening years include Thank U, Hands Clean and Everything.
Morissette has devoted recent years to wellness endeavours, including her Conversation With Alanis Morissette podcast, and bringing up her six-year-old son Ever and baby daughter Onyx, born last year.
She was back in the public eye throughout 2015 as she celebrated the 20th anniversary of Jagged Little Pill.
After a handful of concerts in North America this year, her only other shows at this stage will be the Australian concerts.
Tickets go on sale on Monday.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Onyx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palais Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All I Really Want</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jagged Little Pill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thank U</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oughta Know</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conversation With Alanis Morissette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morissette</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICC Sydney Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alanis Morissette</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
