<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409608308730679</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/trump-helped-sons-russian-meeting-like-any-father-would/8765620</url>
  <title>Donald Trump weighed in on son's Russia statement 'like any father would': White House</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

The White House has confirmed Donald Trump played a role in formulating a statement in which his son denied a meeting he had with a Russian lawyer was related to the 2016 presidential campaign, comments later shown to be misleading.
"He certainly didn't dictate [the statement]," White House press secretary Sarah Sanders said.
"But ... he weighed in, offered suggestion like any father would do.
"The statement that was issued was true and there were no inaccuracies in the statement."

Last month Mr Trump Jr  he was told was a Russian government lawyer who might have damaging information about Democratic presidential candidate Hillary Clinton.
He released the emails after the New York Times reported details of the meeting.
On Monday, the Washington Post said Mr Trump's advisers discussed the new disclosure and agreed that Mr Trump Jr should issue a truthful account of the episode so that it "couldn't be repudiated later if the full details emerged".
But the President, who was flying home from Germany on July 8, changed the plan and "personally dictated a statement in which Mr Trump Jr said he and the Russian lawyer had 'primarily discussed a program about the adoption of Russian children'," the Post said, citing unnamed people with knowledge of the deliberations.
It said the statement, issued to the New York Times as it prepared to publish the story, emphasised the subject of the meeting was "not a campaign issue at the time".
Reuters

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Trump Jr</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
