<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409582538926557</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/vsco-video-editing-tools-2017-8</url>
  <title>VSCO, the best free photo app on the market, just added video editing tools  --  but you'll have to pay for them</title>
  <content>
Your smartphone videos are about to get a lot better looking. 

VSCO, the free photo app that's long been lauded as the , unveiled its  for iOS users on Tuesday, with an Android version in the works. The release was first spotted by . 

Oakland, California-based VSCO lets users create beautiful photographs using advanced photo-editing tools and stunning filters. The app is used by everyone from casual photographers to  and is constantly adding new preset filters and tweaking its interface. 

But the newest addition is one of the biggest updates yet: Users will now be able to edit video right on their phones. VSCO is adding new preset video filters along with the ability to perform more traditional edits, like tweaking the contrast or boosting the saturation. 

There's only one catch: The new tools are only available for those using VSCO X, a yearly membership that costs $US19.99. The membership includes upgraded editing tools, more filters, and now, video editing. 

Here's a look at the new tools in action:

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>iOS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VSCO X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California-based VSCO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VSCO</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US19.99</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
