<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409436510035975</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/why-you-dont-have-much-chance-of-a-pay-rise-anytime-soon/8764584</url>
  <title>Pay rise not likely anytime soon with wage growth at record lows</title>
  <content>
Are you happy with your pay packet?
Chances are you're not. I mean, who is? Unless you're earning more money than you know what to do with.
Even if you're on an above-average wage, most Australians still want a raise. The costs of living (especially utilities bills, and health insurance premiums) keep rising, and we all want to, at the very least, maintain our standard of living.
Right now in Australia wage growth is at record lows. That's not news. What is news is that no-one, not even the experts, can confidently predict when, or even if, this will change.
RBA labels wage stagnation 'insidious'

Late in 2015, Bureau of Statistics figures showed wages, on average, rose just half a percentage point in the final three months of the year. Annual wage growth had eased from 2.3 per cent to just 2.2 per cent - the lowest since records began.
There simply hasn't been any lift-off in wage growth since then.
Last week, the governor of the Reserve Bank chose one of the more significant monetary policy speeches of the year to talk about wages and the labour market.
Philip Lowe devoted a large part of the speech to low wage growth.
"From the mid-1990s until a few years ago, Australians got used to average hourly earnings increasing by around 4 per cent a year," he observed.
"Over recent years," he added, "growth has been a bit less than half of this."
He then commented on the long-term implications and used a word that, to a central banker who rarely goes off script, was profound.
"If workers are getting no real wage increase year after year after year, that's insidious."
Of course it is! Who wants to be stuck in a wages rut? The reality, though, is that millions of workers around Australia are in that position, and there appears little hope they will be able to claw their way out of it in the near future.
What's causing the wages funk?

Economists and the Reserve Bank point to a number of factors stopping workers from going cap in hand to their bosses and asking for a pay rise.
The first is that we need to be working smarter - producing more, with roughly the same amount of effort. That increase in what economists call "productivity" should, the experts say, lift economic growth and wages.
Another big contributor to low wage growth, however, is the casualisation of the workforce. More workers are competing for less hours in insecure jobs, and that leads to lower pay.
Part-time work exploded throughout 2016, and that growth only now seems to be slowing a little.
There are personal stories too.
Mortdale RSL in Sydney's south is a modest community club. George Coorey is the manager and has been working there for years. He told the ABC he needed to work on Sundays to make ends meet, but the penalty rate cuts introduced in July are going to make his life more difficult.
Worse still, he said students and foreign workers were happy to come and take his job for much less pay. He is genuinely worried about his future.
But does the problem run deeper than that?

The Australian economy may have found itself in a nasty negative feedback loop. And if it truly is in this loop, you can forget asking confidently for a pay rise for years to come.
Here's the theory behind it. When Wall Street giant Lehman Brothers collapsed in late 2008, it sparked a credit crunch. Business confidence collapsed overnight.
It has arguably never fully returned. The ANZ Bank and NAB's business surveys certainly show as much.
The reason confidence is important is it leads to business owners dishing out long-term employment contracts. That in turns gives employees a sense of security and the inclination to progress within the organisation and ask for wage increases.
Right now, that isn't happening. And the governor of the Reserve Bank, Philip Lowe, isn't offering much by way of hope.
"It is possible that things could change in the not too distant future, particularly in those countries at, or near, full employment ... we could hit a point at which workers, having had only modest pay increases for a run of years, decide that it is time for a catch-up," Dr Lowe said.
"If such a tipping point were reached, inflation pressures could emerge quite quickly. In this scenario we could see a period of turbulence in financial markets, given that markets are pricing in little risk of future inflation."
That's what we want, right? Except for the financial markets turbulence bit. But then came the clincher:
"It would seem, though, to have a fairly low probability in Australia, especially in light of the continuing spare capacity in our labour market," Dr Lowe said.
In other words, workers aren't confident in asking for a pay rise, which means they're not out their spending more money on goods and services, which in turn is hurting business turnover, and leading to more job insecurity and low wages.
Dollar complicates

The rising Australian dollar has also complicated things.
As the dollar rises against the greenback, it puts the brakes on the economy - much like an interest rate rise. Indeed, Westpac's chief currency strategist, Sean Callow, told the ABC if the dollar were to move above 85 US cents it would warrant a cut to the official cash rate.
From a broader economic perspective, the higher the Australian dollar moves against the greenback, the less hope there is for upwards pressure on wages.
The Reserve Bank said as much in its latest policy statement: "The higher exchange rate is expected to contribute to subdued price pressures in the economy. It is also weighing on the outlook for output and employment."
What does all this mean for you?

Borrowers: it's unlikely the Reserve Bank will raise interest rates this year.
Consumers: shoppers, on average, will likely have less disposable income than they might have thought for some time.
Workers: it's likely it will be difficult to negotiate a pay rise for the foreseeable future.
Government: Westpac's Sean Callow says the Reserve Bank may be left with no choice but to cut its economic growth forecasts - which would be embarrassing for the Government.
Is there any hope for wages?

Employment researchers Esher House and JobReady have been looking at the changes that are due to affect Australia's employment landscape from 2020 to 2030.
Their findings point to "significant societal change" because of "suppressed bargaining power for higher wages", due to underemployment and a "more flexible workforce".
In other words, policymakers aren't going to make a dent into low wage growth, workers need to speak up, loudly.
Esher House's research, across tens of thousands of people, also showed Australians under 21 are considerably less optimistic about their future than the over 21s.
Can you blame them?

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lowe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Coorey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esher House</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Callow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JobReady</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mortdale RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lehman Brothers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac's Sean Callow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
