<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409457984872877</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/new-life-on-the-coast-was-a-long-way-from-the-city/3206105/</url>
  <title>New life on the Coast was a long way from the city</title>
  <content>
DAD, mum and I arrived on the Sunshine Coast in 1971.
Dad was a professional fisherman and decided Mooloolaba was the best port to fish out of. The population at the time was just 35,000 and nobody locked their houses or cars.
In Sydney, at Lady Star of the Sea Catholic School, it was all about long pants, long-sleeved shirts and some very cranky nuns. So my first day in Year 3 at Maroochydore Primary School was a culture shock. You could wear what you liked: shoes were optional and uniforms were only worn when school photos were being taken.
The first kids I met were our neighbours in the Cotton Tree Caravan Park: the Meningas. Mal, Geoff, Cameron and Bevan Meninga and their parents, Norm and Leonie, were great people and Geoff and Cameron are still mates of mine today.
We rode our bikes to school on dirt roads and through the canefields where the Sunshine Plaza is now. There were no helmets in those days.
The principal was Mr Christ, who lived on the school grounds in an old Queenslander. He was the good cop and a lovely man. The deputy head was Kevin Aspland. He was the bad cop who terrified us but in reality he had to and I got to know him in later years and found he was also a good man.
Life was pretty simple at school in the early 1970s. We played rugby league before and after school in the winter, cricket in the summer and surfing all-year round. Red rover and brandy were popular in the schoolyard.
Teachers had a lot more freedom to "read it how they saw it". Certainly different to the politics and control methods of today.
One memorable day I was playing cricket at lunchtime and big Monkey Mullens and I had a disagreement over a decision and decided to biff it out. Ron McMullin, who has a cricket oval named after him, caught us and gave us a lesson in how to throw a proper punch, then told us to get back to the game.
Ron Hegarty was a great teacher and a good bloke who would sneak up behind you when you were talking in class and and hit you in the middle of the back, saying "shut up Abbott!".
Mrs Theiss was a teacher not to be messed with and once threw Gavin Haylock (now sadly deceased) out of a window and onto the oval.
The teachers were all a good bunch and names that come to mind are Chris Dunk (soccer tragic and great guy), Mr Capper, Mrs Jackson and Mr Berry.
School athletic carnivals were great and we would compete in everything. We all did "the scissors" in the high jump, landing in sawdust. That was unless you were Allan "Spud" Dievers, who only had one foot and would run straight at the bar and dive over it.
We had a couple of gangs in primary school: "Spud and The Potato People" and "Dookie's Warriors". No one got really hurt when we fought. It was just practice for later in life.
I met my now wife, Kerri Schonknecht, in Year 3 and we had our first kiss playing spin the bottle at Colin "Chooky" Nielson's party.
There were far too many kids to remember but some have stuck in my mind.
Roland "Razz" Rasmussen was a surfing buddy and we would ride our bikes along the beach between Alexandra Headland and Maroochydore looking for the best wave, which we would then have to ourselves.
Peter "Stick" Holmes was also a good mate. His dad Harvey was the school groundsman.
Craig "Macca" McKenzie was also a mate. His mum and dad owned the takeaway next to the "fun parlour" in Cotton Tree when pinball was 10 cents and pool 20 cents a game. We spent lots of time there when we probably should have been doing homework.
Mark "Fat Mac" McDonald was a good bloke and managed to be one of the best golfers on the Coast. The police let him drive at 15 so he could take his dad to Brisbane to see his sick brother.
Graeme "Goob" Dobere was a motorbike fanatic who is still on the Coast and still riding bikes.
Peter Walsh was another good friend who I didn't see for years and now he's manager of my son's Maroochydore Rugby League Football Club side - the same place we started playing footy in 1972.
Tim McKee, who won the school fancy dress party hands dwn when he turned up as Paul Hogan, is now a school teacher on the Coast.
Brad Lawson was a Golden Gloves boxing champion who came to Maroochydore Primary in Year Seven. He could run faster than all of us and could also fight, so he became my best mate.
In my first year at Maroochydore High School, we met heaps of new mates as there was only one private school on the Coast and we had a big pool of new kids from Buderim and Mooloolaba primary schools.
We had to wear shoes and uniforms had stepped up a little as we had two choices: standard shirt and shorts or black stubbies and a yellow T-shirt.
Surfing is now a subject at school and it was for us back then, only we didn't tell the teachers.
High school seemed massive. There were lots of big dudes but I was lucky as I knew a lot of them and soon got into the groove playing rugby league with Jeff "Fanga" Treloar, Greg "Oxy" Oxenham, Craig Cornwall, Geoff Meninga and others. Playing senior footy in Year 8 wasn't pretty, it was plain scary!
Our swimming carnivals were great fun and were held at Nambour, where Duke Sherwell had the only 25m pool in the area. My claim to fame is coming second to Grant Kenny in a 50m freestyle race but the reality was that as I turned at the 25m mark, he was getting out of the water at the 50m.
We were the first students to do a subject called Study of Society with a new-wave teacher called Jules Johnston. She was groovy and fun.
The boys in Year 9 were trialled in home economics with Mrs Hastings. The first job was an apple crumble, which was not a good look and the trial failed.
Teachers who come to mind include Milton Hasthorpe (Earth Science) who was a terrific bloke and could hit you with a piece of chalk from 20 metres. Sadly, he has since passed away.
Danny Boyle was a PE teacher and a pocket rocket who could play or do anything. He's another one who is no longer with us.
Peter Haskas was also a PE teacher and a good man who still lives on the Coast.
Allan "Keg" Clarke taught us biology and chemistry. He was a rugby union legend and I see him often.
Kay Phillips taught PE and was a good sort who all the boys loved.
Daryl Leethar taught manual arts and coached rugby league while Mrs Hasouras was my form teacher and the most beautiful creature in the world.
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Aspland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Cornwall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dievers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Capper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ron Hegarty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Meninga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milton Hasthorpe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dobere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ron McMullin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Haylock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim McKee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hastings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monkey Mullens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jules Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Lawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Theiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Razz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hasouras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Dunk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rasmussen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earth Science</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Haskas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spud</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meningas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nielson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Study of Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fat Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Christ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke Sherwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daryl Leethar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Glove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kay Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dookie's Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fanga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerri Schonknecht</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Rugby League Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treloar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chooky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Potato People</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Star of the Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree Caravan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bevan Meninga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Kenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
