<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409436510035980</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/moreton/osprey-pair-in-race-to-rebuild-nest-at-deception-bay-after-strong-winds-blew-it-away/news-story/89bbaea057900ec10ba119a233b100c4</url>
  <title>Clock ticks for lovebirds</title>
  <content>
THESE ospreys are in a race against time to rebuild their nest so they can breed after strong winds blew it away. Keen birdwatchers say they are giving it a red hot go.
The well-known nest at Deception Bay, north of Brisbane, was blown away in June to the dismay of nearby residents who enjoy watching the birds return to mate and raise their young each year.
Osprey House volunteer Pip Grant-Taylor said many residents feared the birds would not be back this year and were thrilled to see the male osprey, named Andy, return.
This year he has a new mate, they have named Brandy, and the pair is busy creating a home for potential offspring but the clock is ticking.
"They are rebuilding it with great speed," she said.
Ms Grant-Taylor is checking the nest twice a week, but has several residents in the nearby nursing home and aged care complex keeping a watchful eye on things.
She said she was not sure if the birds would have enough time to finish the nest, mate and raise their young before the usual deadline in September. The dedicated observer said the typical gestation period was 35-39 days.
"The nest has been there for 20 or so years and added to by a few different pairs over those years. Although I don't have figures it has been successful at producing chicks, indeed one chick successfully fledged and flew with its parents for summer break at the end of last year," she said.
Ospreys are medium-sized fish-eating raptors, or birds or prey, and are protected by law.
Ms Grant-Taylor has started a so residents can keep track of the birds' progress.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deception Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pip Grant-Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Grant-Taylor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Osprey House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ospreys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
