<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409784402393033</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/president-trump-personally-dictated-statement-on-russia-meeting-according-to-reports/news-story/5ac00e228e5a394857b71c68654770a7</url>
  <title>What Trump said on Air Force One</title>
  <content>
EXACTLY what President Trump said on Air Force One could prove problematic following reports he drafted a controversial statement for his son about a meeting with a Russian lawyer.
reports the President "personally dictated" a statement for his Donald Junior to explain the subject of the June 2016 meeting that also included Jared Kushner and then campaign manager Paul Manafort.
The statement was in response to a New York Times request for information about the meeting,
It ultimately led to Donald Jr releasing an email chain showing him say he would "love" to hear out a Russian offer of sensitive and high-level information about Hillary Clinton.
claims the President worked with aide Hope Hicks and his son on the statement while flying back from the G20 summit in Hamburg last month.
Donald Jr's initial reply to the New York Times said he "primarily discussed a program about the adoption of Russian children".
However, he was forced to clarify this three times before eventually releasing the entire email trail, sparking major debate over whether it amounted to a conspiracy to collude with Russia in the election campaign.
The Post cited reports the President's involvement was "unnecessary" and said it could leave him vulnerable to allegations of obstruction of justice.
"Now someone can claim he's the one who attempted to mislead. Somebody can argue the President is saying he doesn't want you to say the whole truth," a source told the paper.
Contact between members of the Trump team and Russian officials is currently the subject of a special investigation led by special counsel Robert Mueller, who was appointed after Trump fired FBI Director James Comey.
Trump has repeatedly denied working with Russia and called it a "witch hunt" against him. He also praised his son Don Jr, for his honesty and character in releasing the emails.
His lawyers told the Washington Post the accusations are of "no consequence" and "misinformed".
Lawyers for Trump Jr said drafting the statement was a "communal situation" that "involved communications people and various lawyers."
On Tuesday, President Trump addressed claims a new order would be imposed in the White House following the appointment of General John Kelly as Chief of Staff.
"Only the Fake News Media and Trump enemies want me to stop using Social Media (110 million people). Only way for me to get the truth out!" he tweeted.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Media (110</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Manafort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillary Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake News Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hope Hicks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Jr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI Director James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Force One</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Junior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
