<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409737157751989</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/tv-shows/big-bang-theory-spinoff-more-details-revealed-about-young-sheldon/news-story/423360c6b533daccf08f4308e2246c9d</url>
  <title>'Big Bang Theory' spin-off: More details revealed about 'Young Sheldon'</title>
  <content>
TV Trailer: Young Sheldon
5:15

CBS has released a preview clip of their 'Big Bang Theory' spin-off 'Young Sheldon'. Courtesy: CBS

May 18th 2017
2 months ago
/video/video.news.com.au/Entertainment/

Big Little Lies star Iain Armitage stars as Young Sheldon.

Blanche JohnsonFox News

Share

THE Big Bang Theory and Sheldon Cooper fans learned more about the highly-anticipated prequel series Young Sheldon at the Television Critics Press Association press tour.
Young Sheldon will feature a single-camera set up and focus on Jim Parson's character's childhood. The Big Bang Theory has been a ratings superstar for CBS, and Executive Producer Chuck Lorre said the pressure is on for the spin-off show.
"I'm a nervous wreck," he said.
"It's an entirely different animal. It's a wholly different way to tell a story, and the working process is very different. It's much slower ... I think the pacing is obviously very different."
The spin-off follows nine-year-old Sheldon Cooper living with his family in Texas and going to school.
"We're going to show there was a great deal more to the man than we discussed over the years on Big Bang," Lorre promised.
Lorre added, "We have a lot of freedom with the backstory."
The seasoned producer also revealed that The Big Bang Theory spin-off drew inspiration from another hit show: The Wonder Years.
"We absolutely discussed Wonder Years when we were writing," Lorre said.

"I've never worked with narration before and narration changes the way you write. We looked for inspiration that used it beautifully and no one did it better than The Wonder Years."

Iain Armitage, front left, a cast member in Young Sheldon, answers a question as executive producer/narrator Jim Parsons, front right, looks on during a panel discussion at the 2017 Television Critics Association Press Tour.Source:AP
Parsons also spoke about Young Sheldon and the actor had a hard time putting in to words just what it felt like to have an entire spin-off series based on his loveably neurotic character, Sheldon Cooper.
"It was a moving experience to me to see something I've put a decade of my life toward [come to this]," Parsons said.
"I never felt, in the 10 years that we worked on the Big show, that ... I can't talk! You don't think you're putting together these kinds of things that will add up to something like [a prequel]."
Iain Armitage plays young Sheldon, and Parsons revealed to Fox News he shared some advice with Armitage's family once he noticed just how much buzz the series was getting.
"When I saw the marketing and all the posters with Iain's face on them, I texted [Iain's mum] immediately, 'prepare.'"
He said of the Armitage family, "I think they are prepared."
During the press panel, Parsons was asked if he was similar to the young Sheldon Cooper character, who is nine on the series. The 44-year-old actor, who is gay, said he wasn't much like Sheldon at that age.

Executive producers/co-creators Chuck Lorre and Steven Molaro of Young Sheldon speak onstage.Source:Getty Images
"I didn't befuddle my parents ... that came much later with my sexuality," he told reporters.
After 10 seasons of The Big Bang Theory, Parsons knows the ins-and-outs of playing the quirky Sheldon Cooper, and he said he was able to give Iain some advice about the brilliant, eccentric physicist he plays on Big Bang.
"One of the hardest things for someone like Iain playing the character is Iain is so empathetic to other people and so in tune to other people's needs and ... those are great qualities to have, but in this particular character you almost have to let them play under the surface," he said of Sheldon Cooper.
Young Sheldon premieres in the US on September 25th after the Season 11 premiere of The Big Bang Theory on CBS.
No word yet on when it will air in Australia.
This article was originally published on
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iain Armitage</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bang</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chuck Lorre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blanche JohnsonFox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Lies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Producer Chuck Lorre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheldon Cooper</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Television Critics Association Press Tour.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheldon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wonder Years</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Bang Theory</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Sheldon</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Season 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armitage</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorre</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Television Critics Press Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bang Theory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iain</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Parson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parsons</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Molaro of Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV Trailer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
