<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409698503045473</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4819187/fresh-from-the-garden/?cs=2373</url>
  <title>Fresh from the garden</title>
  <content>
IN BLOOM: A Delicious Bunch by Linda Brennan is out now, RRP $39.99. For further information on edible flowers visit ecobotanica.com.au.

Edible flowers are proof that we eat with our eyes first. One horticulturalist and keen cook is taking it one step further, though, and making them the hero of a dish. 
Linda Brennan is the author of  A Delicious Bunch: Growing and cooking with edible flowers. She spent her childhood wandering the bush with her parents, picking wild foods, harvesting honey and growing vegetables and fruit in the family garden in Gippsland, Victoria.
She has lectured in food, environment and sustainability and even developed an edible garden program for primary schools. Her book is part gardening guide and part recipe book and, she says, the first that talks specifically about what can be grown here in Australia. 

"For centuries the Chinese have eaten daylilies, the Egyptians roses, the South Americans yucca flowers and bougainvillea, while the English and French enjoyed elderflower and violets," she told Food & Wine.

"I think the popularity of edible flowers today is in part due to the desire for stunning presentation. I'd like to see more edible flowers used as the key ingredient in a dish rather than the pretty decoration that we look at then push to one side of the plate."
Brennan has developed flower-based recipes like the lavendar shortcake and banana bell sambol over many years of running gardening and food classes. 

"I tend to enjoy growing perennials as they are easy to grow and care for and as a cook I love a whole range of savoury and sweet flowers. My favourites would have to include torch ginger; elderflower made into fritters; cornflowers, especially when crystallised as they taste so richly perfumed; and banana bell flower for its exotic uses in curries and salads."
You can't just choose a flower at random to cook with, though. Do your homework first.

"A misconception is that foraged food is pure and clean. Think twice about foraging for edible flowers from roadsides, drains and parks as these can be areas of highly concentrated toxins," Brennan said. 

"You need a positive identification before putting anything to your mouth. Some commonly-grown flowers that should never be eaten include agapanthus, azaleas, duranta, oleander and angels trumpet. One oleander flower may be enough to kill a child. The inedible ones usually do taste awful but it may not always be the case."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>South American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linda Brennan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gippsland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Egyptian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brennan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delicious Bunch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RRP $39.99</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
