<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409462279840225</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/private-schools-making-a-mark-on-the-coast/3206109/</url>
  <title>Private schools making a mark on the Coast</title>
  <content>
WHILE the Sunshine Coast has long enjoyed a reputation for providing excellent education, it is only in more recent years that large private schools have made their mark.
Two examples are Matthew Flinders Anglican College and Sunshine Coast Grammar, which were not even thought of when the Sunshine Coast adopted its new name 50 years ago.
Matthew Flinders had its genesis in 1988, when a sub-committee was formed under the Rural Deanery on the Sunshine Coast, with the view of starting an Anglican school.
In April 1988, Rod Forrester was elected chairman by the parish representatives and led a feasibility study before an application was lodged with the federal government for approval to develop a school catering for students from pre-school to Year 12.
On approval, the search began to find a name for the new school - something that would reflect the principles and standards the students would strive to uphold.
In September 1988, the school was officially named Matthew Flinders Anglican College. A site was located, the land was purchased and construction began in September 1989.
Enrolments opened and within one month, the college had more than 200 children registered. It opened in January 1990 with an enrolment of 161 students in Years 5-8.
Six years later, Sunshine Coast Grammar School came to public attention, with the laying of its first foundation stone.
In 1997, it opened its doors to around 300 students in Years 1-7 and the following year added pre-school and Year 8.
Grammar's first Year 12 Students graduated in 2002.
The school has continued to grow at a rapid rate, with a Leaf Early Learning Centre opening its doors in 2006 to cater for children from six weeks to school age.
Its latest milestone project, the Grammar Aquatic Centre, will soon become a reality.
The largest capital project in the history of the school, it will provide a world class, 10-lane, 50m FINA-certified heated swimming pool as well as an enclosed 15m learn-to-swim pool, a 700-seat undercover grandstand, a gymnasium, tennis centre, classrooms, change rooms and a kiosk.
Matthew Flinders has also continued to grow and now has a student population of 1320 from Prep to Year 12.
It has built an enviable reputation upon its students' academic performance, their commitment to personal achievement, coupled with their involvement in sports and the arts.
An Early Learning Centre caters for 124 of the youngest in the community of learners as the school focuses on preparing students for a life "beyond the school gates".
Grammar, too, is planning for the future and has embraced a vision for powerful learning, by helping its students become ethical, responsible and caring citizens of the world, with a digital mindset for the future.
In 2013, it launched its digital 1:1 technology program, which means students have iPads, laptops, iwatches and iPods at their fingertips. Many free online coding resources offer students the opportunity to explore and create imaginary worlds online to share and play with other children from their classes or even across the globe.
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Grammar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Early Learning Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Grammar School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grammar Aquatic Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Flinders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FINA-certified</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1988</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1989</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 12 Students</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Forrester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Flinders Anglican College</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 12</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leaf Early Learning Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rural Deanery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 1988</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
