<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409698503045440</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/05/41/brisbane-bus-drivers-to-strike-again-today-amid-ongoing-pay-dispute</url>
  <title>Brisbane bus drivers to strike again today amid ongoing pay dispute</title>
  <content>
Further transport delays are expected across Brisbane as council bus drivers walk off the job for the fourth time in three weeks today over an ongoing pay dispute.
After negotiations failed over safety, rostering and pay rates, the Rail, Tram and Bus Union (RTBU) advised Brisbane City Council some drivers will take industrial action between 10am and 2pm today.
A rally of workers from several unions, including the ETU, CFMEU and AWU, is expected at King George Square from midday.
The RTBU and the council have held several meetings in recent weeks but have failed to agree on wages, work hours and safety measures for drivers.

It comes after half of the council's drivers went on strike between 2pm and 6pm on Friday, leaving commuters stranded and forcing them to find alternative transport home. Bus drivers also walked off the job for two hours last Tuesday and Wednesday.

The RTBU has been negotiating for safer buses, a wage increase and a new roster, and each party has accused the other of stalling in the protracted negotiations.

A six-hour meeting between the council and the union on Thursday failed to resolve a dispute over pay and conditions that saw drivers stop work twice the week before last.

Related Articles

Deputy Mayor Adrian Schrinner said he was "losing confidence" an agreement would be reached, and of instances of abuse from union drivers who abused employees who continued to work during the strike.

"Obviously that's not on," he told the Daily Telegraph.

Bus services are likely to be affected until almost 3pm when services begin to return to normal.

Translink's seven tips for a smoother commute
- Travel outside the afternoon peak.

- Consider another mode (such as train or ferry) if available to you. There will be additional CityCat services - see details below.

- Allow more time to get to your destination.

- Journey Planner and real-time through the app may be unreliable for BCC bus service information.

- Other bus transport providers will operate as normal, but may experience crowding.

- Consider walking or cycling to reach your destination.

- Avoid unnecessary travel or consider working from home.

A full list of affected services can be found . For more information on how to get around today, visit .
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Mayor Adrian Schrinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TransLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CityCat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
