<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409741452719404</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/markets/us-could-put-a-50year-bond-on-its-refunding-schedule-20170801-gxng4l.html</url>
  <title>US could put a 50-year bond on its refunding schedule</title>
  <content>
The US government's refunding schedule wildcard this week will be if the US Treasury Department gives any indications on whether it will issue a longer-dated debt maturity.
The Treasury said in May it was considering issuing an ultra-long bond, with a maturity of 50-years seen as most likely, or reviving a 20-year issue that was abandoned in 1986.Photo: Jim Young
An ultra-long bond would fit in with the Treasury's objective to fund the US government at the lowest cost over time.
"The big event this week is the refunding on Wednesday (tomorrow)," said Blake Gwinn, an interest rate strategist at NatWest Markets in Stamford, Connecticut. "You could potentially get some move forward on a commitment to ultra-long issuance, or at least some further guidance on what they're thinking there."
Plans to increase longer-dated debt would likely send thirty-year bond yields higher and steepen the US yield curve.
Depending on the size of the issuance, a sufficient amount of ultra-long bonds could also lengthen the average maturity of the US government's marketable securities, said Marc Chandler, global head of currency strategy at Brown Brothers Harriman in New York.

The average maturity of US government debt at the end of June was a record 71 months, up from 49 months at the end of 2008.
Market participants will also be watching for information on how the government plans to increase debt issuance to make up for the Federal Reserve's declining bond purchases.
A Reuters poll of primary dealers last week showed that Wall Street's top banks expect the Fed to announce a date when it will kick off the reduction of its $US4.5 trillion balance sheet after its meeting on September 19-20.
The refunding announcement will be made on Wednesday at 8.30am in Washington.
The Fed buys debt in addition to that offered in US Treasury auctions, and as it backs away, the government will need to increase debt sales to the public to make up the difference.
Analysts expect - at least initially - the Treasury will issue shorter-term debt to make up for declining Fed participation, which should be readily absorbed.
Money fund reforms have increased inflows into funds that only invest in Treasury bills, which gives the government room to boost bill issuance without market disruption.
"There is a ton of capacity to issue bills," said Michael Cloherty, head of US rates strategy at RBC Capital Markets in New York. "And in that case there's not a lot of duration flowing into the market, so it will have very little market impact.
The Fed has said it will take a slow approach to tapering purchases, setting the initial cap for the reduction of Treasury holdings at $US6 billion per month and raising it in $US6 billion increments every three months over a 12-month period until it reaches $US30 billion per month.
The Treasury in recent years has cut public auction sizes of short- and intermediate-dated coupon debt, which gives it room to ramp them back up to make up for the Fed's declining participation.
The government's debt issuance will be restricted in the coming quarter as it bumps up against the debt ceiling. The Congressional Budget Office has said US lawmakers need to raise the debt ceiling by mid-October to avoid defaulting on debt payments.
The Treasury said on Monday that it expects to borrow $US96 billion in the third quarter, but that is expected to swell to $US501 billion in the fourth quarter as the government replenishes its cash levels in the aftermath of the expected debt ceiling standoff.
Longer-term, the Treasury will face rising cash needs from an aging population and as the Fed accelerates its balance sheet reduction, with financing needs expected to jump in the second half of 2018.
That will mean that the government will have to increase longer-dated debt sales to make up the difference.
"Over time they are going to have to issue further out the curve," said Subadra Rajappa, head of US interest rate strategy at Societe Generale in New York. "They have to issue more because of the Fed reinvestments and because the (budget) deficits are poised to rise regardless."
If a new debt issue is on the cards, it would make sense to announce it at this week's refunding. That would give the market time to prepare for its introduction and have initial test sales before the bonds are needed, said NatWest's Gwinn.
"The funding gap really starts to grow in late 2018, but you don't want to wait until that happens to start issuing for it," Gwinn said. "You want to roll that out in a calm market, when you are not jacking up the auction sizes along the rest of the curve."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Societe Generale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US501</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US4.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Treasury Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Treasuries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subadra Rajappa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$ 6</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gwinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NatWest's Gwinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NatWest Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cloherty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown Brothers Harriman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Congressional Budget Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stamford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Chandler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBC Capital Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Gwinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connecticut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$96</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
