<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409651258404428</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/coroner-critical-of-care-agencies-following-teenage-girls-overdose-death-20170801-gxn20g.html</url>
  <title>Coroner critical of care agencies following teenage girl's overdose death</title>
  <content>
On the night before she died, 16-year-old Maria Liordos​ showed up at her care unit looking severely drug affected then left with her partner to visit a man at his home nearby.
Workers at the unit did not enact the crisis plan devised for the at-risk teen, which including calling an ambulance or police. Photo: ABC
Less than 12 hours later, Maria was found dead in the man's home from a drug overdose. It was the morning of September 24, 2013, two days after her 16th birthday.
The inquest into Maria's death uncovered a "litany of adverse incidents" related to the Salvation Army's Westcare, the agency which ran the St Albans care unit where Maria lived. They included Maria's allegations she was sexually assaulted and supplied drugs by staff.
The teenager was living at the care unit because of her drug and alcohol problems, her criminal behaviour and history of absconding and self-harm. In 2011 she disclosed a history of being sexually abused, and in 2013 she was diagnosed with Hepatitis C.
Given her vulnerabilities, the coroner who investigated Maria's death on Tuesday found the teenager was let down by Westcare and the government department responsible for Victoria's most troubled children.

Coroner Audrey Jamieson said the Department of Health and Human Services and Westcare both failed to protect Maria even though she was the subject of a specific crisis plan.
An inquest last year heard three Westcare staff who were working that night never called for an ambulance to treat Maria, did not enact the crisis plan specifically devised for the teen and failed to call police and request an arrest warrant.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Ms Jamieson said while two of the workers -  the one who had direct contact with the teen and the colleague on the next shift - were relatively inexperienced in their roles and did not know about Maria's crisis plan, there was a "dereliction of care" from the third staff member given she was the case manager and was contacted as the on-call worker that night.
"There is a dearth of evidence that she took any meaningful action to keep Maria safe on the night of 23 September, 2013," Ms Jamieson said of the case manager.
The coroner said though the DHHS and Westcare did not cause Maria's death, the department failed to ensure Westcare provided the care it should have, and the agency did not train its staff properly.
"Both organisations failed to achieve any of the significant goals for Maria, including reunification with her family, reform and rehabilitation and her substance misuse, and significantly, to keep her safe from her own behaviours," Ms Jamieson said.
The department, the coroner said, could not be absolved of its responsibilities by contracting out the job of caring for troubled teenagers.
"The department cannot totally divest itself of its responsibilities to the state's most vulnerable children merely by contracting intensive case management to another agency," she said.
Ms Jamieson recommended the department review its after-hours emergency system and ensure care agencies had the right contact numbers.
Ms Jamieson said Westcare had since reviewed its methods and implemented risk prevention measures and self-assessments.
A DHHS spokesman said the department extended its sympathies to Maria's family.
The department took the safety and wellbeing of young people very seriously, the spokesman said, and would implement each of the coroner's recommendations.
"The department is fully committed to sharing information with government agencies and community service organisations to ensure the safety of vulnerable children and young people in our care," he said.
The Salvation Army has been contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coroner Audrey Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jamieson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria Liordos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westcare</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army's Westcare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hepatitis C</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Albans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
