<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408933998853305</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/theranos-walgreens-settlement-2017-8</url>
  <title>Theranos just settled its lawsuit with Walgreens</title>
  <content>
Theranos just reached a settlement with its former biggest partner.

The settlement dismisses the lawsuit, concluding that there was "no finding or implication of liability."

In November 2016, Walgreens filed a $US140 million lawsuit against Theranos, accusing Theranos of a breach of contract. Walgreens had ended its relationship with Theranos a few months prior  2016. It had operated Theranos Wellness Centres, where people could go have their blood tested in the company's stores.

Until October 2016, Theranos's business model was based around the idea that it ran blood tests using proprietary technology that requires only a small amount of blood. Since then, the company has pivoted to focus solely on the company's miniLab technology and is considering renting out its headquarters in .

The settlement with Walgreens is the last in a series of major settlements between Theranos and investors, as well as the state of Arizona.

On April 17, , the government agency responsible for regulating blood-testing labs. As part of the settlement, Theranos has to pay $US30,000, and the company won't be able to own or operate a clinical lab within the next two years. In return, the CMS is no longer revoking Theranos's CLIA certification, which is needed to run a blood-testing lab.

On April 18, Theranos  to refund anyone who paid to take one of Theranos's blood tests, and will also pay $US225,000 to cover civil penalties and attorneys' fees.

And on May 1, Theranos  with Partner Fund Management, a hedge fund that invested $US96.1 million in the company.

Theranos has been under fire since October 2015 after the Journal published  that questioned the accuracy of its blood test. Eventually, one of the company's lab-testing locations was shut down, and its founder - Elizabeth Holmes - was originally barred for two years from running a clinical lab, , the government agency responsible for regulating blood-testing labs by agreeing to not own or operate a clinical lab within the next two years.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$140</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US96.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arizona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Partner Fund Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theranos</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walgreens</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theranos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>miniLab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US225,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theranos Wellness Centres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theranos's CLIA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$30,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
