<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409780107425676</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/sport/usain-bolts-plan-is-to-retire-undefeated-unbeatable/news-story/8af60f4f218eb3b8ffc3b1bb5c290c5c</url>
  <title>Bolt's plan: retire undefeated</title>
  <content>
There is one headline that Usain Bolt wants to see splashed across the world's media after he concludes his career at the world championships in London next week. "Unbeatable''.
At his pre-championships press conference in London, Bolt said that he wanted to retire undefeated over 100m in the major championships.
He has not lost a global final in the 100m since he exploded onto the scene in 2008.
In nine years, he has accumulated eight Olympic gold medals and 11 world titles and he plans to run his last individual race in the 100m final on Saturday night. The only blemish on his record is his disqualification for a false start before the 100m final at the 2011 world championships in Daegu.
Bolt said that before every season he came up with a goal for the year to motivate him, and this year's ambition was to be declared "unbeatable''.
"Usain Bolt has retired unbeatable in individual events,'' he said.
"For me that will be the headline. Unbeatable, unstoppable.''
Bolt's early season form was far from impressive but he seemed to be finding his speed at the Monaco Diamond League ten days ago where he broke 10 seconds for the first time this year, clocking 9.95 sec.
And he insisted today that he was ready to defend his titles.
"Yeah, without a doubt,'' he said.
"If I show up for the championships, if I'm here, you know I'm fully confident and ready to go."
The young Canadian Andre De Grasse, who won the bronze medal in the 100m and silver in the 200m at last year's Rio Olympics, is widely regarded as the greatest threat to Bolt's supremacy in London.
In Rio last year, they appeared to be developing a playfully competitive relationship but that has soured in recent weeks.
De Grasse's coach Stuart McMillan claimed his athlete had been "booted out'' of the Monaco meet because Bolt wanted "not such an elite field against him''.
Bolt's management denied the accusation but it has clearly rankled Bolt.
After Rio, he said the future of sprinting was "in good hands'' with De Grasse, but today he was asked to nominate who he thought would be the next great sprinter after him, and he declined.
"I'm not going down that road,'' he said.
"The last guy I said was going to be great disrespected me so I'm not going to say who's going to be great. I'm going to leave it to whoever shows up and is willing to fill my shoes.''
Asked specifically about the state of his relationship with De Grasse, Bolt said: "I see him around I say "Hi'', that's it, I guess. I don't have his number or anything.''
Asked if De Grasse would be his main challenger in London, he played a straight bat his junior cricket coach would have been proud of in the days when Bolt wanted to play cricket rather than run faster than anyone in history.
"Seven people who are going to be in that race, they are going to be my best challengers'' he said.
And of De Grasse: "In the past he's won a bronze medal, he's won a silver medal. It shows that he has talent, so we will see what happens in the future. It's all about consistency.''
Bolt appeared a trifle miffed that he was not the favourite to win his fourth world 100m title on Saturday night.
"For some reason, I'm the underdog again,'' he said.
"That's what I keep reading and what my team keep telling me. I've got to prove myself once more.''
And what if the unthinkable happens and Bolt loses? One of his countrymen asked him if he would reconsider retirement if he was beaten, to which he chided his questioner.
"The Jamaican is going to ask me that question ... it's not going to happen so we won't have that problem, don't worry.''
"The last race I ran was 9.95 and showed that I'm going in the right direction. I'm going forward, I'm not worried. It's a championship, it's a final, it's all about who can hold their nerve, who is ready to challenge. I've been here many times and I know I'm ready. It's go time.''
At the end of the conference, Bolt's parents Wellesley and Jennifer presented him with his final pair of championship spikes. They are gold and purple, with Forever Fastest written on them.
Bolt explained that the purple was his school colour. The gold requires no explanation.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian Andre De Grasse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WELLESLEY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grasse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Grasse</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daegu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forever Fastest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart McMillan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
