<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409750042654128</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/penis-enlargement-surgery-death-sparks-warning/3207695/</url>
  <title>Penis enlargement surgery death sparks warning</title>
  <content>
A HEALTHY young man in Sweden has died during penis enlargement surgery which involved injecting fat from his stomach into his penis.

Fears are growing for the safety of the procedure after the fluid injected into the perfectly healthy 30-year-old's manhood to boost girth began leaking.

The fat then travelled all the way to his lungs, resulting in an embolism that in turn ruptured blood vessels, according to a study published in the Journal of Forensic Sciences.

Within minutes the patient, who had no previous heart conditions, had a cardiac arrest.

Despite CPR he died two hours later.

The study said: "This is the first described case where a seemingly simple and safe procedure of penis enlargement by autologous fat transfer caused sudden death in a healthy young man".

Urologist Tobias Kohler, of the Mayo Clinic, who was not involved in this study, told BuzzFeed that one reason many advise against the "completely useless" surgery, is because it "never works" and because of "other horrible consequences, from disfigurement to permanent erectile dysfunction to even worse".

In April last year, a fake doctor in New Jersey was jailed for five years after performing the botched penis enlargement surgery that killed 22-year-old Justin Street.

Authorities said the lethal injection shot directly into Street's bloodstream, shutting down his vital organs and leading to his death the following day.

A medical examiner found the young man died from a silicone embolism - a rare complication of cosmetic surgery - and has ruled his 2011 death was homicide.

As reported by Norman Rowe, a board-certified surgeon, a 10-minute Botox-style procedure can add 1.5 inches to the circumference of a man's member.

NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
THERE have been major changes in education since 1967.
Noosaville man killed in five-car fatal smash on Bruce Hwy
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tobias Kohler of the Mayo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Journal of Forensic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BuzzFeed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botox-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
