<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409449394938077</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/memories-of-happy-days-in-a-school-now-gone/3206085/</url>
  <title>Memories of happy days in a school now gone</title>
  <content>
GROWING up on a 40ha sugar cane farm on Dunethin Rock Rd, Maroochy River, my childhood was a very happy, simple, adventurous and cherished time.
I was born in December 1960 and my family - Bill and Beryl O'Hanlon and my younger brothers Kerry and Daren - were part of a small, tight-knit farming community. Maroochy River State Primary School was the heart of that community.
There were not (and still aren't) any shops at Maroochy River. Farmers drove to Yandina to do their shopping at Mr Duck's general store, which was a treasure trove of grocery supplies, farm tools, sewing materials and more. That building is now the Yandina Art Gallery and Dunethin Rock Rd is now called Yandina-Bli Bli Rd.
Many farmers during that era supplemented their cane income with other crops such as beans, bananas or pineapples. My folks always had a big bean patch growing in a paddock right on the banks of the Maroochy River.
I remember very clearly as a four-year-old in 1965 helping my folks pick beans and stack them in thinly-woven hessian bags with our surname stenciled in black paint on the front. I looked up from the bean rows and watched a boat pull up on our side of the river and drop a young girl off at the neighbour's wharf - she had a school port in her hands.
"That's the school boat," my folks said. "Next year, Wendy Jane, you will also catch that boat when you start school."
Well, I was so excited ... but I missed that boat! The daily school boat service (which in past decades also delivered mail, milk and bread to the farmers) had begun operating in 1917 but was discontinued at the end of 1965, with only six students using the service.
I started Grade 1 in 1966. Totally missed the boat!
Maroochy River State Primary School was opened as a Provisional school on June 27, 1911. It was built on a slight hill on the south bank of the Maroochy River near Dunethin Lake and had a huge "oval" where we would play rounders, Red rover and practise athletics for the annual regional carnival.
It was the site of an old Aboriginal shell midden. With the river and lake nearby, this was a perfect feasting and gathering place.
The school population always swelled during the six-month cane season when itinerant cane-cutters would move to our region with their families and stay in cane barracks - a "must-have" for many farms back then. The main families when I was at school were (as I remember) the Atkinsons, the Pages, the Huttons, the Walshes, the Cerins, the Flowers and the O'Hanlons.
I only remember the school as having about 15 students at most - sometimes about 30 during the cane season.
My only teacher was Neville Hegarty, who was the principal at this little one-teacher school during my entire primary schooling. He lived in the school residence next door and had actually attended the school as a student with my uncle Geoff.
He had a great respect for the indigenous people who had called the region home for thousands of years.
Mr Hegarty would lead our little school on treks in the surrounding bush and around Dunethin Rock, where we would discover rock paintings and chiseled stones. We left everything where we found it.
Some of my clearest memories of attending Maroochy River State School include my dad taking the whole school to swimming lessons at Nambour's Blue Pacific Swimming Pool in the back of his ute.
Warm milk was delivered in bottles every school morning and on Mondays we held parade to God Save the Queen.
I remember our school trip to the new Bli Bli Castle and being invited to Bli Bli's school oval to welcome Mt Everest climber Sir Edmund Hillary on his Queensland tour. I raised my hand and asked him the question: "Did you ever see a Yeti?" He said he saw what might have been a Yeti - leaving hope for a wide-eyed girl. This was surely an early indication that I would later forge a career as a journalist.
I was always running around in bare feet. We did not have a school uniform but we did have a purple and yellow sports bib with the capital letters M.R. emblazoned on the front for when we competed in the regional primary school athletics.
One year, we had so few students that our school could not even field a 10-member tunnel ball team - but my brother Kerry and I won our sprint races, thus amassing enough points that our school came second-last on the points table. Phew!
Tuesday and Thursday afternoons were singing lessons, when we would tune into ABC radio. The whole school would gather around this big brown box of a radio positioned at the front of our one-room classroom. In our outspread hands were our Queensland Government Let's Sing music books. And sing we did!
I remember walking to Dunethin Lake and the river wharf for excursions, skipping along the train lines in the vine forest between the lake and the dirt road.
I had my poem The House on the Hill published in the Queensland Schools Magazine when I was 10. "... an eremite once took refuge there; sore was he when he could not bear; the cold, rough winds that rushed everywheres; through doorways, windows and under the stairs...". The Queensland school inspector later visited our school and asked me how a 10-year-old even knew what an "eremite" was. The same poem was published in The Sunday Mail later that year!
While there were cards and stickers to collect in Kelloggs' cornflakes packets, our little school was engrossed in another collection: gathering as many cane tickets as possible from the area's cane-farming families.
Each farmer had their own tickets clearly showing their surnames which were affixed to the cane stick trucks before going to the Moreton Mill in Nambour. My brother Kerry and I (and our black dog Sammy) would often spend an afternoon hitching a ride on the cane loco.
The loco drivers (I remember Mr Plater) invited us to join them up front in the cabin and we would actually cross the Maroochy River to the east as they delivered the empty cane trucks back to the farms. This gave Kerry and me a huge advantage in collecting family tickets from farms across the river as well. We would return with a clutch full of tickets we found along the train lines.
While I have the singular claim to fame of "missing the boat", I can boast that I was the last-ever graduate of Maroochy River Primary School. In my years from Grade 1 to 4, my only year-level classmate was Robbie Walsh. When the Walsh family moved their children to Catholic schools in Nambour, I was the only one left in my class from Grade 5 onwards.
At the end of my Grade7 year, in December 1972, the Queensland Government closed the school down. I was the last student to ever graduate. All eight students of the school were presented with special gold medallions marking the school's lifetime. - June 27, 1911 to December 1972. The then State Member for the area, David Low, presented the medallions and books and we all enjoyed a final break-up picnic.
The last students (from my memory) were Wendy, Kerry and Daren O'Hanlon, Gregory and Teresa Hutton, Bernie and Kym Facer and Neville Hegarty's daughter Angela.
The next year, the Hutton family bought a little white van and parents Clem and Shirley became the school bus drivers  to ferry us to and from Nambour primary and high schools.
In a lovely "circle of life" ending to this tale, in 1992 when I was Nambour Chronicle editor, I arranged to meet Neville Hegarty at the old school site. The school building and grounds had been bought by the Nambour District Scout Association. The building itself had been destroyed by white ants and was being demolished.
I took a photo of Neville Hegarty holding the weather-worn green, black and white sign: "Maroochy River Primary School". I ran the story on the front of the newspaper on March 18, 1992.
During this meeting, I was able to introduce Neville Hegarty to my new-born first child, Billy. And it was here that Neville remarked to me that he had taken all my poems ("fine examples of poetry") with him to teach his new students at Bli Bli and later Maroochydore primary schools. So that solved that mystery! I'm glad I have also played my part in educating our young Sunshine Coasters!
My Maroochy River State Primary School played a valuable role in Sunshine Coast history. It was the venue for the education of almost 1000 students who went on to shape the character of this region. The names on the school's register - names such as Thomson, Venning, Pampling, O'Rourke, Browne, Apps, Pearce, Ramm and Savimaki (to highlight just a few) - are family names closely linked with the development and growth of our Sunshine Coast.
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Everest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pampling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 27, 1911</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>M.R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Rourke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour's Blue Pacific Swimming Pool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour District Scout Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Plater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunethin Rock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teresa Hutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God Save</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bli Bli</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hegarty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shirley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hutton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Hanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Browne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Member</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cerins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neville Hegarty</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yeti</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Chronicle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kym Facer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina-Bli Bli Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Edmund Hillary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River Primary School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina Art Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kellogg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River State Primary School</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daren O'Hanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunethin Rock Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sammy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walshe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Schools Magazine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Duck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savimaki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Low</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerry</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government Let</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Walsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1960</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1972</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunethin Lake</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bli Bli Castle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beryl O'Hanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Mill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
