<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409462279840297</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/it-took-a-combined-effort-to-make-our-university-a/3206099/</url>
  <title>It took a combined effort to make our university a reality</title>
  <content>
IN the early 1990s, the Sunshine Coast's population was booming but the lack of a university meant young people had to leave the region to obtain degrees.
That was the catalyst for the community working together to create a facility that now boasts 12,600 students and more than 1000 staff at its main Sippy Downs campus.
It offers 120 degrees, has a $200 million annual budget and a proud place in the history of the Sunshine Coast.
Peter Owen, who was editor-in-chief of the Sunshine Coast Daily from 1990 to 2004, said the battle for higher education on the Coast started well before he arrived.
"Residents had been beating the drum since the '80s and earlier," he said.
"The local economy was suffering because of its reliance on tourism, retail and construction, and declining rural industries. If you had kids on the Coast, you generally had to send them away to do tertiary study, in Brisbane or Toowoomba or Sydney maybe, and the chances were they wouldn't come back.
"There was this awareness that a university would help the region become more sophisticated in its development; that a university would be a catalyst for all kinds of things, not just in education but socially, environmentally, economically, culturally."
"University a milestone" was the headline on an editorial that ran in the Sunshine Coast Daily on April 26, 1996 - exactly two months after the first 524 students walked into the two low-rise building on campus.
It read: "Today's official opening of the Sunshine Coast University is a milestone in the development of the Sunshine Coast. It is difficult to imagine that there has been a more important or such a potentially beneficial project ever undertaken in our region."
One of the prominent campaigners was Alison Barry-Jones (then Kerr), a voluntary community activist since the 1970swhose zeal for educational and regional advancement fuelled her political lobbying and seven years in public office (including a term as mayor of Maroochy Shire from 2000).
The influential Sunshine Coast University Association she formed and chaired from 1986 to 1994 helped concentrate public awareness on the issue, sent delegations and submissions to government and was involved in early planning.
Ms Barry-Jones recalls with pride and angst each victory and setback in site selection, government approvals and funding on the path towards gaining an independent university.
Never one to mince words, in a 1992 article in national newspaper The Australian, next to a photograph of her talking to senior bureaucrats on the bare USC site about the need for funding, she declared: "It's disgraceful that an area like this doesn't already have a university. All the people are for it, all the politicians are for it, and it'll be a great economic boost for the region."
She says today: "The university is manifest, and it is delivering exactly the vision that I perceived back then."
An abbreviated history was noted in the first annual report of the Sunshine Coast University College in 1994, alongside a photograph of Queensland Education Minister Pat Comben "turning the sod" at a public launch that September to mark the start of site works.
"The establishment of a higher education facility on the Sunshine Coast was first mooted in 1973 but a subsequent Commonwealth Government embargo on new higher education institutions - which lasted until 1984 - delayed any real development of the proposal until late in the 1980s," it stated.
"The proposal was reopened in 1986, included public submissions on the need for the facility and evaluation of potential sites, and earned Commonwealth support between 1988 and 1990.
"In 1989, the search for a site for the new university concluded with the selection of a 100-hectare site at Tanawha (now Sippy Downs), south of Buderim ..."
The population living within 30-45 minutes driving time of the site is around 400,000."
Rod Forrester, managing director of one of the Coast's biggest property companies, FKP, was already such a firm believer in educational choices and jobs for locals that he built a private school (Matthew Flinders Anglican College) in the late 1980s.
USC could not come fast enough for Mr Forrester and his wife Jan, who watched all three children move to Brisbane to study.
"I saw a real need for it. It was the next phase of growth for the Coast," said Mr Forrester, who served as the USC's deputy chancellor from 1998 to 2004.
"Our three children went to Brisbane to achieve university degrees that weren't available here.
"I joined the board of the university and its capital works committee in the year it opened. I worked with Paul Thomas and (USC facilities manager) Mark Bradley in strategic planning at such a pace that we were developing a new building at least every 18 months.
"It was rewarding. Paul was an entrepreneur and that's what drove it.
"When Paul kicked off USC's Innovation Centre (in 2001) to generate start-up businesses, I thought it was such a worthwhile venture that I joined the board.
"The Coast really needed to establish more businesses, mentor them and keep them here. I'd had trouble recruiting at FKP in the late '80s when highly-qualified people from out of town wouldn't come here because of the lack of education facilities for their kids.
"USC really has delivered on what we had hoped to provide: a university-level education to allow children to stay at home and get educated like they can in capital cities."
Queensland University of Technology in Brisbane was a critical factor in the university getting off the ground.
The hard-won Commonwealth Government support was conditional on the new development being effectively parented by an established university, and QUT stepped in.
Emeritus Professor Dennis Gibson, a British-educated academic who was QUT Vice-Chancellor for 21 years until 2003, recalled its "small contribution" as a simple decision that followed its provision of higher education courses at Nambour since 1989 through the Brisbane College of Advanced Education, with which QUT amalgamated.
QUT soon seconded its enthusiastic Associate Dean of Education to the job of planning president of the new university.
Professor Paul Thomas, a Welsh miner's son-turned-academic known for his eloquence and enterprising nature, had been in head positions at QUT's Kelvin Grove campus for 15 years.
"We knew he would represent the new university well, with his management experience and academic background," said Prof Gibson, who was a member of the panel that selected Prof Thomas from 40 highly-qualified global applicants to fill the inaugural vice-chancellor's position in 1996.
Prof Thomas had heard first-hand the pleas of Sunshine Coast people for their own university, in his interactions with the parents of students attending first-year business and education courses at Nambour.
"I wanted to do something different so I decided to give it a go," he said.
"There was no guarantee I'd get the kinds of monies needed, or attract staff to a new place called a university college. A minority, however, said it would be an interesting opportunity that I could probably make work. That's the view I held personally. It was too good to miss."
Professor Gibson, now retired from a seven-year role as Chancellor of RMIT University in Melbourne, said QUT's affiliation with the Sunshine Coast had served a good purpose.
"USC has been a great success and that reflects well on all those who were the founders," he said.
"It has a very strong regional role and is a good player on the national and international scenes. It's an economic powerhouse for the region and the region has been very supportive of the university.
"USC has come a long way in 20 years and is well placed for the future, in a part of Australia that is growing fast in terms of economy and population and is attractive to people from overseas.
"There's a lot of competition in higher education but the Sunshine Coast can take advantage of some powerful strategies and really go for them and build reputation. Again, that will be driven by its people."
In 1994, the multitude of issues and weight of community expectation tempered the excitement for Prof Thomas.
"It was a huge task to get everything done from scratch for an opening in 1996. I had 18 or so months to put in place all the academic programs and develop the empty campus so we had buildings to put the students in."
He was soon joined by a small group of employees and consultants (January 1996 records showed 48 staff on the payroll) and by the first University Council, headed by pre-eminent Queensland Supreme Court judge Tony Fitzgerald AC.
Prof Thomas said even the council seemed startled by his budget for operations in 1994: "It was $649,000. That's peanuts. How could it possibly cover hiring new staff - including myself - for a university due to open in 18 months?
The amount rose to $2 million the following year, with the Commonwealth also providing $9.7 million for capital development across 1994 and 1995.  
"At first I was driving up from Brisbane, working out of my car and staying in motels. I was using a phone and a Camry borrowed from QUT and kept all my files in the boot of the car.
"I did hundreds of talks with community groups and was overwhelmed by the level of interest and support. I spoke with every club that would have me - Rotary, Lions, Zonta, U3A, all of them - at places from bowls clubs to the Super Bee tourist attraction.
"They all hoped I could make this work but they were reasonably pessimistic because it had been talked about for so long and the land had been designated for a while. Some were worried there weren't enough jobs to support university graduates here."
Ken Hicks, who was Maroochy Council chair of finance and councillor for the Sippy Downs area until 1991, remembers advocating for a university site that was central to the Coast's population.
"Noosa and Caloundra both wanted it, or it could have been on the old Nambour quarry," said the former surveyor and town planner who went on to deal closely with USC as chair of the Sunshine Coast TAFE Council for 12 years.
Mr Hicks said he was delighted with the university's success in keeping students on the Coast and becoming one of the area's biggest employers.
"It has a great teaching staff and is receptive to new ideas," he said.
"This is not a stuffy university."
Reprinted with permission from Visions: The story of one of Australia's fastest growing universities: its people, its achievements, its legacy.
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caloundra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUT Vice-Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Bradley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rotary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British-educated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Welsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Daily</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Education Minister Pat Comben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Barry-Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chancellor of RMIT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof Thomas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Forrester</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane College of Advanced</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUT</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alison Barry-Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U3A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Fitzgerald AC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Associate Dean of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Shire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast TAFE Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUT's Kelvin Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland University of Technology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC's Innovation Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Forrester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zonta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hicks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emeritus Professor Dennis Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hicks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanawha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Flinders Anglican College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FKP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1996</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Bee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Owen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Paul Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
