<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409221761667444</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/3330688/stansfield-stands-tall-in-souths-win/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Stansfield stands tall in Souths win</title>
  <content>
Stansfield stands tall in Souths win

Action from Newcastle Netball Open Championship betweem Souths and Forsythes. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

Action from the Newcastle Netball Open Championship betweem Souths and Forsythes. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

Action from the Newcastle Netball Open Championship betweem Souths and Forsythes. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

Newcastle Netball Open Championship betweem Souths, in red, and Forsythes, in blue. National Park Netball Courts, Newcastle West. Picture shows Forsythes GA Jade Smallhorne, right.  Picture: Jonathan Carroll

Newcastle Netball Open Championship betweem Souths, in red, and Forsythes, in blue. National Park Netball Courts, Newcastle West. Picture shows Forsythes GA Jade Smallhorne, right.  Picture: Jonathan Carroll

Souths celebrate their victory. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

exit

A SPECULATIVE move in pre-season to recruit Katelyn Stansfield as cover for Tiffany Gilmour proved a premiership-winning decision for Souths on Saturday as they came back from seven goals down to beat Forsythes 40-36 in the Newcastle open netball championship grand final.
Stansfield, who moved from BNC this year, played a match-winning hand at goal attack as Souths completed an unbeaten season and back-to-back major and minor premierships.
Forsythes started slowly in a 40-24 loss in last year's grand final but burst out of the blocks on Saturday at National Park to lead 13-6 at quarter time.
From there, the game slowly swung back in Souths' favour after they brought on Georgia McVey for Katrina Tresidder at goal shooter and Forsythes lost centre Aneeka Marcozzi to an asthma attack.
 Forsythes led 24-18 at half-time and 30-28 heading into the last quarter, when Marcozzi and Tresidder returned. Defenders Jordan Ladwig, Tianna Cummings and Lisa Spencer stepped up in the final quarter to help Souths take control.
Souths coach Trude Yen said Stansfield was the shining light for her side through the decider, converting 29 of 32 attempts to match the efforts of towering Forsythes shooter Sabina Gomboso.
Yen was thankful ex-national league player Gilmour, star of last year's premiership, gave her the nod to bring Stansfield to Souths.
''The opportunity to take Katelyn was presented to me but we had three shooters already,'' Yen said. ''In the back of my mind I thought Tiffany might fall pregnant again, so I called her and asked 'what do you think'. She said, 'I think it might be a good idea.' Tiffany did fall pregnant and Katelyn's been an absolute gem for our team. She was the matchwinner for us because we needed to match what Sabina was doing.''  
Yen said the fitness and composure of her side came through in the end. 
 ''At the start, we just couldn't get the ball into the circle, their defence was very strong, and their shooter, Sabina, was on song,'' she said. ''It rattled us a little bit, but looking back at the whole game, we did what we do best. 
''We were slow and steady, we think really well, and we are fit, and we just broke them down.''
 Souths are planning to stick together for another premiership run and Yen expected Forsythes, who are the Charlestown under-21 representative side, to again challenge.
 ''It's a great effort from them to be in the competition two years and make two grand finals,'' she said. ''They are going to go places, big time.  That was difficult this year so I can't imagine how it's going to be next year. We know we have work to do to maintain and improve that level.''
Forsythes coach Traci Baber said the loss of Marcozzi and changes to her line-up in the final quarter proved turning points.
Baber said she made the decision to give all of her 10 players court time ''because I think that's really important in a grand final''.
 ''They scored six unanswered goals at one point in the last quarter and that really killed us,'' Baber said. ''There were a few little things I wouldn't have done under normal circumstances and some changes that were forced. It was there to be won so the girls are all really disappointed, but they played extremely well.'' 
She said her  team  were keen to stay together and work on fitness. 

''Souths are way fitter than we are and in the end I think that was the deciding factor,'' she said. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BNC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia McVey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilmour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stansfield</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sabina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trude Yen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiffany Gilmour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katelyn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baber</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcozzi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katelyn Stansfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Park Netball Courts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tresidder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sabina Gomboso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forsythes GA Jade Smallhorne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aneeka Marcozzi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Netball Open Championship</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tianna Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Traci Baber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiffany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Ladwig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forsythe</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katrina Tresidder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
