<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409792992327849</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/broncos-forced-into-reshuffle-by-mccullough-injury/3207548/</url>
  <title>Broncos forced into reshuffle by McCullough injury</title>
  <content>
GOLD Coast skipper Ryan James knows first-hand how much of a disruption losing your star No.9 can be.

It's a situation that has befallen the Titans' round-22 opponents Brisbane after some Adam Blair friendly fire resulted in a season-ending knee injury for hooker Andrew McCullough.

The Broncos have scrambled to replace their 214-gamer, moving State of Origin representative Ben Hunt from halfback to hooker and recalling Kodi Nikorima to the starting side for the derby showdown on Saturday night.

Hunt will go head-to-head with Gold Coast ace Nathan Peats, whose impact is perhaps best measured by the extent to which the Titans have missed him when he has been absent.

Since joining the club midway through last year, the Titans have won 13 of 25 matches (52%) with Peats in the side.

Without him, through either injury or Origin duties, their record plummets to 11%, with only one victory from nine starts.

Peats' expertise around the ruck has also made a noticeable difference on his captain's ability to find the try line.

James has failed to register a single try in those nine games Peats has missed; in the 25 they have lined up together, James has bagged 12 tries, including two doubles.

The front-rower joked it was a correlation his teammate had quickly pointed out.

"I'm just not getting over as much (this year) and Peatsy was injured and he said it was him," James said.

"Then when he came back he gave me three try assists. He reckons it's all him."

Queensland coach Kevin Walters labelled McCullough's injury a "big blow" for the Broncos but he believes the situation could have been worse.

"If this happened in the finals, you would have to say their season would probably be over but I think that they have got enough time up their sleeve the next few weeks to find a capable replacement," he said.

Wife heard screaming on dashcam footage
NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peatsy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kodi Nikorima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Walters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCullough</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Peats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McCullough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peats</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
