<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409655553371780</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/breaking-news/trump-wont-stay-off-social-media/news-story/356d9f97e30769fa377f4ca3519442d3</url>
  <title>Trump won't stay off social media</title>
  <content>
Catherine LuceyAssociated Press

Share

President Donald Trump may be trying for a reset in the West Wing, but he is making clear that he is not changing his twitter habit.
On Tuesday the president tweeted: "Only the Fake News Media and Trump enemies want me to stop using Social Media (110 million people). Only way for me to get the truth out!"
The tweet came one day after retired general John Kelly took over as Trump's new chief of staff.
Tapped to bring order to the chaotic West Wing, Kelly quickly made his presence known on Monday - ousting newly appointed communications director Anthony Scaramucci and revising the command structure so that all senior staffers report to him.
Those moves were praised on Monday by allies and politicians, who expressed hope Kelly would stem internal conflicts and advance a policy agenda after six months of tumult.
But less clear is how much control Kelly will have over Trump's predilection for sowing conflict and making off-the-cuff comments on social media.
White House spokeswoman Sarah Huckabee Sanders repeated on Tuesday that Kelly had full control over the staff. Asked at a press briefing if senior advisers Ivanka Trump, Jared Kushner and others would be able to drop in to see the president, she said: "I don't think anyone just wanders into the Oval Office."
Sanders added that "General Kelly is going to work with the entire team as he has been doing over the last couple of days."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Media (110</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fake News Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Wing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanka Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine LuceyAssociated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
