<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409449394938169</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/changing-times-in-the-classroom/3206145/</url>
  <title>Changing times in the classroom</title>
  <content>
MY arrival in Nambour in 1950, at the age of 25, was caused by my transfer as a primary school teacher to Nambour, from a tiny school in Baralaba.
Nambour was then the largest school on the Sunshine Coast and the only school that enabled children to continue education to Grade 12. In those days, many children needed to leave school at 14, where most could acquire a job.
Nambour was divided into three schools. The youngest pupils were grouped until they completed Grade 2 with a head mistress in charge - Miss Pruie Lowe in my time.
The next section went through to Grade 7 with a head teacher, Mr Cheesman, in 1950. At the end of Grade 7, children state-wide sat for Scholarship Examination if they wanted to continue to high school.
There were many teachers. Today I think only two of us are still alive from those times - the other being Mrs Val Seeney.
Quite a few of the unmarried teachers boarded at a huge single-storey house that we called "the boarding house" in Coronation Dr, not far from the school. Now that building has been replaced by a motel and next door is where Beaurepaires stands today.
Our school grounds were boarded by Petrie Creek, which also flowed through the town of Nambour and was prone to flooding, isolating the school from a large area. Not many people had cars in the early 1950s and petrol was still rationed from World War Two days.
In early 1958 when I married my husband Dick, I resigned and stayed home to rear our three children. I returned to teaching in 1967 at Yandina.
In 1970, I was transferred to the same Nambour school that I was at in 1950. By this time, I had a car and drove to school.
Our school classes in those days were quite large with mostly over 50 pupils per class. Today, with a class number under 30, it is hard to believe such large classes existed.
At Nambour State School, many pupils came to school by train. To make sure these children could catch a train home, we had to adhere strictly to finishing school at 2.45pm.
During my second service at Nambour State School, about 1978, we introduced an experiment of "team teaching" for the first time on the Sunshine Coast.
Volunteers (teachers) for this first year of trial were two pairs - Elvie Rasmussen and I were one pair and Hughie Pearson and Keith Dean the other. We had 60 children per pair. There was a special building added to the school with the classrooms to accommodate us.
We divided our 60 children into 10 groups of six. These new groups did different activities for a certain time and then rotated with their gear to another set of desks and activity.
They had maths, English, music, science and social studies as some topics.
The physical education teacher in the late 1970s organised a school camp for Grade 7 students near Wappa Falls, which was owned in those days by the Seventh Day Adventists.
There was the physical education teacher, two other male teachers, Fay Thorogood and myself. The camp lasted from Monday morning until Friday afternoon and we travelled there by coach. I mention this because it was the first school camp of this length on the Sunshine Coast.
Even in the 1950s, there were quite a few one-teacher schools. Now I doubt if any exist as the children come by bus to the largest nearby school. I remember a temporary transfer to Hunchy. North Arm School almost had to close due to low numbers, but today it is a thriving school.
Popular new burger joint a smash hit with customers flocking in
EndED is changing Coast lives with their permanent support services.
Drug and property crimes target of local police operation
TAFE's history is rich and our achievements are many.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wappa Falls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coronation Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvie Rasmussen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cheesman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Val Seeney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baralaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fay Thorogood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughie Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scholarship Examination</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaurepaires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Arm School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Pruie Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 7</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War Two</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Dean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seventh Day Adventists</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
