<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409870301740553</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/queanbeyan-palerang-former-mayors-seek-place-in-merged-council/8764374</url>
  <title>Queanbeyan and Palerang's former mayors to face off for a spot in merged council</title>
  <content>
Two former mayors will have to duke it out for a spot on their now merged councils.
Former Queanbeyan mayor Tim Overall and former Palerang mayor Pete Harrison have both thrown their hat in the ring.
Both could be elected on the new council during the election in September but this time it will be the council who elects the mayor, not the public.
And they come with very different interests -  brings together a city of more than 40,000 people with a vast expanse of rural farmland.
And while as former mayors they got on well, if elected, Mr Overall and Mr Harrison will be forced to reconcile those competing interests.
"We're very much aware of that. They went ahead [with the amalgamation] anyway. So we'll deal with the situation as best we can," Mr Harrison said.
Both mayors opposed the merger when it was proposed.
But they were already merged when the

The former Palerang mayor said the merger had brought together two different worlds: one a "suburb of Canberra", the other a region where the nearest internet connection could be an hour's drive away.
"That's the challenge ... you could waste a lot of resources, or waste a lot of time," Mr Harrison said.
The former Queanbeyan mayor appeared more optimistic.
"I think this has been a really good result for our region," Mr Overall said.
"We have the resources, we have the scale and capacity to deliver for all of our communities," he said.
But Mr Harrison said he was worried the Palerang region might not be heard over the city noise.
"It's always been a concern. It's a concern to any minority community," he said.
"If people are not committed to working together, you'll end up with the sort of political bickering that we see at higher levels of government.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Harrison</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Overall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Overall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palerang</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
