<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409823057099474</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/melbourne-express-wednesday-august-2-2017-20170801-gxn815.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne Express: Woman groped on Route 59 tram.</title>
  <content>
Just as I predicted, the foggy Melbourne morning pics are starting to appear on social media.

This moody one from Age deputy sport editor Mel Coulter-Ryan looks like something out of 'The Exorcist': 

Police are appealing for public assistance after a woman was sexually assaulted on the route 59 tram last Thursday. 

The woman reported to the tram driver that she was groped as she got on the outbound tram, and was followed around on the tram by the groper until he disembarked a few stops later. 

She remained on the tram until it reached the final stop, when she told the tram driver what had happened.

The driver said he would report the incident to police and urged her to do the same, but detectives believe she is yet to make that report.

The groper is described as being a white man, about 183cm tall with a thin build and white, balding hair. At the time he was carrying a black backpack. 

Police are urging anyone with information about the incident to come forward and call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.

They are also urging the woman, described as an Asian woman in her 20s, to come forward and report the matter to police.
It's bitingly cold at right now, with temperatures sitting on a chilly four degrees. 

The weather bureau is warning to expect some morning frost, so I expect we'll start seeing some frosty Melbourne pics on social media soon. 

It should be a sunny, 15 degrees today, but there will be some morning fog. 

Tomorrow will be slightly colder, with a top of 12 degrees expected. There is also a decent chance of rain that day, which is a good thing considering how dry our July was. 

I don't think I've ever seen that fog icon before. Is it new?  Photo: Craig Butt

Good morning and welcome to the Melbourne Express blog. 

Craig Butt here filling in on Wednesday's blog. I normally only run the blog on Thursdays and Fridays, and almost wrote today's date as 'Thursday, August 2' when I hopped into the blogging chair this morning. 

You all know the routine - I'll be keeping track of breaking news, trains and traffic until about 9am. If anything happens on your way into work, do let me know.  or a tweet (@CraigDButt) if you get a chance. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Butt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Express</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Route 59</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel Coulter-Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Exorcist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CraigDButt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
