<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409530999318149</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/mads-mikkelsens-disastrous-fantastic-four-audition-was-only-about-long-arms/</url>
  <title>Mads Mikkelsen's Disastrous Fantastic Four Audition Was 'Only About Long Arms'</title>
  <content>
, Mads Mikkelsen revealed that he had actually auditioned for a part in Josh Trank's fantastically awful Fantastic Four reboot. But what caused him to abandoned his attempt to join the movie altogether? According to the actor, a truly weird audition that was all about the length of his arms. Yes, really.

Image: Marvel Studios/Disney

The actor revealed more to  at London Film and Comic-Con over the weekend, rolling back his own earlier claims that  - but also revealing that his audition was incredibly bizarre: There were no lines, and all he was asked to do was to wildly splay his arms around like he was stretching them:

Oh, to be a fly on the wall for that audition.

Most people have assumed that Mikkelsen was auditioning for Doctor Doom - because, duh, wouldn't he be perfect for that? - but everything he's said about the failed audition seems to point in the direction of it actually being for Mr Fantastic himself. Aside from this "all arms, all the time" revelation, he's  that the audition involved some arm stretching, and that's definitely leaning more to Reed Richards than it is Victor Von Doom. That means, at one point, we could've had a much older Fantastic Four than we got in the final team, which is an interesting prospect. If only Mads had been more keen about flailing his arms around!

But don't worry, FF fans who'd still love to see Mikkelsen don Doom's iron armour, especially  - the actor is at the least open to the idea of it:

Just make sure there's some lines in the audition this time and less arm waving.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comic Con</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Arms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Trank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reed Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Film</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fantastic Four</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mads Mikkelsen's Disastrous Fantastic Four Audition Was</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marvel Studios/Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fantastic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Von Doom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikkelsen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doctor Doom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mads Mikkelsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
