<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409870301740561</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/secret-targaryens-is-unthinkable-game-of-thrones-theory-actually-correct/news-story/a001bb49f403b4a3fc5906b9c73682e0</url>
  <title>Unthinkable Game of Thrones theory might be true</title>
  <content>
MY FELLOW Game of Thrones fans, the time has come for me to fall on my fandom sword.
I have been nurturing a theory for years and years and I have kept it quiet. On the few occasions I've offered it up to fellow fans, they've laughed it off. But after this past week's episode, The Queen's Justice, I have to wonder if maybe I'm not so crazy after all. I can no longer hold my peace.
Here it is: I think Cersei and Jaime might be the Mad King Aerys's bastards by Joanna Lannister.
Let me back up and break this down - and it's going to get nerdy.
The first part of this puzzle is simply this: a lot of hardcore fans of the books have been speculating for years that Tyrion Lannister is secretly a Targaryen. This theory has been buttressed by several references in the books - specifically one in A Dance With Dragons - that suggest that the Mad King Aerys, Daenerys's evil father, had more than a flirtation with Tyrion's mother, Joanna Lannister. In fact, there's evidence to support the idea that they were either lovers in the time before she married Twyin Lannister, during her wedding night to Tywin, or in the time immediately after. It's even been suggested that Tywin so loathed Tyrion not just because he was a dwarf or because his birth resulted in Joanna's death, but because he wasn't 100 per cent sure he was his own child.
This theory is especially attractive to fans who want to see all three of Dany's dragons ridden by the series' three major "heroic" characters: Dany, Jon, and ... Tyrion.
The show confirmed at the end of last season that Jon is indeed Rhaegar Targaryen's son by Lyanna Stark, which means we could see Jon on a dragon yet. Tyrion's parentage has never been put into question on the show, but it's not like Bran couldn't flashback to establish a third Targaryen heir. The other reason why the "Tyrion is a Targaryen" theory is so popular? Because it falls in line with a saying that pops up throughout the books with regard to the Targaryen line: "The Dragon Has Three Heads." The idea being there must be three major Targaryens at the forefront of the conflict ahead, just as there were three Targaryens who conquered the Seven Kingdoms way back when, (Aegon and his two sisters, Visenya and Rhaenerys), and just as there are three dragons alive and well today.
Here's why this theory has never sat right with me: It's too neat for Game of Thrones.
Author George R.R. Martin not only envisioned his series, which he calls A Song of Ice and Fire, as a place where fantasy could be complex, lurid, shocking, and as gritty as true medieval history was, but he also wanted it to buck fantasy convention. In other series, it would make sense to see an underdog character like Tyrion ascend to a position of true heroic leadership. But to very loosely quote one Arya Stark, that's not Game of Thrones.
So why would Martin pepper his last two books with allusions to the Mad King Aerys's obsession with Joanna Lannister? Why insert the idea that Joanna and Aerys had an affair - and that a child may have come from that illicit union? Because it is important to the story Martin's telling. It's important because Cersei and Jaime have been secretly Targaryens this whole time.
Think for a moment about the traits that define Targaryens - besides just silver hair and dragon-riding. They're typically beautiful, strong, and prone to incest. It's also said that they either come out truly noble or incredibly cruel and crazy. Personality-wise, Cersei and Jaime have far more in common with the Targaryen dynasty than they do with the overall Lannister family tree. Cersei's penchant for power, Jaime's prowess on the battlefield, and their unholy romance are all par for the course in the Targaryen family tree. (The books even reveal that the only other man young Cersei ever crushed on besides her brother was Rhaegar Targaryen, who, if this theory holds, would also be her brother.) And if you're worried about how much they look like Lannisters, remember that Jon is half Targaryen and he looks full Stark. If anything, it would seem that the bloodlines of the great houses overpower the Targaryen features.
Indeed, there's more in the books to suggest that this theory isn't completely out there. In A Feast For Crows, Genna Lannister, gives Jaime a really odd bit of family wisdom:
"Jaime," she said, tugging on his ear, "sweetling, I have known you since you were a babe at Joanna's breast. You smile like Gerion and fight like Tyg, and there's some of Kevan in you, else you would not wear that cloak ... but Tyrion is Twyin's son, not you. I said so once to your father's face, and he would not speak to me for half a year."
This is the passage that made me wonder about Cersei and Jaime's parentage in the first place. Why would this enrage Tywin so much? Maybe because deep down he knew that Tyrion was the only child he was sure was his.
The ironic thing is that if Cersei and Jaime are Targaryens, it sets up some interesting symmetry within the Game of Thrones narrative framework. "The Dragon Has Three Heads?" Well, look at the game board of Westeros right now. There are three monarchs who have come out of seemingly nowhere to vie for power over the realm: Dany, Jon, and Cersei. Jaime killed the Mad King Aerys? Well, make Aerys Jaime's father and you create a brand new connection between him and his beloved brother Tyrion - both brothers killed their own fathers. Also, if Cersei and Jaime are indeed Targaryens, it means the Targaryen bloodline continued to rule over Westeros even after Robert's Rebellion. That's fun, right?
The reason that I find myself returning to this theory again and again lately is because the show itself seems to want to compare Cersei's reign with Aerys's. Blowing up King's Landing with wildfire aside - and that's a HUGE aside - the show has shown her to have a similar flair for torture as Aerys and it's physically placed her among his prized dragon skulls. This parallel runs even deeper if we see Cersei as one of Aerys's bona fide heirs.
Of course, the show has never flirted with Aerys's reported fling with Joanna Lannister, so none of this might mean anything. (I know! I know!) All three Lannister siblings could be Tywin's children - or Aerys's - and the TV show's plot probably wouldn't change much at this point. I just like to consider this theory from time to time because of the potential added weight it lends the story. If you don't think it's true, that's fine. I just like this theory, okay? And after last week's episode was chock full of Cersei/Aerys parallels, I can't 100 per cent rule it out.
This article was originally published on
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twyin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyanna Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragon Has Three Heads</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aerys Jaime</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad King Aerys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Kingdoms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daenerys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aegon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feast For Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George R.R. Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Targaryen</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arya Stark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhaenerys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dany</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tywin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaime</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genna Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanna</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad King Aerys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lannister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanna Lannister</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Visenya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei/Aerys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Song of Ice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aerys</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert's Rebellion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aerys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cersei</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhaegar Targaryen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westeros</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FELLOW Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dance With Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twyin Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Landing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyrion Lannister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
