<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409870301740566</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/blowing-trumpet-to-tune-of-52m/news-story/a06495f26b4dd49600337eefb30f79ea</url>
  <title>Blowing trumpet to tune of $5.2m</title>
  <content>
THE Australian Festival of Chamber Music has brought more than tunes to Townsville, with an estimated $5.22 million boost to the region's economy.
Now in its 27th year, the AFCM has run over 28,000 nights, with performers and visitors remaining in the region over the 10-days to enjoy all it has to offer.
AFCM executive director Justin Ankus said the event had gone from strength to strength with approximately 16,500 concert attendees from all over Australia and from as far afield as -London.
"Where else would you rather be in winter than here in Townsville listening to the best musicians in the world perform in some unique locations," he said.
Jam Restaurant owner Matt Merrin who supported the festival said it had benefited his business and the region.
"We see an influx of interstate guests dining at Jam throughout the day. The impact of the festival on my business is a very positive one and we are able to offer our young part-time staff more hours which in turn benefits our -economy."
General manager of Quest Palmer Street Annabelle Javinez said the AFCM's guests were eager to explore and spend in the region.
"Festival artists and their families stay with us and we have many interstate guests who return each year for the festival which creates a wonderful atmosphere here," she said.
Tickets are sold out for closing night but available for all other remaining concerts at the Civic Theatre, including the families' concert on Saturday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jam Restaurant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civic Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Merrin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Ankus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Festival of Chamber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFCM</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quest Palmer Street Annabelle Javinez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
