<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409831647034253</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/dark-towers-production-was-plagued-by-too-many-vetos-report/</url>
  <title>Dark Tower's Production Was Plagued By Too Many Vetos: Report</title>
  <content>
Well, this might be the answer we've been looking for. Variety has a story detailing the issues that The Dark Tower movie has run into. It's an interesting read, but the detail that sticks out the most is that three separate entities apparently had some form of veto power over the film.

Image: Sony

Variety has sources detailing clashes between director Nikolaj Arcel, Sony Pictures and Media Rights Capital (MRC). But there's also the interesting fact that all three are united in saying that there were no real problems, and that every stumbling block was just the result of normal growing pains for a big fantasy movie.

There have been a lot of questions about The Dark Tower, including why the  and why . The answer to the former may be that test screenings reportedly showed that viewers couldn't understand the story, so perhaps it's been streamlined. The answer to the latter is probably in this bit of the Variety article:

That means Sony made a movie that MRC and author King both had veto power over. And Sony could object to any decision MRC made. It's no longer surprising that it took so long to get trailers and other marketing for this movie - it's apparently a miracle that we got any. The movie could be good, we don't know yet, but this definitely sounds too many cooks; even if they get there in the end, there is no way this was smooth sailing.

We reached out to Sony but had not heard back at time of writing.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dark Tower</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sony Pictures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Media Rights Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tower's Production Was Plagued By Too Many Vetos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikolaj Arcel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
