<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408835214603601</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/under-40s-home-ownership-plunge-plays-into-labors-hands-20170801-gxmva2</url>
  <title>Under 40s' home ownership plunge plays into Labor's hands</title>
  <content>
Matthew Undy, a truck mechanic at Krueger Transport Equipment in Melbourne's west, and his partner Emma have been trying to buy a house for most of this year.
On Tuesday Undy, 28, made an offer of about $280,000 on a 400 square metre block of land at Tarneit, a rapidly expanding suburb west of Melbourne, where he and Emma plan to build a home for themselves and their children, Sadie, four, and Harper, five months.
They've opted to build, and settle for a smaller block, after missing out on established homes which didn't even come onto the market at auction until the bidding was well above the advertised range.
"We wanted a home with a nice big backyard but now we just want to get into the market before we cannot afford a house at all," Undy - who was still waiting to hear if his bid was accepted - told The Australian Financial Review. 

Rob Homer

If their plan succeeds they'll be among the lucky ones. The  has plunged by nearly a third since 2001, underlining the stiff challenge for policymakers to reverse the trend of this key indicator of living standards in later life.

The 2017 Household Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia survey reveals that 36 per cent of Australians aged 18-39 owned their own homes in 2002, but by 2014 the figure had fallen to just 25 per cent. 
Lower incomes, fewer homes

Home ownership rates have fallen across incomes, education and occupations as house prices have soared through the century - and the data doesn't capture the impact of the runaway growth of the past two years.
But in general, the lower the survey respondents' educational levels, incomes and occupational status, the more their home ownership rates have fallen, suggesting the issue plays into  

AAP

For Roger Wilkins, the director of the HILDA survey and an economics professor at the University of Melbourne, the culprit is  and the trend is alarming because owning your own home makes a big difference to retirees' living standards.
Mr Wilkins said the Turnbull  government should worry more about the budget threat of greater reliance on the state pension by retirees in future and look to curb incentives for housing investors - but is burying its head in the sand.
The government opposes if it wins the next election.  
"I don't think there is an appreciation or an explicit recognition of the laws of maths. If you want more home owners you are going to have to have fewer rental properties," Mr Wilkins said. 

More home ownership, fewer investors

"Ultimately if you want more home ownership you are going to have to have less of an investment incentive for housing. It's not just about increasing supply even though we have done poorly at that." 
Even when young people get their feet on the home ownership ladder, they are taking on much higher levels of debt to do so and struggling to pay it off. 
Average mortgage debt for under 40 homeowners doubled from $169,999 in 2002 to $337,000 in 2014, but average equity in the home only increased $13,632 to $241,000. Between 2006 and 2014, average equity shrank by $32,499. 

Mr Wilkins said while baby boomers look good for retirement, the trend for following generations is less promising. Many are destined to retire as renters with higher living costs and lower living standards. 
Matt and Emma Undy live with Emma's parents at Truganina and hope to build on the Tarneit block for about $200,000 if their offer is accepted. 
"I am worried about my kids because they'll never be able to afford a house unless we buy it for them," Mr Undy said. "The way things are going I cannot see any of the kids of the next generation being able to afford a house."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Undy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Household Income</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Undy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Undy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Undy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilkins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday Undy, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Krueger Transport Equipment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Truganina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Homer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tarneit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sadie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
