<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409711387947617</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/bullst-terror-accuseds-father-defends-charged-son/3207693/</url>
  <title>'Bulls**t!': Terror accused's father defends charged son</title>
  <content>
ONE of the men in police custody over an alleged terror plot to smuggle a bomb on board a plane has been described as "always smiling" and said to have "never been to a mosque in his life".

Khaled Merhi was taken into police custody during the anti-terror raid over the weekend along with former butcher Khaled Khayat, 50. Two other men are also being held and none have been charged.

Khaled Merhi's boss told The Daily Telegraph the former van driver had been behaving erratically in the days leading up to his arrest having allegedly racked up gambling debts.

"He kept not turning up so I told him I wasn't interested in employing him anymore," his employer said.

"He was always smiling and laughing, you'd never think he was capable of anything to do with terrorists."

One of the unnamed men in custody is believed to be related to Khaled Merhi. They are also reportedly related to Australian-born Islamic State fighter Ahmed Merhi.

Overnight, Khaled's father Omar, 76, broke his silence to say his son had "never been to a mosque in his life" and it was "bull***t that he wanted to blow up a plane".

"He works hard for his child and his girlfriend, who was always asking him for money, $150 here and there for jewellery and clothes, it was never enough, it felt like he was working to buy everything for her," he told The Daily Telegraph.

Police have been granted seven days to carry out investigations on the four men in custody.

"It should be noted that the presumption of innocence applies to these persons," AFP said in a statement.

"Investigations remain ongoing and further information will be provided at an appropriate time."

NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
THERE have been major changes in education since 1967.
Noosaville man killed in five-car fatal smash on Bruce Hwy
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
Rental vacancies disappear as Coast heads for boom
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-born Islamic State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omar, 76</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Merhi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
