<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409436510035927</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/so-youve-been-sucked-into-a-phone-billing-scam/8762610</url>
  <title>So you've been unwittingly signed up to a phone billing 'scam'. How do you escape?</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

If you're reading this because you've fallen victim to confusing charges on your phone bill for services you never signed up for, you're not alone.
On Monday, we published a story on  - a world of unhelpful telcos, unexplained fees and potentially millions of affected Australians.
Since then, our inboxes have exploded with stories from around the country of others who have found themselves embroiled in the same problem.
Our first email this morning was from an Optus customer called Mark, explaining how his 12-year-old son had been unwittingly signed up for online porn.
"I'm straight up pissed off. He's 12," Mark said when we phoned him.
Mark told us his account was being charged about $9 a week, which was billed as a "premium content" service on his monthly Optus bill.
Somehow, his 12-year-old was innocently browsing the internet and must have clicked on something that created the subscription.
"We're trying to teach him the proper ways of using technology. Then this thing just comes from nowhere," Mark said.
"It stinks. It really stinks."
Mark's story is just one in the overwhelming response we've received.
Robyn told us her teenager had also been signed up to a premium service without her consent, and that her telco, Optus, denied responsibility.
"I've spent ages on Optus chat trying to get it resolved and removed from my bill," she said.
"It is theft and they're trying their best to pass the buck, throw up their hands and say, 'Sorry, ma'am, it's not us'.
"'You have to pay anyway and someone will contact you eventually'."
Hugh wrote in to say his five-year-old, while playing a mobile game, managed to sign the account holder up to a premium service.
"I had no idea such a thing was even possible," he said.
"While the basic principle of frictionless transactions makes a bit of sense, when it is employed for such low-end, scammy rubbish it indicates Telstra really just care about the dollars."
How many people are affected by this?

So many. The Australian Communications Consumer Action Network (ACCAN) reports it could be around 1.9 million people.
And after reading email after email, we realised just how similar each story was. Amazingly, no-one knew how they'd been subscribed.
No-one knew where they could find the so-called "premium content" they were paying for.
In many cases, the telco had fobbed the customer off, telling them they'd have to call the premium content service for a refund.
"When a mysterious charge appears on your credit card, they [the credit card company] refund you and go and check it out themselves," dad Mark said.
"You should have to opt-in by default, not opt-out.
"I can't work out why we've got to be involved in the process. You go and shut these bastards down or do what you've got to do, but don't expose me to that rubbish."
After we received nearly 100 emails, we decided to crunch some of the numbers to see which telco was mentioned the most.
We went through each email, and tagged it either "Telstra", "Optus", "Vodafone", "Other" or "Unknown/not mentioned".
Telstra was the most complained about, Optus second. Vodafone was only mentioned a couple of times.

External Link:

Nearly 100 third party billing complaints
How do I get out of these charges?

Many people were horrified the practice of third-party billing was legal.
Third-party billing is where one company - in this case the nation's major telcos - handle the invoicing and billing for another company through your phone bill.
It does have legitimate uses for things, like paying for Google Play purchases, but it is also used by companies selling so-called "premium content".
"I have received two notifications from an unknown source telling me I will be charged $9.99 a week for a subscription to a gaming site I know nothing about," Bernadette wrote to us in an email.

What about my money?

If you did not subscribe to these services, ACCAN suggests you request a refund from the content provider.
If you are unable to get in touch with the content provider, take your complaint to your telco.
If you are unsatisfied with the response from your telco you can raise your complaint with the Telecommunications Industry Ombudsman.

"I have not attempted to opt out as it reads like spam. Now that I have read the ABC article on 3rd party billing, I am even more nervous."
We asked ACCAN what tips it could offer people who want out.
They suggested to first try replying "STOP" to the number you're receiving messages from. This should work, but as we found out, the "STOP" messages are often ignored.
The next step, according to ACCAN, is to call the content provider's hotline.
This should also work, but again, as we found out when we were hung up on twice, it may not.
From there, it's worth calling your telco, and if you're not happy with its response, the .
ACCAN says it's worth asking them to block all third-party billing "to avoid further charges".
What are the telcos doing about this?

We contacted all three telcos but received no real explanation for how they are going to ensure consumers aren't erroneously subscribed in the future, beyond offering the ability to opt-out of premium content services.
As for why opt-out "STOP" messages were often ignored, the telcos say they require providers to comply and will investigate them if they don't.
That may be of little comfort to millions of customers, who may find themselves on the hook for premium services while simply browsing the internet.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Communications Consumer Action Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google Play</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCAN</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vodafone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernadette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Optus</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telecommunications Industry Ombudsman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
