<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409827352066840</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/06/31/hunt-for-alleged-bankstown-function-centre-arsonists</url>
  <title>Hunt for alleged Bankstown function centre arsonists</title>
  <content>
Police are searching for two people they believe may have been responsible for lighting separate blazes at a function centre in Sydney's south-west in January and December of last year.
The pair were filmed on CCTV visiting Bellevue Function Centre on Restwell Street in Bankstown, which was affected by a fire at 4.45am on Boxing Day last year.
The dramatic security vision shows a large fireball erupt shortly after the men are seen in the building with what appears to be cans of petrol.
Firefighters managed to extinguish the blaze, but not before it had caused major smoke damage.
Eight days later on January 3, a second fire was started about 6pm, sparking significant structural damage. No one was injured by either blaze.
Police have also released CCTV of a vehicle seen in the area around the time the first fire was ignited, as part of a public appeal for information.
They have identified the vehicle as a black 2002 to 2016 XR model Ford utility truck with black-on-yellow registration plates.

Related Articles

Anyone with information is urged to contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>XR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellevue Function Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bankstown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Restwell Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boxing Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
