<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409350610688615</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/households-had-more-money-to-spend-in-2009-than-2015-hilda-survey-finds-20170801-gxmxxm</url>
  <title>Households had more money to spend in 2009 than 2015, HILDA survey finds</title>
  <content>
It's not hard to see why Labor leader .
The typical Australian household had less real disposable income in 2015 than in 2009 - the peak year for incomes, coinciding with the global financial crisis - according to the Household Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia survey for 2017.
A typical household's real annual disposable income peaked at $77,411 in 2009 - a huge increase on $58,956 in 2001 that reflected the benefits of the mining boom for a wide swathe of Australians.
Since then it's been a few steps back, and a few steps forward, and a few more back. The typical - or "median" - household, the one with half of all households below it and half above, was left with a real disposable income of $76,224 in 2015, the last year for which the HILDA survey has been completed.

AAP

In other words, incomes for most Aussie households rocketed in the eight years to the GFC, and while we were enjoying such buoyant incomes, we didn't seem to notice that the incomes of others - typically those earning more than we were - were rising even quicker.

Mean, or average, incomes, which are more influenced by the swifter increases in upscale incomes, continued to increase after the GFC and the collapse of the mining boom until 2014, when they topped out at $89,940 before slipping to $89,341 in 2015.
What about me?

When the music stopped, the feelgood factor evaporated.
As we began to struggle with rising bills for energy, groceries, health insurance premiums, out-of-pocket expenses and school fees, to name a few, we became much more likely to notice the neighbouring households that seemed to be doing it easier, and to wonder how they were doing it.

Zoe Mongey

That in turn made us much more likely to tune into Shorten's siren song about inequality and the measures Labor will take to reduce it -  across the board.
Correspondingly, it made us much more likely to tune out accusations from Treasurer Scott Morrison or the Business Council that the Labor leader is lying about inequality and taxes for electoral gain.
The inequality brawl that electrified politics in most rich countries after the GFC - culminating in Britain's shock Brexit vote and Donald Trump's alarming presidency in the US - came to us late because of the lingering benefits of the mining boom.
But come to us it has - even though on the HILDA survey's preferred measure inequality hasn't increased this century - and if anything has fallen slightly, along with the poverty rate.

The , complied for the federal government by the Melbourne Institute of Applied Economic and Social Research, has followed about 7000 households from 2001 until now, asking them questions about a wide range of topics and crunching the results to build a picture of Australian family life and economic wellbeing over time.
Poverty rate down

Survey director Roger Wilkins argues HILDA's measure of real household disposable incomes provides a better basis for calculating income inequality than either Australian Bureau of Statistics' data on pre-tax incomes or Australian Tax Office data for income shares of the top 1 per cent, or the top 10 per cent because HILDA takes into account the tax and benefits that overwhelmingly favour lower income households under Australia's progressive taxation system.
The ABS has also improved its data collection, while the ATO has become better at sniffing out income, which could exaggerate the increases they detect at the top end - thereby exaggerating inequality.

Peter Braig

HILDA calculates its Gini coefficient - a measure of inequality in which zero is perfect equality and 1 is perfect inequality - using equivalised (adjusted for the number of persons) real household disposable incomes.
HILDA's Gini coefficient increased from 0.303 in 2001 to 0.314 in 2007 just before the GFC, bottomed at 0.291 in 2009 just after the GFC, rebounded to 0.311 in 2011 at the peak of the mining boom, and has since slipped to 0.296 in 2015.
Essentially, it has bobbed around 0.3 for the entire 15 years of the HILDA survey. Moreover, the poverty rate - the proportion of households whose incomes are less than half the typical household's income - has fallen from just above 13 per cent in 2001 to just under 10 per cent in 2015.
That's one reason Morrison is pursuing Shorten so hard on this.

Reasons to fret

Even so, there are reasons to be concerned. HILDA has its critics. Households drop out, and it's hard to replace them with like households. Also, it only goes back to 2001. Ideally, for such an important issue, you'd prefer to use longer time horizons.
To do that, we have to rely on pre-tax income data from the ABS and data on income shares of the top 1 per cent or 10 per cent from the ATO. These show clear increases in inequality from the 1970s - or earlier - until now.
Wilkins says they overstate the increase in inequality, creating fertile ground for inflammatory statements.
Still, he concedes, "if you twisted my arm and asked, 'has inequality gone down or up?', I'd say it has gone up. There is little doubt in my mind."
There are other reasons to be worried. Poverty rates for single parents have not improved, and nor have poverty rates for the children living in single-parent households. They are double the overall poverty rate.That makes it harder for single parents to provide their children with the resources they need to thrive at school and in social settings that can help to prepare them for the workforce.
Home ownership

As we live longer and have to support ourselves in retirement for longer, wealth and home ownership become more important determinants of economic wellbeing. Wealth inequality has increased this century, Wilkins says. HILDA also reports that home ownership for under 40s plunged from 36 per cent to 25 per cent from 2001 to 2014, with the least educated and lowest paid faring the worst.

That's bad, Wilkins says, because owning a home makes a big difference to living standards in retirement. It's a worry for the government too, because people who retire with large mortgages may use their super to pay them off.
Either way, the government may have to fund larger state pensions than it realised, exacerbating pressure on an overstretched budget.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Institute of Applied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilkins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA's Gini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Household Income</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Mongey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Tax Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Braig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
