<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408663415908097</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/3258291/couple-who-havent-gone-off-the-rails/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Couple who haven't gone off the rails</title>
  <content>
Platinum pair: Nellie and Mervyn Barton marked their 70th wedding anniversary at Albury's Commercial Club on Tuesday. Picture: ELENOR TEDENBORG

THE railway siding where their romance was kindled is long gone, but 70 years later Mervyn and Nellie Barton's marriage is still steaming along.
The Baranduda couple on Tuesday celebrated seven decades of marriage with a family lunch at Albury's Commercial Club.
The Bartons have faced happiness and heartache with their home destroyed by fire and their first-born dying a day after birth.
"We lost our house and all our belongings in a fire in 1974 at Kiewa, that was a big blow," Mrs Barton said.
They grew up on nearby farms at Kiewa and Tangambalanga before their relationship took off.
"We were driving sheep to Huon railway siding, which is not there any more, for trucking to Melbourne," Mrs Barton said.
"His parents had sheep and mine had some and he asked me if I was going to the dance on Saturday night and that was the start."
They wed at St Luke's Anglican Church, Wodonga, on August 4, 1945 and settled at the family farm at Kiewa.
After nearly 70 years on properties at Kiewa and Tallangatta, the Bartons moved to a self-contained home at Westmont Aged Care in December, 2013.
They nominated perseverance in different forms as the key to their 70 years together.
"It's hard work, working at it, it doesn't come easily," Mrs Barton said.
"It's understanding the other's problems and not believing that doesn't suit you," Mr Barton added.
The couple's oldest son, Kelvin Barton, said the pair's different traits gelled.

"He's a great reader and thinker and she's just a great organiser and doer with all sorts of groups, she's been president of the CWA and mothers' union," Mr Barton said. 
"They're dedicated to family.
"They've lived their life for their kids and given us every opportunity and they probably get a lot of satisfaction out of that and seeing us grow up."
The Bartons have four children, seven grandchildren and 12 great-grandchildren.

An anniversary party involving the youngsters was held at the Mitta hotel on Sunday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mervyn Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nellie Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Luke's Anglican Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wodonga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baranduda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mervyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ELENOR TEDENBORG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4, 1945</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Barton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westmont Aged Care</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiewa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Platinum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albury's Commercial Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tangambalanga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tallangatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Barton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CWA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelvin Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nellie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
