<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409878891675315</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:52</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/bindi-irwin-flying-visit-butterfly-sanctuary/3207710/</url>
  <title>Bindi Irwin in flying visit to butterfly sanctuary</title>
  <content>
HEARTS were aflutter at the Australian Butterfly Sanctuary on the weekend after they had a surprise visit from a famous wildlife warrior.

Bindi Irwin popped in to check out the colourful butterflies at the Kuranda tourist attraction on Sunday, en route to Cape York.

Sanctuary staff remarked how friendly and relaxed the young TV star appeared.

Irwin, the 19-year-old daughter of Steve "The Crocodile Hunter" Irwin, was heading to the Wenlock River with her family for the annual Australia Zoo-sponsored crocodile research trip, 80km northwest of Weipa.

The family is joined each August at the Steve Irwin Wildlife Reserve on the Wenlock River by a team of scientists, conservationists, media and other guests to conduct research on crocs.

Previous trips to the Cape reserve had helped unlock secrets about crocs, including that they can spend seven hours underwater.

Last year, Bindi took her boyfriend, US wakeboard Chandler Powell, to the Steve Irwin Wildlife Reserve, where the young couple were photographed wrestling crocodiles together, in the name of science.

Wife heard screaming on dashcam footage
NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuranda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weipa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bindi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crocodile Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Irwin Wildlife Reserve</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wenlock River</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bindi Irwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chandler Powell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Zoo-sponsored</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Butterfly Sanctuary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
