<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409522409383452</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/knightsbridge-acid-attack-the-latest-in-a-terrifying-london-trend-20170801-gxnfyw.html</url>
  <title>Knightsbridge 'acid attack' the latest in a terrifying London trend</title>
  <content>
London: London's acid attack crimewave has come to the heart of the capital, in a robbery just a block from the upmarket Harrods department store in ritzy Knightsbridge.
On Monday night two men, dressed head to toe in black and wearing black helmets, rode a moped up to a 47-year-old Qatari man and tried to steal his expensive watch, spraying a corrosive liquid from a bottle into his face.Photo: AP
A bystander said the liquid burned the victim's eyes, though police later said it had not been a highly concentrated acid.
Though the location was unusual, the scene was worryingly familiar.
The last year has seen a surge in robberies and assaults in London where corrosive liquids have been thrown or sprayed in the face of victims - often leaving them with life-changing injuries.
Criminologists say London's muggers are swapping guns and knives for acid because it is relatively easy to buy, possession is hard to police, and if you are caught the charge is typically grievous bodily harm rather than attempted murder.

An investigation by one newspaper found that litre-sized bottles of highly concentrated sulphuric acid could be bought for just £6 ($9.80) in east London hardware stores.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Another theory is that the switch was driven by a new 2015 law that mandated a six-month jail sentence for repeat offenders convicted for carrying a knife without good reason.Photo: Isobella Fraser
Acid attacks are still much less common than gun or knife crime, but last year the number of attacks doubled from 2015, with 455 acid attacks, or threatened attacks, in the capital. Numbers are expected to be up again this year.
The attacks have been mostly in deprived areas in east London.Photo: Isobella Fraser
Last week London police were issued with new 'acid response kits'. Police cars get packs of eyewear and gloves so police can treat victims immediately, and five-litre water bottles to help prevent skin damage.
Police in east London will carry chemical kits to test for acid and other corrosive liquids.
Just a day after the kits were deployed, there was another attack.
On Tuesday last week, two men ran into a Bethnal Green shop, screaming in agony after concentrated bleach was poured on them. The liquid was so corrosive that it melted their clothing, a police officer told reporters at the scene.
On Friday, a 23 year-old was charged with two counts of wounding with intent to do grievous bodily harm, and one count of possession of an offensive weapon.
The victims, aged 23 and 24, suffered "life changing injuries" in the attack, police said.
Stephen Timms, an MP for east London, called for carrying acid to be made a crime.
"These are life-changing injuries," Acting Detective Superintendent Mike West, the Met's lead officer for corrosive-based crime, told the Evening Standard.
"While the volumes in comparison with knife and gun crime are small, the injuries are a life sentence for victims."
In June two cousins, out for a 21st birthday celebration, were waiting at a traffic light in their car in east London.
A man threw acid through their open window causing "life changing injuries" to the man, 37, and the woman, 21, who had been hoping to start a career as a model.
"I saw my clothes burn away in front of me," Resham Khan told ITV News.
"The pain was excruciating. We stripped off in the middle of the road, running around screaming and begging for water.
"I keep wondering if my life will ever be the same ... I loved my face and body."
She said she felt her life had been stolen from her.
Police treated the attack as a hate crime; the cousins were both Muslim. A 24-year-old man was charged over the attack last month. He had allegedly made Facebook posts expressing solidarity with far-right extremists.
Reportedly, almost three-quarters of acid attacks in London since 2010 have not led to a successful prosecution, mostly because the victims could not identify their attackers.
This is partly because London has also seen a big increase in offences involving scooters and mopeds in recent months. Scooters have grown in popularity generally, as a way to beat the London traffic, but they are an easy target for thieves who then use them to commit robberies.
One criminologist told the BBC that it was a crime that "suits the moment", with so many potential victims walking around carrying valuable phones and headphones.
Two weeks ago, two teenagers on a moped went on an astonishing crime spree through north and east London, carrying out five acid attacks in just over an hour.
Police charged a 16-year-old boy with 15 offences, including three counts of robbery and five counts of attempted grievous bodily harm, and also arrested a 15-year-old boy on suspicion of grievous bodily harm and robbery.
At the time police said they were "hideous offences".
Chief inspector Ben Clark, from Hackney, dismissed rumours that the victims were food delivery riders set up in advance of the attacks, but he confirmed all the victims were riding mopeds at the time of the attacks.
The two teens allegedly rode up on a moped and threw a corrosive substance in their victims' faces. One two occasions they stole their victim's moped.
"Of late we have seen more attacks using corrosive substances in London," the inspector said.
He urged businesses and parents to stop people who they suspected of trying to buy corrosive substances.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hackney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Superintendent Mike West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isobella Fraser</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resham Khan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Timms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ITV News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knightsbridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>-17</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evening Standard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bethnal Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
