<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651408916818983816</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/world/associate-of-malaysian-pm-najib-razak-on-corruption-charges-in-france-20170801-gxnft1.html</url>
  <title>Associate of Malaysian PM Najib Razak on corruption charges in France</title>
  <content>
A close friend and former adviser to Malaysia's Prime Minister Najib Razak has reportedly been charged in France over alleged multi-million dollar kick-backs in a case linked to the murder of a glamorous Mongolian socialite and allegations of high-level bribery, blackmail and betrayal. 
Abdul Razak Baginda, a Ferrari-driving businessman and former director of the Malaysian Strategic Resource Centre, has been charged with "active and passive complicity in corruption," according to the Paris-based Agence France Presse (AFP), quoting a French judicial source. 

Up Next

Young Australians' home loan hangover

02:05

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Sirul Azhar Umar: Villawood's Malaysian murderer

As reported in May 2015, Sirul Azhar Umar has been at the heart of one Malaysia's greatest political murder mysteries.

French prosecutors investigating the case have also charged four French industry executives with corruption, which they deny. 
Mr Razak was at the centre of a $US2 billion deal in 2002, when Mr Najib was defence minister, for Malaysia to buy two French-Spanish Scorpene submarines.

Prosecutors allege that more than $US132 million was paid to a purported shell company linked to Mr Razak, according to AFP. 
Mr Razak has previously said the payment was for legitimate work. 

The submarine deal has been linked to  who became Mr Razak's lover and worked as a translator in the later stages of negotiations. 

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Ms Shaaribuu was dragged from a car by two of Mr Najib's bodyguards, knocked unconscious and shot twice in the head in a patch of jungle in the Kuala Lumpur suburbs on October 19, 2006, as she begged for the life of her unborn baby. Photo: Bloomberg
The killers wrapped her body in C4 explosive obtained from the military and blew her up, ensuring the foetus was destroyed, along with identity of the father, according to court testimony. 
Mr Razak was charged with abetting murder, but a judge dismissed the charge in 2008 before any evidence was heard in court, sparking an outcry and opposition allegations of a cover-up. Photo: Supplied
He denies any wrongdoing. 
The charging of Mr Razak in Paris after a seven-year investigation by French prosecutors comes as Mr Najib is preparing to contest his second election.
Allegations the Prime Minister was connected to the killing of Ms Shaaribuu and received kick-backs in the submarine purchases have dogged him since he was installed in office by his party in 2009. 
But Mr Najib says he has sworn on the Koran he never met Ms Shaaribuu and describes attempts to link him to the case as "entirely false smears motivated by political gain." 
His government also denies any wrongdoing. 
Former prime minister Mahathir Mohamad, now a fierce Najib critic who heads a new opposition alliance, has called previously for the reopening of investigations into the case in Malaysia.
Mr Najib, a close ally of successive Australian governments, is embroiled in a separate scandal over multi-billion losses at the sovereign wealth fund  (1MDB), which he set-up and oversaw through an advisory committee. 
Almost $US1 billion turned up in Mr Najib's personal bank accounts which international investigations claim originated from 1MDB.
Mr Najib also denies any wrongdoing in that case. 
Allegations have simmered for years that Ms Shaaribuu was murdered to keep her quiet about purported kick-backs to Malaysian officials. 
Before her murder, she wrote a letter claiming she was owed $US500,000 for helping broker the submarine deal.
Azilah Hadri and Sirul Azhar Umar, commandoes in an elite police unit responsible for guarding Mr Najib and other politicians, were sentenced to death by Malaysia's High Court in 2009 for Ms Shaaribuu's murder. 
Sirul told a judge during his trial he was the "black sheep who has been sacrificed to protect unnamed people." 
He fled to Australia in 2014 while on bail pending an appeal against his conviction, which has been rejected. 
Sirul is being held indefinitely in Sydney's Villawood immigration detention centre following his arrest in Queensland. 
Australia has made clear it would not agree to any Malaysian request to extradite him unless Kuala Lumpur gives an undertaking he would not be executed.
In late 2015 before he was arrested, Sirul made a video  and saying "I state here ... in God's name ... the most honourable Prime Minister Najib Abdul Razak was never involved and had no links to the case." 
Messages retrieved from Sirul's mobile phone indicated an earlier attempt to blackmail the government in Kuala Lumpur to keep quiet.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$132</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MDB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia's High Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirul Azhar Umar</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Najib</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mongolian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris-based Agence France Presse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari-driving</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Shaaribuu</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysian PM Najib Razak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French-Spanish Scorpene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sirul</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Villawood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mahathir Mohamad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Razak Baginda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia's Prime Minister Najib Razak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KUALA LUMPUR</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Najib</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Azilah Hadri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysian Strategic Resource Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Najib Abdul Razak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villawood's Malaysian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$500,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Razak</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malaysia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>C4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
