<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409956201087936</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/prezley-has-redbank-plains-high-boys-rocking/3207719/</url>
  <title>Prezley has Redbank Plains High boys rocking</title>
  <content>
ANY outstanding team needs a great leader and Redbank Plains State High's Prezley Vaoiva is a young man his teammates would willingly go to war with.
Vaoiva, the side's hooker, will captain Redbank Plains in the south-east Queensland GIO Cup quarter final with Wavell High at Wynnum today and said the boys were keen to avenge the loss two years ago against Wavell, which knocked them out of a corresponding competition.
"I am keen to get them back and give them a run for their money," Vaoiva said.
"I love the bond we have with each other and the chemistry that we have in our team. It is one of a kind.
"Everyone is there for each other. There are no individuals. If someone is doing something wrong, no-one hesitates to tell them. It is an honour to captain this side."
Coach Nick Faulkner said it was also an honour to have Vaoiva as captain.
"Prezley is the school captain as well and he is a leader that these boys follow and really respect," Faulkner said.
"He is the sort of bloke they would go to war with."
All the players will need to fire but second-rower Wilson Malaesilia and star fullback T-Max Dixon will be keys.
"Wilson is an Ipswich Jets' Mal Meninga Cup player of real quality. He has got a really big frame on him," Faulkner said.
"T-Max was injured in our last game but he is our X-factor. He can run 100m in 11 seconds flat so we are just hoping he gets a bit of space."
Faulkner said assistant coach Kelly Brooks, the daughter of former Balmain Tigers star David Brooks, had been a great support to him.
"Kelly is our other rugby league coach and she has been a massive help to me," he said. "To these boys she is in a way a mother figure to them and they have immense respect for her.
"The things she does behind the scenes are invaluable. When she directs them, they listen. She has been a massive asset to this team and has a great rugby league background herself."
Vaoiva said the players would rise to the occasion against Wavell and do their coaches proud.
"We will put everything on the line in this game. It is do or die and I am confident," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Faulkner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Brook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-Max Dixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Brooks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wavell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland GIO Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson Malaesilia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redbank Plains High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wynnum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wavell High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prezley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balmain Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vaoiva</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Jets' Mal Meninga Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X Factor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redbank Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faulkner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redbank Plains State High's Prezley Vaoiva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
