<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409956201087940</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/uber-addresses-rumors-travis-kalanick-ceo-return-2017-8</url>
  <title>Uber is trying to quell rumours that Travis Kalanick will return as CEO</title>
  <content>
Uber reportedly addressed rumours that Travis Kalanick will return as CEO of the ride-hailing giant during an Tuesday all-hands meeting.

General counsel Salle Yoo told employees that the company is "looking forward" in its search for CEO - an apparent attempt to quiet rumours that Kalanick will stage a comeback,  reported.

Uber did not immediately return Business Insider's request for comment.

Kalanick has been , a plan he has referred to as "Steve Jobs-ing it," according to a  earlier this week. Jobs, the legendary cofounder of Apple, returned to the company after being fired in 1985.

Five of Uber's major investors demanded Kalanick resign in June following a string of scandals that pointed to a toxic work environment. Kalanick's resignation was the culmination of a four-month investigation that resulted in 20 firings and 215 complaints about Uber's work environment.

Kalanick remains on the company's board of directors. More than 1,000 employees have  in support of Kalanick's return.

Uber is narrowing down its list of potential CEO candidates to fewer than six and a . Meg Whitman, the CEO of HPE, recently .

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of HPE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meg Whitman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalanick</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Kalanick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Jobs-ing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salle Yoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
