<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409947611153150</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/the-greenies-are-right-about-the-galilee-rail-line/news-story/2e79997baf78fb4789bc31b394acb24a</url>
  <title>Greenies lob flames of 'truth' at me</title>
  <content>
OPINION: After months of dodging flaming tomahawks of "truth" hurled by the greenies, I've decided they are absolutely right on Adani's Galilee rail line.
Yes, I'm agreeing that the Federal Government definitely shouldn't help fund it.
Malcolm Turnbull and the Coalition should build it themselves.
That's right. I say the Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility should stop thinking about granting a loan to Adani and instead the Government should take over the plan and build it themselves.
Immediately.
Such a move would trigger instant jobs for North Queenslanders and provide great stimulus for fabricators in central Queensland and South Australia.
But most importantly for the economy of Queensland and hesitant investors being lulled by the "coal is dead" drumbeat, it would send a bold message to the world markets that Australia's relationship with fossil fuels and coal mining is far from finished. Which is the truth.
In the past 24 hours we have seen an "independent" business analysis paid for by the Australian Conservation Foundation, whose stated aim is to #StopAdani and end the coal industry.
The ACIL Allen report, which is part of the ACF's submission to the Senate Economics References Committee's inquiry into the NAIF and its governance, says any loan provided to Adani will not likely be paid back, disqualifying the project from consideration.
According to the ACF, the report found "widely held pessimism" about the future of coal, and cannot see how the money would be paid back.
I suppose it is easy to see the ACF's perspective on coal when you consider activists propagate their message via vacuous social media and dropping "exclusives" to left-wing city media.
Similarly, everyone at their rallies, which attract tens (yep, tens) of protesters, agrees, so it must be true.
I challenge this "widely held pessimism" claim and would ask the ACF to come to Townsville and talk to people outside the green social media bubble about their feelings on coal and the North's energy future.
Talk to the local businessman putting off staff because he can't afford his power bill, which has doubled in the past year.
Have a chat with the tourism operator whose business you are killing by telling the world the Great Barrier Reef is dead.
I argue activists' exaggeration of both the reef's demise and the reasons for its flagging health are doing more than coal ever will to endanger the 69,000 tourism jobs they claim will vanish when Adani goes ahead.
Book a meeting with people in economic development, big business and leadership and show them your PowerPoint presentation explaining how to develop Northern Australia with windmills and solar.
The fact is apart from your brainwashed disciples and misinformed trendoids who don't read anything but the green-left Guardian Australia and Fairfax, anyone with a clue about how the world works - indeed, how Australia was built - will laugh you out of town.
A government-built rail line into the Galilee Basin would be a revenue generator for taxpayers for its lifetime and ensure tens of thousands of hardworking Queenslanders have a career and a life in regional Australia. The opening of the Galilee will herald the start of a new age of economic growth for Queensland and especially North Queensland and lay the foundations for the next wave of nation-building development in Northern Australia.
Taxpayers should have a significant stake in that growth, apart from billions in royalties, and Malcolm Turnbull should put his money where his mouth is and provide some much-needed confidence to the resources sector by building this rail line.
As for coal being dead, dozens of new coal-fired power plants are being brought online in Asian nations (despite what you've read to the contrary) and new figures over the weekend show coal is still the US's No. 1 power source.
Coal and natural gas account for more than 60 per cent of US power generation, followed by nuclear - yep, nuclear - at nearly 20 per cent.
Renewables, hydro, wind and solar account for 23.9 per cent combined. We have a long way to go before fossil fuels are a thing of the past.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>StopAdani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galilee Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Barrier Reef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani's Galilee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Australia Infrastructure Facility</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greenies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Economics References Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACIL Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Conservation Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galilee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACF</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PowerPoint</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US's No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
