<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409702798012861</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/south-west/twolevel-queenslander-with-white-picket-fence-ready-for-auction/news-story/3bb85408233a2be6d55742ce231b0bea</url>
  <title>Two-level Queenslander with white picket fence ready for auction - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
3 Kings Rd, Taringa.

Greg Jones says his Taringa property could well be every woman's dream.
The four-bedroom, two-bathroom home is a short three-minute walk from the train station and close to the Brisbane CBD.
"You could catch the train to Toowong or Indooroopilly and mosey on around the shops," Mr Jones said.

3 Kings Rd, Taringa.

Mr Jones has owned the property at, since 2006.
Now retired and living on the Gold Coast, Mr Jones has decided to sell the home via auction on August 12.

3 Kings Rd, Taringa.

Mr Jones said the property would suit a range of people, including a couple with teenagers.
"There's a teenager's retreat downstairs. Even a university student would really love that space," he said.

3 Kings Rd, Taringa.

Describing the property as a "beautiful, old Queenslander", Mr Jones said he had recently painted the property inside and out. Blinds, shutters and airconditioning have also been installed in the home.
The circa 1900 Queenslander is spread across two levels.

3 Kings Rd, Taringa.

Set on a 683sq m block, the home features a formal dining room, formal lounge, family room, casual living room, colonial-style kitchen, and a wide front and rear veranda.
Mr Jones said the swimming pool would come in handy during the summer months.
"It's just beautiful out there," he said.

3 Kings Rd, Taringa.

He said his favourite spot in the home was the balcony or pool area, to have drinks.
"Sitting on the front balcony of an evening watching people going home and enjoying the chilled breezes is nice," he said.
Lori Jones Quality Real Estate - Indooroopilly selling agent Lori Jones said the property was "full of charm, old-world elegance and class".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lori Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taringa</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Rd</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lori Jones Quality Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indooroopilly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Jones</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
