<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410037805468430</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/business/nqav-relocates-to-site-with-more-exposure-and-to-provide-showroom/news-story/68604a5f1851caf695df1cfd5b1804c5</url>
  <title>Tech business sees new opportunity</title>
  <content>
A NEED for more exposure on a main road and a move into the residential market has prompted a long-time Townsville technology business to relocate to new premises.
NQAV has leased the former offices of the Hermit Park bus service at 33 Ross River Rd after operating in the industrial heartland of Leyland St, Garbutt, for many years.
NQAV managing director Kevin Booth said the new site came at the right time and price for them to provide a showroom and hopefully attract more of the consumer market.
Mr Booth said they mostly had been oriented to the commercial market over the past 10 years and, sensing discretionary spending was starting to kick in, were looking to move into the consumer or residential sector.
They provide audio visual services including home theatre systems, wireless technology with the ability to consolidate controls into smart phones, commercial touch screens and conferencing systems and digital signage.
"This is a strategic move for us," Mr Booth said.
"It's about being on a main road, having more exposure and having a showroom. For us, it was more about the different heading to both consumer and the commercial market."
Mr Booth said they thought the market was starting to shift with major projects getting under way and giving people more confidence to spend.
"I think we will start to see discretionary spending kick up again," he said.
Ray White Commercial leasing and sales agent Troy Townsend said they had been active in leasing commercial space along Charters Towers and Ross River roads.
"There has been a very high level of vacancies in office and retail space which has pushed prices downwards to $150 to $250 per square metre for offices and $180 to $300 per square metre for retail space," Mr Townsend said. "The 200sq m space leased by NQAV was very appealing because of the easy access and large on-site carpark. The building also has large fascias and rooftop signage."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garbutt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NQAV</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Booth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hermit Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Commercial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy Townsend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Townsend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leyland St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charters Towers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Booth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross River Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
