<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409951906120532</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-now-news-in-90-seconds-for-august-2-2017-20170801-gxn6cq.html</url>
  <title>Canberra Now: Person dies in fiery crash, and universities fight sexual assault</title>
  <content>
Good morning Canberra,
There's supposed to be some frost and fog about to start the day, but we're fog-free here in Fyshwick. The good news is that there is another sunny afternoon on the cards. We had a chilly minimum just shy of minus 2 degrees this morning, but a high of 14 degrees is expected later on.
Let's take a look at today's headlines.
'One is too many': Universities pledge to tackle sexual assault

New research from the Human Rights Commission has revealed the scale of sexual assault on Canberra's university campuses.
At the Australian National University there were 116 students who reported being sexually assaulted in 2016, while five students reported sexual assaults at the University of Canberra.
In an emotional press conference on Tuesday, ANU vice-chancellor Brian Schmidt pledged to address the issue.

Emily Baker.

ANU Vice Chancellor Brian Schmidt speaks to media following the release of the 'Change The Course' report on sexual assault and harassment at universities. Photo: Rohan Thomson

One person dies in fiery crash in Canberra's north

A person died after their car crashed into a rock retaining wall on Fairbairn Avenue, Campbell, and caught fire late on Tuesday night.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Police urge anyone who may have witnessed the incident and have not yet spoken to them to contact Crime Stoppers.

The car crashed into a rock retaining wall.

Last-ditch bid to save rail museum rejected

A last-ditch bid to save Canberra's historic rail museum has been kicked to touch by liquidators.
The museum's assets will go to auction on Wednesday to help pay-off about $700,000 of debt.
Local businessmen Ian Oliver and Dallas Dogger had planned to buy the museum's assets for the purpose of re-establishing the defunct rail museum, but were knocked back by liquidators.
.

The Canberra Railway Museum's Garry Reynolds with some of the carriages on site. The museum has recently gone into liquidation. Photo: Rohan Thomson

ACT government risks 'boring the people'

The ACT Greens have urged the government to have another crack at a proposed citizens' jury initiative.
Assembly member Caroline Le Couteur said the proposed topic - examining third party insurance - should be scrapped in favour of something a little more engaging.
Ms Le Couteur said she suspected few were passionately interested in insurance and that Chief Minister Andrew Barr risked "boring the people of Canberra".
Kirsten Lawson.

The Greens' Caroline Le Couteur says the government risks boring people with a proposed citizens' jury into insurance. Photo: Jay Cronan

Today's cartoon

David Pope

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fyshwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greens' Caroline Le Couteur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Greens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairbairn Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Le Couteur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Cronan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Dogger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Railway Museum's Garry Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Pope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Minister Andrew Barr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirsten Lawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANU Vice Chancellor Brian Schmidt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Le Couteur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
