<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410342748152733</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Mining</source>
  <url>https://www.australianmining.com.au/news/nera-offers-15m-energy-resources-projects/</url>
  <title>NERA offers $15m for energy resources projects - Australian Mining</title>
  <content>
Latest News

More than $15 million has been made available by National Energy Resources Australia (NERA) to assist the industry to become more innovative and globally competitive.
Announcing the latest round of its project fund, NERA is encouraging resource sector partners to submit collaborative, industry-led, innovative energy resources projects for funding consideration.
NERA was established last year as an industry growth centre to promote diversity, collaboration and growth of the Australian energy resources sector to benefit the national economy.
Chief executive Miranda Taylor said a key objective for NERA was to assist industry in the transformation and collaboration pathway as it continues to become more innovative and adaptive in a disruptive energy market.
"Our role at NERA is to assist the energy resources sector transform into a leading global competitor. The only way we can do that is to transform our thinking and processes and become better equipped to deliver innovative solutions for the energy resources sector," Taylor said.
"The NERA project fund is ready and waiting to enhance the sector's productivity, competitiveness and sustainability. Proponents can apply to us for as much as $3 million in funding."
Further details on eligibility and the application process are available .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miranda Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Energy Resources Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NERA</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
