<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410295503511434</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/tassie-kids-miss-mark-in-latest-naplan-literacy-tests/news-story/281c59b43ed9b370d60b9c698c766f01</url>
  <title>Tassie kids miss mark in literacy tests</title>
  <content>
SOME Tasmanian students are failing to meet minimum national standards for literacy measures, the latest NAPLAN test results show.
The Australian Curriculum, Assessment and Reporting Authority has released preliminary results of the National Assessment Program - Literacy and Numeracy testing of students in years 3, 5, 7 and 9 nationwide.
Although Tasmanian students performed well in numeracy across all year groups, the figures showed the state continued to lag the rest of the country in literacy measures, particularly in senior years.
Among the results:
A QUARTER of Tasmanian students in year 9 failed to meet national minimum standards for writing, compared with fewer than a fifth nationwide.

TASMANIAN year 9 students were also below the national average for grammar and punctuation, spelling and reading.

TASMANIAN students were generally close to the national average for numeracy in every year tested, and exceeded the national average in year 3.

LITERACY results for year 3 students were much closer to national figures than in later years.
Results from NAPLAN testing across Australia showed there was no significant improvement in average results compared with 2016.
"The NAPLAN data shows that over the last 10 years, since NAPLAN was introduced in 2008, there has been some improvement across all year levels in most domains," said Robert Randall, chief executive of the Australian Curriculum, Assessment and Reporting Authority.
"Importantly, we see a gradual redistribution of students from lower bands of achievement to higher ones, particularly in some domains and year levels, such as year 3 reading. In other areas, this improvement has not always been great enough to significantly impact average national results, but it is a positive trend."
NAPLAN testing is expected to move online from next year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Randall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reporting Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUARTER of Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Assessment Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Curriculum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
