<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410209604163901</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/british-jihadi-threatens-rome-istanbul-trump-in-propaganda-video/news-story/8cd1b462212625eb8ffcf1dfd55f9141</url>
  <title>British jihadi threatens Rome, Istanbul, Trump in propaganda video</title>
  <content>
US-Backed Kurdish Forces Rescue Families From Southwestern Raqqa City. Credit - Manbij Military Council via Storyful
0:51

Following the capture of the Raqqa Children's Hospital in southwestern Raqqa city on July 25, Kurdish forces found a number of families besieged by nearby fighting. On July 28, dozens were evacuated by US-backed Manbij Military Council fighters. The Manbij Military Council, a faction of the Syrian Democratic Forces comprised of Kurds, Turkmen, and Arabs, was established in 2016 during the launch of the US-backed Raqqa Offensive. While their primary base of operations is in the Manbij District, they were recently deployed towards Raqqa during the fourth stage of the offensive to retake the city. Credit: Manbij Military Council via Storyful

July 30th 2017
3 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

An Islamic State jihadi with a British accent has appeared in a new propaganda video.

Jamie Seidel, APNews Corp Australia Network

Share

'WE will slaughter you in your own houses': An Islamic State jihadist with a British accent has threatened President Trump and warned of fresh terror attacks.
With the self-proclaimed Caliphate on its knees in Iraq and Syria, a short video clip released by Islamic State propagandists on social media shows a young man with a British accent threatening attacks on Italy and Turkey.
The fighter is standing in what appears to be a heavy machinegun position defending the besieged 'capital' of the Caliphate, the Syrian city of Raqqa.
The jihadi calls President Trump 'the new Pharaoh' - a reference to the biblical oppressors of the Old Testament.

'This is a message to the new pharaoh of today, Donald Trump. You may have your eyes on Raqqa and Mosul but we have our eyes on Constantinople and Rome," he asserts.
"(With God's permission), we will slaughter you in your own houses."
It's not the first time these capitals of the medieval world have been referred to in Islamic State propaganda. Both featured prominently during the Crusading era.
But the finger-jabbing jihadi's defiant words appear born of desperation.

An Islamic State jihadi, believed to be within the besieged city of Raqqa, warns - in a British accent - of attacks against Rome and Istanbul.Source:Supplied
Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF) troops are slowly advancing through the outer suburbs of Raqqa, Islamic State's last major stronghold.
The US-backed forces encircled the capital, breaching the fortified defences and moving closer to the heart of the city. Officials are predicting a long, tough battle, estimating that more than 2000 militants are holed up with their families and tens of thousands of civilians in the city's centre.
The 50,000-strong city's southern outskirts have largely been secured since the assault began in June. Fresh advances are beginning in the east and west.
Syrian Kurdish forces claim they have captured several Islamic State fighters from Sweden.
The Ekot news program says jihadi fighters from other countries are also being held by the People's Protection Units, or YPG, the Kurdish militia that forms the backbone of the Syrian Democratic Forces.
Ekot didn't provide details on how many jihadi fighters from Sweden are being held.
Sweden's security service, known by its initials SAPO, has said that up to 300 people from Sweden have joined radical Muslims in the past six years. There was no immediate comment from the Swedish Foreign Ministry.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constantinople</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAPO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweden</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurdish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raqqa</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISTANBUL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pharaohs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mosul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Seidel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekot</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manbij Military Council</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SDF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arab</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-backed Manbij Military Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkmen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-backed Raqqa Offensive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YPG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian Kurdish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-backed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-Backed Kurdish Forces Rescue Families From Southwestern Raqqa City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Testament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Istanbul.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swedish Foreign Ministry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manbij District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian Democratic Forces</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People's Protection Units</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raqqa Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
