<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410295503511461</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-updates/incidents/passengers-stuck-on-grounded-plane-in-unbearable-heat-call-police/news-story/6f7c59009a61d4a030bc4632aa8b2599</url>
  <title>Passengers stuck on grounded plane in 'unbearable' heat call police</title>
  <content>
Passengers Stuck on Grounded Plane in 'Unbearable' Heat Call 911. Credit - Twitter/Brice de Schietere via Storyful
1:18

Passengers on board an Air Transat flight from Brussels to Montreal on July 31 were left stranded on the plane at Ottawa's Macdonald-Cartier International Airport for more than five hours after the plane was diverted, due, in part, to stormy weather. As time wore on, passengers started sharing updates about their situation on social media, complaining the aircraft lost power and air conditioning, leading to "unbearable" heat, according to Brice de Schietere, a Belgian diplomat who posted these videos on Twitter from inside the plane. De Schietere noted that passengers began calling 911 after a number of hours when they were unable to leave the plane. On Twitter, Air Transat said it was waiting for an authorization from the airport to allow passengers off the plane. The airport, however, tweeted that it is "up to the airline to determine whether to deplane or wait it out." Credit: Twitter/Brice de Schietere via Storyful

August 2nd 2017
5 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Furious passengers called 911 during a five-hour flight delay. Picture: Twitter/Brice de Schietere

Share

PASSENGERS who became stranded on a grounded plane in Canada for five hours resorted to calling the police as temperatures inside the sweltering cabin reached an "unbearable" heat, with some struggling to breathe.
The Air Transat flight from Brussels to Montreal on Sunday, local time, was grounded for more than five hours at Ottawa's Macdonald-Cartier International Airport after the plane was diverted, partly due to storms.
But as the hours ticked on passengers began to complain on social media the plane had lost power and the air conditioning stopped. The plane also ran out of drinking water, the airline later confirmed.
Heat unberable. Medical staff on board  when do you deplane us? 5 hours
Brice de Schietere, a Belgian diplomat who was on the plane, said the loss of power lead to an "unbearable" heat inside the cabin and passengers began calling 911 for help.
Another passenger, Laura Mah, told Canada's CBC News passengers were struggling to cope.
"We've got the doors open and one kid is puking and people are just losing their minds," she said.
"The police are in here and the fire department's in here and they're telling us that they can't do anything, that we just have to stay put."
I'm sorry to hear that - it's up to the airline to determine whether to deplane or wait it out when a flight diverts.
Emergency personnel arrived and began handing water bottles to the stranded passengers.
On Twitter, Ottawa airport said it was up to the airline to determine whether to allow passengers to deplane or wait it out when a flight had been diverted.

Quebec-based Air Transat released a statement on Tuesday, local time.
"Unfortunately, this unusual situation beyond our control caused delays of several hours for our passengers," it said.
"Ottawa airport staff were unable to provide with loading bridges or stairs that would have enabled the passengers on the Brussels flight to disembark or our ground crews to replenish the aircraft's empty drinking water reservoir."
Canada's parliament is soon expected to pass a law that would force airlines to provide passengers with food, water and the possibility of getting off the plane, if safe, if they have been stranded for three hours or longer on the tarmac. It will also force airlines to explain why the flight has been delayed.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Mah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ottawa's Macdonald-Cartier International Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quebec-based Air Transat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRUSSELS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unbearable' Heat Call 911</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada's CBC News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air Transat</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter/Brice</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grounded Plane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schietere</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ottawa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Storyful</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brice</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montreal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
