<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410209604163852</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4827674/satirical-newspaper-inspires-anti-adani-mural/?cs=7</url>
  <title>Anti-Adani artist paints Betoota Advocate article on Fortitude Valley bar wall</title>
  <content>
The Betoota Advocate inspired anti-Adani mural on Brunswick Street in Fortitude Valley. Photo: Supplied

Another anti-Adani mural has popped up in inner-Brisbane, with the latest creation depicting an article from popular satirical publication, The Betoota Advocate.
The man behind the mural was also responsible for a similar creation on the side of the Greens' office in New Farm two months ago, which illustrated Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk holding a gun to Nemo's head.
Both have attracted plenty of public attention, but Tuesday's painting also led to uniform police and detectives speaking to artist Scott Marsh, after they received several complaints.
Mr Marsh said the mural had taken five days and had been inspired by a , which joked that Ms Palaszczuk said coral bleaching was low on her list of priorities after a rise of graffiti in Brisbane.
The latest painting used the side of Bloodhound Corner Bar & Kitchen in Fortitude Valley as a canvas, with the manager giving permission to the street artist.
Mr Marsh said most passers-by had stopped to read the entire article, which he was pleased to see.
"People walk past and think it's hilarious because they know Betoota is satirical, but other people do fall for it and say they can't believe Palaszczuk would say something like that, which I think is even more funny," he said.
"I think that speaks volumes for the opinion of Premier Palaszczuk and her government."
Mr Marsh said he had been unable to completely finish the mural since he had been told by police he would be charged with trespassing if he ventured back onto the vacant land beside the bar.
Brisbane City CIB detectives also visited Mr Marsh in Fortitude Valley, asking whether he had been given permission by the bar manager to use the building as a canvas.

Mr Marsh said he was a "massive fan" of the Betoota's work and knew he had to paint the article as soon as he read it.
It seemed the feeling was mutual, with The Betoota Advocate editor Clancy Overell impressed by the street artist's work.
"There is a bit of a sense of humour in everyone and in this bloke," he said.
"To pull something like that off in the CBD, with a police presence, takes character.
"I think we have found a bigger platform and medium for our reporting here and I think it (the mural) is great for Australian journalism."
However, Ms Palaszczuk did not share the admiration for the mural or Mr Marsh.
"Whoever she or he is, the artist seems to have a lot of time on their hands.

"As Arts Minister, I'd be happy to find something for them to do in my electorate of Inala," she said in a statement.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arts Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloodhound Corner Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fortitude Valley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Marsh</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City CIB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clancy Overell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betoota</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betoota Advocate</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nemo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
