<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410170949457424</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/razzle-dazzle-from-bowen-gets-jets-home-for-coach/3207728/</url>
  <title>Razzle dazzle from Bowen gets Jets home for coach</title>
  <content>
RUGBY LEAGUE: The Jets rose to the occasion during a tough time for their BRL coach Mark Bishop to beat Valleys Diehards and keep their finals hopes alive.
Bishop lost his father John last week before the home 32-30 win over the Diehards and all the Jets players, Cup and BRL, stood in a line as a mark of respect after the BRL side had won.
The Jets were chock full of emotion as they took the field and they did their coach proud.
They raced to an early lead and hung on at the end as Valleys launched a late charge.
"We led 32-18 with about four minutes to go and they scored two and had another crack at us right on the bell," Bishop said.
"We switched off a little bit but we just had to win.
"It doesn't matter how we get there just so long as we get there."
Centre Chastyn Bowen was a star and scored two tries in a stellar display.
"We pushed him out one wider because Chris Ash came back," Bishop said.
"The old combination of Ash and Mika Beattie played really well in the halves and gave Chastyn early ball and he really carved them up.
"Chastyn played left centre. He's got really silky footwork and if you can give him some early ball he can beat a bloke pretty easy and set his outside men up as well.
"That was his first crack at centre but he went really well."
Captain Tu'u Maori and hooker Peter Whittaker were also standouts and that has been the case all year.
The win keeps the Jets in the hunt for the finals. Destiny is in their own hands and if they keep winning they will make it.
Wests Panthers await this weekend in another must win game for the squad.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BRL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mika Beattie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishop</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chastyn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valleys Diehards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Panthers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUGBY LEAGUE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centre Chastyn Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Whittaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
