<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409994855794712</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-cafes-to-become-bike-stops-20170801-gxmvj1.html</url>
  <title>'Bike stops' at cafes to entice more Canberrans to cycle in the city</title>
  <content>
Canberra cafes will soon open their change rooms, showers or even offer up their ironing boards to cyclists in a bid to get more people on the bike around the city.
"Bike stops" are an ACT government initiative to connect Canberra businesses with facilities cyclists, walkers or runners want.Photo: Rohan Thomson
Active travel co-ordinator Anna Gurnhill said the program, which might be an Australian first, would encourage more people to cycle into the city for meetings or appointments, as most offices already had end-of-trip facilities for cyclists who commuted to work.
"Businesses need to offer at least two facilities people can come in and access whether it's water, whether it's toilets, whether it's a tyre pump, extending out to things like an ironing board and iron, a hairdryer, showers or lockers," Ms Gurnhill said.
"For me if I was coming in for a meeting today, I wouldn't want to be carrying my pannier with me so to have somewhere I know I can come into, leave my pannier and go off and do the business I need to do and come back at the end of that, get my stuff and go off on my bike is great."
Businesses that sign up to be a bike stop will be placed on an online map and receive a shopfront window sticker.

Transport minister Meegan Fitzharris said the program was a "win" for both cyclists and cycling groups, and was especially great for tourists.
"It's also a win for small businesses, which overnight will become an attractive place for cyclists to stop and rest after finishing their journey," Ms Fitzharris said.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Pedal Power ACT executive officer John Armstrong said cycling was "very good for business".
"Every time there has been a cycling-based infrastructure go past the front door of a business it has led to sometimes different but increased economic success for the business," Mr Armstrong said.
He said if Canberra was to succeed in becoming the cycling capital of Australia, ideas like this were necessary.
"It's a very low-cost option for government so it's a great idea to do it but beyond that it opens up this notion that Canberra as a community is open for the cycle tourist and for those who do choose to commute," Mr Armstong said.
City Walk cafe Kindle was the first to sign up as a bike stop.
Owner Jean Kirkland it was a way for her to give back to her customers and bring new people in. 
"It's a pretty perfect spot and we've got pretty perfect facilities to jump on board," Ms Kirkland said.
Canberra businesses who would like to sign up to become a bike stop should contact the ACT government's Active Travel Office on 6207 7302 by August 29.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kindle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gurnhill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Armstrong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberrans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Walk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Power ACT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Gurnhill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kirkland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean Kirkland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meegan Fitzharris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fitzharris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Armstrong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Active Travel Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Armstong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
