<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410432942467303</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/white-spot-disease-found-in-two-coast-supermarkets/3207752/</url>
  <title>White spot disease found in two Coast supermarkets</title>
  <content>
A TEAM of researchers chasing the "gun" responsible for the white spot "bullet" which tore through south-east Queensland's prawn industry has found the ​DNA sequence​ disease in two Coast supermarkets.

University of the Sunshine Coast associate professor Wayne Knibb is leading the Aquaculture Genetics Research Group and says "nearly everything" they tested at two Sunshine Coast supermarkets was found to be positive for white spot disease (as detected by PCR and DNA sequencing).

The testing was done on 15 frozen retail items purchased just in the last few weeks and included marinara mix, dim sims and spring rolls.

He said the items tested were from Vietnam, Thailand and China, and 14 of the 15 tested positive for the disease.

Assoc Prof Knibb said they'd only done the DNA testing on the samples, and hadn't analysed whether the items contained the live virus - and were therefore infectious - as they weren't permitted to test for the live virus.

He said it was proof Biosecurity Australia was still "dropping the ball" when it came to stamping out white spot disease.

The disease has been spotted in two locations in Moreton Bay and decimated the south-east Queensland prawn industry, after seven prawn farms on the Logan River tested positive for the virus.

White spot disease is a highly contagious virus which is harmless to humans, but devastating to prawn populations.

Infected prawns can stop eating and become lethargic and can be catastrophic for farmed prawns, with mortality rates of over 80% in farmed prawns if the disease takes hold.

"We detected white spot DNA in nearly every retail sample that are now in the shops, today," Assoc Prof Knibb said.

"We even found white spot in their cooked samples."

He said the positive samples all came from the frozen, packeted sections, not the deli, as imports were no longer allowed in the deli.

He questioned whether Biosecurity Australia were even testing cooked samples, or whether it had assumed processed prawns weren't a threat.

The Daily has contacted Biosecurity Queensland, the Department of Agriculture and Fisheries and the Federal Department of Agriculture and Water Resources for comment.

Wife heard screaming on dashcam footage
NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aquaculture Genetics Research Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assoc Prof Knibb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Department of Agriculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PCR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biosecurity Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thailand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biosecurity Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Agriculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Knibb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
