<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410471597173865</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4763964/cordeaux-heights-man-faces-court-after-importing-banned-designer-steroid/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Cordeaux Heights man faces court after importing banned designer steroid</title>
  <content>
Robert Nedeski

A Cordeaux Heights-based wholesaler who imported a banned designer steroid and what he thought was an illegal appetite suppressant/aphrodisiac has faced court after border officials swooped. 
Robert Nedeski ordered almost half a kilo of the steroid from a Shanghai-based trader in late-2015. Australian Border Force (ABF) intercepted the delivery on December 4, 2015 as it was bound for a Unanderra warehouse, home to Nedeski's wholesale supplements business, Superior Nutraceuticals Pty Ltd. 
Testing revealed the powder was pure methasterone - an anabolic-androgenic steroid and controlled substance under the Therapeautic Goods Administration.
Border Force officers subsequently searched Nedeski's home. He told the officers he had previously checked the Therapeutic Goods Administration's website for Superdrol, a brand name for methasterone.
A USB drive seized during the search contained a spreadsheet titled Natural Micron International Co Limited - List for Prohormones. The ninth entry on the list was '(Huperdrol) Methasterone'.
Nedeski admitted to having placed an order for another banned substance, the plant-derived yohimbine. The drug can reverse sedation in animals and is also used as an aphrodisiac and for weight loss. Nedeski acknowledged the ABF had warned him off importing yohimbine in the past, but said he was addicted to it. 
Nedeski contacted ABF officers when the package arrived in February, 2016. Testing later revealed it was not yohimbine but creatine - a compound for supplying energy to cells, not prohibited in Australia. 
He was charged and later pleaded guilty to intentionally importing tier one goods (495 grams of methasterone) without approval, and attempting to import a prohibited plant. 
Nedeski was convicted in Wollongong Local Court on Thursday, fined $200 and sentenced to 50 hours community service. 
He told the Mercury he had unwittingly imported the methasterone.

"The issue is, what's banned in Australia is not necessarily banned overseas," he said. "They [the TGA] constantly come up with new ingredients that aren't subject to the banned list. You don't know what's legal and what's not. I've learnt to do my due diligence in regards to what I import."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Border Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Nedeski</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Therapeautic Goods Administration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TGA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Therapeutic Goods Administration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cordeaux Heights-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superior Nutraceuticals Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Methasterone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natural Micron International Co Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cordeaux Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prohormones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superdrol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nedeski</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABF</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unanderra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huperdrol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
