<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410514546847693</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/rear-window/gillian-triggs-is-back-and-this-time-shes-on-the-samesex-marriage-warpath-20170801-gxn3mu</url>
  <title>Gillian Triggs is back! And this time she's on the same-sex marriage warpath</title>
  <content>
Just when the federal government thought it had rid itself of its Triggs issue, she's back. Former Australian Human Rights Commission president Gillian Triggs has emerged as one of the headliners in a new  campaign.
Just three working days since finishing her five-year, trouble-prone stint at the AHRC, during which she waged controversial battles with the government over its human rights record particularly its treatment of asylum seekers, Triggs has emerged as one of the drivers of Two People: a movement of Australian lawyers pushing for same-sex marriage legislation.
Triggs is a campaign committee member, along with constitutional law expert and University of New South Wales law faculty dean George Williams, AO, and Marque Lawyers managing partner Michael Bradley.
They are the public faces of the campaign, which attracted almost 200 pledges and 400 social media shares within hours of going "live" on Tuesday morning.

On a dedicated campaign website, the lawyers argue the change required to the Marriage Act would be simple: "delete the words 'a man and a woman' and replace them with 'two people'."

Bradley is the brains behind the movement. The former Gadens managing partner (he left to start up Marque in 2008), lists on his firm profile that his only regret is "that the Spice Girls aren't together any more". True story. Presumably, the absence of same-sex marriage can now add to this list.
Bradley told Rear Window there were two reasons behind the movement: one, "lawyers have a powerful voice when we speak together" and "we all know people who are being hurt by this continuing inequality. That includes one of my own partners."
He says having Triggs on board is a great thing because "hers is a voice of great integrity and impact, particularly on human rights".
Great, we suppose, when the definition of "great" is getting the government of the day off-side from the get go. Seriously. If they had wanted to pick a more polarising character from the federal government's point of view, there's no way they could have done better than Triggs.

"Like her, this campaign is apolitical," Bradley continued, straight-faced. "We are seeking nothing other than the righting of a legal wrong, and we will continue the campaign until we've achieved that. Then we'll close it down and have a party."
The campaign makes a clarion call to the nation's 66,211 practising solicitors, and more: "If you're a lawyer, or you work with lawyers, are studying law, teach law, yes even if you're an ex-lawyer who's now in Parliament, we mean you," the campaign site declares.
The bigger question is why, after the last five years of semi-regular maulings by senior government ministers and The Australian, would Triggs be sticking her head up again? Surely retirement is meant to be easier than this.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bradley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triggs</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillian Triggs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rear Window</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Two People</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marque Lawyers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AHRC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spice Girls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gadens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
