<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410510251880297</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/markets/equity-markets/dow-poised-to-top-22000-as-big-techs-paced-by-apple-surge-ever-higher-20170728-gxl8s3</url>
  <title>Dow poised to top 22,000 as big techs paced by Apple surge ever higher</title>
  <content>
by
Timothy Moore

Wall Street's long bull market - with a potential opening leap in Apple shares at Wednesday's opening - appears to be accelerating again.
America's technology giants continue to defy nay sayers with stellar sales and seemingly endless higher market valuations and Apple's latest results are poised to drive the Dow Jones Industrial Average through the 22,000-point mark.
Tech investors in particular show few signs of altitude sickness, and for good reason, according to AQR Capital Management: Apple, Amazon, Alphabet, Faceook, Netflix and Microsoft have been among the top contributors to the bull market, their contribution is "ordinary" by historical standards and its normal for leaders of specific sectors to be outperforming at the same time.
The Dow came within 10 points of the 22,000 mark overnight before ending the session up 0.3 per cent at a record closing high of 21,963.92. It's up more than 11 per cent this year. The S&P 500's information technology subindex is up 22 per cent this year - for a one-year return of 27.7 per cent.

Bloomberg

With shares of the most valuable public company in the world, Apple, surging 6.1 per cent in after-hours trade , it's difficult to see what would stop the Dow from at least opening sharply higher tomorrow. Dow futures were up 0.3 per cent.

The iPhone maker's market cap stood at $US777.1 billion at the closing bell on Tuesday (Wednesday AEST) in New York, up 1.3 per cent on the day. A potential 6.1 per cent opening leap tomorrow would add another $US47.4 billion to its overall valuation.
What's driving the enthusiasm in Apple? The California company gave a forecast for sales for its fiscal fourth quarter of between $US49 billion and $US52 billion - compared with analysts' expectations of $US49.1 billion.
"We've put everything we know into coming up with the guidance," chief executive officer Tim Cook told Bloomberg.
The forecast, and investors' embrace of it, is fuelling optimism that the company will unveil the next iteration of its dominant product, the iPhone 8, in September. That would be enough time to capture some early sales before the fiscal quarter ends. And it foretells a massive iPhone upgrade quarter through Christmas perhaps peak iPhone demand.

FactSet

No dot com comparison

Apple is the last of the major techs to report this season and the results overall have exceeded expectations albeit not by every metric.
Amazon's shares lost some ground after its latest results highlighted continuing high operating costs with no sign they will slow anytime soon despite rising revenue. Alphabet's shares also have been hit somewhat by concerns over rising costs. Facebook's value surged after it reported an unexpected leap in mobile sales ads. Netflix crushed expectations on subscriber targets. Microsoft's profit exceeded expectations on the strength of its Cloud computing business.
"There's little sign that technology companies are dramatically overvalued," said Capital Economics' Oliver Jones last week. 

FactSet

"The key difference between today and the dot com bubble of the late 1990s and early 2000s is that the recent strength appears justified by improved earnings, both actual and projected."
Mr Jones also said the price/estimated operating earnings ratio of the US technology sector today was in line with that of the stock market as a whole, in contrast to the dot com bubble, when it was far higher.
"In light of this, we do not think that there is a bubble in the technology sector, or that recent falls herald the start of much larger falls in the prices of IT shares or equities more generally," Mr Jones said.
To be sure, there are risks to US stocks. Mr Jones sees these risks primarily as economic. "We suspect that the most likely cause of a big correction in equities is a downturn in the US economy, the risk of which we think will be rising in 2019, rather than a plunge in technology shares specifically."

Back to Wall Street. Upward momentum seems intact for now.
The Dow topped 20,000 for the first time on January 25 on then optimism about newly inaugurated President Donald Trump's pro-growth agenda and solid earnings. The 21,000 mark was taken out on March 1 on heightened expectations Trump would move fast on "massive" tax reform and infrastructure spending boost.
Through March however, the widening investigation into Russia's influence in the US 2016 presidential election and potential collusion between the Trump campaign and Russia, knocked the wind out of the Trump reflation trade. It wasn't until investors shifted their focus from the diminishing outlook for Trump's agenda to the potential for rising corporate profits, that the Dow's upward momentum was renewed.
The Dow has been making far steadier advances since mid-May.

Index weight is the key

In its June report, AQR Capital Management said investors shouldn't be too concerned about the concentration of price gains in the power techs variously known as FANG, FAANG and FAAMG.
Shares in Facebook are up 47.6 per cent year to date, Amazon's are up 32.9 per cent and Alphabet's (Google's parent) are up 20.6 per cent. Netflix has risen 47 per cent and Microsoft is up 16.8 per cent.
"Stripped of the acronyms, some large technology sector stocks outperformed in 2015, then didn't outperform in 2016, and then outperformed again in the first five months of 2017," AQR found. "Is this a remarkable coincidence or something that happens all of the time?"
AQR said it's important to note that there's nothing that binds these tech companies other than they are among some of the largest companies by index weight. "To perhaps state the obvious, when examining top index contributors, starting index weight matters a lot."
Secondly, AQR said "companies from the same sector tend to be top contributors at the same time (this isn't too surprising - companies in the same sector will tend to outperform or underperform together). For instance, in more than one-third of the five-month periods since 1994, three or more of the top five contributors were from the same sector".
"Abnormally large movements do happen. Here that would mean extremes that themselves are really extreme versus historical extremes. But we simply have not seen them lately despite some rather breathless reports that would make you think otherwise," AQR said.
The likelihood of the Dow and the S&P 500 and Nasdaq therefore setting more record highs in the near future seems inevitable given the dominance of the big techs and because a record number of S&P 500 companies are exceeding sales estimates. 

FactSet's senion earnings analyst John Butters said that of the 57 per cent of the S&P 500 companies which had reported actual results on Friday, 73 per cent of them reported sales above estimates.
"If 73 per cent is the final percentage for the quarter, it will mark the highest percentage of companies reporting sales above estimates for a quarter since FactSet began tracking the data in Q3 2008," Mr Butters said. "The current record for the highest percentage for a quarter is 72 per cent, set in Q2 2011."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US49.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q2 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US47.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faceook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US777.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AQR Capital Management</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Butters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Economics' Oliver Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FactSet</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Jones</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones Industrial Average</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Butters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q3 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FAANG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FAAMG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AQR</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FANG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$52</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US49</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
