<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410381402859026</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/accused-killer-drink-driver-puneet-puneet-claims-australia-is-racist-in-bid-to-avoid-extradition-20170801-gxngri.html</url>
  <title>Drink-driver killer Puneet Puneet claims Australia is racist in bid to avoid extradition</title>
  <content>
A man who fled to India after killing a teenager while drink-driving in Melbourne is reportedly claiming Australia's justice system is racist in a bid to avoid facing justice.
Puneet Puneet​ had been on bail and was awaiting sentence after pleading guilty to culpable driving over the 2008 death of Dean Hofstee﻿ when he fled Australia using a friend's passport in 2009. He was arrested four years later in India.Photo: Angela Wylie
Mr Puneet was a 19-year-old learner driver when he hit and killed Mr Hofstee, 19, and seriously injured Clancy Coker, 20, in Southbank  on October 1, 2008. Police estimated Mr Puneet was driving at 148km/h - more than double the legal limit in the area. He also tested positive for alcohol.
Mr Puneet is fighting extradition to Australia.Photo: AP
On Monday night, Melbourne time, he appeared before a New Delhi court to ask  not to be sent back to Australia.
To support his bid,  chef Jayant Dagore appeared in court  claiming to have been racially abused and mistreated while working in Australia, News Corp has reported.

"Australians are biased towards Indians so I request Indian authorities to take care of its nationals," Mr Dagore reportedly told the court.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Indians are not safe in Australia, and every case against India has some racial point into it. Puneet should be free. India should help Puneet, not Australia."Photo: John Woudstra
Mr Dagore claims to have suffered spinal and neck injuries after an eight kilogram  box of frozen chicken wings was thrown at him by another chef while he worked at a Crown Casino restaurant several years ago. The chef also racially abused him, he told News Corp.
Melbourne-born designer Anna Maria D'Annibale﻿ also testified. Photo: Supplied
"I am not supporting Puneet - if he has done a crime, let the court decide his punishment," she said outside the New Delhi court, News Corp reported.
"My concern is that if my government is fighting to get Puneet back to Australia and face justice, then they should also use the same yardstick for (its) own nationals who abuse Indians there.
"It should be justice for all."
Mr Hofstee's father, Peter, said delays extraditing Mr Puneet were prolonging their ordeal.
"In October, it will be nine years since Dean's death and each year passing is another year too long."
Last month, Mr Puneet limped into a courtroom for a procedural hearing. He was coughing and wearing a face mask, claiming he was extremely ill.
The matter has been put over until September 5.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hofstee, 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puneet Puneet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annibale﻿</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hofstee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dagore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayant Dagore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Maria D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Wylie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Woudstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Puneet</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Casino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Delhi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clancy Coker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
