<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410080755142157</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/minings-days-are-numbered-in-tasmania-says-geologist/8765002</url>
  <title>Tasmania's mining industry could be dead within a decade, geologist warns</title>
  <content>
A Tasmanian mining expert has raised concerns about the future of the industry in the state, saying it could end in the next ten years if the current trends continue.
University of Tasmania Professor of Geology Ross Large said mining activity has been decreasing in the state for decades.
"We need to ask the question in Tasmania. Is this a trend we want to see continue? Because mining will really go out the back door in the next 10 years if this does continue," he said.
"We always used to think mining was going on and on, they just keep mining and adding to their reserves and that's what's happened at Rosebery [mine in the state's west].
"But it's not going to continue, I don't think, indefinitely.
"It used to be one of the major industries for Tasmania, a real producer, but more recently other industries have picked up and mining has declined."
Professor Large said large mining companies needed to spend significant money to find new deposits.
"They're taking our resources but they're not putting money back into serious continuous exploration.
"So I would say the companies have a fault, the Government has a fault because they're not supporting the industry enough in terms of exploration again."
'Most mineral resources exploited'

Mining in the state had suffered due to downturns in commodity prices as well as tragedies.
Hundreds of jobs were lost at Queenstown's Mt Lyell copper mine when it  but .
The Henty gold mine rebooted earlier this year with 120 jobs created after spending two years in care and maintenance.
Still, economist Saul Eslake said the mining's importance in Tasmania was diminishing.
"It's a relatively small employer except for on the west coast and, unfortunately, its contribution to the state's economy isn't what it once was," he said.
"It's not that the Tasmanian Government is anti-mining, it's that most of the known mineral resources which Tasmania had ... have been more or less fully exploited.
"Nobody has discovered any commercially viable new ore bodies that could provide the basis for a new future for mining in Tasmania.
"If they believed there's a reasonable prospect of finding a commercially viable ore body, I'm sure they would be looking for it.
"But it appears that the mining industry has concluded that there isn't much point in spending a lot of money exploring for minerals in Tasmania because there aren't many to be found."
Mr Eslake said mining represented about 1.2 per cent of Tasmania's economy, compared with nearly 7 per cent in the 1970s.
"If we had more mining we would have a more productive economy," he said.
'Mining's still important to Tasmania'

Premier Will Hodgman said the State Government's outlook was positive.
"I think the fact that we're partnering with mining businesses that are in fact wanting to expand their exploration and to be part of Tasmania's mining sector shows that there is a more buoyant outlook," he said.
"Mining is still the largest export sector for our economy ... its importance to Tasmania's economy remains strong."
Mr Hodgman said the mining industry had experienced a difficult period in recent years but was regaining confidence.
"We've had some terrible tragedies, we've seen a downturn in commodity prices," he said.
"The levels of confidence that are returning are in fact very strong."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor of Geology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Large</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Large</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saul Eslake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenstown's Mt Lyell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Eslake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Will Hodgman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
