<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409964791022833</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/take-companies-to-court-over-price-hikes/3207442/</url>
  <title>Take companies to court over price hikes</title>
  <content>
WHERE will it end? What's next?
Proof of where you were conceived and to satisfy the perfectionists after a holiday abroad, maybe a pregnancy test on arrival at customs.
Or will a declaration on the card alongside banned imports be sufficient.
All this waste of time which should be spent on taking the companies to court to justify their price increases being blamed on the costs of renewable energy.
Anyone watching the news and the lady whose weekly cost of electricity and gas would rise to $176 if she didn't contact the supplier to arrange a better deal.
Now there's a company that needs to prove where they were conceived.
Not on this planet for sure.
ERNEST WRIGHT
Sunrise Beach
Wife heard screaming on dashcam footage
NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ERNEST WRIGHT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunrise Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
