<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410252553837709</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/television/former-bachelor-contestant-ali-oetjen-reveals-secrets-about-the-show/news-story/c4b7af0824d25a0ced29d0504874c0e9</url>
  <title>Bachelor contestant spills show</title>
  <content>
Ali gets dumped on The Bachelor

A FORMER contestant on The Bachelor has revealed what it™s really like to appear on the show, saying, oeIt really does mess you around in the head".

Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season of the show in 2013 and made it to the final three before being sent packing by The Bachelor, Tim Robards.

Speaking to Adelaide's , Oetjen spoke about how the women on the show are plied with booze, are forced to share rooms and prevented from calling their loved ones.

Here are her juiciest revelations:

ROSE CEREMONIES

Sure, the rose ceremonies really drag on when they're shown on TV but that's nothing compared to how long they actually take to film.

"The first rose ceremony that we ever had where we got introduced to the Bachelor, it actually went over two nights," Oetjen told the radio hosts.

"You had to wear the same dress and you had to get your hair done the exact same way. Everything took ages."

BOOZY BROADS

We've seen some shocking behaviour from some of the Bachelorettes over the years, but keep in mind they were probably a bit tipsy at the time.

According to Oetjen, the women are "drinking so much, all the time".

"They [the producers] did cotton on as the show went on to give us more drinks so that we would relax and we would do more of what the producers asked of us."

MENTALLY CHALLENGING

"It really does mess you around in the head," Oetjen said about filming the show.

"Being in the house for about two to three months, not being able to speak to anyone else, your mind is completely focused just on this man.

"My advice would be to someone considering going on The Bachelor, make sure you're in for a mental rollercoaster ... it's not all fun and games."

GETTING FRIENDLY IN THE BEDROOM

The Bachelorettes had to share bedrooms and according to Oetjen some of the roommates really hit it off during her season.

"Everyone had bunk beds," she said, "There were about six huge bedrooms and each had our own bathrooms and each had our own dressing rooms".

"We did suspect two girls [were hooking up] because they would always stay in their room and never come out together ... we all thought something was going on."

REALITY TV LIES

Ali Oetjen broke her leg during filming and had to have two surgeries and a knee reconstruction.

The accident happened when she was swinging off the top of a yacht and landed on a canoe, snapping several ligaments in her knee.

But that's not what viewers saw when that particular episode aired.

"I was really annoyed when I watched the episode for the first time," Oetjen said.

The show was edited to make it look like she simply landed awkwardly on the water with the suggestion she faked the injury for attention.

"I just broke down in tears when I saw that episode because I couldn't believe that's what they showed Australia had happened to me," she said, "but that's the world of TV".

OVERALL EXPERIENCE

Despite some of her revelations, Oetjen said she doesn't regret appearing on The Bachelor at all.

"It made me so strong as a person, mentally, physically and it was really fun," she told Mix 102.3's Jodie & Soda.

"In the house you didn't have to worry about your bills ... you didn't have to worry about anything. I don't regret going on. I learnt so much about myself."

Oetjen enjoyed her time on the show so much that she seriously considered an offer to be The Bachelorette.

"I was approached twice to do The Bachelorette," she said.

"The head producer actually rang me six to 10 months later [after the first season aired]," but Oetjen turned it down because was in a relationship at the time.

"And then probably about three months later he rang me again and said, 'Just checking are you still in a relationship?'"

The Bachelor Australia continues on Network Ten tonight at 7.30pm

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mix 102.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oetjen</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Network Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FRIENDLY IN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>oeIt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Robards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROSE CEREMONIES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV LIES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
