<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410561791488960</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/st-kilda/nick-riewoldt-opens-up-on-dealing-with-grief-of-losing-sister-maddie/news-story/a7ed5fd9e1c737d0df7db1b5c9b46ebf</url>
  <title>'I talk to Maddie as though she is still here'</title>
  <content>
BY HIS own admission, Nick Riewoldt has never been the easiest AFL player for the footy public to warm to.
The retiring Saints champion even said on Tuesday night that he has been "robotic" and "sterile at times" throughout his esteemed career.
But the tragic death of his sister Maddie in February 2015 has changed Riewoldt's perspective on life - and made him a better, more rounded person.
Riewoldt, who helped start up Maddie Riewoldt's Vision, opened up on Fox Footy's AFL 360 on Tuesday about how he and his family deal with the grief of losing Maddie after her five-year battle with aplastic anaemia.
WATCH THE INTERVIEW IN OUR VIDEO PLAYER ABOVE
Co-host Mark Robinson said he often felt Riewoldt talked about Maddie as if she was still present - something that was particularly evident to Robinson during the key forward's retirement press conference.
Riewoldt said he and other members of his family often sense Maddie's presence, despite her passing over two years ago.
"That's how we still feel," Riewoldt told AFL 360.
"I can be driving along in the car and I will talk to Maddie as though she is still here and she can hear me. I don't know whether that's true or not, but it makes it easier.
"Anyone who's been through losing someone in grief would relate to that."
Riewoldt joked that his wife Catherine has often caught him with a "resting b**ch face" in the past, either on the footy field or during a media opportunity.
But Maddie's passing and the subsequent change in outlook has provided the AFL community with a different view of Riewoldt.
"When you're vulnerable and you let things wash over ... when a tragedy like that happens, you become a bit more relatable," Riewoldt said.
"To have the AFL landscape to leverage and provide us as a family with a lot of support and, in turn, celebrate my sister's life, it's one of the things I'm most grateful about."
A Queensland boy originally, Riewoldt moved down to Melbourne to begin - and ultimately finish - a stellar career with St Kilda.
And if it hadn't have been for his family's support, Riewoldt said he wouldn't have had the career he's had.
"One thing I've reflected on over the past couple of days is what my family has done around my career and relocating to Melbourne, making the move - Mum, Dad, my sister all coming down - that's all been on the back of my career, them coming down to watch the footy and be a part of the St Kilda family," Riewoldt said.
"All of the friendships, all of the relationships that I've forged wouldn't have existed if I had gone to the Brisbane Lions, which almost happened."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maddie</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maddie Riewoldt's Vision</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riewoldt</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-host Mark Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INTERVIEW IN OUR VIDEO PLAYER ABOVE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
