<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410596151228030</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/miss-mauds-iconic-perth-cbd-hotel-up-for-sale/news-story/0b8054ad5951961cf0cebb38e923dee2</url>
  <title>Miss Maud's iconic hotel up for sale</title>
  <content>
MISS Maud's Swedish Hotel in the eastern heart of Perth's CBD is for sale for about $10 million, with the proceeds expected to finance the expansion of Miss Maud's core coffee shop and bakehouse enterprise.
Savills Barney Dear and Chas Moore said the 52-room, 2740sqm hotel at 67 Murray Street on the corner of Pier Street was about 300m from Perth's central railway station and would be a beneficiary of the push by the Adrian Fini-led Historic Heart project to upgrade the streetscape and introduce street art.
The hotel has a reception, takeaway shop with alfresco dining, a 200-seat restaurant, a separate conference and dining room, a full commercial kitchen and a rooftop garden on a 1162sqm site.
Mr Dear said the sale was a rare opportunity for a buyer to enter or consolidate their Perth hotel interests.
Also, he said the site offered significant upside development potential. It had a potential 7.5:1 plot ratio and almost 70m frontage to Murray and Pier streets.
"The site offers the flexibility of rebranding and continuing current operations, refurbishment or complete redevelopment," Mr Dear said.
Mr Moore said there were few CBD hotels for sale and a growing pool of foreign and local capital searching for strategic investment opportunities.
Miss Maud Swedish Pastry House was first established in Perth in 1971 by Maud Edmiston, who was WA's 2001 citizen of the year in industry and commerce.
Ms Edmiston's empire has expanded to 17 WA-based pastry houses, an online catering business and a bakehouse and the hotel. Her latest coffee house, in Mandurah, opened last week.
The property is for sale via expressions of interest closing on September 7.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maud Edmiston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA's 2001</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Maud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dear</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandurah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maud Swedish Pastry House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chas Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Edmiston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Fini-led Historic Heart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maud's Swedish Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savills Barney Dear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pier Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
