<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410725000249205</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/newcastle-woman-spreading-kindness-with-secret-book-deliveries/8762474</url>
  <title>Newcastle woman spreading kindness with secret book deliveries in community</title>
  <content>
With news bulletins regularly filled with stories reporting the troubles of the world, a woman in the New South Wales city of Newcastle is bringing smiles to the faces of residents through a random act of kindness project.
Amy Lovat, a creative writing teacher, recently started Secret Book Stuff, where she wraps her pre-loved books and leaves them in public places for people to pick up and take home.
"I had wanted to do a random act of kindness project in Newcastle for a while," she said.
"I have almost a thousand books to my name, and every time I move to a new house, I lug these boxes of books everywhere and I always end up giving heaps of them away for free to friends.
"So, then I thought, 'if there's a way that I could do that on a bigger scale, I'll be able to minimalise my life a lot better and get rid of more pre-loved books, but then also spread the magic for other people'.
"I'm doing little book drops of a pile of three or four books in a lot of different cafes around Newcastle, and on bus stops; if I'm driving past a house and it looks like a fun little house, I'll drop one on a doorstep. It's pretty random at the moment - it's just for whoever finds them."
People can also donate to the project to have a book sent to a person of their choosing.
Ms Lovat said she wanted to spread good in the community.
"I think there's so much kindness that we can spread in the little things in life, whether that's a smile for a stranger, or a random pre-loved book that's sitting in a cafe that people can unwrap and take home," she said.
"In a lot of global turmoil that we often have, good news is always good news."
Wrapping parties and recycled paper

Ms Lovat said she mainly delivered novels, and hoped to spread a love of literature.
"On my end, I wrap the books in 100 per cent recycled brown paper and then wrap them with hemp twine which is biodegradable, so there is a bit of an environmental focus - I'm not trying to bring more 'stuff' into the world," she said.
"It's very secret, you don't know what's inside until you open it.
"I had to actually let go of the idea that I would know exactly who was getting the book and what book it was, and how they felt about it, and whether it was the right thing for them."
With piles of books still to be delivered, Ms Lovat said she involved her friends in the project.
"I don't really see it as work because it's been so enjoyable for me. I've just been doing it in my spare time with Netflix on in the background," she said.
"I've had a few little wrapping parties with friends who come over, we catch up, have dinner, and then they help me wrap some books, which is a fun way to bring a little bit of a community element to it."
Project looking to spread change

Ms Lovat said she took a lot of personal satisfaction away from starting the project.
"It feels amazing. It's exactly what I wanted out of this," she said.
"I didn't set out to make myself feel better, but it is just one of those by-products of doing nice things for other people and spreading kindness - it comes back ten-fold.
"Change honestly does start in your own backyard, and if you're doing something kind for someone right next to you, on the bus, or your neighbour, or a friend, or a family member, that will plant a little seed of happiness and peace in that person's mind.
"Then hopefully that will spread as well. It really does have a ripple-effect. Kindness is great like that."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secret Book Stuff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amy Lovat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lovat</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
