<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409994855794685</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4825315/end-of-era-at-the-illawarra-connection-for-roger-summerill/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Roger Summerill steps down after 12 years as president of the Illawarra Connection</title>
  <content>
Changing of the guard: Graham Lancaster, Roger Summerill, Canterbury Bankstown Bulldogs CEO Raelene Castle and Peter Buckley at Tuesday night's Illawarra
Connection dinner. Picture: Greg Ellis.

Roger Summerill surprised the Illawarra business community on Tuesday night by announcing after 12 years as president of The Illawarra Connection he has decided to step back and give someone else the opportunity to lead the peak networking body.

End of era at The Illawarra Connection for Roger Summerill

exit
"It is a good time to step down," he said.
"The Illawarra Connection is going from strength to strength, is financially stable and doing good things." 

Mr Summerill made the decision prior to the last board meeting where Graham Lancaster, of Lancaster Law and Mediation, was elected president and Peter Buckley, of Peoplecare, vice president. "I'm leaving it in good hands. Being President of TIC has been one of the most privileged and enjoyable  roles I have held. However, I feel this is an opportune time for a leadership change".

There have only been two presidents of TIC in the last 25 years. Mr Summerill was elected president in 2005.

That was when founding president Peter Kell decided it was time for him to hand over the baton to someone else.

Mr Summerill said during this time he had enjoyed working with a great board and three outstanding executive directors in Barry Wood, Sharon Wingate and Yvonne Walker.

Mr Summerill said he planned to keep attending TIC dinners.

Memorable moment: Former NSW premier John Fahey, Sean O'Connor and Bob Millward with Roger Summerill at TIC after the Dragons NRL Grand Final win in 2010.

Related stories:

Kell honoured for 12 years with The Illawarra Connection - Feb 2006

THE board of Illawarra's peak networking body this week paid tribute to its founding president by presenting him with life membership of The Illawarra Connection.
Peter Kell was presented the honour by new president Roger Summerill in recognition of his 12 years at the helm of one of the region's most consistently strong business organisations.
Mr Summerill said this week's first Connection dinner of the year provided an opportunity to formally recognise that commitment.
He said Mr Kell was one of a small group of business leaders responsible for establishing The Illawarra Connection (TIC) in 1993 to promote the region for the benefit of all regional businesses and the community.
He said the group was successful in establishing an ideal forum for communication between regional business and community leaders on a wide range of topical interests
"Peter Kell's leadership of the Connection is something that really just can't be measured," he said.
"He has been dedicated to the Connection as a body and, more importantly, Peter has had a real commitment to the values of the Connection and the Illawarra community."
Mr Kell said the networking body had become very much a part of he and his wife Faye's life. He said he had spent a lot of time with many Connection members growing the organisation to its existing position.
"It was with regret that other circumstances in my life led me to the point of thinking it was time to stand down," he said.
"But I don't think that was a bad thing because after all that time I think it was time for a change.
"I'm delighted to, as the Mercury Enterprise magazine said, pass the baton to Roger Summerill who is an old friend and someone I know will be a wonderful president and leader."
Radio stalwart to sign off from ABC - June 2007
HE has toured Australia with Skippy the Kangaroo, worked with some of the biggest names in radio and television, established a film and television school and been honoured with an Order of Australia Medal.
Now Roger Summerill has decided to turn the "on air" signal off after a 41-year career in the media. His full-time career will end on July 13 when he steps down as ABC's NSW Local Radio manager.
Despite no longer travelling daily to Sydney from his Shell Cove home, Mr Summerill won't have time to take up lawn bowls or line dancing just yet.
He intends to spend more time with his wife Anne and children Matthew and Roger and their families.
He will also channel his energy into consultancy and community roles, including as a lay preacher at St Paul's Anglican Church Shellharbour, chairman of The Illawarra Grammar School and president of The Illawarra Connection (TIC).
Tuesday's TIC dinner with guest speaker ABC managing director Mark Scott just happens to coincide with Mr Summerill's 41st anniversary in the broadcast game.
In the days before television, he was a self-confessed radio groupie. He loved to watch stars such as Jack Davey record their programs live.
Mr Summerill won a Sydney eisteddfod radio announcing competition in 1965, but came to radio as a career via a circuitous route because his father did not consider radio a real job.
From 1966, he juggled work in a bank Monday to Friday with the midnight-to-dawn shift on radio 2UE on Friday, Saturday and Sunday nights.
He moved to 2UW and read news on Channel Nine before a series of on-air and media management roles.
A highlight was being upstaged by a kangaroo when he toured Australia with Skippy to promote crockery featuring the popular television star.
"We took the kangaroo to the Gold Coast once and we had every school between Tweed Heads and Southport bring the kids out onto the road to wave to Skippy as it went past in an open car," he said.
Mr Summerill was also the head of the Australian Film, Television and Radio School in Sydney for four years.
He presented the Saturday breakfast show on ABCradio in Wollongong before making the sea change to Nowra in 1985 to manage 2ST.
He became involved in the community, chairing the Shoalhaven Tourism Board for 12 years and was later awarded the Order of Australia Medal for his contribution to tourism.
Another career highlight was launching the region's first commercial FM radio station, Power FM. He moved to Wollongong in 1997 to manage Wave FM, but two years later joined the ABC in Sydney.
TIC speakers during Roger Summerill's time as president

June 2017 -  John Borghetti AO - CEO and MD, Virgin Australia
April 2017 - Michael Grinder - Expert in the science of non-verbal communication
February 2017 - Chris Joscelyne - Managing Director, Australian Projects Pty Ltd 
December 2016 - Greg Champion
October 2016 - Unveiling of the 2016 Olympic Tile for the Olympic Tribute Wall
August 2016 - Alex Frino - Deputy Vice-Chancellor (Global Strategy), UOW

July 2016 (luncheon) - Keith Suter - Futurist
June 2016 -  Chris Allen - Paratrooper, Policeman, Counter-terrorism Expert and Global Best-Selling Author
April 2016 - Allan Mills - Partner, Finance and Performance Management, Deloitte
February 2016 - Alex Malley - Chief Executive, CPA Australia
December 2015 - Sam Bailey - Father, Pilot, Husband and Best-Selling Author

October 2015 - The Hon Justice Jane Mathews AO - First Female NSW Supreme Court Judge
August 2015 - Geraldine Doogue - Presenter, Journalist and Author
July 2015 - Professor the Hon Stephen Martin - Chief Executive, Centre for Economic Development Australia

June 2015 - Peter Baines - Founder of Hands Across the Water and Expert in Sustainable Leadership
April 2015 - Peter Martin - Economic Editor, The Age
February 2015 - Jerrold Cripps - Former Commissioner of the Independent Council against Corruption
December 2014 - David Stephens - Singer / Cabaret Performer
October 2014 - Ryan Campbell - Young Adventurer of the Year 2013
August 2014 - Rod Matthews - Human Performance Specialist
June 2014 - Her Excellency Professor The Honourable Marie Bashir - Governor of NSW

April 2014 - Major General B.W. (Hori) Howard AO, MC, ESSM (Retd)
February 2014 - Brendan Lyon - Chief Executive, Infrastructure Partnerships Australia 

December 2013 - Brendan Dowrick - Commonwealth Games Gymnastics Gold Medalist

October 2013 - Dr Adrian (Adi) Paterson - CEO, Australian Nuclear Science and Technology Organisation (ANSTO)
August 2013 - Dr Alex Zelinsky - Chief Defence Scientist and Head of DSTO
May 2013 - Kerry Chikarovski - Director, Chikarovski & Associates
April 2013 - Sebastian Terry - Author of The 100 Things
February 2013 - Professor Howard M. Armitage - Director of the Conrad Business, Entrepreneurship and Technology at the University of Waterloo, Canada
October 2012 - General David Hurley, AC, DSC - Chief of the Australian Defence Force
August 2012 - Dr Erica Smyth - Chair, Toro Energy Limited
June 2012 - Jim Maxwell - ABC Grandstand Sports Presenter
April 2012 - Jonathan Pain - Author of The Pain Report

February 2012 - Martin O'Shannessy - CEO, Newspoll
December 2011 - Professor Gerard Sutton AO - Vice Chancellor, University of Wollongong

October 2011 - Hugh Mackay - Psychologist, Social Researcher and Writer
 June 2011 - Ross Gittins OAM - Economics Journalist and Commentator

April 2011 - John McGrath - CEO, McGrath Real Estate
February 2011 - Mark McCrindle BSc (Psychology), MA, QMPR - Director, McCrindle Research
October 2010 - The Hon John Fahey - President of the World Anti-Doping Agency
 August 2010 - David Chalke - Leading Australian Social Analyst
June 2010 - Arthur Sinodinos AO - Managing Director, Institutional Banking, Business Banking Australia
April 2010 - Alex Frino PhD - CEO, Capital Markets CRC Limited

February 2010 - Cheryl Kernot, Director of Social Enterprise: The Centre for Social Impact

December 2009 - General Peter Cosgrove (Ret'd) AC, MC ndc (Ind), jssc, psc (US), Dip Mil Stud, FAICD
October 2009 - Tim Costello - CEO, World Vision Australia
August 2009 - Glenn Stevens - Governor, Reserve Bank of Australia
June 2009 - Karin Moorehouse - TIGS Alumni
April 2009 - Brendan Burkett PhD OAM - Paralympian and Commonwealth Games Medalist
February 2009 - Colin Bloomfield - President of Illawarra Coal and Chair, NSW Minerals Council
December 2008 - Andrew Horabin & Penny Hartgerink
October 2008 - Tim Cope - National Geographic Adventure Honoree 2007 & Australian Adventurer of the Year 2006
August 2008 - Robyn Moore - Communication Expert
June 2008 - Panel of Speakers
April 2008 - John Brogden - CEO, Manchester Unity Australia
February 2008 - Candy Tymson - Leading Business Communicator and Author
December 2007 - Dr J John Smith - Expert on Creativity and Lateral Thinking
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Former NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Managing Director</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Adrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Grandstand Sports Presenter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best-Selling Author</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leading Business Communicator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheryl Kernot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director of Social</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Baines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons NRL Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Economic Editor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hon Stephen Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief of the Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games Medalist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Wingate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robyn Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Vice-Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Alex Zelinsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Social Impact</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCrindle Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communication Expert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Brogden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Maxwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Frino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skippy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Female NSW Supreme Court Judge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ind</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Peter Cosgrove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Geographic Adventure Honoree 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabaret Performer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leading Australian Social Analyst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Major General B.W</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nowra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Howard M. Armitage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark McCrindle BSc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Economics Journalist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercury Enterprise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Counter-terrorism Expert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Waterloo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hon Justice Jane Mathews AO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Bailey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Defence Scientist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Adventurer of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Tile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February, 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan Mills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sustainable Leadership</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Pain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tic</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugh Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Strategies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Best-Selling Author</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Technology Organisation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Banking Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Grinder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QMPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's NSW Local Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Bloomfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Davey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yvonne Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Markets CRC Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Champion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Lancaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Tribute Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Vision Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Candy Tymson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Former Commissioner of the Independent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Executive</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honourable Marie Bashir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Kell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Projects Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Connection</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sebastian Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games Gymnastics Gold Medalist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feb 2006</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karin Moorehouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panel of Speakers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newspolls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Gerard Sutton AO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury Bankstown Bulldogs CEO Raelene Castle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TIGS Alumni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Horabin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General David Hurley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Summerill</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven Tourism Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin O'Shannessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard AO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerrold Cripps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Chalke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wave FM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Sinodinos AO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FAICD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Joscelyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of TIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Adventurer of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Dowrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Suter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Grammar School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Stephens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Paul's Anglican Church Shellharbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the World</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Erica Smyth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Summerill</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director of the Conrad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Borghetti AO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Millward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Order of Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tweed Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Buckley, of Peoplecare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Matthews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Cope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Nuclear Science</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESSM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chikarovski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Excellency Professor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Author of The Pain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Lancaster, of Lancaster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Minerals Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hon John Fahey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Performance Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dip Mil Stud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday's TIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DSC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geraldine Doogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Founder of Hands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Economic Development Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Head of DSTO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Defense Forces</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Frino PhD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toro Energy Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-Doping Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Partnerships Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester Unity Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr J John Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Gittins OAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ADI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lateral Thinking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Performance Specialist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Summerill's 41</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice Chancellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerry Chikarovski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANSTO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shell Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Film</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Burkett PhD OAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Hartgerink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABCradio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
