<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410733590183969</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/for-easier-dog-baths-just-shower-with-your-pet/</url>
  <title>For Easier Dog Baths, Just Shower With Your Pet</title>
  <content>
My best friend and life partner, Tucker Bordeaux III, recently turned 14. While he's thankfully in relatively good health for a man approaching 100 in dog years, he's developed some skin issues in his old age that require me to give him a bath every few days. Tucker, as you might imagine, was not pleased with this development. After many a painful attempt at giving him baths in the kitchen sink and tub on his own, I finally broke down and just put him in the shower with me one day. We were both a ton happier.

E.Price

When I would bathe him on his own, Tucker would constantly shake to try and get the water off, attempt to escape the bathtub/sink where the bath was taking place, and try to avoid being washed at all costs. Baths would take way longer than they should, and I always ended up covered in dog shampoo and water, enough so that I felt like I needed to jump in the shower right after.

And then one day I just put him in the shower with me.

Obviously, your mileage may vary depending on your dog's personality, but for Tucker when I'm showering he for some reason is totally fine just standing there and showering as well. I think when he's the one getting the bath he feels singled out, but if it's what we're both doing then it's for some reason much more acceptable. He's getting attention and he's not the only one that has to stand in the water.

He's happy to just stand in the bathtub and let me shampoo him as long as I'm doing it too. He'll even stand in the shower after I get out and wait for me to come towel him off before he takes off running. It was a refreshing change, and something I regret not trying earlier.

Tucker is roughly 11kg, which is probably bordering on the largest dog you'd want to try this with (you need room in the shower too, after all). If you do try it, I recommend making sure you have a guard up to prevent your drain getting clogged with dog hair. Trust me, there will be dog hair.

That said, if you end up drenched every time you try and give Fido a bath, then give it a try. At least you're trying to get wet this time.

WATCH MORE: Home Ideas & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Ideas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tucker Bordeaux III</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Easier Dog Baths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E.Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tucker</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Shower With Your Pet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FIDO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
