<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410733590183961</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-02/roos-happy-with-scott-but-no-resigning-rush-</url>
  <title>Roos happy with Scott, but no re-signing rush</title>
  <content>
North Melbourne is in no rush to re-contract coach Brad Scott

NORTH Melbourne is in no rush to secure coach Brad Scott's future beyond 2018, with the club to wait until at least the end of this season before having talks, chairman Ben Buckley says.

Scott, who has coached North since 2010, is contracted until the end of next season and Buckley said the club wanted all the relevant information in its hands before entering into negotiations.

"You've got to look at the circumstances, Brad's contracted. If we decided to have a discussion with him about the future beyond next year, well, that's something we'll consider at the end of the year," Buckley told SEN Radio.

"He's been doing a really good job and we've been happy with the performance of the team this year.

"We'll sit down at the end of the year and start to review not only next year but the years ahead, and I'm sure at that point in time we'll have some discussion about the coach's position.

"I think he's enjoying what he's doing. The board is very happy with the coaching staff and the team."

There has been speculation that Scott may want to leave the club and take up an opportunity elsewhere, with North in a transition period over the coming years after letting go of veterans Brent Harvey, Nick Dal Santo, Drew Petrie and Michael Firrito at the end of last season.

Scott has already been linked to the top job at Collingwood if the Magpies decide to re-sign Nathan Buckley.

Buckley said Scott was committed to coaching North Melbourne.

"He's contracted and he's said that he's more than happy with his role at the club," Buckley said.

"I've got nothing to suggest otherwise in all the discussions I've had. Those conversations have been very consistent.

"But, like anything, you always do some sort of review at the end of the year. Are we tracking in line with where we want to be, not only this year but for the years ahead?"

North Melbourne has already signalled it will be a player in this year's trade and free agency periods, with Richmond superstar Dustin Martin and Greater Western Sydney jet Josh Kelly high on its wish list.

Buckley said the club had the opportunity to be bold, with the board backing the football department team's aggressive stance in pursuing star players.

"The football department came to us with a plan and who they wanted to speak to in the uncontracted players and free agency markets, and we talked about the values they might need to spend to attract those players," Buckley said.

"As a board we gave them approval to go out and talk to agents and players and see if they could secure those players to come to North Melbourne.

"Clearly you'd like to land a number of players who would bring elite talent into your football club.

"We'll be very active in the market place. We said from last year that we would have room in the cap to do so, and I said to all our supporters that we would be very aggressive in going to the market place to attract the best possible talent we can."

The Kangaroos are also keen to lock away emerging forward Ben Brown, who comes out of contract at the end of next season.

Brown, who is equal second on the Coleman Medal leaderboard, has had a breakout season for North in 2017, kicking 51 goals.

"I'll leave that to the footy department to have those discussions and plan that out," Buckley said.

But clearly Ben has been an outstanding performer for us.

"We'd love to secure him for some years to come."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Firrito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Dal Santo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEN Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
