<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410729295216540</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/rendezview/my-dad-was-number-60-on-the-road-toll/news-story/c4131bf75b660b566c940392a3c4308b</url>
  <title>My Dad was Number 60 on the road toll</title>
  <content>
Princes William and Harry have in a fatal car crash twenty years ago.
I can't imagine what they endured when that happened to them as children, but I do know what it's like to have someone instantly ripped from your life because of a motor vehicle accident.
Four years ago, my father was number 60 on the road toll. I know this because the last sentence at the end of one of the news articles on his crash was "This takes the state's road toll to 60."
It was a chilling statement to read, and one which I think of every time I get behind the wheel. I suppose I have the 'benefit' of this experience, but many Australians don't.
For the month of June 2017, the national road toll was 111. One hundred and eleven people died in Australia that month in car accident-caused fatalities.
But we all know the cars aren't the main reason accidents happen. It's drivers: speed, fatigue, drugs and alcohol, and mobile phone usage.
We are dying and killing each other at an unfathomable rate.
Perhaps enough of us don't understand the agony and brutality of what happens behind the statistics - but we need to. Making road respect inherent in all drivers is the only hope we have of saving lives.
Fatal car crashes are a violent cause of death. What you read and see in the media about them barely scratches the surface of the graphic details, and the suffering inflicted on anyone else affected by the fatality.
My father, Number 60, had a medical episode behind the wheel, entered an intersection, was hit by an oncoming vehicle, spun around 180 degrees, and smashed into a building. He died at the scene.
And then I learnt about things I never thought I'd have to deal with. The Coroner's Office. The autopsy report. How a dead body doesn't look peaceful, or asleep - it just looks dead. It's very cold to touch, and if there's been an autopsy, where organs have been removed, the body looks deflated. It was no longer the body of the man whose all-encompassing bear hugs I'd grown up with.
I learnt that when the police are done investigating the car, you collect the personal contents that they have bagged, and it will contain some very confronting shattered vehicle glass.
I read my first ever major police report. It was utterly brutal and clinical, and undoubtedly the worst thing I've ever read. I demanded to read it, because I wanted to understand. It was a large document that told the story of how my father died. There were heartbreaking photos of my father's mangled car.
The memory of those photos has helped me keep my cool on the road many times.
It sounds like a cliche, but the part I still struggle with today is that I never got to say goodbye. It made the death surreal for a long time. The suddenness was disorienting. For months I wondered how a person can be alive and well one second, and simply dead the next? How does some just vanish?
Obviously, my experience of losing a parent in a car crash is not exactly comparable to William's and Harry's, who were 15 and 12, respectively (and I'm not royalty). But I can relate to a major part of what they revealed in their interview; the pain of their regret. They spoke of being too busy having fun with their cousins to concentrate on what would be their last ever phone conversation with their mother, and how that has filled them with deep, enduring regret.
Regret is the part of grief that caught me off guard. I wasn't prepared for my overwhelming guilt about the things I didn't say or do when my father was here. I recall one night, a month before the crash, when I unexpectedly saw him at a restaurant. I was too busy to give him time. He wanted to come over later that week, but I wouldn't commit - I said I'd call.
And I did make that call, many, many times. But only after he died. When the regret suffocated me. Four years later, it has only just subsided.
I also feel guilty that I was away on the night of the accident, although, in many ways, I was spared. I didn't have to see my mother's face in the immediate hours after two police officers arrived on her doorstep and gave her the worst news of our lives.
I regularly visit the intersection where my father was last alive. I have left mangoes, my father's favourite fruit, against the damaged wall. I have stood in the morning sun photographing the tyre marks and collecting fragments of that special crumbled vehicle glass from the footpath.
I do all of this because I want him to know that what happened to him fundamentally changed me forever - and one day I hope it will finally feel like a goodbye.
I'm want the details of my experience to shock at least some drivers into concentrating on the enormous responsibility assumed when they put a key into an ignition. I don't think we take it seriously enough.
We must acknowledge that most of the time, cars don't kill people. Drivers kill people.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Number 60</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coroner's Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
