<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410209604163832</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/agedcare-plan-for-perths-hotel-to-the-stars/news-story/aae213db7e2ba64e3ef612d8e6542188</url>
  <title>Aged-care plan for top city hotel</title>
  <content>
PERTH'S exclusive hotel for the stars could become a high-end aged care facility after becoming the first victim of the city's cut-throat hotel market.
It is likely the five-star The Richardson, one of Perth's few privately owned hotels, will close and be converted by the end of the year.
A change-of-use development application has been lodged with the City of Perth.
It will be the first Perth accommodation hotel to close in many decades.
The owners blame the decision on Perth's chaotic hotel market, with the introduction of several new hotels over the last year and falling occupancy rates.
The Richardson opened in West Perth in 2006, with 74 rooms designed by British architect Sir Terry Farrell.
It has developed a reputation as a quiet, meticulously maintained hotel that has consistently attracted celebrities like Oprah Winfrey, Sting, Beyonce, John Cleese and former British prime minister Tony Blair.
Co-owner Joe Oxley said a significant change to the local landscape had put the future of the hotel at the crossroads.
"Things have changed dramatically since the Barnett State government offered a number of sweetheart deals to attract more hotels to WA," Mr Oxley said. "This was done in response to a so-called shortage of hotel rooms.
"But, in fact, there was only a shortage for 30 to 40 days in the year. And this was driven by demand for cheaper accommodation, not by demand for five-star hotels.
"Hotel chains seem to have developed a lemming mentality - if one of them was coming to Perth, the others had to follow.
"Now today, since the arrival of new hotels, they are all cutting each other's throats.
"There are now good hotels in the city offering rooms for under $100 a night."
Mr Oxley and business partner Ted Powell have been exploring a number of options for the Richardson Street hotel building over the last 16 months. At one stage, it was unofficially put up for sale for a rumoured $38 million.
But the option of converting the hotel into an aged care facility has emerged as an attractive option, prompting the development application.
Mr Oxley said changes could occur quite quickly, if the application is approved.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted Powell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oprah Winfrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Terry Farrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Oxley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-owner Joe Oxley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnett State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Cleese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
