<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410737885151277</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/helicopter-crashes-power-lines/3207789/</url>
  <title>Helicopter crashes into power lines</title>
  <content>
BREAKING: A helicopter with two occupants has crashed into power lines near Cloncurry in northwest Queensland.

Emergency crews including firefighters and ambulance officers are rushing to the scene, .

The helicopter is believed to have clipped power lines and crashed.

The incident was reported about 7.40am today.

The crash took place north of Cloncurry near Sedan Dip Road.

A fire has reportedly broken out at the scene of the crash.

The helicopter was believed to have been involved in a mustering operation before clipping power lines and crashing.

A second helicopter nearby is reportedly en route to a nearby station to gather firefighting equipment.

Baby whale rescued on the Sunshine Coast
Up to $214,000 remains on table for refocused investigation
Tensions simmered over in restaurant hygiene dispute.
AT Nambour State School, many pupils came to school by train.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloncurry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sedan Dip Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
