<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410682050575462</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/02/09/27/corn-silo-collapses-and-explodes-on-us-farm</url>
  <title>Corn silo collapses and explodes on US farm</title>
  <content>
A US farmer has come face to face with a tsunami of burning corn after a massive tank collapsed on his property.

Steve White and his son Jordon could do nothing but stare in horror as a huge container full of 352,000kg of corn began to buckle as it was being unloaded into a truck on his Indiana farm.

"Son of a gun," White Jnr could be heard saying off camera as the huge storage container collapsed, sending a bright yellow wave of corn hurtling towards him.

The collapsing silo also hit a nearby power line, causing a spark that temporarily ignited fibres in the air and created a huge wall of fire.

"We're really not sure at this time what caused it. We suspect it may have been a problem with the steel of the grain bin," White Snr told the .

"When that explosion happened... we got a lot of extensive damage. It sent a 180-foot wave that went up to the pipes of the leg... all kinds of electrical damage. We've got a mess."

The US famer said he will have his corn silo back up and running before harvest time despite the extensive damage.

Related Articles

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indiana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Jnr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Snr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
