<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410686345542882</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/canberra-schools-top-most-naplan-measures-20170801-gxmy49.html</url>
  <title>Canberra tops most NAPLAN tests, but not everyone is reaching the standard</title>
  <content>
The ACT has topped the nation on most measures in NAPLAN testing but recorded a weaker performance in helping students meet the national minimum standard.
Preliminary results, to be released on Wednesday, show the ACT was top in 15 out of 20 assessment domains based on students' 2016 mean scores.

Up Next

Man arrested over 'Sydney plane bomb plot' released without charge

00:28

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

NAPLAN 2017: Majority need re-sit to do HSC

For the first time, students in NSW will have to get three band 8's in order to sit the HSC. This year's results show almost seventy per cent fell short of the new standard.

When it came to meeting the national minimum benchmark, Canberra topped 14 out of 20 domains across all year levels. The territory particularly lagged in year 3 writing, where the number of students meeting the benchmark ranked third, and year 3 spelling, where it was fourth.
Using mean scores, the ACT fell behind on writing and spelling in years 3 and 5 and year 7 spelling.Photo: Pat Scala
A suite of recently-released reports have chastised Canberra schools for failing to lift the results of disadvantaged students.
Academics have agreed the territory, widely recognised as benefiting from a higher than average socioeconomic score, should do better.

Wednesday's data showed Canberra maintained or improved students' results on almost all domains between 2008 and 2016 - except for year 5 writing, where mean scores went backwards between 2011 and last year.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Education Directorate school improvement director Kate Smith said the directorate was focused on ensuring all students recorded at least a year's worth of growth from one NAPLAN test to the next.
Ms Smith said the directorate's focused improvement agenda should help the ACT record better results.
"I think with the way that we're focusing on improving our schools through the National School Improvement Tool and really harnessing strong professional learning resources, upskilling our teachers, upskilling our leaders, getting comments out and workshops out into the community ... even in a couple of years time we would be very hopeful that going through this very strong improvement agenda that we would see our results taking a sharp slope up," she said.
Education Minister Yvette Berry said the report showed a high level of student achievement in the ACT and pointed to directorate analysis which found 92 per cent of students performed at or above the national minimum standard across all year groups and most assessment domains.
"While assessing achievement in foundation skills is important, a high quality school education will also support broader learning towards wider educational objectives," she said.
"Through the Future of Education conversation the government is seeking community feedback on how we can better support students with the foundation skills that they need as well as equipping them with skills for work and life."
The Australian Curriculum, Assessment and Reporting Authority, which runs NAPLAN, said analysis of the national results showed there had been growth across most year levels.
"Importantly, we see a gradual redistribution of students from lower bands of achievement to higher ones, particularly in some domains and year levels, such as year 3 reading," chief executive Robert Randall said.
"In other areas, this improvement has not always been great enough to significantly impact average national results, but it is a positive trend."
Schools will receive individual results from mid-August to mid-September, which will then be mailed to students.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Randall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reporting Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National School Improvement Tool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Scala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Directorate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Curriculum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Yvette Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
