<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410682050575453</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/mission-to-name-unmarked-graves-barmera-cemetery/8764444</url>
  <title>Buried without a memorial: One woman's mission to name unmarked graves</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Who is buried in this unmarked grave and why is there no headstone or memorial?
The question plagued Barmera woman Judy Bannear every time she stood at one of the 300 unmarked graves at the Barmera cemetery in regional South Australia.
So with the support of the local council, she has taken it upon herself to try to identify every unmarked grave at the cemetery using old council burial records and cemetery mapping.
"It's my baby, I want to identify graves. I just think it is so sad to see these crosses and they belong to nobody," Ms Bannear said.
"I want to record their date of death and their names."
The graves were unadorned at the time of interment.
The simple white crosses were added more than a decade ago by a cemetery worker, in his spare time.

Most days Ms Bannear can be found walking between the rows of graves in the old section of the cemetery, checking plots against cemetery archives to find out who was buried without any permanent memorial.
"You just wonder, you see names of young children, and you think whatever happened to them, when they were 18 months, six months, three months. It is all so sad," she said.
"If people do come back to find their loved one they can't. It's just something to be recorded and I think it's important.
"I'm prepared to put in whatever it takes. I would like to get it done before the summer.
"I'm well and truly three-quarters of the way through it, but then I will check and double check to make sure I have it right."
A telling part of cemetery history

Unmarked graves tell stories of impoverished lives, social attitudes and burial practices.
The great composer Wolfgang Mozart was believed to be buried in an , while the family of Apple co-founder Steve Jobs requested the exact location of .
Many unmarked graves belong to stillborn babies or babies who died soon after birth.
At Adelaide's West Terrace Cemetery, .

Searching for a baby or sibling after many decades

The unmarked graves at the Barmera cemetery date back to the 1920s.
It was a time when money was scarce as pioneering fruit growers forged irrigation settlements along the River Murray post-WWI.
Perhaps there was less sentimentality over the loss of life; perhaps families wanted to keep some things secret.
Berri Barmera Council cemetery curator Dorothy Freer has often been asked to help find graves belonging to babies and children.
"I think in those days when the young girls were unmarried there was a lot of shame back then to be having a baby," she said.
"A lot of things were kept secret in families and only found when an older family member had passed away and [people] were going through paperwork."
Ms Freer tells the story of a local woman who wanted to find her baby's grave.
"She was looking for a baby, she had been 15 when her baby was born stillborn and she didn't know where her parents had buried the baby, which cemetery it was buried in," she said.
"She was in her 50s, it had been weighing on her mind.
"There are those cases, which are very sad, where 40 years down the track they are trying to find a sibling or child."

There were no details about the type of burial these people received, but some would almost certainly have been without ceremony.
"We have identified certain graves in the cemetery that we would say were council graves," Ms Freer said.
"Looking back in the old books we cannot see that anything was paid for the plot.
"So we would say it was a pauper's grave where council has provided the plot to the person. We are assuming they were buried in some sort of casket or box."
Small plaque to be placed at each grave

The grave of the stillborn baby was eventually located using old cemetery records and maps, the same archives that will be used to identify who has been buried in each unmarked grave at the Barmera cemetery and later the nearby Berri cemetery.
Unmarked graves became rare after the 1950s, and today council requires a small plaque on every burial site.
"A new interment will have a grave marker with a name, date of death, so anyone walking past can find it," Ms Freer said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barmera</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's West Terrace Cemetery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berri Barmera Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Jobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorothy Freer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Freer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy Bannear</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bannear</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolfgang Mozart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
