<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410682050575500</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/business/townsville-school-to-develop-philanthropic-entrepreneurs/news-story/a0c91ba59a08f7207a2b48214f7f20fe</url>
  <title>Catholic school pioneers new subject</title>
  <content>
A CATHOLIC school in Townsville is pioneering teaching in business and entrepreneurism with the launch of a subject called The Start-Up.
The course by St Patrick's College will aim to provide students with the skills they need to manage projects and develop problem solving for philanthropic endeavours.
The college's principal, Paulina Skerman, said the program was about trying to prepare students for a rapidly changing world as well as develop young entrepreneurs driven by the desire to make the world a better place.
"The Start-Up will provide the students with an intensive program of skill development over two years, including contribution from industry," Ms Skerman said.
"It is an innovative way of using education and industry to create a specific skill set that will result in market-ready solutions for real-world needs.
"We are about preparing our girls for the real world, giving them the skills to live fulfilled, purposeful lives of mercy and action."
Students will be required to research and identify a need and create a strategic business solution.
At the end of the two years, -students will present their commercial project to a panel.
Guest presenters from industry will work with the students throughout the program.
"It will develop skills such as collaboration, critical thinking, time management and a strong work ethic," Ms Skerman said.
"It will also draw upon personal values including empathy, compassion, optimism and a desire to make the world a better place through entrepreneurism."
The elective subject will commence in 2018 for 10 girls in Year 9 and will run for two years.
The course will draw on areas -including science, technology, -engineering, mathematics, phil-osophy, philanthropy, entrepreneurship, business and design-thinking.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Skerman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Start-up</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulina Skerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Patrick's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
