<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410733590183933</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/its-time-to-write-that-screenplay-youre-always-talking-about-2017-8</url>
  <title>It's time to write that screenplay you're always talking about</title>
  <content>
You shouldn't have to fuss with trivial details when you're writing the next great screenplay. That's why top writing talent like JJ Abrams, James Cameron, and Aaron Sorkin use  to turn their ideas into award-winning hits.

The industry standard for professional screenwriters and studios worldwide, Final Draft 10 takes the hassle out of formatting and paginating your scripts, so you can spend more time writing Emmy-worthy content. With Final Draft 10, your scripts are automatically paginated to industry standards, and you can use more than 100 templates to streamline your screenplays, teleplays, stage plays, and the like.

Now, you can start writing smarter with Final Draft 10 for 40 percent off its usual price. Get it . And for a limited time, get an extra 15 percent off with code FINALDRAFT15.

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

The Insider Picks team writes about stuff we think you'll like. We aim to highlight products and services you might find interesting, and if you buy them, we may get a small share of the revenue from the sale from our commerce partners, including Amazon. Jeff Bezos, CEO of Amazon, is an investor in Business Insider, the US partner of BI Australia's publishing company Allure Media, through his personal investment company Bezos Expeditions.
Insider Picks are independent of Allure Media's editorial and advertising teams. Click  to learn more.

NOW WATCH: Ideas videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Final Draft 10</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emmy-worthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Sorkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BI Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Bezos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allure Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bezos Expeditions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JJ Abrams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Picks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FINALDRAFT15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
