<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409960496055441</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/02/turnbull-bind-same-sex-marriage-vote</url>
  <title>Turnbull in a bind on same-sex marriage vote</title>
  <content>
Malcolm Turnbull is in a fresh tangle over same-sex marriage, with two opposing groups of coalition MPs determined to get their way.

1 HOUR AGO  UPDATED 8 MINS AGO

Conservative senator Eric Abetz insists the government must hold a national vote on  but won't say whether he will be swayed by its outcome.

Malcolm Turnbull is facing calls from within the Liberal Party to take a second stab at securing parliament's approval for a plebiscite on .

However, there is also pressure for a partyroom meeting next Tuesday to discuss a private member's bill being proposed by a small group of Liberal backbenchers.

Mr Turnbull has reportedly called two of those MPs - Queensland's Trevor Evans and Western Australia's Dean Smith - urging them to support the government's plebiscite policy.

Related reading

But News Corp said the two men were sticking with their plans.

Another pro-marriage proponent, Warren Entsch, told News that he was prepared to continue even if the right continued to threaten Mr Turnbull's leadership.

Senator Abetz, a staunch opponent of , refused to commit to taking heed of a plebiscite if the overwhelming majority of Australians were in favour.

"I think it is appropriate that the minority view, whatever that may be, is still expressed within the parliament," he told Sky News on Tuesday night.

Senator Abetz said coalition MPs crossing the floor on  would be "exceptionally grave" for the Turnbull government.

"What it would tell the Australian people is that the government has lost its authority, has lost control on the floor of the house," he said.

"Any of my colleagues that might be contemplating such action should be thinking about this not two or three times, but a dozen times, and then come to the conclusion that losing government is not worth it."

Related reading

The prime minister has told reporters in Perth the government's position is clear.

"We made a commitment to give every Australian a say on this issue and that is our policy - it has not changed," Mr Turnbull said.

Assistant Minister Alex Hawke says it would be good for the government to resubmit the bill to the Senate and urge crossbenchers to look at it again in the light of strong public support.

Queensland Liberal MP Andrew Laming says the government should remain focused on delivering a plebiscite.

A voluntary postal vote - which did not require legislation - was a "highly worthy option" and likely to be cheaper.

Cabinet minister Peter Dutton, who favours the postal vote model, says it is time for the issue to be dealt with "behind closed doors".

"Now is the time for people, having had their say, frankly to contain their comments until they get back to the party room. That's where the Liberal Party has our best discussions and our best debates," he told 5AA radio.

One of the supporters of a private bill, Victorian Liberal MP Tim Wilson, has told colleagues and local branch members he could cross the floor of parliament.

However, he would not back a Labor version of the same bill.

Other Liberal backers could include Trent Zimmerman from NSW.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Minister Alex Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Abetz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 8 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Liberal MP Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Liberal MP Andrew Laming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia's Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOURS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
