<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410725000249121</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-02/princess-dianas-life-loves-and-legacy-again-in-the-limelight-as-anniversary-of-her-death-approaches/1690502</url>
  <title>Princess Diana's life, loves and legacy again in the limelight as anniversary of her death approaches</title>
  <content>
Twenty years on from her death, Princess Diana has returned to the public spotlight in Britain.
Her items are on display in palaces, old photos have been made public and a string of TV shows are being broadcast, each with tiny titbits of new information about the private life of the "People's Princess".
Royal reporters and "insiders" insist the 20th anniversary of her untimely demise was always going to be a big deal - they are all now cashing in with paid media appearances, "special" magazine editions, books or articles.
To be fair, Prince William and Prince Harry are breaking with tradition and speaking publicly too.
They reportedly wanted to use the milestone to reflect on their mother's life.
"They've talked very recently about how difficult it has been for them to overcome their grief," HELLO! Magazine Royal correspondent Emily Nash says.
"They had to deal with this for a long time in the public spotlight."

Video:(ABC News)
Diana anniversary brings fresh controversy

But forensically examining and debating Princess Diana's life, loves and legacy yet again was always going to lead to some sort of controversy.
Currently, it is a series of tapes .
They were made with Diana's voice coach, Peter Settelen, in the early 1990s.
They capture the princess describing intimate details of her failed marriage and are now the basis for a Channel 4 documentary, which is due to air in a few days.

Photo:(AP: Kensington Palace)
Parts of the tapes have already been broadcast in America, so should anyone care about what was said so long ago?
Princess Diana's brother does. .
Former confidants of the princess are divided.
Some agree with the outraged Earl and have called the decision to broadcast them "grubby" and "shameful".
But others, including Channel 4, say the tapes are now an important part of the public record and allow Diana to tell her own story.
When will the Diana media storm end?

Photo:(Reuters)
In Cafe Diana, where the late princess came for coffee on a few occasions, patrons are intrigued by the debate.
Anniversary pieces about the Royal family usually feature the predictable, heavily sanitised tributes, while this documentary reportedly shows Diana speaking relatively uncensored about bulimia, Camilla and Prince Charles.
"She lived with the media coverage throughout her life, she used to tell me about the cameras following her, she was used to it," cafe owner Abdul Daoud says.
"Now her family has more of the same".
The cafe walls are plastered with pictures of the princess and a few personal letters too.
But some customers say the anniversary has already been blown well and truly out of proportion by the media.
"What I don't particularly like is the focus on her previous romantic relationships," Abida Mian says.
"Her personal life is nobody else's business".
The anniversary is not until the end of the month and in the lead-up more right Royal helpings of Diana stories are planned.
Perhaps once August 31 passes, the princess and her legacy will be finally allowed to rest in peace.

Photo:Tributes are piled up at Place de L'Alma on August 30, 1998, above the underpass where Princess Diana was killed in 1997.(Reuters: Mousse Mousse)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Settelen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cafe Diana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess Diana</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kensington Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Daoud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Nash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 4</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abida Mian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
