<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410767949922834</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/national/public-service/liberal-fissures-lets-fortunate-bill-shorten-bask-in-a-winter-of-content-20170725-gxibcb.html</url>
  <title>Bill Shorten basks in winter of content as Liberals squabble</title>
  <content>
Bill Shorten is in a fortunate position at the moment. The ructions inside the Liberal Party are a decided plus for him. The heat is off. He is basking in a winter of content.
Labor's intricate factional system is less of a turn-off for voters in the context created by the Turnbull and Abbott imbroglio. Nonetheless it is institutionalised and over the longer term it is still a potentially vexed thing for Shorten.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
Shorten is very much a "faction man" (to quote the writer David Marr). Before entering Federal Parliament he was national secretary of the Australian Workers' Union which is a key member of Labor's right faction. 
A good factional player acquires an entourage and Shorten is no exception. Photo: James Davies
At the fag end of the Rudd-Gillard-Rudd era in 2013 his ministerial staff included the scholar and speechwriter Nick Dyrenfurth.  
When he was a Shorten staffer, Dyrenfurth was urged in private (if only by me) to write an insider's chronicle of Labor's downfall in 2013. Realistically a candid account of this kind will never see the light of day, but all is not lost. The next best thing has just appeared in the form of a new history of the AWU, Shorten's old union, written by Dyrenfurth, his former staffer.

This AWU book is entitled A Powerful Influence on Australian Affairs. Such a title is well-justified.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Dyrenfurth's message is one of persistence in a harsh environment. His account shows how the AWU's entrenched power and influence dates back to the earliest years of the Australian federation.  But for the AWU, the nascent Labor Party in the 1890s would have become cooped up in a few easily gerrymandered urban electorates.
The ALP escaped this fate and went to enjoy lusty adolescent growth because it was linked to the AWU.  The AWU unionised pastoral and mining workers scattered across regional and rural Australia. Its paid full-time organisers set up and ran local Labor branches across the wide brown land. AWU newspapers proclaimed the gospel of Laborism.
The AWU, because of its pivotal role in propagating the Labor message, came to be seen as the embodiment of an Australian ethos of egalitarianism and mateship. It helped to consolidate support for key early federal initiatives such as compulsory arbitration and, regrettably, the White Australia policy.
Dyrenfurth is right to stress the AWU's resilience over the years. In the less heady decades that set in after World War I, AWU leaders saw off repeated perceived challenges.
Throughout this long tussle employers and business people have often been the least of the AWU's worries.  As Bill Shorten demonstrated in his years with the AWU, his union prefers to do deals with the business sector.  Where there is animus, it is usually generated against the AWU and other unions by assorted free market ideologues.
The AWU's atavistic enemy instead is other labour people. Dyrenfurth's book is peppered with accounts of conflict with other unions (such as the Federated Ironworkers' Association in its various guises) and with rebellious grassroots industrial activists. Over the years the AWU waged war against the Labor hero Jack Lang, the Communist Party of Australia and the trade union disciples of BA Santamaria.
The AWU's famed cult of mateship has long dwindled into a snaky form of cliquishness. 
Justice Dyson Heydon's Royal Commission in 2014 directed a spotlight on Shorten's time as an AWU deal maker and also on Julia Gillard's 1990s link, via Bruce Wilson, with factionalism in the union. In the case of both individuals no wrongdoing was upheld but the union was put on the defensive.
The pressure has told. For the first time in almost a hundred years the membership of the AWU is below 100,000.
Within the ALP the left faction of late has gained power at the expense of the AWU and its friends in the right faction. The left has an increased presence on the national executive.
It will be a big thing if Shorten does not win the next federal election. Such a defeat would trigger an internal election for a new federal leader involving rank and file party members.
The AWU is uncomfortable with any form of grass roots action that is uncontrolled from above. It can be counted on to do its utmost to prevent a successful rank and file insurgency in any future election for federal party leader. Nick Dyrenfurth's new book provides a reminder of just how hard the AWU eventually hits back when it feels that its core territory is being threatened.
Stephen Holt is a Canberra-based writer. 
 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Workers' Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Dyson Heydon's Royal Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federated Ironworkers' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communist Party of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Lang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laborism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Powerful Influence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Marr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Holt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BA Santamaria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dyrenfurth</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudd-Gillard-Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Affairs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Gillard's 1990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWU</name>
    <count>21</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Dyrenfurth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
