<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410737885151296</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-01/road-to-the-draft-whats-the-latest-with-josh-kelly</url>
  <title>Road to the Draft: What's the latest with Josh Kelly?</title>
  <content>
Join AFL.com.au draft experts  and as we track the best prospects in the land all the way to November's NAB AFL Draft.

On this week's episode:

- GWS recruiting manager Adrian Caruso joins the show
- Caruso chats about the Giants' list and what they'll be targeting this year
- How did the Giants settle on Tim Taranto last year? Caruso gives an insight into some of the club's recent early picks
- We get an update on the Giants' academy prospects and who might be coming through
- What's the latest with out-of-contract Giants Josh Kelly, Jacob Hopper and Devon Smith?
- And how does Caruso rate this year's draft pool?

Subscribe and make sure you don't miss an episode

Featuring exclusive interviews with some of the top draft prospects, leading AFL recruiters and talent experts, Road to the Draft is the best way to find out who your club is targeting from the next generation of superstars.

Road to the Draft airs every week in the lead-up to the NAB AFL Draft.

Click here to subscribe to Road to the Draft  or .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB AFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devon Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November's NAB AFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Taranto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caruso</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Hopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giants Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Caruso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
