<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410295503511437</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/astonishing-xray-pictures-show-why-you-should-always-wear-a-seatbelt/news-story/57952f5353cc9f65f0bc1dbf63a266fe</url>
  <title>Stunning before-and-after car crash pictures</title>
  <content>
THESE amazing medical scans show a woman's skull before and after reconstructive surgery following a horrific car crash.
The CT scans are of a 25-year-old woman who was thrown from a car in America while not wearing her seat belt.
She required several hours of surgery to reconstruct the injuries to her face, which included her eye being found near her nasal cavity.
The ophthalmology surgeon who treated her posted the pictures on medical website Figure 1.
He said: "A trauma work-up revealed a traumatic brain injury with intracranial haemorrhage, a traumatic eye injury requiring enucleation, and extensive facial fractures.
"This CT shows her completed facial reconstruction. Thanks to a dedicated multidisciplinary team, the patient is now ambulatory and recovering well."
The surgeon has been praised for his handy work and the post has been viewed more than 644,000 times.
A registered nurse said: "Amazing job.
"The repairs turned out perfect. Nice work."
Another said: "Literally spectacular. Medicine at its finest right there."
While another user, a midwife, wrote: "Such a fantastic job.
"An absolute credit to reconstruction talent.
"It is work like this that makes the long tedious hours of training worthwhile."
Many likened the case to putting Humpty Dumpty back together again.
The surgeon who posted the pictures later informed those who had followed the case that the patient was doing well after the surgery.
He wrote: "Patient is actually doing well and looks great."

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Humpty Dumpty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Figure 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
