<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410166654489932</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/man-arrested-over-sydney-terrorism-plane-bomb-plot-released-without-charge-20170801-gxngtw.html</url>
  <title>Man arrested over 'Sydney terrorism plane bomb plot' released without charge</title>
  <content>
One of the Sydney men arrested in connection with an alleged terrorist plot to bring down a plane has been released without charge.
The 50-year-old man was taken into custody with three other family members on Saturday after international intelligence agencies became aware of an alleged elaborate  from Sydney to the Middle East.Photo: AAP
The other three men remain in custody after being arrested by the NSW Joint Counter Terrorism Team in a series of raids in Surry Hills, Wiley Park, Lakemba and Punchbowl.
On Wednesday morning, a joint statement from the Australian Federal Police and the NSW Police Force said the investigation into the alleged plot was ongoing.

The three other men will remain in detention under "specified time" provisions outlined in the Crimes Act.
Security sources said the alleged plot involved a meat grinder that would either explode or disperse a deadly gas on a flight.
The alleged plot was uncovered after intelligence was provided to Australian agencies by US and British authorities.
Two of the men arrested are believed to be related to a man who has joined the so-called Islamic State group in Syria in 2014 and was once regarded as an active recruiter.
The ABC reported that another of the other men arrested, Khaled Khayat, has a brother who is a senior Islamic State figure in Syria.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle East.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Joint Counter Terrorism Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crimes Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Khaled Khayat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
