<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410342748152764</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/gws-giants-recruit-brett-deledio-set-for-club-debut-ahead-of-round-21-clash-with-melbourne/news-story/466551a8dbc32f336f731540b779f8f5</url>
  <title>'There will be nervousness everywhere'</title>
  <content>
GREATER Western Sydney had to take the risk and blood veteran recruit Brett Deledio for his club debut this weekend, according to former AFL great Garry Lyon.
Deledio, who has battled calf injuries for the best part of 13 months, is yet to represent the Giants having moved to the club via a trade from the Tigers at the conclusion of last season.
However, he will finally do so when GWS takes on Melbourne in Canberra on Saturday, despite playing only six quarters of NEAFL football since making his return to the field.
Deledio finally ran out in Giants colours a fortnight ago, racking up 17 disposals in a half for the side's NEAFL team in a narrow victory over Sydney University.
He then played a full four quarters last weekend as UWSG went down to Gold Coast, winning 25 disposals from eight marks in a promising display that had him pushing for a senior recall.
Although his preparation for this week's clash hasn't been ideal, Lyon believes the time is right with four weeks remaining in the AFL season to finally risk Deledio at senior level.
"You divert to the experts at GWS who have got a greater understanding of where he's at," Lyon said on SEN Breakfast on Wednesday morning.
LISTEN TO THE ROUND 19 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW, OR
"There will be nervousness everywhere when Brett Deledio plays on Saturday against Melbourne, mostly from Brett himself and from his family and his footy club.
"We've seen it with Harley Bennell, who has had a similar recurrence. I don't care how much training you do - he would've trained for a long time without having an incident.
"You can play another six NEAFL games, but until you get into the cut and thrust of an AFL game where it's demanding and it's explosive and you have to go, you're not going to know.
"It's probably that time at Round 20 where we might as well find out right now. Put him out there, let him go and if he breaks down, he breaks down."
Western Bulldogs captain Robert Murphy missed the majority of the side's 2016 season with a knee injury and conceded you still have to take a "leap of faith" before returning to footy.
However, he dismissed suggestions that Deledio would be underdone having played only six quarters in the NEAFL over the last two weeks.
"When you first hear it, you think it doesn't sound like a lot of footy," Murphy said.
"But because of how closely they can monitor your player profile - in terms of how you run, how much you run, metres per minute - they're probably able to replicate the game running more in training than they can in a lower level of footy.
"You can do all of the preparation, all of the numbers and all of the data, (but) there's still a leap of faith."

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley Bennell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UWSG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROUND 19 REVIEW FOX FOOTY PODCAST BELOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEN Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
