<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410553201554060</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/property/leasing-turmoil-as-murray-goulburn-cuts-costs-20170801-gxmvtq.html</url>
  <title>Leasing turmoil as Murray Goulburn cuts costs</title>
  <content>
Renewed turmoil at beleaguered dairy co-op Murray Goulburn could stall a move to swank new office space at Collins Square.
Murray Goulburn last year committed to the two top floors of tower four at Lang Walker's $2.5 billion office development at Docklands.Photo: Jared G Marshall
It is understood a $10 million dollar fit-out has been completed at the 5200-square-metre space but management is poised for a backflip as part of its corporate restructure.
Market speculation is rife. Some parties say Murray Goulburn will stay at Freshwater Place, where it has sublet 4000 square metres for the past five years, and sublease the Collins Square space.
A Murray Goulburn spokesperson said: "We are exploring options for our head office location to ensure that we have the most cost-effective and appropriate solution. Until a decision regarding the location of our head office is reached, we will continue as a short-term tenant at Freshwater Place with Essendon Fields sublet."
The co-op sublet space from Pricewaterhousecoopers but its lease expired last year and it moved to new digs next door. A new lease would likely be struck around $540 a square metre, or $2.16 million a year.

Market sources put the rent of the Collins Square space at $580 a square metre - $3 million a year - with an incentive that paid 75 per cent of the $10 million fit-out.
This is Murray Goulburn's second major office upset.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Six years ago, the co-op sold its Brunswick headquarters and signed a 10-year, $20 million deal for a new 5000 square metre building at Essendon Fields, a business park developed by Lindsay Fox and Max Beck's at Essendon Airport.
But after managing director Gary Helou joined the co-op in mid-2011, Murray Goulburn instead shifted to Freshwater Place.
The Essendon Fields space was later sublet to The Good Guys but it cost the co-op a one-off $6.27 million payment and the lease runs until 2023.
Last year, nearly five years after his appointment, Mr Helou resigned amid controversy after net profit forecasts were slashed by 40 per cent.
Conditions have not markedly improved. The rising Australian dollar and a slew of dairy farmers signing up with other milk processors are contributing to declining performance.
Milk factories are slated for closure or sale and international offices have been shut. Murray Goulburn is also writing off $148 million in liabilities created by extending loans to dairy farmers who were out of pocket last year over the discrepancy in milk prices.
To top it off, the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission is prosecuting the co-op, Mr Helou and financial officer Bradley Hingle alleging false and misleading representations were made over the milk prices in 2015-16.

 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Beck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Docklands.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Helou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Goulburn</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Good Guys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freshwater Place</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collins Square</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradley Hingle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Helou</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared G Marshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindsay Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lang Walker's $2.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon Fields</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PricewaterhouseCoopers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
