<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410862439204650</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/mum-laughed-step-dad-punched-teen-court-hears/3207801/</url>
  <title>Mum laughed as step-dad punched teen, court hears</title>
  <content>
FORCED TO run for "two hours", fed burning hot sauce, punched in the face and stomach while his mother laughed and a cane toad thrown at him.

This is the abuse a south-east Queensland teenager says he suffered at the hands of his step-father who is on trial in Brisbane District Court.

The offences allegedly happened from July 1 to Christmas Day, 2013, at locations north of Brisbane.
The Crown alleges the man, DX's mother and the parents of MQ forced the four children to run alongside a moving car, subjected them to repetitive 'boot camp" type exercises and other forms of abuse.
DX revealed the alleged violence to police in interviews recorded in 2014.
The tapes were played at the trial of DX's 58-year-old step-father who has pleaded not guilty to four charges of torture relating to DX, DX's two little sisters and a neighbourhood girl, MQ.

"I don't want to talk about it," DX told police during their first interview as he hid his face in his arms.

In the next interview, DX was more composed, describing how his mother "laughed" as his step-father allegedly punched him in the face and stomach.

"He (the accused) used to punch me in the mouth," DX told detectives.

"He used to give me the strap all the time.

"He would give me some hot sauce that starts with a T ... Tabasco and he used to take me to the forest and make me run for two hours with the three girls.

"He chucked a toad at me, I don't like those."

The three co-accused have been dealt with by another court and are expected to give evidence at the accused's trial this week.

- NewsRegional
Baby whale rescued on the Sunshine Coast
Up to $214,000 remains on table for refocused investigation
"Nice deal if you can get it!"
AT Nambour State School, many pupils came to school by train.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DX</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NewsRegional</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabasco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
