<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410776539857653</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/elderly-woman-hospitalised-after-crashing-scooter-/3207792/</url>
  <title>Elderly woman hospitalised after crashing scooter into tree</title>
  <content>
AN AMBULANCE has rushed to the aid of an elderly woman on the Sunshine Coast after she crashed her mobility scooter into a tree.
A Queensland Ambulance spokeswoman said paramedics were alerted to the Battery Hill crash at 8.30am.
Medical practitioners from a nearby Beerburrum Street health facility witnessed the crash and called an ambulance for assistance.
The woman, aged in her mid 70s, suffered leg injuries and was taken to Sunshine Coast University Hospital in a stable condition.
Baby whale rescued on the Sunshine Coast
Up to $214,000 remains on table for refocused investigation
More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
AT Nambour State School, many pupils came to school by train.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beerburrum Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battery Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
