<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410815194563740</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/sport/primo-primed-for-success-at-powerlifting-championships/news-story/f45a09a91bb11db64080f33af6eeeeeb</url>
  <title>Primo primed for success at powerlifting championships</title>
  <content>
A Cairns teenage weightlifter is using engineering principles to power his way towards gold this week.
Primo Fantin is one of seven members of the Portsmith-based Iron Strength gym travelling to Melbourne for the Australian Powerlifting Championships this weekend.
Fantin, 17, who deferred offers to study engineering at some of Australia's most prestigious universities this year, said the sport of powerlifting required a rare mix of both brains and brawn.
"The mechanics behind it all is one of the things that really attracted me to the sport," Fantin said. "People have different opinions but in the long-term it's all about data, really."
"Your powerlifting program is just percentages of a projected one-rep max (lift). Every session you're just following numbers you've set out in order to overload your central nervous system to gain kilograms on your total (lift)."
Despite weighing just 66kg, Fantin can bench press 100kg, squat lift 170kg and dead lift 200kg. But the sub junior competitor said he's capable of more this week.
"My programming has been really fruitful so I hope to put up some bigger numbers at the competition," he said.
Iron Strength coach Elias Wright said the growth of his youngest weightlifter competing was impressive.
"He's a good chance to win his category," Wright said. "He's quite lean but he just loves it."
"Like a lot of our athletes he's training five days a week, generally for about 2  1/2 hours."
Iron Strength's team will be rounded out by three masters competitors, Ross Dingle, Suzanne Smith and Marina Anthony who is hoping to inch closer to a world record dead lift within her weight for age category.
Dingle, 57, is the winner of last year's masters two category but has had an injured-riddled lead-in to the event.
"I've had a knee operation for a torn meniscus and a shoulder issue so the prep hasn't gone as well as expected," Dingle said.
"But I've spent 12 months planning for the event and told work 'no more travel' so I'm hoping it goes well."
The championships start Friday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Dingle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dingle, 57</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fantin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Powerlifting Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iron Strength</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portsmith-based Iron Strength</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzanne Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fantin, 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dingle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elias Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
