<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410858144237200</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/world/turkey-failed-coup-hundreds-appear-in-court-20170801-gxnijn.html</url>
  <title>Turkey failed coup: Hundreds appear in court</title>
  <content>
Sincan, Turkey: Almost 500 suspects accused of taking part in last year's failed coup against Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan appeared in court on Tuesday.
The 486 defendants are accused of plotting the coup effort from an airbase outside Ankara, where fighter jets took off to bomb the Turkish parliament and where senior military officers loyal to the government were held prisoner.

Up Next

New FBI director is Christopher Wray

00:26

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Hundreds on trial over failed Turkey coup

Nearly 500 suspects are on trial for bombing government buildings and attempting to kill President Recip Tayyip Erdogan in 2016.

Among the suspects is Akin Ozturk, a former head of Turkey's air force, whom prosecutors say was one of the leaders of the coup. Mr Ozturk is accused of terrorism, conspiracy and treason but denies the charges.
Stripped of his rank and military titles, Mr Ozturk was paraded into the court room in front of waiting television cameras along with 40 other of the most prominent defendants. As has become customary with these large trials, supporters of Mr Erdogan waited outside the court to hurl abuse at the men as they were marched in.Photo: AP
Some called for the death penalty, although it was abolished by Turkey in 2004, and threw nooses at the handcuffed men.
More than 50,000 people have been arrested over the coup attempt. The case focuses on Akinci air base, which was a main military hub for rebel soldiers during the attempt to overthrow the government on July 15 2016.

F-16 fighter jets took off from the base and bombed the Turkish parliament building in Ankara, according to the state-run news agency Anadolu.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Other jets from the base reportedly put Mr Erdogan's plane in their missile sights but did not attack.Photo: AP
General Hulusi Akar, the head of the Turkish military, was held prisoner at the base for several hours during the coup attempt until he was freed by loyalist forces. He remains the chief of the general staff today. At least 249 people were killed during the campaign.
Most of the 486 defendants face life in prison if they are convicted.
Seven people are being tried in absentia in the case, including exiled Muslim cleric Fethullah Gulen.
The Daily Telegraph, UK
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Erdogan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Almost 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F-16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ankara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Recip Tayyip Erdogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ozturk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Hulusi Akar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Wray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fethullah Gulen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Akinci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15, 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sincan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anadolu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Akin Ozturk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
