<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410853849269865</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/opinion/columnists/weak-us-dollar-a-headache-for-central-bankers-20170801-gxngfz</url>
  <title>US dollar dilemma: what can be done about the plunging greenback?</title>
  <content>
If US central bank chief Janet Yellen happens to look over her shoulder at the next gathering of international financiers and see her peers from Australia, Canada, Japan, and the euro zone huddled together in intense talks she'll know immediately that there's only one possible subject of conversation: what to do about the falling US dollar.
Central bankers around the world are at their wits' end, trying to work out how to respond to the drop in the US dollar, which shows little sign of abating. They're worried that as their currencies strengthen against the US dollar, their country's goods will become much more expensive in global markets, which will crimp demand, while imported goods will become cheaper. Falling exports will dampen growth, while cheaper imports will put further downward pressure on feeble inflation.
And greenback has had a highly unusual trajectory this year. It began the year at a 14-year high, prompting Donald Trump - who was then US President-elect - to complain that that it was "too strong".
He repeated the charge three months later. "I think our dollar is getting too strong, and partially that's my fault because people have confidence in me", he told Wall Street Journal in April. But, he added, the strength of the currency "will hurt ultimately". the US economy.

If Trump's plan was to make America Great again by debasing the currency, he's succeeded beyond his wildest dreams. Since the start of the year, the US dollar index - which measures the greenback against a basket of major currencies - has tumbled more than 9 per cent, pushing it back to levels last seen in early 2015, shortly after the US Federal Reserve ended its massive bond-buying program known as quantitative easing (QE).

And this is triggering huge consternation amongst world's central banking fraternity who are seeing their hopes for economic recovery and rising inflation jeopardised by the plunging greenback.
Reserve Bank of Australia governor, has signalled his discomfort with the rising Australian dollar.In the statement he released after yesterday's Reserve Bank board meeting, Dr Lowe said that a strengthening currency "would be expected to result in a slower pick-up in economic activity and inflation than currently forecast."
This followed his comment a week earlier when he told a business luncheon in Sydney that "it would be better if the exchange rate were a bit lower than it currently is. It would help generate more jobs, it would help push inflation a bit closer to target."
The trouble is that even if Yellen takes note of the growing protests from her central banking peers, she's not likely to do much to remedy the situation.

The US central bank has always taken the view that its over-riding priority is to decide the correct policy for the world's largest economy, without paying too much consideration of what this might mean for other countries - an attitude that Reserve Bank deputy governor Guy Debelle once aptly summed up as "basically, suck it up, sunshine".
What's more,  reflects some factors that are outside Yellen's control.
The greenback has come under downward move reflects a growing scepticism that investors have increasingly sceptical Trump will deliver on his promised massive tax cuts or a major infrastructure spending program that would boost US economic activity and inflation. Investors also believe there's little likelihood that the Fed will raise rates again this year because of sluggish US inflation.
As a result, investors are looking for greener pastures elsewhere. The euro surged close to a two-year high against the US dollar after European Central Bank boss sounded an upbeat note in describing economic growth and inflation in the euro zone. Similarly, the Canadian dollar has climbed sharply after the Bank of Canada nudged its key interest rate up to 0.75 per cent, the first hike in seven years.

All the same, the fact that US official interest rates remain well above levels in the eurozone, Canada, the United Kingdom and Japan suggest that investors are becoming increasingly worried by signs of dysfunction in Washington, amid the alarmingly rapid turnover in Trump's key advisors, the probe into the Trump camp's alleged collusion with Russia and failure by congressional Republicans to repeal and replace Obamacare.
But the weaker greenback isn't bad news for everyone. The Fed is hoping that weaker dollar will push up the cost of imported goods, helping to nudge the US inflation rate closer to its 2 per cent target.
Meanwhile, Chinese exporters are feeling the benefits of the Chinese central bank's policy of anchoring the Chinese yuan to the US dollar, which means that their currency has weakened against competitors such as the Japanese yen and the Korean won.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy Debelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President-elect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yellen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Central Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obamacare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janet Yellen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>America Great</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
