<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410123704816257</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/stylish-instagram-posts-become-free-advertising-for-businesses/8763778</url>
  <title>From breakfast to business boon: How Instagram photos have become priceless free publicity</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Instagram has become a gold mine for companies that benefit from free publicity as people photograph and promote products to try and gain sponsorship or help style their social media image.
Scott Murray barely has to spend a cent on advertising for his business - his customers do it all for him.
The Shellharbour, NSW cafe owner produces one of Instagram's most posted images - the colourful acai fruit bowl.
"I knew acai bowls were the go-to photogenic Instagram photo, but the response has been overwhelming, and the amount of customers we've seen take on that trend has been great," he said.
In fact, stand in his cafe for an hour and you will see a large number of people photograph, post and tag his business on their social media accounts as soon as they receive their bowl.
They are usually so pleased with the product, they will also tag his business in the post.
Mr Murray said it was a trend he tried to encourage with his food presentation.

"I look at presenting the bowls as picture-perfect as possible, so every time we do up a bowl, it's not just the quality we look at, but the look, feel and vibe of the bowl," he said.
"We know when a customer receives that bowl, they're going to want to take a photo before they dig in and eat it."
A brief search of #acaibowl on Instagram delivers thousands of results of people looking to promote their healthy eating, and the businesses providing the product.
Why people voluntarily promote businesses

University of Wollongong professor Katina Michael studies the psychological impacts of social media, and said the business/customer relationship could benefit both parties.
"These days, people like to be associated with brands, not just global brands, but local brands," she said.
"People feel they're getting something back, even if it's in-kind, which is about building their persona and reputation online, and local organisations can help you do that."
While some people are paid with cash or products to promote items on their social networks, those people are almost always major influencers with a large following.
The reality is that people with a much smaller following who post stylised promotional photos in the hope of picking up a sponsorship are simply advertising a company for free.

Exercise wear and social media

Illawarra active wear clothing company owner Lisa Trujillo has been a huge benefactor of voluntary Instagram promotion.
She has successfully tapped into two boom areas of Instagram use - promotion of exercise and healthy living, and fashion.
For her, social media is her only method of advertising, and like Mr Murray, much of it is done for her by her customers.
"It is super important and it's free promoting," she said.
"It's good exposure, and a good way to expand my brand and get girls to tag my brand and show photos of them wearing my tights."
Some are hoping Ms Trujillo will re-post their photos and expose them to her following of more than 17,000 people, others are angling for a free pair of tights, while some just want to help a local business.
Regardless of the motivation, the promotion for the business is the same.
"My business wouldn't be where it is today without social media. It would be 10 steps back," Ms Trujillo said.
"Instagram for me is my best selling point."
Money disappearing from conventional advertising

External Link:

Acai Insta
In the age of free social media promotion, businesses no longer have to put advertising dollars into traditional mediums such as print or television.
Word-of-mouth or friend-to-friend social media referrals can also carry more weight than mass media advertising.
By adopting and promoting brands, people have revolutionised the way small businesses that provide a fashionable product on Instagram operate.
"It's very valuable. The exposure I've gained from it has allowed me to not only reach my social media following, but a much wider audience of thousands of people because of it," Mr Murray said.
Professor Michael said while it could be a win-win for businesses and customers, people should be aware that at the heart of it was a commercial message.
"We should be aware these are business messages and their message is sales maximisation and we are consumers," she said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katina Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Trujillo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Murray</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Trujillo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>23</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
