<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410767949922857</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/health/magic-mushrooms-may-be-among-the-safest-illicit-drugs-study/news-story/132c73bbb800c962af658fd8981b9436</url>
  <title>What's the 'safest' drug?</title>
  <content>
IT gets you high. It's not very addictive. It's difficult to overdose on. You can grow it yourself. Sound too good to be true?
Magic mushrooms are illegal because of their mind-bending fallout.
But the  says that if you insist on using illicit substances, perhaps play it as safe as possible.
The study, which canvassed 120,000 people worldwide, found 79.3 per cent of its sample had taken drugs in their lives. Some 37 per cent of which had used in the prior month.
By far the most heavily used illegal drug was cannabis, with a 77.8 per cent take-up rate.
Magic mushrooms came in at ninth place overall with 29.4 per cent admitting to its use.
The most popular drug is also mostly legal: alcohol. It has a 98.7 take-up rate.
Statistically, the safest buzz appears to come from psychedelic mushrooms.
The study found methamphetamine users were 40 times more likely to visit emergency facilities than mushroom users. Cannabis concentrates and synthetics are also high cause for admittance.
While the , it says more traditional drugs are still a serious cause for concern.
But the humble mushroom is among those least likely to send you to hospital, the study says.
Magic mushrooms directly affect serotonin receptors in the brain. Other drugs also stimulate many others. And taking more 'shrooms doesn't increase a high - which makes them less addictive.
But they will often not give you the kind of high you want.
As a psychedelic, it will amplify existing moods such as paranoia and anxiety.
And it's such 'bad trips' that make magic mushrooms illegal. Users can be a danger to themselves, family, friends and passers-by.
Also, the apparent 'safety' of magic mushrooms may be a distortion in the statistics.
It doesn't take into account incidents of mistaken identity.
Many of the more poisonous kinds of mushrooms look very similar to their psychedelic cousins. And a lack of care, experience - or even an optimistic buzz - could quickly contaminate any stash.
And the toxic side-effects could be fatal.
This is a very real risk as many magic mushroom users tend to scour fields and reserves for varieties growing naturally. The alternative - growing them yourself - is illegal.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
