<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410853849269810</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/queensland-naplan-results-show-improvement-but-not-for-writing-20170801-gxnhgx.html</url>
  <title>Almost a quarter of Qld's Year 9s miss writing minimum standard</title>
  <content>
Older Queensland students' writing skills have dropped significantly, according to preliminary NAPLAN results, while some of the state's best ever performances have been recorded in other categories.
After disastrous test results in the early years of the national standardised education test saw the state outperforming only  the Northern Territory, the latest figures were fast catching NSW, Victoria and the ACT for average results in most categories.
Compared with 2008, when the test was introduced, preliminary 2017 results showed major improvements in younger students, with students in years 3 and 5 particularly boosting their average results in reading, spelling, grammar and numeracy.
But the news was much worse for writing, where mean results for students in all grades either stayed relatively flat or declined versus baseline results recorded in 2011.
There were less drastic changes, both positive and negative, in most categories when compared against the 2016 test result.
That was in line with national results, which showed improvements in average reading and numeracy scores from the previous year while writing went backwards.

The average results were worse for older students in Queensland. The state's year 7 and year 9 students both lost ground in writing compared with 2008, with flat results for year 7s in reading and numeracy and an increase in year 9 numeracy results.
As compared with last year, average results stayed close to flat in all grades.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Queensland Education Minister Kate Jones praised the state's results, saying the test saw more students than ever in the upper two performance bands across 11 of the tested areas.
"So we're actually seeing more students achieving at the highest level they can in NAPLAN," she told the ABC.
Generally speaking, the results in average results were mirrored in the percentage of students achieving the national minimum standard.
Across the board, more students were hitting that target in 2017 than in 2008 for reading, numeracy, spelling and grammar, with many cohorts improving on their 2016 results too.
But the writing situation was dire in parts, with almost one quarter (22.9 per cent) of year 9 students missing the mark, along with about 15 per cent of year 7 students.
All grades except for year 3 saw less students hitting the minimum standard for writing than in 2008, with the older grades displaying particularly significant drops.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld's Year 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Education Minister Kate Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
