<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410514546847685</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/afl-billys-incredible-bake-treloars-big-gripe-deledios-long-wait-over/news-story/b75cb2cafb81daf218a777f6447949aa</url>
  <title>Billy Brownless has never been this angry</title>
  <content>
BILLY Brownless isn't taking Patrick Dangerfield's suspension too well.
The Geelong star yesterday accepted a one-match ban for a dangerous tackle on Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer on the weekend, meaning he is ineligible to win his second successive Brownlow Medal.
The 27-year-old was essentially in a two-horse race with Richmond's Dustin Martin to take out the top gong in grand final week, but Geelong refused to challenge his suspension and risk rubbing the gun midfielder out for two weeks.
Footy Show personality Brownless - who played nearly 200 games for the Cats - lost his mind over Dangerfield's ban and unleashed an extraordinary rant on radio on Tuesday afternoon.
"Patrick Dangerfield is a national treasure, you know what the Match Review Panel (MRP) are? *****," Brownless said on Triple M Melbourne's The Rush Hour, which he co-hosts with James Brayshaw.
"Fair dinkum, they can all get f***ed. Last time I checked you're still allowed to tackle in our game. Last time I checked, it's still known as a contact sport. The last time I checked, in a contact sport, there's still a chance you're going to get hurt. Not according ot the f***wits running the MRP.
"He pins the arms - perfect tackle. He brings Kreuzer to the ground."
Brownless didn't stop when Brayshaw - laughing hysterically at his colleague's obviously over-the-top assault - tried to point out the Blues ruckman had already got rid of the ball when Dangerfield completed the tackle.
"Jim, if you f***ing interrupt me I'll knock your smug f***ing head right off," Brownless said.
"The rules that apply to the rest of the competition don't apply to Patty, it's that simple. If some list-clogger from another crap club knocks a bloke out with a tackle give him six weeks, no one gives a f***. This is Danger, the best player in the comp, he can do whatever the hell he likes.
"It's like I always say Jim ... I've forgotten what I always f***ing say.
"Jim, this is a disgrace. (Former VFL CEO) Ross Oakley, you can get f***ed.
"(Former AFL CEO) Wayne Jackson, (former football operations manager) Adrian Anderson, (former CEO Andrew) Demetriou, (former Brisbane Bears president) Paul f***ing Cronin, (former Hawthorn president) Jeff Kennett, you're all f***ing idiots.
"Patty is gold, he's an angel."
And scene.
TRELOAR UNHAPPY: 'IT'S RIDICULOUS'
Collingwood star Adam Treloar is frustrated by umpires' inconsistent interpretations of the rules in 2017.
Officials have cracked down on the deliberate out of bounds rule and . Umpiring came under the microscope again when the Fox Footy commentators were bewildered the whistleblowers let several indiscretions go late in the final quarter of Port Adelaide's thrilling win over St Kilda on Saturday.
Treloar says players are confused by the amount of rules and how they're being policed.
"A lot of the rules are inconsistent," Treloar told SEN's The Run Home.
"Quite often it's inconsistent in a game. You'll get something called one minute that isn't the next. Then the next week it's different to what was called the week before.
"But that also shows how difficult it is being an umpire.
"In the heat of the moment and having so many rules, its almost ridiculous.
"It's just so inconsistent. I'd just say be consistent."
WAIT FINALLY OVER FOR GWS STAR
The wait is almost over for Greater Western Sydney fans and their prized recruit Brett Deledio, who will make his debut for the AFL club this weekend. GWS confirmed on Tuesday the former Richmond champion will play against Melbourne in Canberra on Saturday.
It will be his first senior game in just over a year since he turned out for Richmond against Essendon at the MCG in mid-July 2017.
Deledio was traded to the Giants after last season but has been sidelined by recurring calf issues.
He has played for the Giants reserves in their last two NEAFL games.
Deledio notched 17 touches in a half in his first match back and followed up with 25 disposals in his second hitout in the midfield and across half back. He played 243 games in 12 seasons for Richmond, kicking 182 goals and winning two best and fairest awards.
- with AAP
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRELOAR UNHAPPY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Brownless</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rush Hour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Oakley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Brayshaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S RIDICULOUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bears</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Kennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Run Home</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brayshaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Treloar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond's Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple M Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownless</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demetrious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treloar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FINALLY OVER FOR GWS STAR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
