<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410342748152633</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/queensland-government/premier-annastacia-palaszczuk-heckled-at-gold-coast-town-hall-meeting/news-story/2b199313ae09fcd88c14160d627fb210</url>
  <title>Premier heckled: 'Where's your integrity?'</title>
  <content>
AN anti Adani protester was removed by police from last night's town hall meeting after heckling Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk about her Government's support for the controversial melamine.
Burleigh Heads resident and social worker Matthew Ross, 31, was escorted from the Currumbin RSL and ordered to leave the premises after he walked towards the Premier chanting "down with Adani".
"You lied to us," he shouted.
"Where's your integrity?"
Ms Palaszczuk was unapologetic about her Government's support for Adani's Carmichael coal mine as it would create jobs in struggling North Queensland communities.
"I care about people having a job and a roof over their heads," she said.
About 500 people packed into the RSL in what was the biggest town hall event conducted by the Palaszczuk Government.
Ms Palaszczuk said mining and resources were important to the Queensland economy - and kept the lights on - but the State Government was moving towards its 50 per cent renewable target by 2030.
"We actually want to start talking to people about investing in a battery factory here in Queensland," she said.
"I want to see how I can attract a battery factory to Queensland so we are moving in that direction."
It comes as Townsville City Council has signed a memorandum of understanding with Boston Energy to build a lithium-ion battery factory.
Surprisingly, one of the controversial issues was the Gold Coast light rail Stage 3 linking Broadbeach to Burleigh.
Several people questioned Ms Palaszczuk and Transport Minister Jackie Trad about the project and a "stop the tram" chant erupted at one stage.

Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk has resorted to robocalling Gold Coast residents to drum up interest in a town hall meeting.

Annastacia Palaszczuk robocalls residents
Ms Trad said congestion would get worse unless public transport on the Gold Coast improved because of the expected population growth.
"Anyway you look at it, we are going to have more congestion unless we can deliver more public transport options for people," she said.
Ms Palaszczuk received a standing ovation when she spoke about her Government's controversial decision to scrap the $3 billion casino and resort development on The Spit.
She said a brunnel - a bridge and tunnel combined - was required to manage the increase in traffic associated with the development.

The State Government has torpedoed a $3 billion casino resort earmarked for the Gold Coast's Southport Spit. Vision: 9 News Gold Coast

State Government terminates ASF plan for casino on Gold Coast
"It would have been an ugly eyesore on the broadwater," she said.
But Ms Palaszczuk said the decision to scrap the ASF development was a difficult one.
"It's one, I must say, that I had a few sleepless nights about," she said.
"It's a bit hard to sometimes separate the emotion from what you loved and where you've gone to as a young child.
"But you have to separate that and you have to make a decision in the best interest of all the facts that are put before you."
Ms Palaszczuk said the 160 hectares of parkland at The Spit would be preserved as part of the master planning process.
Last night's meeting came after the Premier resorted to to drum up interest in the event.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbeach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Ross</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani Carmichael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currumbin RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast's Southport Spit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Jackie Trad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stage 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
