<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410944043584278</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/nt-news-and-staff-named-panpa-finalists-in-10-categories/news-story/c65991ae38b944e1697eb6402a2c22a5</url>
  <title>NT News up for 10 gongs at PANPA awards</title>
  <content>
THE NT News and its staff have been named finalists in 10 categories in the 2017 PANPA Newspaper of the Year Awards.
The NT News is a regional finalist for the Daily Newspaper of the Year award while our website - ntnews.com.au - is a regional finalist for the News Site of the Year.
NT News picture editor Elise Derwin is a regional finalist in two categories - in the portrait and sport photography awards.
Fellow photographer Justin Kennedy is a regional finalist in the news photography award.
Our Darwin Print Centre has been named a finalist in five categories for technical excellence for our NT News, Centralian Advocate, The Weekend Australian and Off The Leash products.
The print centre is one of three finalists in the Print Centre of the Year category.
NT News editor Matt Williams congratulated the newspaper's staff for being named finalists in 10 categories.
"We have an awesome team of staff who work their backsides off to make the NT News something our readers can be proud of," he said.
"Yes, we're known for our quirkiness but we are much more than that. In the past year we have introduced a new weekly NT Business Review section and new Mad Monday sports liftout.
"Our Let's Make the Territory Greater campaign has also gained a lot of traction in the NT and it's something we're proud of.
"We've also produced an abundance of colour magazines for our readers including the 75th anniversary Bombing of Darwin magazine."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centralian Advocate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territory Greater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad Mondays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elise Derwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT News</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weekend Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Site of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PANPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Business Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bombing of Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Print Centre of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Print Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Newspaper of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PANPA Newspaper of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
