<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410909683845593</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/02/10/23/north-korean-missile-launch-came-close-to-french-airline</url>
  <title>North Korean missile launch came close to French airline</title>
  <content>
The US has further condemned North Korea's missile tests after a rocket fell back to Earth near a French commercial airline.

Pentagon spokesman Captain Jeff Davis told  the July 4 missile test posed a serious risk to airlines and shipping vessels.

"This missile flew through busy airspace used by commercial airliners. It flew into space. It landed in Japan's exclusive economic zone, and an area that's used by commercial and fishing vessels. All of this completely uncoordinated."

Radar showed the French Boeing 777 travelling west of Hokkaido from Tokyo to Paris with 323 people on board as the ICBM was airborne.

However, Air France told the US media outlet it did not share the Pentagon's concerns about the recent missile test.

"(North Korea's missile tests) don't interfere in any way with Air France's flight paths," the airline said in a statement.

"Moreover, in cooperation with the authorities, Air France constantly analyses potentially dangerous flyover zones and adapts its flight plans accordingly."

Related Articles

Yesterday the US raised concerns the rogue nation may be preparing for an amphibious attack on US soil after detecting "unprecedented levels" of North Korean submarine activity and underwater launch tests.

A US defence official told  that North Korea - which has a fleet of approximately 70 submarines - has been performing ejection tests, which is the first stage needed to launch a ballistic missile out of a sub.

The US official said the test coincides with unprecedented submarine activity and reports North Korea now has the capability to launch an intercontinental missile at the US.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hokkaido</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tokyo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pentagon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Jeff Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French Boeing 777</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Air France</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICBM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
