<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410982698290575</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/workers-should-be-entitled-to-take-a-sickie-for-spiritual-wellbeing/news-story/95c08b500de9e7971ad159c252e7360a</url>
  <title>Taking sickies for spiritual wellbeing</title>
  <content>
WORKERS should be allowed to take sick days without giving their boss a reason with employers ordered to get innovative with how they combat mental health problems among staff.
Workplaces have been called on to do more for their staff's mental wellbeing by businesswoman Lucy Brogden who will be announced today as the new National Mental Health Commissioner by federal health Minister Greg Hunt.
"I'd like people to be able to take sick leave without having to say why. The old food poisoning, migraine (reason) -- that's often covering up for a mental health day," Ms Brogden said.
"(That way) staff don't have to disclose until they're ready, if they're anxious than disclosing it upfront or in the early stages may not help their recovery."
She said at least two or three days of unexplained sick leave should be allowed.
Businesses leading the charge in supporting staff include Woolworths which Ms Brogden said is exploring the option of giving loans and counselling to employees who are at risk of falling victim to loan sharks because of a mental health or gambling problems.
Optus has psychologists and GPs on-site in some offices for staff to seek treatment.
The commission works with government to form health policy and Mr Hunt said Ms Brogden's appointment was unanimously backed by cabinet.
Mr Hunt said workplaces should be the "real frontline for support" for people with mental health challenges.
"When we have done our assessment of where can we find the greatest additional support for early identification management and recovery of those who've been through mental health challenges the workplace is right at the top of the tree," Mr Hunt said.
Ms Brogden will also work with Mr Hunt on suicide prevention programs with Friday's meeting of Australia's health ministers to focus on this.
Preventing suicide among patients after they are discharged from hospital following a self-harm attempt will be at the forefront of the meeting with the government to bolster the services available to these people after they leave a facility.
"Far and away the highest incidence of suicide is from those who have been in hospital," Mr Hunt said.
He said the current prevention programs for this cohort are not "fully developed".
Ms Brogden's husband John, a businessman and former NSW Liberal leader, was recently discharged from hospital where he sought treatment for depression.
"We're now at 112 days post discharge with no follow up and this is what we have to build (into the system). The clinical practice guidance ... and the community based supports. We know how to navigate the system but not everybody does - it's a complex process," she said.
According to researchers, there is little difference in the vocabulary or reasoning of youngsters whose mothers go back to full employment.
This is despite previous claims that women may harm their child's development by being away in the day and too tired for quality time in the evening.
A team found that working mothers try to compensate for time spent apart by dedicating more hours to educational activities with their children. They followed some 2,200 babies born in Scotland a decade ago until around their fifth birthday. Their mothers' employment was recorded in yearly surveys, with their children's development tested.
Study authors Dr Markus Klein, from Strathclyde University, and Dr Michael Kuhhirt, from the University of Cologne in Germany, said: 'The exaggerated claims of benefits and the harmful effects of working mothers on their children are not supported by our research, at least when it comes to early language acquisition and reasoning ability.' The study, published in the journal Child Development, added that small changes in a child's development appear to be driven not by their mother's employment, but her education and the number of siblings. The results show neither a significantly positive nor negative effect of mothers going out to work.
The researchers added: 'By bringing in money and raising the family income, working mothers may be able to provide a more stimulating and safer environment for their children. This is a matter of better living conditions. 'All policies that enable women to choose whether they go back to work or not should be encouraged. Pressure on women one way or the other is not going to improve their child's development.'
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Brogden</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Child Development</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Markus Klein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy Brogden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Michael Kuhhirt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Greg Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathclyde University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Cologne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Mental Health Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hunt</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Optus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
