<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410905388878208</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/west-coast-employ-deadeye-goalkicking-legend-to-alleviate-inaccuracy-20170802-gxnk0d.html</url>
  <title>West Coast employ dead-eye goalkicking legend to alleviate inaccuracy</title>
  <content>
A stuttering West Coast has employed the masterly coaching talents of goal-kicking sensation Austin Robertson.
One of the finest exponents of the prolifically used drop punt, the legendary full-forward is a part-time specialist goal-kicking coach.
Robertson will work especially closely with powerhouse forwards Josh Kennedy and Jack Darling as well as offer refinement to the finishing qualities of West Coast's midfielders.
Emerging small forwards Willie Rioli and Jake Waterman are young Eagles expected to benefit from specialised training and skills tutoring from the master goal-kicker.
Robertson's recruitment sends a pointed message that Eagles management wants to eradicate a decline in scoring proficiency.
Generating alternatives to a heavy reliance on the brilliant Kennedy as a primary scoring source is also on the cards.

West Coast scoring potency has tumbled over the past three seasons since the Eagles almost took an unexpected premiership in 2015 as the second-most potent scoring outfit in the league, averaging around 106 points a game.
Kennedy spearheaded the scoring as the game's leading goal-scorer with 75 and 80 and consecutive Coleman Medals.
The Eagles ranked fifth for scoring last year at 98 points a game when finishing seventh but have tumbled further to 10th for scoring this season at 88 points in each engagement, despite Kennedy kicking 49 majors and Darling 34.
Kennedy, 30, has missed six appointments with a serious achilles heel injury. 
Robertson, 74, booted a Western Australian record 1211 goals across 251 games with Subiaco at a remarkable average of almost five majors a game.
A feature of his near flawless kicking style and accurate finishing was a disciplined physical and mental preparation rounded into a rhythmic and athletic run-up into his set-shot kick.  
He headed WAFL goal-kicking lists a record eight times with five season tallies of more than 100 and three other personal hauls of 89, 94 and 98.
He was belatedly entered into the prestigious AFL Hall of Fame two years ago.
Robertson has previously offered his coaching services to Fremantle and was rejected.
He is working at West Coast in conjunction with Eagles forward coach Jaymie Graham.
Robertson is acclaimed as the finest set-shot for goal in history, with WAFL folklore claiming the deadly accurate drop-punt kick went at an around an 80 per cent goal-scoring reliability.
He was also superbly fit and smooth moving as an athletic key focal point, with a lightning fast lead and powerful grip to complete his dash into position, and a vice-like marking ability out in front of his body
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Darling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subiaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willie Rioli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robertson, 74</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austin Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WAFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling 34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Waterman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robertson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaymie Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
