<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410986993257925</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/daniel-sturridge-injury-update-news-liverpool-v-bayern-munich-highlights/news-story/1c4f551b14f28d834cbb39ad6acc6ced</url>
  <title>Klopp, Sturridge update on striker's untimely injury</title>
  <content>
DANIEL Sturridge hobbled off with a thigh injury during
Sturridge, who seemingly sustained the injury while chipping home a fine third goal for Liverpool at the Allianz Arena, was substituted three minutes later by Jurgen Klopp.
But the forward said after the match he was "feeling great" and hoped the knock was "just fatigue".
The England striker had come on in the 67th minute for Liverpool, with Klopp's side 2-0 up thanks to goals from Sadio Mane and summer signing Mohamed Salah.

Football: Daniel Sturridge breaks more Liverpool hearts, pulling up with a thigh injury after scoring against Bayern Munich

Sturridge scores, cops injury
Will you still pick Sturridge in your FOX SPORTS EPL FANTASY side?

Asked about the seriousness of the injury after the game, Klopp said: "I can't say. He hurt his thigh. He has prepared really well. I just hope he can play really soon.
"The goal was great and he had a chance just before that. You could see how fast he is. It's a shame and I hope it's nothing serious."
Sturridge himself told Liverpool's official website: "I think it's just fatigue to be honest, so I'll be OK.
"I'm feeling great. I have put in the work, I trained a lot in the summer.
"I've not missed many sessions here, they have looked after me. We've done triple sessions and I have trained almost every single session.

Football: Liverpool have had an impressive outing against German giants Bayern Munich.

Reds fire past German giants
"So I'm feeling great, the best I have felt for a while.
"I am looking forward to the season and hopefully we can have some success."
Sturridge most recently struggled with hip injuries during the 2016/17 season, and missed a large chunk of the previous two seasons with hamstring problems.
Just earlier this week, Adam Lallana said Sturridge is "world class" would be like two new signings for Liverpool if he can stay fit.
"Listen, Studge has been absolutely brilliant in pre-season so far," Lallana told the Telegraph. "You couldn't put a price on him.
"He is a world class player. He has come back from the summer looking absolutely brilliant, so fit. He is going to be a massive player for us this season. I can feel it.
"He is looking really sharp and to have him firing on all cylinders would be like having two new signings if we can keep on the pitch and get him scoring goals."
Read more:
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Sturridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Lallana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sturridge</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allianz Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lallana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Studge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Salah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Klopp</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurgen Klopp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayern Munich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sadio Mane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS EPL FANTASY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
