<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410982698290581</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/08/17/a-peek-inside-qantas-rigorous-seven-week-training-program</url>
  <title>A peek inside the Qantas cabin crew's rigorous seven-week training program</title>
  <content>
Chicken or beef?
From demanding passengers, to midair emergencies, Qantas Cabin crew have pretty much seen it all.
But what you might not realise is it actually takes seven weeks of intense training before any pilot or flight attendant can earn their wings.
With safety the number one priority for Qantas, trainees must attend a special flight training facility and undergo the aviation equivalent of boot camp, covering all aspects of safety and customer service.
"The first three-and-a-half weeks is pretty much like boot camp, a lot of high level theory and practical exams,"  Aviation Safety Training Instructor George Farmakidis told 9NEWS.
"The pass mark for theory is 80 percent, practically even higher, because you can't get this wrong."
As part of their training, participants undergo a water evacuation using a specially constructed simulator.

Related Articles

For many trainees, this can be a nerve-wracking experience.                                                                                                            
"When you're in the simulator and in the raft, you really put yourself in the moment, in what could be a simulated emergency, so the adrenaline does pump," cabin crew trainee Matt Thompson said.
The program also sees aspiring cabin crew learning the finer points of cutlery service, so as to ensure they provide customers with a "restaurant experience".
"It's a very tight space, and very hard - you have to be very organised," Rockpool chef David Speck told 9NEWS.
"And so the operation that backs all that up, and the crew bringing it together to please the customer, is an incredible experience now."
Mr Farmakidis said the program should serve as a reminder to viewers that cabin crew's duties extend well beyond serving passengers food and beverage.
"Not only are they serving you tea and coffee, and that chicken, but they're also there to save your life," he said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Speck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Thompson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas Cabin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aviation Safety Training Instructor George Farmakidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockpool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Farmakidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
