<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410896798943477</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828174/unions-rally-against-foreign-crews/?cs=4200</url>
  <title>Unions rally against foreign crews</title>
  <content>
PORT IN A STORM: The Helvetia berthed in Newcastle in July. Picture: Simone De Peak

UNION workers will rally in Newcastle on Wednesday afternoon, ramping up their opposition to metalworkers from overseas used in the Port of Newcastle. 
The rally is the second since four Singaporean nationals were found aboard the Helvetia, a cargo ship, while it was berthed in the city. 
The union branded the use of the workers as "under-handed".
"Although first thought to be part of the transport ship's crew, it appears the foreign workers were flown in from Singapore on special visas to help unload its cargo," the Maritime Union of Australia said in a statement. 
The Newcastle Herald previously reported the four men were employed to remove metal lugs from the deck of the ship after it brought wind turbines to the port. 
Questions sent to the ship's owner via an Australian agent after unions initially flagged concerns last month went unanswered. 
Acting Newcastle branch secretary Dennis Outram said on Wednesday that port security was one of several factors his members found concerning. 

"At a time when we are seeing unprecedented surveillance and scrutiny at our airports, anyone can seemingly come and go through our sea ports," he said.
Union members are scheduled to rally at 3pm on Wednesday. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Singaporeans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helvetia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port of Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Outram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PORT IN A STORM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Union of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Herald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone De Peak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
