<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410162359522609</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/movies/new-movies/dunkirk-critic-faces-backlash-after-slamming-films-maleness-in-bizarre-review/news-story/cda2ff6cc1444e8faee911b7a92d84d9</url>
  <title>Dunkirk critic faces backlash after slamming film's 'maleness' in bizarre review</title>
  <content>
MOVIE REVIEW DUNKIRK
1:08

Movie review for Christopher Nolan's new film Dunkirk

July 19th 2017
14 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/Movies/

Harry Styles, Aneurin Barnard and Fionn Whitehead in a scene from Dunkirk. Picture: AP

Fox News

Share

DUNKIRK may be winning at the box office, but it can't catch a break with some critics.
The Christopher Nolan-directed film was accused last week of whitewashing and now a new review of the movie in Marie Claire called out the film for being too male-centric.
"Dunkirk felt like an excuse for men to celebrate maleness - which apparently they don't get to do enough," Marie Claire's Mehera Bonner .

Not a woman in sight. Picture: APSource:AP
Bonner added that while she does not need all movies to feature "strong female leads," Dunkirk "screams 'men-only'" and Nolan should have made a movie about either women or "any other marginalised group."
Bonner's criticism was mocked online by various news outlets and Twitter users, who felt her critique missed the mark and ignored historical facts, with many pointing out that a film about World War II soldiers would inevitably feature a male cast.
Possibly the grossest bit of feminist virtue signalling I've seen this year.
Your review spits on the heroism and self-sacrifice of every man on that beach.
My wife's grandfather was captured by Nazis. He lost his toes to frostbite as a POW. Was he 'celebrating his maleness' too much for you?
Considering what those MEN accomplished and what those MEN sacrificed- I, a woman, would gladly celebrate their "maleness"🙄 every damn day.
Sorry history offends your feminity. I bet those boys who died that day would rather have been celebrating their maleness in other ways.
Or it's a historical movie about people who died for your freedom you selfish moron 😂💪🏼
You do realise it was based on reality don't you.... unless you think they should have thrown a few T-Rex's in to pep it up a bit.... 🙄🙄
Sounds like an excuse for you to whine about the existence of another gender and ignore history.
Nolan's World War II drama tells the story of thousands of Allied troops being forced onto the beaches of Dunkirk after the invasion of France by Nazi Germany.
The movie also was previously slammed for having too many white cast members.
for leaving out soldiers from the Royal Indian Army Services Corp companies from the film for their contribution to the war efforts.
This story originally appeared on  and is republished here with permission.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marie Claire's Mehera Bonner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunkirk</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nolan's World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REVIEW DUNKIRK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marie Claire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>POW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fionn Whitehead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aneurin Barnard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Nolan-directed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Nolan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War II</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Styles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-Rex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Indian Army Services Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
