<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410901093910800</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/queensland-mp-dares-lnp-boss-to-disendorse-him-over-samesex-marriage-stand/news-story/c11c79d5ccca9822c00b65cecbe29519</url>
  <title>MP to LNP boss:</title>
  <content>
Warning of 'consequences' of marriage vote

QUEENSLAND LNP MP Warren Entsch has dared his party boss to disendorse him as the same-sex marriage debate continues to create rifts in the party.

LNP president Gary Spence sent an extraordinary letter to party members on Tuesday night, castigating MPs speaking openly about a free vote in parliament on same sex marriage.

Mr Entsch, a supporter of same-sex marriage said he rang Mr Spence last night, saying he'd never seen a letter like that from the party in 21 years in Parliament.

"For him to send something like that with veiled threats, it worries me that it intimidates new members," he said.

"I said to him if you're not happy mate, bring it on, disendorse me."

The Turnbull Government holds the lower house with a majority of one seat.

First term Brisbane MP Trevor Evans is one of four MPs who have spoken out about the potential for a parliamentary vote, and has not ruled out crossing the floor.

In the letter, obtained by The Courier-Mail, Mr Spence said the LNP's position was "perfectly clear" that there should be no change to the definition of marriage under the Marriage Act 1961.

Mr Spence's letter stated that the party's membership voted "overwhelmingly" at its 2014 convention that there should be no change, while at its 2017 convention it voted that a postal plebiscite should be held.

"I am disappointed that views that do not accord with the party's policy have been aired publicly," he said.

MPs may face preselection threat on marriage

"I am equally disappointed that members elected under the LNP banner have chosen to take a position that defies LNP policy and the wishes of the LNP's membership."

Mr Entsch said the state convention passed "all sorts of resolutions" which did not necessarily accord with Federal Party policies or where politicians stood.

"There wouldn't be a single contentious issue where opinions aren't divided. It's up to me to make a call on what I think is right," he said.

"At least I can be judged by the voting public.

"I'm a paid elected member for all my constituency, not just a small minority."

Member for Petrie Luke Howarth said there was a difference between crossing the floor, that is voting against a Government Bill, and supporting a Labor or private member's Bill.

"It would be a dog act," he said.

"If people are silly enough to do that, they will have to deal with the consequences."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Bills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act 1961</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUEENSLAND LNP MP Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spence</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane MP Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie Luke Howarth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
