<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410939748616921</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/macro-bee-photographer-student-snaps-australian-geographic-cover/8764248</url>
  <title>Photographer James Dorey buzzing after bee snap makes cover of Australian Geographic</title>
  <content>
A love of bees has landed photographer James Dorey the coveted cover of Australian Geographic this month.
The Bachelor of Science honours student is currently studying the evolution of Fijian native bees, but his love of nature's pollinators began a long time ago.
"A couple of years ago I had a trip around Australia taking photos of native bees," he said.
"I spent three-and-a-half months in my van, driving around the country, camping wherever I could, collecting bees and taking photos of them," he told 's weekend program.
"Lots and lots of photos have to be taken and stacked together to get most of the bee in focus."
After his trip Mr Dorey contacted Australian Geographic and offered to submit an article and images.
"A little bit before the magazine came out they said, 'Hey, we might use your image for the front cover'," he said.
Mr Dorey's image of a honey bee graced the cover of the July-August edition.

Stung by curiosity early

The Flinders University student said his love of photography began when he bought a second-hand macro lens.
This spurred his interest in insects, beginning with wasps.
Then he discovered 34 different native bee species on a single tree out the front of his home and was hooked.
"I didn't know that there were that many species of bees in Australia," he said.

"There are 1,650 described species and we think there might be between 2,000 and 2,500 species [of bees in Australia] in total."
In his travels around Australia Mr Dorey said he had found approximately 130 different species of bees, with hopes that a couple he photographed might be new species.
He said he hoped to continue to be able to photograph bees as part of his studies, with the world's largest bee, the 45mm Megachile pluto bee, atop his wish list.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dorey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Mr Dorey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor of Science</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fijian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Dorey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megachile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Geographic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July-August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
