<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410982698290597</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/sport/northern-pride-throw-gideon-gelamosby-into-fullback-to-combat-souths-logan-star-jamayne-isaako/news-story/2f0ab6833f98ce9498ae407717a6d2e4</url>
  <title>No.1 reason to show up to Pride</title>
  <content>
A BATTLE of two of the most exciting players in the Intrust Super Cup is set to ignite Barlow Park on Saturday night.
Northern Pride coach Ty Williams has bitten the bullet and named Gideon Gela-Mosby to play at fullback against Souths Logan this weekend, when he will line up against recent Broncos NRL debutant Jamayne Isaako.
Gela-Mosby has slowly crept infield this season from wing to centre and now into the No.1 after filling in impressively due to injury in Bamaga then started there in a late change against Ipswich, but finally will be clear for free rein come Saturday.
Williams said it would be an exciting night for the fans and hoped the spark of his Cowboys allocation would make sure the Pride came out in front.
"It gives him that open space but also takes him away from just sitting on the wing and gets him involved," he said.
"His carries have been outstanding as well so we'd be silly not to utilise him in the middle and see how he goes against these big Souths Logan boys.
"Every time he touches it everyone sort of gets a bit excited, so this gives him more of an opportunity and at home as well, it will be good to see."
Williams said Gela-Mosby could well be a future NRL fullback given not only his elusiveness but his amazing sleight of hand.
"He's got a deft touch about his pass and that's created a fair few opportunities for us the last few weeks and his speed, that's the big one. He beats guys with two or three steps," he said.
"It would be stupid leaving him on the wing and especially with Javid Bowen as well and they've got a pretty good combination going on there at the moment."
The lure of watching live-wire Gela-Mosby in full flight could be just the tonic to keep the crowds rolling through the gates for the last few home games despite the Pride being out of finals contention.
Williams said while giving Gela-Mosby room to move would help against the Magpies, his players had to be equally wary of the threat of opposite number Isaako, rated as one of the most dangerous players in the competition.
"He's their danger man. He's been outstanding for them," he said.
"We just need to get a good game plan around how we can limit his touches within the game and when he does touch the football, make sure we do a job on him, whether it's kicking the footy into touch or kicking it high and trying to stand him still I'm not too sure yet."
Patrick Mago was left out of the Cowboys NRL squad and could be an inclusion in the Pride line-up. The Pride will be wearing a special strip to mark the QRL's Women in League round this weekend.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ty Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QRL's Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaako</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowboys NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Souths-Logan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gideon Gela-Mosby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Mago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barlow Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bamaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gela-Mosby</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javid Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamayne Isaako</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intrust Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Pride</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
