<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410905388878172</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/motor-sport/video-why-rally-finland-makes-revheads-lose-their-mind/news-story/2d74ae80366279d2029310901466d8b2</url>
  <title>Why revheads lose their mind over this race</title>
  <content>
THE Rally of Finland is the fastest event on the World Rally Championship and is driven over a course which regularly sees competitors fly through the air incredible distances.

It is the rally fans rally of choice, and if you want to know why, click on the video below and watch Tor Andre Borresen's excellent edit of the action from this year's edition.

Esapekka Lappi earned his first ever victory in sealing the Rally in his homeland on Sunday ahead of Briton Elfyn Evans and compatriot Juho Hanninen.

Belgian Thierry Neuville took over the world championship lead from Frenchman Sebastien Ogier despite finishing only sixth.

Ogier had been forced to abandon the race on Friday following a crash and scored no points.

But in finishing sixth in the race and third in the power stage, he took 11 points to draw level with Ogier on 160, and goes ahead by virtue of three rally victories to two this season.

Lappi was competing in only his fourth rally. He won a special in his second rally, in Sardinia, and now just four races into his career has claimed his home rally too.

The 26-year-old had led at the end of Friday's eight specials before losing the lead to Toyota teammate and compatriot Jari-Matti Latvala.

But Latvala broke down on the 19th stage, ending his hopes of a fourth victory in the Rally of Finland, and Lappi never looked back.

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esapekka Lappi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latvala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Briton Elfyn Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sardinia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgian Thierry Neuville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ogier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jari-Matti Latvala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frenchman Sebastien Ogier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rally of Finland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Rally Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juho Hanninen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lappi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tor Andre Borresen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
