<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410905388878194</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/cctv-footage-shows-people-in-building-linked-to-obeids-before-suspicious-fire-20170801-gxnh8f.html</url>
  <title>CCTV footage shows people in building linked to Obeids before 'suspicious' fire</title>
  <content>
Police have released CCTV footage in an appeal for information about two suspicious fires at a building linked to .
The Bellevue function centre in Bankstown in Sydney's south-west caught fire twice in eight days over the 2016/17 Christmas and new year holiday period.

Up Next

Man arrested over 'Sydney plane bomb plot' released without charge

02:15

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Video shows arson at Obeid-linked function centre

Police have released CCTV footage of two people and a vehicle as they investigate two suspicious fires at a Bankstown function centre linked to the Obeid family.

Emergency services were called to a fire at the unoccupied building on Restwell Street at 4.45am on December 26.
They extinguished the blaze but the building was left with significant fire damage.Photo: Kate Geraghty
Eight days later, they were called to a second fire at the building, this one causing significant structural damage.
Police believe the fires were deliberately lit and have released CCTV footage of two people inside the centre on Boxing Day and an image of a black XR-model Ford utility seen in the area at the time of the fire.

The building is owned by a company called Redpoc, whose directors are Eddie Obeid's long-time friend and former business partner Wally Wehbe and Eddie Obeid's son Paul Obeid. 

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The building is listed on company documents as Redpoc's "principal place of business".Photo: NSW Police
The same building was damaged by fire in 2015 after an unknown person forced entry and a blaze started shortly afterwards.
In 1993, a tenant in the building contacted police after noticing petrol dripping through the ceiling.Photo: Christopher Pearce
There is no suggestion that Mr Wehbe nor Mr Obeid had any involvement in the fires.
Mr Wehbe was one of 55 people who provided character references for Eddie Obeid, who was  for misconduct in public office over his family's secret business deals at Circular Quay.
Police are urging anyone with information about the fires to contact .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally Wehbe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obeid-linked</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bankstown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wehbe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obeid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redpoc</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellevue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Restwell Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boxing Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>XR-model Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Circular Quay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Obeid</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Obeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Geraghty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Obeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
