<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410553201554071</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/02/08/57/two-venezuelan-opposition-leaders-jailed-as-crisis-escalates</url>
  <title>Two Venezuelan opposition leaders jailed as crisis escalates</title>
  <content>
Teams of heavily armed security agents seized two of Venezuela's top opposition leaders from their homes in the middle of the night on Tuesday, dragging one into the street in his pyjamas.

The men were detained as the Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro's government continues to defy international condemnation of a plan to assume nearly unlimited powers.

Leopoldo Lopez and Antonio Ledezma are being held at the sprawling Ramo Verde military prison south of the capital.

Lopez's wife posted security-camera video of him being taken from their home and bundled into a waiting car.

"They've just taken Leopoldo from the house," Tintori wrote on Twitter. "We don't know where he is or where they're taking him."

Lopez and Ledezma are accused by the government-allied supreme court of violating the terms of their house arrest by plotting to escape and releasing video statements criticising Maduro.

Shortly after midnight, black-clad members of Venezuela's state security force forced Ledezma from his east Caracas home in his blue pyjamas, yanking him out into the night as a woman screamed for help.

Related Articles

"They're taking Ledezma!" the woman can be heard crying on a cell-phone video released by Ledezma's allies. "It's a dictatorship!"

While the United States and some Latin American allies condemned the arrests, many other nations and international organisations were silent or limited themselves to expressions of concern.

Lopez's supporters released a video he taped last week saying he expected to be imprisoned again soon, and calling on Venezuelans to be firm in resisting Maduro.

Maduro appeared undeterred in his plans to seat a special assembly this week with powers to rewrite the country's constitution and override any other branch of the Venezuelan government.

He has threatened to use those powers to go after his opponents and the arrests on Tuesday appeared to show he was willing to proceed with full force.

Maduro appears to have the full support of the country's most important institutions, including the military, and Venezuelan Defense Minister Gen. Vladimir Padrino Lopez appeared on television Tuesday to affirm his loyalty to Maduro.

Lopez was released from the Ramo Verde prison on July 8 after serving three years of a 13-year sentence on charges of inciting violence at opposition rallies. Many human rights groups considered him a political prisoner.

Ledezma, 62, was also detained in 2015 and has been under house arrest. Like Lopez, he also recently posted a video denouncing Sunday's vote.

Tensions escalated in Venezuela after government-allied electoral authorities said more than 8 million people voted Sunday and the turnout was disputed by the opposition and independent analysts and condemned by many nations in the region and beyond.

On Monday, the Trump administration added Maduro to a growing list of high-ranking Venezuelan officials targeted by financial sanctions.

For now, the Trump administration has not delivered on threats to sanction Venezuela's oil industry, which could undermine Maduro's government but also raise US gas prices and deepen the humanitarian crisis in Venezuela.

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Ledezma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramo Verde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledezma</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leopoldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledezma, 62</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lopez</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3.8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caracas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan Defense Minister Gen. Vladimir Padrino Lopez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leopoldo Lopez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tintori</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
