<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410725000249217</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/lifestyle/cars-bikes-and-boats/cars/ferrari-is-said-to-be-planning-a-utility-vehicle-to-double-its-profit-20170801-gxngl1</url>
  <title>Get ready for the Ferrari 'utility vehicle'</title>
  <content>
by
Tommaso Ebhardt

 is considering adding a roomy four-seat "utility vehicle" as part of a major expansion push beyond its traditional supercar niche in a bid to double profit by 2022, people familiar with the matter said.
The final five-year plan under chief executive officer , who's set to retire in 2021, will target boosting annual deliveries beyond a self-imposed limit of 10,000 cars, which allows the company to operate with less-stringent fuel-economy rules, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the matter is private. 
Under the plan, which is likely to be unveiled early next year and could expose the car maker to stricter environmental regulations, Ferrari will also build more hybrid models to improve its vehicles' efficiency and woo new wealthy buyers, the people said. A Ferrari spokesman declined to comment.
Since taking charge of Ferrari in 2014, Marchionne has been pushing volume, already blowing past an earlier cap of 7000 cars. While that approach risks diluting the brand's exclusive cachet, the 65-year-old flanked delivery growth with exclusive limited-edition models, such as the $US2.1 million ($2.6 million)  convertible. He's now seeking to dial up that effort to secure Ferrari's independence as the auto industry grapples with the strains of shifting to electric-powered cars.

Supplied

Ferrari, which reports second-quarter figures on Wednesday US time, is on pace to increase adjusted earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortisation more than 14 per cent this year to at least 1 billion euros ($1.48 billion). The new strategy is likely to include doubling that figure in five years, the people said.

Shares of Ferrari traded in Italy  4.2 per cent to a record 92.80 euros at the close in Milan, valuing the carmaker at 17.5 billion euros. The car maker's US stock was up 3.8 per cent at $US109.19 as of 11.54am  in New York, putting it on course to close at the highest price there as well. Ferrari shares went on the US market in October 2015 and started Italian trading in January 2016.
SUV objections

Among projects being evaluated is a four-seat family car that offers more space than Ferrari's current two-door . The model is internally dubbed the "Ferrari utility vehicle", following Marchionne's previous  to developing an SUV.
The big Ferrari would be targeted at Asian customers, particularly in China, and may alone contribute 2000 vehicles to annual deliveries, the people said. 

Ferrari is studying ways to ensure its sporty style with the new car, which the manufacturer will try to market as a new industry segment rather than as another high-end sport utility vehicle, following the likes of Maserati, Bentley and Lamborghini, they said. The new auto, which could have two or four doors, is expected to be sold from 2021, the people said. No final decision on the model has been made.
"There is a risk that an SUV could dilute the Ferrari brand," Richard Hilgert, an analyst at Morningstar, said in an email. "If Ferrari made a vehicle that has more space for occupants, looks like a Ferrari, sounds like a Ferrari, and drives like Ferrari, well - it'd be a Ferrari", but the company would have to get it right, he said.
Ferrari's current target is to boost vehicle sales to 9000 cars in 2019 from 8014 in 2016. Analysts at at Mediobanca SpA, UBS Group AG and Bernstein predict deliveries could jump to as high as 15,000 under a new strategy, which Marchionne hinted he was developing during his first-quarter earnings presentation in May.
The business plan poses a risk, as raising annual deliveries to more than 10,000 cars a year would push Ferrari beyond its "small vehicle manufacturer" status, which protects it from some US and European fuel-use and emissions rules. 

Hybrid expansion

To address those issues, the Italian carmaker, which was spun off from  in 2016, plans to introduce more hybrid vehicles starting in 2019 to help comply with stricter environmental regulations, the people said. 
Those models, like the current $US1.5 million LaFerrari, will be equipped with an electric motor to improve performance and add horsepower, the people said. Ferrari can also pay penalties or buy carbon credits and add those costs to the price of its vehicles, Mediobanca analyst Massimo Vecchio said.
Meanwhile, boosting output could prompt Ferrari to add a second shift to its factory in Maranello, Italy, its only manufacturing site, the people said. The carmaker's executives have had meetings with investors in the past weeks to prepare them for the new strategy, the people said.

Marchionne, who is also CEO of former parent Fiat Chrysler, is set to present his final plans for both car makers at the beginning of next year. He intends to step down from Fiat in 2019 and Ferrari two years later.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massimo Vecchio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maranello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morningstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiat Chrysler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Hilgert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tommaso Ebhardt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediobanca SpA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marchionne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maserati</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediobanca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US109.19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy  4.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS Group AG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaFerrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lamborghinis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>23</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
