<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411072892605389</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/boxing/floyd-mayweather-conor-mcgregor-fight-pundits-bizarre-bet-i-will-send-you-guys-a-dk-pic/news-story/d61eaa30fb6544760ef9d0d6f335e7ad</url>
  <title>Floyd Mayweather Conor McGregor fight, pundit's bizarre bet: 'I will send you guys a d**k pic'</title>
  <content>
Floyd Mayweather Jr. and Conor McGregor face off.

Staff writers

Share

FLOYD Mayweather vs Conor McGregor superfight betting just officially crossed the line into bizarre and disturbing - thanks to a former UFC heavyweight.
Brendan Schaub, also a fight pundit during the recent MayMac World Tour press extravaganza, has just bet a 'd**k pic' on the outcome.
Specifically, Schaub has declared that McGregor will last 12 rounds against the undefeated boxing legend in their August 27 (AEST) bout in Las Vegas. If not, Little Brendan will be photographed and distributed.
The 'd**k pic' bet is a doubling down on McGregor from Schaub. The ex-heavyweight apparently bet HBO boxing commentator Max Kellerman that McGregor will win at least one round against Mayweather, to the tune of a stunning $100,000.
"His team, I don't think, is going to take the bet," he said. "They went, 'Are you serious about it?" I said, 'I will transfer the money directly into a joint account right now',"
"Because he's saying Conor won't land a punch or win a round. You're crazy. [McGregor]'s gonna land multiple punches. I guarantee it.

Floyd Mayweather taunts Conor McGregor.Source:Getty Images
"I know what I'm talking about. I boxed for 15 years, fought professionally for 10 years in mixed martial arts. I know boxing, I know mixed martial arts and I know when I got in there with professional boxers, it took them about a round to feel me out and the way I do stand up is traditional. It's boxing. I don't have this weird, awkward style. Conor does.
"With Conor, it's a matter of time on how long does it take Floyd Mayweather to get used to this weird, awkward style. So Mayweather has to download McGregor's movement, everything that he's never seen before. He's gonna do it, it's [just] gonna be how long?
"These old boxing heads, they know boxing and they keep it so tight to their chest. They hope Floyd doesn't lose, because it would be the worst thing to happen to boxing ever, so they trash mixed martial arts but they don't actually know what they're talking about.

Max Kellerman after Mayweather vs Pacquaio.Source:Twitter
"[McGregor will win] at least one [round]. I wouldn't be surprised if he wins two to three [rounds], early on. If you're going to bet on it, you look at the odds, you need to bet in the first two rounds that Conor knocks him out, if you're trying to make bank, bro.
"I will send you guys a d**k pic if it doesn't go all 12 rounds.
"I immediately regret saying that. I'm more worried about sending these d**k pics than about the 100 grand with Max Kellerman. It's gonna be a good pic though. I'm gonna hire glamour shots."

Travis Browne (top) punches Brendan Schaub (bottom) at UFC 181.Source:Getty Images
Schaub also claimed that McGregor was the greater hope of a KO win: "If anyone's gonna get knocked out it's Floyd. I promise you Conor will not get knocked out. If anyone gets finished that night, it's Floyd."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>KO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Schaub</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd Mayweather-Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd Mayweather Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Browne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HBO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schaub</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayweather</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacquaio.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Brendan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MayMac World Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC 181.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Kellerman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd Mayweather</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
