<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409951906120578</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/ephemera-artistry-fill-soul-with-joy/news-story/b6582bf76f55ef86256d8786e76151f1</url>
  <title>Best way to get free parking in Townsville</title>
  <content>
OPINION: Ephemera, wish it could last forever, but sadly it's very name means "temporary". So can we have an Unephemera or Disephemera perhaps?
I love it every two years, and remember fondly with Francis from the gallery talking about it all those years ago, what a huge success it is.
Wonderful to see thousands along our beachfront enjoy the brilliance of these artists.
All ages love this, all cultures, all beliefs, all dogs ... yes, sorry about my Bing, I hope the Giant Pacific Octopus doesn't rust. He's only a small doggie, but fair dinkum he holds some liquid.
And what about the Dirty Car Art, and all the cars parked down on Strand Park beach, brilliant stuff by Scott Wade. Though there must have been a lapse in communication down City Hall way, when our dear parking inspectors came down and booked the lot of them.
And Paul Taylor and the coppers put Police Aware signs on them too. Joking!
Actually, good way of getting free parking anywhere, pull over and shove a Police Aware sign on the windscreen, just hope they're actually not.
Ephemera is thought-provoking, enlightening and delightfully entertaining. Yes, I'm a fan, and I'd love to see the council buy a few. Up to you really, ring up Mayor Jenny and tell her what we should keep. I always wished we'd kept the Duck from years ago.
There's also a group of people I mention every year, and that's our sensational volunteers.
They hand out the books, explain the artworks, many do tours, always there, always happy to help.
When hosting an event, now and then you don't do what pleases someone, and that's what we're fine with, part of the job.
On Friday, while on holidays, I had the privilege of hosting the Ephemera launch, which was great fun, not a big job, so when finished went to have a wine with my girl.
It was there I copped it from a lady for not thanking the volunteers, which I had not, true it was not on my sheet, but not the point, I should have remembered as I look after them each year.
And the Mayor copped it too I may add, but she wasn't there - it was all on me. Why I mention it is, a volunteer came up who heard and said, 'Pricey, that's not what volunteering is all about, it's about the honour of doing the job, and the thanks is in the joy we give'.
How nice is that?
I did grab the mic and do a dedication to the volunteers, to all volunteers. I'm sure she's a lovely lady, and the volunteer work for Ephemera is so fulfilling. I know, because that night I was a volunteer too.
Ephemera forever!
Happy Days, Ooroo.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ooroo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unephemera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disephemera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dirty Car Art</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Jenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giant Pacific Octopus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Wade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strand Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Police Aware</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
