<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411029942931787</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/reality-tv/the-one-big-mistake-survivor-contestants-keep-making/news-story/1551632ed1364fa215cd501f628e20cd</url>
  <title>The one big mistake Survivor contestants keep making</title>
  <content>
Survivor turns x-rated
0:39

Survivor turns x-rated when contestant Locky loses his shorts during a challenge.

July 31st 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/Television/

Has Mark already found love on the island?

Share

WE'RE only a few episodes into the current season of Survivor - but have two of the game's strongest players already made one of the franchise's most common mistakes?
Former Special Ops Commander Mark and endurance athlete Sam were shown getting up close and personal during last night's episode of the show - embracing on camera and spooning each other as they slept, their bodies interlocked.
"Since day one, on the barge, I could feel a bit of a closeness with Sam. It's weird. I'd say it's not more than a friendship," Mark said, before admitting it could be something more.
"Oh look, if I met her on the outside and she was single, I'd definitely be interested," he admitted.
Have Mark and Sam put a target on their backs with their early displays of affection?
In a game where contestants spend a huge amount of time sitting around watching and whispering about each other, the pair's growing closeness didn't go unnoticed.
"I think Mark is Sam's watchdog,' fellow contestant Jacqui said.
"She doesn't let him out of her sight and he seems to do as he's told."

Mark.Source:Channel 10

Sam. Picture: Nigel WrightSource:Channel 10
Sure enough, when several competitors left the camp for a carefully-timed walk to discuss their gameplay, Sam sent Mark scurrying after them to gather info and report back.
On social media, Survivor fans who've watched contestants get visibly intimate had a strong message for Sam and Mark: STOP HAVING CUDDLE TIME, YOU'RE COMPETING FOR HALF A MILLION DOLLARS HERE.

Why are Sam & Mark making it so obvious smh
Samantha gonna be the one targeted over Mark
Samantha and Mark being the Lee and el that fails and gets flung immediately. Here for it
Mark you're not Sam's man. You're her freaking pet
This game play from Sam and Mark is so obvious and high school. I wonder if she got her best friend to tell him she liked him
lol Sam sending Mark to follow Jacqui and Henry omg like he is her bf 😂
Want to unravel Sam? Hit on and flirt with Mark
We saw this last year with contestants Lee and El, who struck up a noticeably intimate friendship during their time in Samoa. It was an alliance that took them all the way to the final three, but saw them both pipped at the post by Kristie, a contestant who'd moved between alliances throughout the competition. While they may have lost out on the half-million dollar prize, the pair at least found a relationshp that continues to this day.

Lee and El insist they were just friends on the island - but they've been a couple ever since. Picture: Jonathan NgSource:News Corp Australia
It's not a cliche to say that entering a relationship - or even getting close enough to another competitor that others can speculate you're more than friends - can put a big target on a Survivor contestant's back. As part of a 'couple', you're immediately more visible; an alliance that needs to be broken up before it gets too powerful.
And yet, so many Survivor contestants end up finding love with their competitors - the US version of the show has  since its debut in 2000.
But those who enter into relationships on the show can find real-world complications make them impossible to continue: Just last year, the 33rd US season of the show saw contestants Taylor Stocker and Jessica "Figgy" Figueroa form a very visible and very physical bond in front of their competitors. It was a loved-up alliance that saw them both voted out within days, but the pair insisted they'd continue their relationship on the outside world.
However, once booted from the show, Taylor learned he had a baby on the way with another woman, which put rather a dampener on things with Figgy. he admitted at the time.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>COMPETING FOR HALF A MILLION DOLLARS HERE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Locky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Figgy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan NgSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Figueroa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Special Ops Commander Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STOP HAVING CUDDLE TIME</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel WrightSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Stocker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
