<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411034237899139</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:21</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/this-e-book-can-help-any-australian-small-business-owner-plan-for-a-better-year-ahead-2017-8</url>
  <title>This e-book can help any Australian small business owner plan for a better year ahead</title>
  <content>
Presented by Bank of Queensland Small Business Banking.  See how our small business experience can help you. Visit  today

If you're a small business owner, there are a lot of common questions that are critical but often complex. Sometimes, knowing where to start and where to look in order to gather answers are the biggest challenges.

With the help of the Bank of Queensland, we've put together a short downloadable eBook which is designed to help entrepreneurs, founders, and leaders in Australian small and medium sized companies think about some of the core questions for businesses over the coming year.

Anyone who has ever run a small business knows no matter what their individual circumstances may be, it's all about confidence and cash flow. Chapter 1 breaks down the essential elements of this year's federal budget and how it will affect small business owners.

Going the way of the blinking dials and spooling tape is the old way of securing contracts. With an overhaul of the government tendering process aimed at making it possible for smaller technology companies, among others, to compete with the established industry players for service contacts. Everything you need to know about government service reform and the opportunities this creates for small business owners is in Chapter 2.

Chapter 3 is all about big data. Its power to drive economic activity has been likened to that of oil. Just like black gold, this data needs to be first mined and then refined for businesses to harness its full potential.

If you've ever had difficulty balancing people and profit, head straight to chapter 4, which focuses on strategies for hiring talent, acquiring customers, and growing revenues.

There's more opportunity than ever before for entering, discovering, and creating new markets as barriers move or dissolve entirely. Chapter 5 focuses on how entrepreneurs can think about entering new markets in a connected world.

To download a copy of 'Australia's Business Challenges 2017' - a comprehensive must-read e-book for small business owners brought to you by Bank of Queensland, fill in your details in the form below.

By completing this form you agree to be contacted by Business Insider and our partners.

This article has been compiled by Business Insider. Bank of Queensland Limited ABN 32 009 656 740 (Australian Credit Licence No 244616) (BOQ) has not been involved in the preparation of this article. This article, and any advice that it contains has been prepared by and is the responsibility of Business Insider. The information contained in this article is of a general nature and has been prepared without taking account of your objectives, financial situation or needs. It is not intended to be nor should it be considered as professional advice. You should not act on the basis of anything contained in this article without first obtaining specific professional advice. BOQ makes no representations or warranties about the accuracy or completeness of the article. To the extent permitted by law, BOQ and its related bodies corporate, employees and contractors exclude liability for any loss or damage sustained by any readers of the article. BOQ accepts no responsibility to any persons for any loss which may be incurred or suffered as a result of acting or refraining from acting as a result of anything contained in this article. BOQ is not responsible for third party websites or articles. They do not necessarily reflect the opinions of BOQ, nor does BOQ confirm their accuracy.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BoQ</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Limited ABN 32 009 656 740</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eBooks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chapter 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Business Challenges 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Credit Licence No 244616</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Small Business Banking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
