<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410639100901792</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/02/09/34/baby-panda-born-china-to-captive-and-wild-parents</url>
  <title>World-first panda cub born to both captive and wild parents</title>
  <content>
A giant panda who was raised in captivity but mated in the wild has reportedly given birth to a female cub in south-west China.
Weighing just 216 grams, the baby panda was born yesterday at the Hetaoping Panda Base in Wolong, in China's Sichuan Province, .
The cub is the first panda to be born to captive and wild parents, marking success in experiments to encourage captive pandas to mate with wild pandas.
Fifteen-year-old female giant panda Cao Cao was born in the wild and rescued by the China Conservation and Research Centre for the Giant Panda (CCRCGP) as a two-year-old cub in 2003.
For most of the last seven years, she has lived at the Hetaoping training centre.
After being released into the wild in March this year, a GPS device attached to her collar showed she naturally mated with a wild panda on March 23.
Cao Cao began showing signs of pregnancy on July 1 before she went into labour at the semi-wild training base on Sunday.

Related Articles

The back-to-nature training program was kick-started by the Wolong centre alongside the CCRCGP in 2005.
Since then, the centre has continued training and releasing giant pandas into the wild under the program.
Currently there are about 471 captive pandas in China which are mainly bred using artificial insemination, .
Zhang Hemin, deputy director of the CCRCGP told local media the only way to increase genetic diversity at the facility was to release captive pandas into the wild to mate naturally.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cao Cao</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giant Panda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Sichuan Province</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhang Hemin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World-first</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hetaoping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Conservation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hetaoping Panda Base</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCRCGP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Research Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
