<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410725000249176</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/national/public-service/i-hate-open-plan-how-to-navigate-unnecessary-noises-in-the-office-20170728-gxko5e.html</url>
  <title>Coach at work: how to navigate unnecessary noises in the office</title>
  <content>
I have a sensitive issue to raise. It is about people making unnecessary noises in the office space. I have a few particular noises that I find are completely unnecessary. They are people chewing gum with their mouths open, excessively clicking pens and whistling. I find that people who make these noises in the presence of others are being completely disrespectful of the right of others in the space. I have often tried to raise my discomfort from being subjected to these noises and nearly always have been derided and scoffed at. Even been told to try to block it out.
Is there some way that people who feel that their space is being infringed on can ask for such noises to be ceased?
The coach:

The way is there, but the level of hurt and sadness in your letter makes me suspect you're going to find the walk pretty hard. So let's tread gently. You want something (quiet in an open plan office), and you can't ask for it; or, the way you ask for what you want tends to stop you from getting it.Photo: Shutterstock
Responding on the surface of this dilemma, you could try a technical fix. Here's a quick summary, before we have a look at what might be going on internally, and potentially also neurologically.  
Three steps: yes, no, yes.Photo: Sari Sutton
The first "yes" is all about affirming something - spelling out what the person, or the team, or the organisation, is getting from the behaviour.
"I get that you guys are having a great time catching up." Or, "It's really hard to work collaboratively in open plan and be completely silent at the same time, isn't it?" 

Step two introduces your "no": the impacts on you of the behaviour. "I'm finding the noise levels a bit out of my comfort zone." This is a statement that identifies clearly and factually what it is that you're saying "no" to.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Step three affirms what you want. The key here is to be highly specific so the person on the end of the request knows exactly what you need them to do differently. You might try, "I'm out of the office this afternoon - are you willing to have the conversation then?" or "I'm really committed to getting this project report finished by noon, and I would really appreciate some quiet until then".
I'm not convinced, however, that a technical fix is going to work for you. Requests for behaviour change are most likely to succeed if you have some social capital (fondness, trust, familiarity) to lubricate the inherent friction that arises between people who have competing needs. That social capital doesn't exist in the scenario you've drawn here, where you're stewing about your colleagues and attributing to them various degrees of awfulness while you remain helpless and innocent over there on your side of the workspace. You can use your own feelings about other people as a measure of how they feel about you: if you're really hating them, they're likely to come right back at you in similar vein. In fact, it sounds like they already have. 
Social bonding makes technical tasks flow easier: people will get back to you quicker, be more willing to work with you, be OK about piping down because they know you're sensitive to noise, if you build relationships with them. You can start by introducing more social interactions with your colleagues into your daily routine. Quick interactions are perfectly fine when you're starting out.
And I get how uncomfortable these noises make you, so let's see what we can do about that.   
Being set off by certain specific noises (pens clicking, people chewing) rather than decibel level indicates noise sensitivity. I have a hunch that the level of upset in your letter is linked to a fear that you're oversensitive, so it might be useful to concede that you are, rather than fighting with others against the possibility. "Yup, I'm definitely oversensitive", rather than, "how dare you imply that I'm oversensitive!".
The corollary to this is not "therefore I must suffer in silence", however. It's "therefore my colleagues and I are going to have to work out a way around this". I know who I'd rather sit next to in open plan. An oversensitive person who knows they are, so I can help them. Wouldn't it be great if you weren't perfect? What a relief, you lovely flawed human, you. Welcome to the rest of humanity.
You might also like to explore the possibility that you have Asperger traits. If you do, you're in terrific company.
Other possible neurological factors in noise sensitivity include brain injury, psychological trauma and other styles of atypical neurology - HSP (Highly Sensitive People) types, for example, can be driven spare by the noise involved in your average work day. If any of this rings true, your solution might end up being therapeutic (talk to your GP for a referral to a specialist).  
Neurological factors might also make the technical fix of asking for what you want, or increasing your social contact with your peers, out of your reach for the time being. Please honour your own limitations and spend some time gathering information and expert advice on what's behind your current difficulty before you move to solutions that are too far outside your comfort zone. Your distress is real, even if you (and others) find it hard to relate to.  In the meantime, earplugs sound like a good idea for the sake of staying on an even keel in the midst of sounds you can't tolerate. Go gently, and give yourself all the time and help you need. I wish you every success. 
Jacqueline Jago is an executive coach and the principal of . Send your questions to .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sari Sutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shutterstock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqueline Jago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highly Sensitive People</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asperger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
