<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411029942931757</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/lifestyle/health/pete-evans-documentary-about-the-benefits-of-the-paleo-diet-has-been-slammed/news-story/776a9c5ab941071be62026ca81ee9753</url>
  <title>'Just plain mean': Pete Evans savaged</title>
  <content>
A NEW documentary by celebrity chef Pete Evans - which depicts the paleo diet as a treatment for chronic diseases as severe as diabetes, cancer and autism in children - has been slammed the Australian Medical Association.
Evans' The Magic Pill, which is currently screening at selected cinemas around Australia, follows people suffering from different chronic illnesses who adopt the ketogenic high fat, low carb diet for five weeks and are all shown to drastically reduce their symptoms and reliance on pharmaceutical drugs.
According to director Rob Tate, the film makes a case for "holistic land management with ethically raised animals" to aid human disease and better care for the planet.
One of the case studies is Abigail, a four-year-old non-verbal autistic girl suffering from up to 50 daily seizures, who by the end of the film is able to speak for the first time.
AMA president Michael Gannon yesterday likened the film to controversial documentary Vaxxed, saying they were competing "in the awards for the films least likely to contribute to public health".
"Elements of the discussion are just plain hurtful, harmful and mean," Dr Gannon said.
"The idea that a high-fat diet can change a child's behaviour in a month is just so patently ridiculous ... and yet the reality is the parents of autistic children are so desperate they will reach for anything.
"I enjoy (Evans') emphasis on protein because there's no question that lean meat, eggs and fish are superfoods ... but exclusion diets never work."
Other participants included people suffering from type-2 diabetes, asthma and a woman who claimed to have shrunk the cancerous tumour in her breast by eliminating the glucose from carbohydrates.
A disclaimer is shown prior to the film, urging viewers to seek medical advice before altering their diet.
Mr Tate said The Magic Pill would "preach to the converted" but he hoped to appeal to the public's "sense of science" when it came to food's effect on health.
"It stands counter to our government-sanctioned guidelines. Counter to the pharmaceutical industry. Counter to most food industries," he said
"It's especially easy to mock a celebrity, but reality exists whether the public likes it or not. This way of eating is scientifically sound."
"We've been misled - sometimes purposefully, sometimes through bias or ignorance - but slowly scientific clarity is bringing us back."

Pete Evans talks to Sunday Night about the babies and bone broth controversy. Courtesy: Channel 7/Sunday Night

Pete Evans addresses bone broth controversy
The film was made over two years throughout Australia, the US, South Africa and the UK and includes the Yolngu community in northeast Arnhem Land.
It also suggests the healthy eating pyramid be flipped to place a greater emphasis on protein with grains and wheat as the smallest portion of the diet.
Nutrition Australia Queensland nutritionist Aloysa Hourigan said there was a lot to gain from plant-based diets but it was important to balance the intake of fats.
"It's not healthy advice. About 80 per cent of your grain-based food should be wholegrain and those wholegrain foods are really important for your gut health," she said.
"We have got to be careful not to mix up what's good for individuals ... with advice for the whole population."
Evans, who has previously defended his views on the paleo diet, has not returned a request for comment.
Screenings of The Magic Pill are being organised by different hosts through online platform FanForce.
It will screen in Toowoomba tonight.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abigail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Medical Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pete Evans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Tate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yolngu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Gannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday Night</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7/Sunday Night</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magic Pill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vaxxed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Gannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aloysa Hourigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nutrition Australia Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FanForce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
