<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411077187572829</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65453/2018-renault-clio-rs-facelift-price-and-features-for-australia</url>
  <title>2018 Renault Clio RS Facelift - Price And Features for Australia</title>
  <content>
has revised its hot hatch entry-point, updating the  pocket rocket with fresh styling, a revised range, and extra equipment.
As before, the Clio RS is powered by a 1.6-litre turbocharged four-cylinder engine, driving the front wheels via a six-speed Efficient Dual Clutch transmission. Changes for the 2018 model year also see a fuel-saving stop-start system added, dropping official consumption figures to 5.9 l/100km, down from 6.3 l/100km previously.
The most obvious change to the new model occurs at the front end where the Clio RS picks up a new front bumper design, reshaped headlight internals, and Renault Sport's newest visual signature, chequered flag-inspired LED fog lights.

Renault has also trimmed the model range back to just two variants starting with the Clio RS Sport from $30,990 plus on-road costs with the more focussed Cup variant, with a unique suspension tune, priced from $32,490 plus on-road costs.
The Sport includes silver 17-inch wheels to go with its more forgiving suspension tune, though black wheels are an option, while the Cup upsizes to black 18-inch wheels offset by red-painted brake calipers.

Both RS models come standard with climate control, keyless entry and start, cloth trim, leather wrapped steering wheel with shift paddles, rain sensing wipers, self-dimming rear view mirror, LED cabin lighting, and a 7.0-inch touchscreen infotainment system.
Available options will include a black pack ($500) that brings a black front bumper blade, bootlid, rear diffuser, badges and wheels, a leather pack ($1500) that adds dark leather with red stitching and heated front seats, and an entertainment pack ($1500) for satellite navigation, a Bose stereo, Android Auto phone mirroring and more.

The Clio RS is currently on sale, and will be joined in Australian showrooms during 2018 by a new five-door .
Overseas model shown.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clio RS Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renault</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renault Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renault Clio RS Facelift</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Efficient Dual Clutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clio RS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Android Auto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
