<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411034237899169</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/second-scissor-attack-sydney-station-armed-man/3207827/</url>
  <title>Second scissor attack at Sydney station by armed man</title>
  <content>
A SECOND man armed with scissors at Sydney's Central train station has been arrested a week after police shot dead an ice addict who attacked a railway florist with scissors and a broken bottle.

NSW Police confirmed that at 8.30am on Wednesday a man armed with a pair of scissors entered a shop at Central.

The report of the attack came as news of a violent incident in Melbourne's suburbs was also emerging.

The scene of the latest Sydney attack was a shop located in the Henry Deane Plaza at the Broadway end of the Central Station tunnel.

After the man entered the shop allegedly armed with the scissors he closed the shop door, NSW Police Media told news.com.au.

A staff member managed to contact police and officers attended the shop where the man was arrested without incident.

Police officers descended on Central station a week after the fatal incident on Wednesday evening of last week.

In Melbourne's east, police have closed off a road in the suburb of Boronia after a man was assaulted overnight and threatened with a firearm.

A week ago at Sydney's Central station, florist Emmanuel Theoharis was attacked by a man wielding up to four pairs of scissors and a broken bottle.

Danukul Mokmool entered Mr Theoharis's shop on Eddy Avenue at 6.20pm and put his arm around the elderly shop owner's throat, saying "don't move, call the police".

Mokmool, who had two pairs of scissors in his belt and two in his hand pushed the broken bottle into Mr Theoharis's throat, inflicting a 5cm-long wound.

Alerted to an armed robbery in progress, police arrived on the scene and confronted Mokmool.

Officers told the assailant to put down his weapon and when Mokmool refused, they shot him dead.

Graphic video posted on social media filmed by an eyewitness shows two police officers with their guns drawn and aimed at a man inside a florist before someone yells "down".

The man appears to run from the florist towards police before four shots are fired at him.

"F***, f***," an onlooker can be heard screaming.

The man can then be seen lying lifeless on the ground as police come to his aid.

"Everybody move away," someone can be heard saying before the video ends.

Following the latest incident, a man was taken to Day Street police station on Wednesday for questioning.

Baby whale rescued on the Sunshine Coast
Up to $214,000 remains on table for refocused investigation
"I'm absolutely heartbroken to hear the two humpback whales died."
AT Nambour State School, many pupils came to school by train.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Theoharis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emmanuel Theoharis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mokmool</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danukul Mokmool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Deane Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boronia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddy Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Central</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
