<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410256848805088</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/ffa-cup-sydney-fc-not-taking-darwin-rovers-lightly-ahead-of-knockout-clash/news-story/231c96ba0ed4fa41573e860d1dda66c9</url>
  <title>Rovers receive Sydney FC coach</title>
  <content>
SYDNEY FC boss Graham Arnold took a step back when asked if tonight™s FFA Cup clash between his Sky Blues and Darwin Rovers was a classic minnows versus giants event.

The A-League champions are raging favourites for the Round of 32 knockout game, but Arnold was quick to play down any giant-killing talk.

"It depends how you want to put that," he said. "I wouldn't pay any disrespect to Darwin.

"It's an important game, it's the FFA Cup and a trophy Sydney FC has never won before, so we're definitely ready to go.

"We've got our best front line up here - Bobo, Charles Lokolingoy and Matt Simon - and some boys you might see wearing a national team shirt very soon."

Arnold expects his team to put on a performance worthy of the national champions.

"I want our best performance, a professional attitude, professional mentality and we do not underestimate anyone," he said.

"For us it's always about ourselves, the standards we set and though we had a fantastic season (last year), it's history.''

The Sky Blues lost a close final to Melbourne City nine months ago, but Arnold said there was no talk of redemption, preferring to focus on his players lifting to another level for what was a new campaign against better opposition.

"We're still in the middle of recruiting and still have more players to bring in," he said.

"The players believe we can get better and I believe we will be better. This is the first real game of the season and we're looking forward to it.

"We trained in spray jackets all week to try and make it a little bit warmer, though the weather in Sydney hasn't been too bad."

Rovers manager Jimmy Culligan said his players were as "confident as we're going to be and as fit as we have been".

"The boys are all in great shape and great spirits, we're just looking forward to the game now and doing what we have to do," he said.

"It's not about scoring early and sitting back, it's important we don't concede early."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Simon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARWIN Rovers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Lokolingoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Arnold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Blues</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jimmy Culligan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnold</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
