<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410162359522597</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/with-roe-8-axed-how-will-perth-congestion-problems-be-solved/8761164</url>
  <title>With Roe 8 axed, how to solve the real problem of traffic snarls?</title>
  <content>
One of the first acts of the McGowan Government was to stop construction of the controversial Roe 8 highway extension, bringing plaudits from protesters and anger from industry.
But while the road is gone, the congestion problem remains, and the number of trucks on the roads into Fremantle Port is set to continue growing.

The planned new outer harbour at Kwinana is still at least several years away from turning the first sod, so what is being done to ease congestion in the meantime?
Not enough, say critics like Cam Dumesny from the WA Road Transport Association, with traffic jams a regular occurrence on the roads to Fremantle Port
"It's bad and it's only going to get worse. This will be an increasing point of congestion, both for our industry and the community," Mr Dumesny said.
"Any point where we've got congestion, any point where we slow, or impose costs on, the supply chain is going to affect jobs in the broader economy."
Road upgrades needed

Supporters of Roe 8 have already put numbers on what the end of the road means for traffic.
Pro Roe 8 group convenor and Cockburn Councillor Steven Portelli said major road upgrades would be needed over the next five years.
"Without Roe 8, we're looking at Farrington Road having something like 50,000 extra traffic movements a day, we're looking at Berrigan Drive [with an extra]14,500 traffic movements, we're looking at Beeliar Drive with 17,500 extra traffic movements a day," he said.
But the McGowan Government maintained it has both a short-term and long-term plan to tackle congestion in lieu of Roe 8.

The long-term plan is the outer harbour. Ahead of that, the Government is talking with the City of Fremantle to decide on the best design for a $118 million upgrade to the intersection between High Street and Stirling Highway.
It is one of the worst bottlenecks along the route to the port, with only one lane turning right onto Stirling Highway and trucks banking up daily waiting to round the corner.
The upgrade is being funded as part of a $2.3 billion road and rail package with the Commonwealth, which also includes widening parts of Kwinana Freeway and creating a new entry to the Fiona Stanley Hospital and Murdoch Hospital precinct.
Transport Minister Rita Saffioti said the Government was also increasing the subsidy to put containers on rail. Its target is to increase freight brought to Fremantle Port by rail from 15 to 20 per cent.
"We're looking at a number of other options in relation to empty containers, other options in relation to the operation of the port and how we can spread the peak traffic as well," she said.
"I think it will relieve the pressure, and ultimately, as I said, we'll be in the planning phase for the outer harbour, looking at what time frame we can develop that."
But even some of the most ardent opponents are not convinced.
'Band aid fix' not enough: residents

Tania and Damon Smirke live alongside Leach Highway in Palmyra and were prominent opponents of the initial plan for trucks to come off Roe 8 and past their house.
Ms Smirke thought the High Street-Stirling Highway upgrade would not be enough, given 80 per cent of freight to Fremantle would still be delivered by trucks.
"It's just a band aid fix to the whole system, because of the fact the port's a certain size, there are still so many cars that need to go through there," Ms Smirke said.

"It doesn't matter what you do, there's still going to be traffic jams. It's still going to be a problem. Perth does need the outer harbour."
The Smirkes were relieved when Roe 8 was canned, but now want it deleted from the Metropolitan Regional Scheme (MRS).
"The thought's always there, if there's a change of government again, will it come back on the agenda?" Mr Smirke said.
It is what pro-Roe 8 campaigners are counting on.
"As far as I'm concerned the fight's not over yet, the money's still set aside," Mr Portelli said.
"Hopefully Labor's out at the end of this term and we get a Liberal Government returned and they put it in."
Ms Saffioti said she was looking at removing Roe 8 from the MRS in the next year.
The State Opposition vehemently opposes such a move, pointing to studies it commissioned in Government suggesting Fremantle Port still had 30 years' of capacity and only Roe 8 could accommodate the growth.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling Highway</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro Roe 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smirke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kwinana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGowan Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damon Smirke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smirkes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murdoch Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berrigan Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle Port</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmyra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan Regional Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dumesny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beeliar Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Rita Saffioti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Saffioti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Smirke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Road Transport Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam Dumesny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roe 8</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Portelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farrington Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cockburn Councillor Steven Portelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kwinana Freeway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Stanley Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Street-Stirling Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leach Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
