<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409960496055465</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4826082/full-house-as-600-hit-city-for-bowls-finals/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Full house as 600 hit city for bowls finals</title>
  <content>
ROLL UP ROLL UP: Club Maitland City's Sports and Sponsorship Manager DJ Dilworth said preparation for this weekend's event is huge.

Maitland is set to roll out the full house signs as an estimated 600 lawn bowls enthusiasts flock to the city for the  finals.
The event will be held over three days at Club Maitland City at Rutherford and at Lorn Park Bowls Sports and Recreation Club.
Club Maitland City's Sports and Sponsorship Manager DJ Dilworth said the event is huge for the clubs involved and huge for the city from an economic point of view.
The Grade 3 State Pennant Finals will see 16 teams comprising about 250 players compete for the top honour in a round robin event.
Maitland City hosted the event several years ago and according to Dilworth clubs are only allowed to host them once every three years.
While the event is held over three days, Dilworth said visitors have allocated themselves a four-day stay at various locations across the city.
"Both our motels, Maitland City and The Old Maitland Inn, are fully booked and I'd say it's pretty much the trend right across town," he said.
Dilworth said the event has been months in the planning with the two clubs working closely together.
"We've been flat out for about four months to make sure everything runs smoothly over the weekend.
"We need an army of volunteers, about 20 from each club, to co-ordinate everything.
"We've ordered extra kegs, extra meals, extra sausages, extra staff.
"Our green keeping staff have put in a tremendous amount of work on the greens which look fantastic. So it's a big thanks to them," Dilworth said.
"This is certainly the biggest event we have held here at Club Maitland City.
"It's a great way to promote the club, put Maitland on the map and showcase what we have to people from Wagga to Kempsey."
Maitland City Council's Visitor and City Economy Co-ordinator Martin Payne said Maitland is a popular destination for sport events.

He said the city boasts many facilities of regional and state quality and a range of accommodation options that can cater for over 1380 visitors.

"Events such as this are a perfect opportunity to showcase the city to a large audience, who may also return as a leisure visitor in the future," Mr Payne said.

"Economic modelling suggests that an event of this size would have a direct economic benefit of $245,000 to the Maitland economy."
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sponsorship Manager DJ Dilworth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dilworth</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club Maitland City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grade 3 State Pennant Finals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rutherford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROLL UP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland City Council's Visitor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kempsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Maitland Inn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club Maitland City's Sports</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Economy Co-ordinator Martin Payne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorn Park Bowls Sports</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Recreation Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
