<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411072892605324</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/retail/executives-are-more-worried-about-amazon-than-trump-20170731-gxmnmg.html</url>
  <title>Trump or Amazon? Online giant is the bigger worry, executives say</title>
  <content>
What keeps corporate leaders up at night?
It isn't the chaos in Washington or rising worker pay. It's what Amazon is, or could be, doing to their business models, according to a Bloomberg analysis of the conference call transcripts of  America's latest profit reporting season.

Up Next

Apple jumps, Dow hits record high

01:14

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Are companies like Amazon good for society?

NYU Stern Professor of Marketing Scott Galloway looks at whether other tech giants have to fear the Amazon juggernaut.

The expanding online behemoth has morphed from a retail category killer to a much broader enterprise that now competes with everything from high-end grocers to technology developers. It's safe to say companies have taken notice -- and are increasingly concerned about the competition.
Looking at the last 90 days of earnings calls and other corporate events such as investor days, a trend emerges. Amazon comes up a lot. It was mentioned a staggering 635 times over that time frame, while President Trump came up just 162 times and wages were discussed 111, the earnings call data show. It's become even more pronounced over the past 30 days, with Amazon garnering 165 mentions compared with 32 for Trump and 22 for wages.

The trend holds over the past 12 months, which encompasses the period when Trump pulled off his surprise election victory. Yet, Amazon was mentioned 1800 times on earnings calls over that span, compared with 1000 for Trump and 406 for wages.

A representative for Amazon didn't immediately respond to an email seeking comment.
Amazon typically comes up in discussions about efforts to expand into new business lines in a shifting retail landscape. For instance, on the McDonald's second-quarter earnings call this month, Chief Executive Officer Steve Easterbrook pointed to Amazon's purchase of the upscale grocery chain Whole Foods Market as an example of how rapidly the food industry is being transformed.Photo: Joseph Nair
"It just demonstrates how disruptive the business world is and how quickly it moves," he said.
Executives are also quick to point out partnerships they have with Amazon. Mark Parker, the CEO of Nike, highlighted the shoe manufacturer's pilot brand-registry program with the retailer on his June earnings call.
"As we do with all of our partners," he said, "we're looking for ways to improve the Nike consumer experience on Amazon by elevating the way the brand is presented and increasing the quality of product storytelling."
Bloomberg
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Galloway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Parker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whole Foods Market</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Executive Officer Steve Easterbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NYU Stern Professor of Marketing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Nair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
