<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409964791022877</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/draw-a-line-in-the-sand-when-it-comes-to-kids-spor/3207426/</url>
  <title>Draw a line in the sand when it comes to kids' sport</title>
  <content>
IF IT be true that "parents are attempting to bubble-wrap their children" within the context of sport, then I doubt there would be football codes for kids to play in.
Parents often live through their kids and present a toxic scenario as they use aggression as their tool of trade to incentivise their offspring and we wonder why?
Well, you just have a look at the awful dash-cam pictures of road rage on our screens on many nights - some children learn the way to solve their issues is to become violent rather than using threats and intimidation not at all or as a very last resort.
With many parents pushing them to win at all costs on the field, be it football codes or lifesaving, children soon learn the lesson that winning is paramount.
Games need to remain games and enjoyment for the participants, some of whom will become better people for the inclusion but who will never aspire to Commonwealth or Olympic games levels.
Parents and carers need to draw a line in the sand with their involvement once the game begins.
CLAIRE JOLLIFFE
Buderim
Wife heard screaming on dashcam footage
NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CLAIRE JOLLIFFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
