<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411111547311809</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/personal-finance/superannuation-and-smsfs/to-sell-or-not-to-sell-a-commercial-property-20170801-gxmqtb</url>
  <title>When you should sell a commercial property to finance superannuation</title>
  <content>
by
Sam Henderson

I am 63 years old and my wife is 60. We are semi-retired. I am running a small business at home with hardly any turnover - less than $20,000 last year - and I have not paid tax for the past three years. Basically, the business is my pastime and keeps me sane. My wife stays at home and has an investment commercial property which she rents out for an annual income of $60,000, excluding GST. We own our residential property. We took out a mortgage (on our residential property) when we purchased the commercial property. We have not applied for any Centrelink benefits and intend not to until we reach our retirement age. My wife tries to put aside $10,000 into superannuation every year and she also contributes $2000 into my super every year. Shall we sell the property and pop the money into super? Or, continue to hold on to the commercial property, worth about $1 million, and live on the rental when we retire? What is your advice if we intend to receive some sort of pension when we retire in a few years. Ronald
Ronald, this is indeed a great question and an issue many Aussies face. The exact answer would depend upon some essential missing information such as the location and type of property (you mentioned commercial but that includes industrial property, offices etc), your current super balances, any other assets or income and if there's debt against the property albeit secured by your principal residence. So in the absence of further information, I'll do my best to answer your question.
The question about whether to sell is simply a function of net income. Many commercial properties produce good income, sometimes up to 10 per cent or more, but the costs need to be accounted for. What's your income net of expenses such as the agent's management fees, land tax, repairs and maintenance, and potential strata fees or utilities costs?
If you are getting a reasonable return, say more than the current rate on cash in the bank after costs, (greater than 3 per cent but ideally greater than 5 per cent) and you're getting exposure to capital gains with a long-term outlook, then perhaps hang on to the property.

If like many residential property investors you are receiving a low after-cost return of 2 per cent or less, then you know your property is potentially overvalued and its future as an investment may be limited. A property with a 3 per cent net return has a price (PE) earnings ratio of 33.3 times. Shares typically have a PE of around 14 times. So, too, income on many shares is around 5 per cent, with growth of around 3 to 5 per cent per annum, so your money may well be better deployed elsewhere.

The question is one of capital deployment. Where do I invest to get my optimum return given my needs and objectives? There's actually not a straight answer because we never know what the future holds.
Importantly, you need to consider liquidity, or the speed at which you can turn your asset into cash if the need arises. The need rarely arises when economic times are good. So I often say to clients: "We are investing for the bad times and not the good times. A rising tide lifts all boats." The latter is a Warren Buffett quote.
If you don't need the money and you have a few years of cash available, and you have a good property in a good location, then I'd probably hang on to it. If you have any doubts, then it may be worth selling, depending on the capital gain you are likely to make, while the market is good, because I'm not convinced this boom will go on forever.
You can also maximise your after-tax contributions to super between now and age 65. You could also use taxable contributions to potentially lower your CGT liability and even use a reserving strategy, whereby you claim a tax deduction on two years worth of taxable contributions, or $50,000 tax deduction for each partner if property is owned jointly. You really need some advice on your options.

Would you please comment on the three-year bring forward rule. What is the latest date a person who is a 73 at their next birthday can exercise the bring forward rule? By the end of the 2018 financial year? Before their 73rd birthday or before their 75th birthday? Mike
Mike, unfortunately this ship has sailed. You may only use the three-year bring forward strategy if you are 65 or under. If you're 65, it can only be used in the tax year in which you turn 65 and the work test must be met (40 hours of work in 30 consecutive days) to make the $300,000 contribution.
For those people under 65, there is no work test. It should also be noted that if you're close to 65, say 63, and you have a few spare dollars around, it may be worth making $100,000 non-concessional contributions each year and then making the full $300,000 in the year in which you turn 65 to maximise your super savings, assuming you have less than $1.6 million in your fund.
Mike, keep an eye on the new rules about to be introduced in the next financial which will allow over 65s to make a $300,000 contribution to super if they sell their principal residence after having owned it for more than 10 years. This may be your best opportunity.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Buffett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CGT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
