<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410432942467357</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/backing-cane-changer/3207753/</url>
  <title>Backing Cane Changer</title>
  <content>
LATE last week at a Canegrowers Policy Council meeting, Queensland Minister for Environment Steven Miles signed a commitment to the sugarcane industry recognising decades of grower investment in environmental outcomes.
The Cane Changer commitment was signed in front of representatives from all sugarcane growing regions in Queensland.
While as a collective we remain opposed to regulation of farming practices in the catchments of the Great Barrier Reef, we as an industry also remain committed to the Smartcane BMP program as the most enduring direction for our industry to meet its obligations to improve water quality targets set by the State Government.
The Cane Changer project, backed by the Queensland Government and delivered by Behaviour Innovation in the Wet Tropics region, is unique in Australian agriculture.
It is a platform recognising the work being undertaken on our cane farms to protect the Great Barrier Reef and progressing planning for environmentally sustainable practices. It puts growers and their businesses at the centre of responsible land stewardship, and sets the record straight.
This project is being rolled out in the Innisfail, Tully and Cairns cane growing regions with plans to extend its reach in the future.
The document signed by Steven Miles recognises the important role cane growers play in the state of Queensland and acknowledges the ongoing efforts of Queensland cane growers to improve their farming practices, especially as they relate to the health of the Great Barrier Reef.
Cane Changer also commits the State Government to working collaboratively with the sugar industry for a better future for the industry and the environment.
This sends a significant message to the cane industry on many levels, and we are pleased to have the government's commitment to recognise the time, money and creativity growers have invested to achieve favourable environmental outcomes.
In just five months, 109cane growers have signed Cane Changer commitments, and this momentum is growing.
In the past 20 years, the pace of innovation and change in the Queensland sugarcane industry has been rapid, driven by the need to remain profitable in a competitive world sugar market while minimising the impact of our farming practices on the wider environmental front, particularly the Great Barrier Reef.
And now our industry is proud to have its own best management practice program, Smartcane BMP, that is strengthening and driving that process further.
Wife heard screaming on dashcam footage
NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Behaviour Innovation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Barrier Reef</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innisfail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cane Changer</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canegrowers Policy Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tully</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wet Tropics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smartcane BMP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Steven Miles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
