<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411115842279148</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/moonee-valley-council-turns-down-second-chance-offer-to-buy-strathmores-strathaird-reserve-from-state-government/news-story/a7e84ce3029aabf4ba2b0274602106b3</url>
  <title>Fight for reserve turns sour</title>
  <content>
A PEACEFUL park in Strathmore has turned into a political battleground.
The State Government and Moonee Valley Council are continuing to clash over the sale of Strathaird Reserve, leaving residents confused and disappointed.
The council last week turned down a second-chance offer from the State Government to purchase the land from VicRoads, who it is understood is now proceeding with the sale of the land on the open market.
Instead, the council is pushing for the land at 1-15 Strathaird St to be gifted to the council.
At last week's council meeting, Cr Richard Lawrence said the park should be gifted, as they have maintained the land for 40 years.
"It's been a long time that council has maintained and looked after it," Cr Lawrence said. "But we get nothing. Because the State Government is demanding we pay money, because they're being greedy."
Strathmore mother of two Sharon Mumford said she was disappointed when councillors voted against buying the land.
"It felt very staged, like it had already been decided," Ms Mumford said.
Essendon state Labor MP Danny Pearson arranged for the sale of Strathaird Reserve to be put on hold last week to give the council more time to consider the purchase and hit back at claims the State Government was being greedy.
"Council have now twice failed to examine this issue on its merits, for the benefit of future generations," Mr Pearson said.
"I am disappointed that councillors have yet again put aside the best interest of the community to advance their own political agendas."
Moonee Valley Deputy Mayor Cam Nation said he hoped both levels of government could come to an amicable resolution.
"I'd like to think ... rather than council and the local member trading barbs, we sit down in a room to discuss the issue frankly," Cr Nation said.
"Two levels of government going tit for tat only sees the residents lose out."
But it may be too late for discussions, with VicRoads commercial enterprises and business development director Adrian Tofful saying the land would be sold via a public process on the open market.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MP Danny Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathaird Reserve</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathmore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Tofful</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharon Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonee Valley Deputy Mayor Cam Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Lawrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicRoads</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonee Valley Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathaird St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Richard Lawrence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
