<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410862439204665</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/south-east/renovated-him-with-room-for-a-swimming-pool-has-perfect-views/news-story/2ad3718b7ac131baa3e2e1d4a424869b</url>
  <title>Renovated him with room for a swimming pool has perfect views - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
1 Cloverbrook Place, Carina.

THE view from Sue Dyer's home is something special.
The four-bedroom, two-bathroom home at , has acres of parkland at the backdoor of the lowset brick home.
Mrs Dyer, an IT sales manager, has lived at the property for five years and has owned it for seven.
"We initially bought it as an investment property," Mrs Dyer said.
"It's a very quiet area and the aspect with the field and the cows next door is lovely."

1 Cloverbrook Place, Carina.

Mrs Dyer, who has an eight-year-old child, said a mixture of young families and retirees lived in the area.
With room to add a swimming pool, the home has been fully renovated over the past 18 months.

1 Cloverbrook Place, Carina.

Mrs Dyer said she had added a modern touch to the relaxed property.
"There's new bathrooms, a new laundry, and a new kitchen," she said. "The home has had a full repaint, the roof repointed and repainted, tiles replaced, a car port added and a shed."

1 Cloverbrook Place, Carina.

Mrs Dyer said the home was originally purple and pink, however she had revamped it to a white and black colour scheme.

The 3D Diakrit floorplan of 1 Cloverbrook, Carina.

WJ Tobin Real Estate - Carina selling agent Pathrina Watson said: "This type of property is rarely available for sale in this area - especially in the tightly held and highly regarded Carrington Green Estate".
"The lovely 606sq m north facing block is securely fenced on all sides and there are electric gates at the front," Ms Watson said.
"You have direct access to the adjoining parkland and walking tracks via a gate at the rear.
"The yard is the ultimate in low maintenance, though it also presents an opportunity for a keen green thumb to work their magic here and further enhance the street appeal."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Dyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pathrina Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrington Green Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloverbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D Diakrit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloverbrook Place</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WJ Tobin Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Dyer</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carina</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
