<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410862439204605</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/photos-of-hiroshi-restaurant-silicon-valley-2017-7</url>
  <title>Inside the $750-a-head Silicon Valley restaurant where Google and Apple executives eat gold-flecked steaks</title>
  <content>
is an unusual restaurant for an unusual clientele.

Located in Los Altos, California, the newly-opened Japanese restaurant accommodates only eight people per night and has no menus, no windows, and one table. Dinner costs at minimum around $A500 a head, but averages between $A630 and $A750 including beverages and tax.

Chef-owner Hiroshi Kimura left his last restaurant in Hawaii and moved to Silicon Valley in 2016 to launch a concept that would appeal to the deep-pocketed tech elite. Hiroshi hosts three to five dinners a week and is booked solid when a convention comes to town.

We took a tour of the restaurant to see why it's becoming a favourite in Silicon Valley.

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Source:

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

It was made from an 800-year-old Japanese keyaki tree. Biggerstaff told me that the table took 10 men and a small crane to lift into the restaurant. New walls were constructed around it.

Courtesy of Hiroshi

Courtesy of Hiroshi

He decided the tech elite needed a high-end place to eat. The restaurant's details -- from the privacy shades on the windows to the discreet back entrance -- caters to their needs.

Hiroshi accommodates just one seating of up to eight people per night. If a customer's party has only six people, they must buy out the whole table. Dinner starts at $A500 a head, but Biggerstaff said it averages much closer to $A630 to $A750 including beverages and tax.

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Courtesy of Hiroshi

Wagyu steak, which is sometimes called Kobe beef depending on the breed of cow it comes from, is a premium meat known for its intense marbling and tenderness.

Wagyu fetches high prices. American steak purveyor Allen Brothers  for $A200 online. Two ribeye steaks  a whopping $A350.

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider
Chef Kimura cooks a different cut of meat over the hibachi for a demonstration.
The hibachi reaches 800 to 1,200 degrees Fahrenheit, which gives the steak its charred outside and tender, juicy inside. Chef Kimura cuts the steak into thin slices before serving.

Courtesy of Hiroshi

The dish arrives on a sheet of thin, fragrant wood, which prevents the sharp cutlery from destroying the plates.

Courtesy of Hiroshi

Chef Kimura said one of his biggest pet peeves is when guests photograph their steaks before eating them. Wagyu steak is best enjoyed while it's hot, according to the chef.

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Melia Robinson/Business Insider

Courtesy of Hiroshi

Courtesy of Hiroshi

The diner made only one complaint.

'The only thing that turned me off was the gold flake. Gold flake looks nice but it does not add any flavour to the food. I prefer them to spend the money on real food instead,' they .

Courtesy of Hiroshi

Source:

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>KOBE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fahrenheit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melia Robinson/Business Insider</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japanese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hiroshi</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagyu</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chef Kimura</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Altos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chef-owner Hiroshi Kimura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen Brothers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biggerstaff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
