<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411111547311812</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828389/light-rail-could-include-relics-photos/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Light rail could include relics | Photos</title>
  <content>
Light rail could include relics | Photos

Centuries-old sandstone walls have surfaced as part of works in the former Newcastle rail corridor. Pictures: Marina Neil

BYGONE ERA: Honeysuckle station, built in 1872, was one of the oldest in the Hunter. Picture: The University of Newcastle

Centuries-old sandstone walls have surfaced as part of works in the former Newcastle rail corridor. Pictures: Marina Neil

Centuries-old sandstone walls have surfaced as part of works in the former Newcastle rail corridor. Pictures: Marina Neil

Centuries-old sandstone walls have surfaced as part of works in the former Newcastle rail corridor. Pictures: Marina Neil

Centuries-old sandstone walls have surfaced as part of works in the former Newcastle rail corridor. Pictures: Marina Neil

exit

Old brickwork that was part of the historic former Honeysuckle railway station could be incorporated into the design of Newcastle's light rail, Revitalising Newcastle says.
Sandstone remnants of the station were  between Steel Street and Kuwumi Place more than a year ago.

Revitalising Newcastle program director Michael Cassel said on Wednesday that the sandstone blocks were being assessed to possibly be used in the light rail design.

"Heritage experts have verified the materials formed part of the former Honeysuckle railway station, which was built in 1872," he said.
"When the station was closed in 1936 with the opening of Civic and Wickham stations, part of the [Honeysuckle] station was buried beneath the heavy rail corridor."
The material will be excavated, stored in a secure location and assessed for possible incorporation into the urban design elements of the light rail project.
"The community has told us that they are proud of their city and want to see it revitalised, but that the city's history and character should be respected as part of revitalisation activities," Mr Cassel said.
Pedestrian access through to Steel Street will be maintained while the materials are being removed.
The materials have been investigated and assessed in accordance with NSW Office of Environment and Heritage requirements, a statement from Transport for NSW said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuwumi Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marina Neil</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steel Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cassel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Office of Environment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cassel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honeysuckle</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wickham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
