<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411081482540193</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65452/ferrari-backflips-on-anti-suv-stance-report</url>
  <title>Ferrari Backflips On Anti-SUV Stance: Report</title>
  <content>
Seemingly nothing lasts forever, and despite Ferrari's  that it will not enter the SUV market a report suggests that a 'utility vehicle' has been earmarked for a 2022 introduction.
Bloomberg claims that company insiders have revealed the formative stages of a five-year plan that will see Ferrari focus on doubling profits by expanding customer deliveries beyond the current self-imposed 10,000 cars-per-year mark.
Also included in the five-year forecast, the last to be curated under the leadership of current CEO Sergio Marchionne, is an expanded hybrid powertrain reach as the supercar maker comes under increasing pressure to reduce emissions.
The so-called 'Ferrari Utility Vehicle' at the centre of the plan is expected to distance itself from regular SUVs, with a focus on performance as well as passenger accommodation. Nonetheless the new vehicle is being modelled to provide room for four passengers beyond the space provided by the shooting brake-style .

Ferrari GTC4 Lusso

Decisions still pending include whether to make the new vehicle with two doors or four, although given the utility vehicle will likely be aimed primarily at Chinese customers, who hold the belief that two-door cars lack status, a four or five-door form could be more likely.
Along with adding a new more practical model, Ferrari is also considering expanding hybrid technology across its range, having debuted hybrid assistance with the LaFerrari hypercar. The move would also match plans by rivals including , and  to make electric assistance a key part of future plans.
Having already moved to an all-turbocharged range of engines, Ferrari's next step to maintain profitability without the need to purchase carbon credits to offset range-wide vehicle emissions could see both performance and economy benchmarks improved thanks to electric assistance although an all-electric Ferrari supercar still seems unlikely in the near future.
MORE:

Published 2-Aug-2017

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Sergio Marchionne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari GTC4 Lusso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari Backflips On Anti-SUV Stance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari Utility Vehicle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUVs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaFerrari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrari</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
