<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410381402859039</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/adelaide/brodie-smith-says-adelaide-must-solve-a-50-contested-ball-blowout-against-collingwood/news-story/fa119591e6c373cef0e8aa4045f99c0b</url>
  <title>Issue Crows must 'figure out' for Showdown</title>
  <content>
It's the Missing in Action midfield effort against Collingwood that Adelaide must "figure out", concedes gun half-back Brodie Smith.
Adelaide was smashed 167-117 in contested possession and 80-68 in tackles but conjured a pulsating draw out of supreme ball use and goals from turnovers on Sunday at the MCG.
Adelaide has been the No.1 contested ball side this year and must regroup to topple Port on Sunday.

AFL: With 25 seconds to go, Collingwood's Jordan De Goey gets Adelaide forward Josh Jenkins holding the ball, but the Crows weren't done yet.

McGovern's manic game saver
"The really disappointing thing was the contested ball and tackling numbers we were -62 which is huge and something we have been good at all year," Smith told Radio 5AA.
"It is something we have to figure out as it is something we were so good at against Geelong and then we came into the game knowing Collingwood were good in that area. For whatever reason we didn't rock up in that area."
Port't engine room was carried by in a thrilling two-point win against St Kilda on Saturday night. The midfield battle will dictate who breaks a 21-21 Showdown deadlock and Adelaide must service Taylor Walker's forward line with ruckman Sam Jacobs pivotal.
"We have had some good wins in recent times," said Smith with Adelaide leading wins 4-1 at Adelaide Oval against Port.
"Their midfield is good and we have seen what Paddy Ryder can do. It will be a big week for Sauce to get up against Ryder. If we win the midfield battle and feed Tex and the boys it will go a long way to beating them."
Smith's raking kick and run has marked the 2014 All-Australian as a potential midfield key. Smith says his defensive game must improve to join fellow half back Rory Laird in swinging through the midfield.

"I have tried every year to get through the midfield but that hasn't happened. Lairdy plays really well when he goes through there," said Smith.
"I have to be a good defensive player. When I have had poor games this year my defence has really dropped away which has resulted in goals against.
"The second half of the year has been really good for me. I was disappointing against Hawthorn and happy to turn that around."
Adelaide will almost certainly seal a top-two finish and home finals with a 22nd Showdown triumph. The Crows' dismantling of Geelong in round 18 offered a taste of the September pressure that will unfold on Sunday.
"We are in a great spot and in a really good position to give ourselves home finals, focus on Port," said Smith.
"It was finals like and we took a lot of confidence out of that. We need that intensity to win finals."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddy Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood's Jordan De Goey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Laird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio 5AA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lairdy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
