<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410686345542860</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/local-afl/ffa-cup-darwin-rovers-believe-they-can-upset-aleague-champions-sydney-fc/news-story/eb16a2b993bb09ff5ec49ab1c66fbaf8</url>
  <title>Rovers believe they can upset Sydney FC</title>
  <content>
SAM Rowley was deadly serious when he said his team of part-timers at Darwin Rovers can create football history at Darwin Football Stadium tonight.
Rowley and his teammates face the might of A-League champions Sydney FC in their FFA Cup Round of 32 clash.
Rank outsiders at 25-1 to beat Sydney, Rowley said the Rovers desperately wanted to write their names down in Australian football's history books.
"We're all confident going into the game, there's a brilliant mood among the players and as dedicated individuals we know we can win this game," he said.
"Absolutely we can win this game, we go into every match with the ambition and thought process that we can win it, even more so against a great side like Sydney."
Rowley is likely to mark Sky Blues marquee player Bobo in tonight's game, a task the lad from the Lakes District in northern England still cannot believe.
"I'll be working overtime for sure,'' he grinned. "It's a surreal experience for me having only been in Australia for five months and only because my friend Will asked me to come over and have a kick for the Rovers.
"Now I'm playing against Sydney FC and marking a class player in Bobo.
"You've really got to look at it as another player and another team, you can't let the occasion get to you and hopefully I won't.''
Rowley said the players had received a "mountain'' of support back home, to the point several pounds had been placed on a Rovers win.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Football Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARWIN Rovers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakes District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Blues</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rowley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup Round</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAM Rowley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
