<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411115842279138</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/national/public-service/calls-for-an-inquiry-as-10-further-ato-outages-revealed-20170802-gxnjvj.html</url>
  <title>'Blaming public servants not an option': 10 more ATO outages revealed </title>
  <content>
Labor has renewed calls for an inquiry into Australian Tax Office website failures after new data showed online systems collapsed 10 times in five months this year.
Information provided to a Senate committee, first reported by the ABC, revealed a further series of outages lasting between a few minutes and two business days.Photo: Andrew Meares
The log of serious outages does not include the major ATO meltdowns in December and July, which prompted widespread criticism and by the failures.
In February, the ATO's website, online portals, Australian Business Register and business reporting channels were unavailable for two business days, while a series of outages hit users on April 19 and four separate dates in May.Photo: Louise Kennerley
A further four outages hit in June, including a three-and-a-half-hour outage of all internal and external systems on June 22.
Officials told the committee the ATO had received 18 complaints about the failures since February, as well as seven letters or emails from tax professionals and taxpayers expressing a loss of confidence in ATO systems.

"The ATO is aware of the impact that our recent IT issues have had on our clients and we are committed to delivering systems that have minimal disruption to the community."

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"We manage a large and complex IT environment and given this complexity, we will occasionally encounter unplanned issues with our systems that result in a degradation, and in some cases outages, to our services.
"Our real-time monitoring aims to detect and resolve issues before they have an impact on the services that we provide to the community. The nature of these unplanned outages are varied and there is no single systemic or underlying cause of these issues," officials said.
Industry groups have called for compensation to accountants who have struggled with online failures during peak tax time.
Assistant Treasurer Kelly O'Dwyer, who has responsibility for the ATO, has been contacted for comment.
Labor's shadow assistant treasurer Andrew Leigh and spokesman for digital economy Ed Husic called for an explanation.
"The ATO is trying as hard as it can, but it's been left struggling thanks to staffing cuts by the Coalition," the pair said.
"Just last week we read reports that the Turnbull government is planning to continue with its cuts over the next three years, climbing to almost $30 million.
"Labor has repeatedly called for an investigation into these interruptions, but Malcolm Turnbull has team have done nothing to reassure the public. He needs to step up and ensure the Tax Office has the support it needs to do its job.
"When Australians are facing days and days of IT outages, blaming the public servants is not an option."
Last month the ATO launched an investigation into a significant failure of online systems which forced tax return systems offline at short notice.
A report on the major pre-Christmas outages .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Business Register</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Tax Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tax Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Leigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Kennerley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Husic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATO</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Treasurer Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
