<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411111547311804</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-02/iconic-vietnamese-sandwich-helps-drive-demand-for-wheat/8766388</url>
  <title>Humble sandwich increasing Aussie wheat exports to Vietnam</title>
  <content>
The iconic Vietnamese sandwich, banh mi, is helping drive demand for Australian wheat in the Asian nation.
Banh mi is a baguette-style sandwich commonly filled with chicken or pork as well as pate, coriander, cucumber, pickled carrot and chilli.
Demand for more westernised foods, such as breads and sandwiches, has seen Vietnam grow to become Australia's second largest export wheat destination.
Ten years ago, just 380,000 tonne of wheat was sent to Vietnam, compared to 1.5 million tonne now.
Proximity to market is bonus for Australia

Roslyn Jettner, from the Australian Export Grains Innovation Centre, said Vietnam was a very important trading partner.
"It's our second biggest market in both volume and also value," she said.

"I think Australian wheat has a very good reputation in that market place [and] there are a number of reasons for that.

"Of course, proximity to market - being able to access wheat directly from Australian ports in a very short period of time, so proximity is number one.
"But also, we're looking at attributes like low moisture of the grain which we have in Australia, the white bran or the white colour of the grain.
"We also have very high milling yields and that's principally because of the white bran as well, plus really good functionality of our wheat."
Changing dietary preferences in SE Asia

Ms Jettner said much of the increase in demand over the last decade had been due to changing diet preferences.
"In a lot of South-East Asian markets there has been an increase in consumption of wheat-based products," she said.
"Vietnam, like a number of other countries in the region, is primarily a rice eating nation but as people get more experienced in western style diets, we are seeing an increase in wheat-based products such as instant noodles and bread-style products.

"The number one bread product in Vietnam is banh mi [and] in Vietnam, about 30 to 35 per cent of wheat flour is used in that style of bread product."

However Ms Jettner said the Australian grains industry now had to focus on maintaining its market share.
"You need to know what your customer is using your product for," she said.
"So, why are they using Australian wheat, what are they using it for, what is the quality that is required to maintain their use in that and make sure we are competitive against other origins that may be coming into the market?
"There's no use producing a product that the market doesn't want; you need to ensure that they do want it, it's meeting their requirements and it's competitive.
"There's an indication of all South-East Asian markets growing in their wheat imports [and] I think Vietnam is a very strong wheat importing nation that we need to keep an eye on.
"But I think also, it's not just about growing the market, it's also containing the market so that they have a preference for Australian wheat over alternate origins".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnamese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SE Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-East Asian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roslyn Jettner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Export Grains Innovation Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jettner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
