<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409956201087928</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/basin-scheme-was-always-doomed-to-fail/3207475/</url>
  <title>Basin scheme was always doomed to fail</title>
  <content>
NOT all irrigators are thoughtless people, however, billions of litres of water has been purchased by taxpayers to save Australia's inland rivers - a $13 billion plan.
That sounds real Australian - wrong unfortunately - billions of litres used by some irrigators at the expense of others is more to the point.
Right or wrong, what are the limits to which some people will go and at the end of the day, for what?
The Murray-Darling basin facts: total of 23 river valleys, basin area over one million square kilometres (14% of  the Murray-Darling basin also includes over 30,000 wetlands - some of which are listed internationally for their importance to migratory birds).
It's on record, 90% of the basin's flood plains and wetlands is lost.
Irrigation pumping systems operated by a small group have prostituted the Murray-Darling river system for personal gain.
Pumps capable of extracting one billion litres in a single day from the darling river.
The flow of the river can be reversed. If that's not a wake-up, convince me otherwise.
Pumps have had the metering equipment tampered with so as not to record extraction quantities. Even in low flow periods where the licence calls for no pumping.
This stealing of the water far exceeded the requirements set out in the Murray-Darling basin plan.
The plan was to increase agricultural production and expand the economy of all regions.
Unfortunately the plan was ill-conceived from the onset and doomed to failure.
During the failing period, government records were offered to irrigation lobbyists to share confidential internal documents.
A bit like inside trading. Bloody disgrace In the southern regions and around Broken Hill, some graziers lost everything when they ran out of water.
Most thought it was the result of a prolonged drought.
Flushing a toilet in small settlements were monitored to save water.
Distraught graziers took their own lives.
In situations where having the law on your side, is no justification.
One would say, so un-Australian, a bloody disgrace.
For power and a few more bucks.
JEFF RUMBLE
Parrearra
Wife heard screaming on dashcam footage
NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JEFF RUMBLE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broken Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parrearra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
