<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410209604163812</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/lawyers-for-former-nt-police-commissioner-john-mcroberts-return-to-court/news-story/4ab4c4d89df0a0d09167f251f7ee508c</url>
  <title>'Fishing expedition' summons torn up</title>
  <content>
FORMER police commissioner John McRoberts's messy pre-trial court battle has become even messier with a judge tearing up a "fishing expedition" summons to produce documents served on former health department boss Len Notaras.
McRoberts has been charged with a single count of attempting to pervert the course of justice after allegedly attempting to "deflect" and "frustrate" a criminal investigation into crooked travel agent Xana Kamitsis's rorting of the pensioner travel concession scheme.
Committal proceedings in April stalled after barrister Tony Elliot, for McRoberts, said he would be unable to properly cross-examine a number of witnesses without summonsed documents. Mr Elliot and government lawyer Trevor Moses returned to court yesterday, where Judge John Neill excused former health department chief executive Notaras from complying with an overly broad summons to produce documents to Mr McRoberts.
Mr Moses said the summons, as it was worded, was "simply a fishing expedition".
"It's a prayer that there's something in there, that there's going to be something that's going to assist his defence," he said.
Mr Moses said a broad reference to "the investigation" on the summons should have specified which of the many investigations into the pensioner travel concession scheme Mr McRoberts was seeking documents related to.
With no specified time limit on the summons, bureaucrats would have the "monumental" task of going back through decades of government archives, Mr Moses said.
"The scheme has been in existence since the '70s, it's difficult to see how a complaint that was made in, say, 1985, could be of relevance to Mr McRoberts's defence," he said. Mr Elliot yesterday provided more specific details about the documents Mr McRoberts wanted produced. Mr Neill said: "Well, is saying it informally good enough? "I think we may have to be in the position to issue a fresh summons."
The legal argument case will continue today and tomorrow for more argument about summonses on government agencies and senior bureaucrats. The committal hearing continues in October, when Mr Neill will determine if McRoberts has a case to answer in the Supreme Court.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Moses</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Elliot</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McRoberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xana Kamitsis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Neill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Elliot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Len Notaras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Moses</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge John Neill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McRoberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McRoberts</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McRoberts</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Notaras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
