<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411068597637973</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/real-estate/residential/toorak-fight-is-a-warning-for-real-estate-agents-about-estimating-prices-20170801-gxn4b3</url>
  <title>'This is fair warning that a real estate agent must be very confident of the price they give'</title>
  <content>
John McMurrick's Monday meeting with Ross Savas was very different from the way they used to catch up.
The wealthy businessman and his former real estate agent used to spend their Saturday afternoons chatting over a beer at Mr McMurrick's home in St George's Road, the most prestigious street in Melbourne's most prestigious suburb of Toorak. 
This week's meeting in a mediation room, over a table and surrounded by lawyers at 436 Lonsdale Street in central Melbourne, was a world away from those casual days of February 2012. 
But the  did at least settle  in which Mr McMurrick accused Mr Savas and his agency Kay & Burton of misleading conduct. 

Terms of the settlement are not known - neither side would comment on the confidential arrangement but both maintained they were pleased with the outcome. And Justice Dixon was spared the task of pronouncing one man a liar. Mr McMurrick said Mr Savas told him he could get between $7.5 million and $8 million if he bought and renovated another Toorak mansion a stone's throw away at 46 Canberra Road, while Mr Savas maintained he only estimated a price of between $6 million and $6.5 million. 

The two had previously talked over many such projects. In 2007, for example, Mr Savas managed the $9.65 million Toorak sale to former ANZ chief Mike Smith of the . 
But now, all goodwill had evaporated with the relationship and the two sides were playing a high-stakes game.
"It would seem there will be a clear winner and clear loser at the end of the day," Justice Dixon said. "I would urge careful evaluation of the risks that are involved in proceeding with the case."
But even without a precedent-setting legal judgment that makes agents accountable for the price opinions they give clients, the case that opened and closed in one day will make agents more cautious about what they promise. 

Real Estate Institute of Victoria president Joseph Walton declined to comment on the case. Real Estate Institute of NSW president Malcolm Gunning said, however, that even the settled case would alter agents' behaviour. 
"This is fair warning that a real estate agent must be very confident of the price they give," Mr Gunning said. "You are going to be held accountable. Before, it's been a bit loose, but this is fair warning that the accountability is starting to mount as far as that opinion is concerned."
Mr Savas was certainly going to be tested. In his opening address on Monday, Mr McMurrick's barrister Michael Osborne QC told the court of a sale authority document by which Mr McMurrick engaged Mr Savas as the exclusive sales agent for the renovated house. That document listed the expected sale price as between $7 million and $7.7 million, Osborne said. 
While not as high as Mr McMurrick claimed Mr Savas had estimated, it was well above Mr Savas' argument of $6 million to $6.5 million, Mr Osborne said. 

"McMurrick says that when he saw the $7 million to $7.7 million [figure] he discussed it with Ross Savas and asked why it was not $7.5 million to $8 million and Mr Savas said words to the effect of 'We don't want to scare buyers off'," Mr Osborne told the court. 
Mr Savas's barrister, Peter Cawthorn QC, said the listed price range was evidence that McMurrick's argument was faulty.
"You'd expect if Mr McMurrick is correct, he would have insisted on the amount of $7.5 million to $8 million be included in that document," he responded.
Obvious incentive

There's an obvious incentive for agents to promise would-be clients a higher sale price. 
"Price is often the gateway to the appointment," said Shannan Whitney, a director of Sydney agency BresicWhitney. "There's less focus on perhaps what a sensible estimation is and more focus on what's available to me in terms of securing this appointment? As a mechanism, price is the most seductive and most powerful way to improve one's chances."
Mr Whitney should know. He heads an agency that was . BresicWhitney won when , but Mr Whitney said the prosecution was a "silver lining" that helped change a culture of practices the firm had already identified as a problem and that it has overhauled the procedures by which its agents estimate prices and communicate those prices to the public. 
In a rapidly disrupted real estate industry,  and cut-price offerings  it has never faced before. Even without court cases shining a light into decision-making processes, the traditional industry has to clean up its act to compete against disrupters such as , Mr Whitney said.

"New service providers and new ways of doing business [are] simply responding to a disenfranchised public," he said. "It makes complete sense."
Without offering clients a service that they can trust and can rely upon, the traditional industry won't be able to compete with the disrupters and in the long run will continue to lose business, Mr Whitney said. 
Kay & Burton's insurers, who were running the defence against , would have constantly been evaluating the risks of their position, said Mr Gunning, himself a valuer and an expert witness. 
"The insurers use skilled barristers," he said. "They know after the first day what the evidence is going to look like from both sides and then you'd weigh up - and if you're an experienced silk you're going to know at that stage what your chances are of winning this case."
They certainly would have needed to be confident of their position to keep going.
"A real estate agent in a box is never a great witness," said Melbourne buyers advocate David Morrell. 
And the potential losses for such an insurer - if a precedent was set that resulted in more real estate agent clients being hauled into court - could be substantial. 
"The agent's only reputationally exposed but the insurance company has the financial risk," Mr Morrell said. "That risk could be huge."

It was in the insurer's interest to settle the matter in that room on Level Six of the Supreme Court's mediation centre. 
"The longer it gets oxygen, the more somebody goes 'If he can do it, I will do it'," Mr Morrell said. "They've just tried to get the oxygen out, put the fire out before it gets into a bushfire."
The Australian Financial Review was seeking contact with Kay & Burton's insurer on Wednesday.
But the issue hasn't disappeared completely. This case did not go the full distance, but the pressure on real estate agents to build up their single biggest defence to disruption - trust - is growing. 
And it's only a matter of time before another unhappy client with the persistence and resources of Mr McMurrick takes their real estate agent to court, Mr Morrell said.
"Someone will do it," he said. "Someone will go the whole distance because they're so vexed."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Walton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McMurrick's Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estate Institute of Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George's Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gunning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Level Six of the Supreme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Savas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Morrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toorak</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Savas</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannan Whitney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Osborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Cawthorn QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BresicWhitney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McMurrick</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Dixon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Savas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estate Institute of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Osborne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Osborne QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonsdale Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Gunning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McMurrick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
