<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410995583192721</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-02/red-and-black-set-to-turn-to-green</url>
  <title>Red and black likely to turn to Green</title>
  <content>
Josh Green is likely to return for the Bombers against Carlton

ESSENDON small forward Josh Green looks set to return for the Bombers' clash with Carlton on Saturday after overcoming his hamstring injury.

The former Brisbane Lions goalkicker has missed the past two weeks with the strain, and could return to ensure the Bombers take on the Blues with their band of small forwards back together.

"He's available to go. He's flying on the track, so he's a big chance to come in," coach John Worsfold said on Wednesday.

Green has kicked 15 goals in 14 games at Essendon since joining the club as a delisted free agent at the end of last year.

The match looms as an important one for the Bombers, who squandered a chance to consolidate their place in their top eight by losing to the Western Bulldogs last week.

They may also have Patrick Ambrose back for the contest, who hasn't played at senior level since round five against Collingwood.

The versatile defender had a strong start to the season before back-to-back quad tears at training ruined his campaign, but Worsfold said the tough and disciplined Bomber was ready for a call-up after a handful of games at VFL level.

"We'll look at Patty. He was in such good form earlier in the year for us and he's worked unbelievably hard to have himself in the position where he's available to come back in the side. He's definitely due for us to have a good look at him," he said.

The Bombers' exciting forward line has been lauded this season, but they have leaked goals at different periods, conceding on average 92 points a game (the sixth-worst in the competition). They have scored better than previous years, however, averaging 99 points.

Worsfold acknowledged it was an area they needed to focus on in the final four rounds of the home and away season as they retained their hope of reaching the finals.   

"We didn't play our best [last week] and there were certainly parts of our game that weren't at the level we needed them to be. If you do that then teams are a chance to beat you," he said.

"We would like to be better defensively, so that's an area we need to work on."

Former captain Jobe Watson struggled against the Dogs with several key turnovers proving costly in the tight game, but Worsfold said club and player were yet to discuss the veteran midfielder's future.

However, a call could come before the end of the season on 31-year-old Brent Stanton, who is out of contract and hasn't played at senior level since round 11.

"It's possible, if we come to a decision before the end of the season. And that will just be on-going discussions with Brent and how he's feeling and where we're at.

"We'll be really open and honest about what his role may be at the club next year, and how he's feeling. If we get to that decision before the end of the season we'll certainly announce that, but I can't say that will happen."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent Stanton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Worsfold</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Ambrose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Green</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Worsfold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
