<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410909683845560</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/aurizons-shock-move-to-bring-in-foreign-train-driv/3207797/</url>
  <title>Aurizon's shock move to bring in foreign train drivers</title>
  <content>
AURIZON could bring foreign train drivers to Australia, new Federal Government documents have revealed.

Aurizon's Western Australian subsidiary, Australia Western Railroad Pty Ltd, has been included in a list of new labour agreements released after calls for transparency of the visa system.

SBS is reporting that foreign workers could be offered permanent residency as part of the agreement.

Company-specific agreements can be made on a case-by-case basis where a "genuine skills or labour shortage for an occupation exists" and cannot be filled by Australian workers or other migration arrangements.

"Employers are required to have made recent, genuine efforts to recruit, employ or engage Australian citizens or Australian permanent residents," the government's website states.

Train drivers are not on the Federal Government's list of eligible skilled occupations for 457 visas.

It comes after Aurizon announced in June it would close its Rockhampton rollingstock workshop resulting in the loss of 181 jobs.

Another 126 workers are expected to lose their jobs at Bluff, Gladstone and Stanwell, including train drivers.

The Morning Bulletin has contacted Aurizon for comment.

Baby whale rescued on the Sunshine Coast
Up to $214,000 remains on table for refocused investigation
'Teen fed burning hot sauce, punched in face and stomach'
AT Nambour State School, many pupils came to school by train.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurizon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morning Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurizon's Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Western Railroad Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
