<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411163086920097</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/changes-to-rooming-house-regulations-are-no-win-for-casey-residents-say/news-story/27afb5436209c66aa7d9c46a34741556</url>
  <title>'Ridiculous' rooming house laws hit Casey</title>
  <content>
ANGRY residents and Casey Council say the State Government has failed to regulate the booming rooming-house industry.
The council will oppose Planning Minster Richard Wynne's proposed reforms to public and shared housing, which include a permit exemption for people wanting to build rooming houses with up to eight bedrooms.
Brookland Greens resident Suzanne Vrdoljak slammed the proposal, saying neighbours deserved better protection against rooming houses in their streets. Ms Vrdoljak was one of about 800 people who campaigned against two 10-place shared houses on the corner of Cherryhills Drive, Cranbourne after the council said it was "powerless" to stop them last year.
The furore that erupted prompted the Andrews Government to fix a loophole so new rooming houses in residential zones were required to go through a proper planning process.
But Ms Vrdoljak said the latest changes left residents even more exposed.
Ms Vrdoljak said neighbours had only found out about the Brookland Greens rooming houses "by accident" and the only reason they had not been built was because the owner changed his mind and sold the land to someone else.
"It's ridiculous that somebody can build something like that in a residential area and for the neighbours to have no say, no knowledge," she said.
"That type of establishment can bring unruly people into your community; drug addicts, ex-prisoners. Neighbours have a right to be consulted. There needs to be greater protections in place for residential communities."

Casey statutory planning and building manager Nicola Ward said Mr Wynne's proposal did not address Casey's concerns. "A threshold of six bedrooms is considered to be more appropriate and reflective of a domestic scale, being little more than a large family dwelling," she said.
There are more than 40 registered rooming houses in the City of Casey.

Patrick Lane, spokesman for Mr Wynne, said rooming houses provided a safe place for vulnerable Victorians when they needed it most.
"These important facilities have long been exempt from permit requirements because of the crucial role they play protecting people experiencing hardship or crisis, such as victims of family violence," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherryhills Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicola Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brookland Greens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wynne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrews Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CITY of Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Minster Richard Wynne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Vrdoljak</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzanne Vrdoljak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
