<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411158791952669</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/accounting/remaining-cpa-board-to-appear-before-senate-committee-20160831-gr5lax</url>
  <title>Remaining CPA board to appear before Senate committee</title>
  <content>
The remaining board of CPA Australia will be called to appear before a Senate committee to explain their actions .
The decision was made after a CPA representative said the board and management had decided it wasn't in the best interest of members to send out an email calling for a spill of the current board on behalf of .
The issue arose during a public hearing into updating the Corporations Act to compel companies to provide the email addresses of their membership base to members who ask for it.
That bill, , arose out of a battle by rebel CPA member  his concerns about the way CPA was being run.

DEAN LEWINS

At the hearing, the CPA representative was asked why an email couldn't have been sent out on the past leaders' behalf to deal with privacy concerns over releasing the list of member emails.

The request, made in June, was never acted upon by the board of the CPA. The organisation has seen seven directors resign and CEO Alex Malley fired with a $4.9 million payment in the past two months.
CPA spokesman Stuart Dignam said the decision to not send out the message had been made by the board.
"I'm aware of the correspondence to which you refer, Senator. The board and the management of CPA don't believe that an entire spill is in the best interest of the members," he said.
Mr Xenophon then asked if CPA members, not the CPA board and management, should have made that decision, and then accused CPA of censorship.

Mr Dignam replied: "It wasn't a censoring, Senator."
Mr Xenophon and senator Sam Dastyari then continued to question Mr Dignam on why the message wasn't sent out.
Mr Dignam said that he wasn't able to answer the question and that it had been a decision by the board.
Earlier, rebel CPA member Brett Stevenson told fhe hearing that the CPA "deliberately oppressed" the ability of members to communicate with each other and that most members were still unaware of the slow-moving implosion of the accounting body.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Dignam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Xenophon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporations Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dastyari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dignam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Stevenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Alex Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Lewins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
