<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409956201088025</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/elderly-on-mobility-scooters-endangered-by-obstacl/3207432/</url>
  <title>Elderly on mobility scooters endangered by obstacles</title>
  <content>
SIPPY Downs has a large number of elderly residents, many with mobility scooters as their sole means of transport.
Therefore it is surprising Sunshine Coast Council installs incomplete infrastructure that leads to the elderly being endangered.
Either end of Oxford Close in Sippy Downs provides great examples of this problem.
Footpath crossings allow the elderly to cross University Way but lead to a footpath that stops 20 metres short of Oxford Close, forcing elderly to navigate onto the busy road.
At the other end of Oxford Close, the footpath leading to Sippy Downs Dr has obstruction bars to be navigated around, forcing the elderly off the pathway onto bumpy, slippery, inclined grass.
Council could easily fix these dangerous obstacles, preferring a 'no news is good news' approach.
Unfortunately, this means an accident must occur before the council will support the elderly who use mobility scooters.
RODNEY LOVELL
Kuluin
Wife heard screaming on dashcam footage
NAPLAN results are improving but there is still a major problem
Nine people from the Sunshine Coast region are listed as missing
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
LOCAL radio station a constant on the Coast.
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
What your money will get you in the Beef Cap v the capital city:
Prime block lays dormant for decade in Coast town
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford Close</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kuluin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RODNEY LOVELL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beef Cap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
