<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410853849269860</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/fremantle-dockers/exdocker-shane-yarran-pleads-guilty-to-wa-police-chase-20170802-gxnjog.html</url>
  <title>Ex-Docker Shane Yarran pleads guilty to WA police chase</title>
  <content>
Former Fremantle Dockers footballer Shane Yarran has pleaded guilty to a string of offences relating to a police chase, but denies stabbing a man outside a pub with a broken bottle.
The 27-year-old has been behind bars since May 24 when he reached 125km/h in a 60km/h zone during an early morning police pursuit in the Perth suburb of Gosnells.Photo: Matt Roberts/AFL Media
Police say they chased him through several streets by car and then on foot after he jumped out of the moving vehicle, allowing it to roll across four lanes of traffic.
Yarran then hid in bushes in the front yard of a home before being found by police dog Nacho.
He pleaded guilty in Perth Magistrates Court via videolink from Hakea remand prison on Tuesday to nine offences, including reckless driving to escape pursuit by police, disorderly behaviour and speeding.
Yarran also admitted breaching a violence restraining order secured by his ex- partner.

He will be sentenced on August 21 and told the court he wanted to be there in person.
Yarran also pleaded not guilty to unlawful wounding, a charge that was laid after he allegedly attacked a man with a broken bottle outside the Westfield Tavern in Camillo in July 2015.
Police prosecutors previously told the court the incident began with an altercation involving several people, then Yarran approached the victim from behind as he walked to a friend's car and stabbed him with the bottle in the right shoulder and back.
Defence lawyer Luka Margaretic told the court in June the victim was "opportunistic" as he didn't immediately report the matter to police and it wasn't until December 2015 that Yarran was arrested, after he had been drafted to the AFL club.
A date for a three-day trial is expected to be set when the matter returns to court on October 31 but is not expected to be heard until next year.
- AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westfield Tavern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nachos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-Docker Shane Yarran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hakea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camillo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Yarran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luka Margaretic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarran</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosnells.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Roberts/AFL Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
