<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410338453185204</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/celebrity-news/summer-phoenix-files-for-divorce-from-casey-affleck-20170801-gxnh8w.html</url>
  <title>Summer Phoenix files for divorce from Casey Affleck</title>
  <content>
After 11 years of marriage, Summer Phoenix has filed for divorce from Casey Affleck.
Phoenix, 38, cited irreconcilable differences as the reason for the filing.Photo: Getty
The actress and designer is seeking spousal support from Affleck, 41, as well as joint custody of their sons Indiana, 13, and Atticus, 9.
The filing comes one year after the pair . 
"Casey and Summer have amicably separated," Casey's rep told Page Six at the time. "They remain very close friends."
Following the news, Casey Affleck went on to win an Academy Award win for his role in Manchester By The Sea and faced a number of sexual harassment allegations.

The allegations  on the set of mockumentary I'm Still Here in 2009.
"I believe that any kind of mistreatment of anyone for any reason is unacceptable and abhorrent, and everyone deserves to be treated with respect in the workplace and anywhere else," Affleck "wearily" told the Boston Globe earlier this year of the claims that were settled out of court in 2010.
"There's really nothing I can do about it, other than live my life the way I know I live it and to speak to what my own values are and how I try to live by them all the time."
Phoenix is the sister of River and Joaquin Phoenix, who introduced her to Affleck after starring with his brother Ben in the 1995 film To Die For. After an on and off relationship, the pair married in 2006.
In a 2013 interview with The Daily Beast, Affleck said of their meeting: "She was going out with someone else and I said, 'Man, she's cute,' and [Joaquin] said, 'You should see if she'll go out with you... don't worry about that dude'.
"So he was leaving town one day and said, 'My sister's in my apartment and she's all by herself-would you mind checking in on her?' So I checked in on her, and it stuck."
The pair, both devoted vegans who worked with PETA to promote animal rights, made their last public appearance together in 2014.
Fairfax Media
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indiana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Still Here</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Page Six</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joaquin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Affleck</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joaquin Phoenix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey Affleck</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester By</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOENIX</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atticus, 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Beast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston Globe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Die For</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
