<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411163086920037</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/boss/book-review-the-gamekeeper-20170718-gxdic2</url>
  <title>Busting the gamekeeper boys' club</title>
  <content>
Portia Simpson was one of those children who was always outdoors, up a tree, collecting insects or racing snails. As a teenager in Stonehaven, an old fishing village across the River Dee from Aberdeen, Scotland, the other girls were preoccupied with fashion, music and boys while Simpson was hunting for birds' nests or building shelters of bracken. She didn't grow up with a burning desire to be a gamekeeper.
Fast-forward a few years: as ghillie, she took a client to a remote hillside in the Outer Hebrides where he shot an eight-pointer stag. She gralloched - disembowelled - the beast, removing the stomach and intestines setting them aside, steaming, in the heather and wiped the blood from her arms with a handful of damp sphagnum moss. She dragged the animal down the hill and lifted it onto the back of a hill pony.
Simpson wasn't the first female in the role, but she was the first to graduate as a qualified gamekeeper and wildlife manager. This is an intimate account of how she broke into a conservative and male-dominated profession.
As a woman in a man's world, Simpson was always conspicuous. On her first day at North Highland College in Thurso, one or two "Neanderthals" wolf-whistled and one guy declared to the class: "Women shouldn't be doing this course." She thought, "You absolute bastard, I'm going to get you back for that." She did ...

On a placement at Ardverikie, a 16,000-hectare estate in the shadow of Ben Nevis, she encountered a film crew making the television series Monarch of the Glen. The scriptwriters asked to interview her. In a later episode, a character called Jessica was introduced. She was given the cold shoulder by her male estate co-workers. It was not the experience of Simpson, who was accepted and popular.

The country shooting and fishing magazine The Field asked for an interview. They didn't want her in her ripped and bloodied tweeds. The magazine sent long leather boots, tight moleskin trousers, shirt and leather waistcoat.
"Unwrapping it all, I figured I would be one sexy gamekeeper." After the photo shoot she expected a small pic and inside article. She was front cover. One foot on a rock, rifle over her shoulder and gundog at her feet. The coverline: Move over Mellors [Lady Chatterley's Lover]: the rise and rise of the girl gamekeeper.
Despite the blood and the guts, she wasn't about to abandon her femininity. At a lodge on an estate so remote she was helicoptered in, there were no modern conveniences.
"The only problem was not having electricity for my hair straighteners; even in one of the most remote parts of the Highlands, I couldn't possibly go deer-stalking without having straightened my hair first!" Luckily, gas-powered irons saved the day.

Reading The Gamekeeper inspires a desire to walk the moors and sit beside the lochs of the . It is also an entertaining insight into how one woman overcame prejudice to pursue her chosen career.
The Gamekeeper by Portia Simpson,Simon & Schuster.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portia Simpson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mellor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monarch of the Glen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aberdeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stonehaven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outer Hebrides</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schuster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Chatterley's Lover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neanderthal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Dee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Highland College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ardverikie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Nevis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
