<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410772244890272</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/wa-sport/eagles-coach-simpson-stays-mum-as-priddis-remains-on-outer-for-saints-20170802-gxnj6p.html</url>
  <title>Eagles coach Simpson stays mum as Priddis remains on outer for Saints</title>
  <content>
West Coast coach Adam Simpson has refused to guarantee a recall to retiring Brownlow medallist Matt Priddis for Sunday's big clash with St Kilda in Melbourne.
Rising doubts over the star ball-winner resuming further fuels speculation that Priddis was  as Simpson overhauls his ageing midfield and West Coast drif from premiership calculations.Photo: Scott Barbour
Priddis, 32, stunned AFL circles last week when he announced he will retire at the end of this season, despite having a contract for 2018.
The accomplished ball magnet, who averages around 26 possessions a game this season, was left out of the Eagles team that went on to a comfortable 11-goal win over bottom outfit Brisbane.
Simpson said Priddis was suffering a thigh strain.
The durable follower has played 84 of a possible 88 games under Simpson since the start of 2014 and has missed just 16 outings over the past decade in his 235-game career.

Priddis trained with his Eagles teammates in Perth on Tuesday, after Simpson declared in his weekly Channel Seven interview the popular on-baller was "touch and go" for selection to confront that Saints in a crucial showdown that will help shape this season's final top eight.
"We'll see how he goes with that quaddy," Simpson said.
"We will have to see how he pulls up this week."
Simpson refused to elaborate on the extent of what is understood to have been blunt discussions with Priddis last week that led to his decision to end his playing days.
Priddis is understood to have been unwilling to accept heading back to West Coast alignment team East Perth as Simpson continues a now highly-public transition of the Eagles squad headed for a major makeover at the end of the season.
Hawthorn import Sam Mitchell is expected to announce his retirement from the AFL on Wednesday after just one season with West Coast.
"I think it's almost disrespectful to talk about Pridda. Let's just celebrate the fact he's had a wonderful career," Simpson said.
"He made a really brave decision last week.
"Let him play out the year and give him some space."
Simpson did not rule out recalls to inconsistent veterans Chris Masten and Sharron Wellingham after impressive outings from both with East Perth.
The Eagles will also monitor a mounting calf strain complaint for another struggling midfielder Lewis Jetta.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Masten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharron Wellingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Jetta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saints</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Barbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pridda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simpsons</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
