<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411025647964372</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/news/veteran-grocer-sculli-brothers-to-headline-fresh-food-precinct-at-greensborough-plaza/news-story/0b52282041b712f95bbca2625d8d60d8</url>
  <title>Fresh start for green grocer in the valley</title>
  <content>
A VIBRANT fresh food precinct will be launched at the heart of Greensborough Plaza.
Veteran grocer Sculli Brothers will take centre stage in JB Hi Fi's former shop as the shopping centre reveals stage three of its redevelopment.
Seoul Kitchen, Sushi Hub, Bonbons Bakery and Boost Juice will also be part of the new Village Green precinct.
Sculli Brothers first opened its doors on Main St Greensborough in 1960 before moving into the shopping complex during the 1990s and changing its name to Growers.
It will now revert back to its original name when it moves into the fresh food precinct.
Co-owner Andrew Sculli believes they've lasted the test of time due to quality produce and supporting the community by sponsoring sports clubs or worthy causes.
"We speak to growers on a daily basis and where possible we try to source Australian produce for our customers so that we are offering everyday market freshness," Mr Sculli said.
Centre manager Isaac Tait said the demand for healthy food options has increased in the past three years and they've tried to cater for that change.
The shopping centre's transformation kicked off in 2015 with the launch of the Kids on the Green before the urban style casual dining precinct, Tables on the Green, was rolled out a year later.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isaac Tait</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sculli Brothers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co-owner Andrew Sculli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greensborough Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Village Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bonbons Bakery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JB Hi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seoul Kitchen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sculli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boost Juice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main St Greensborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sushi Hub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
