<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410609036130149</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/family-distraught-after-cat-found-with-legs-severe/3207696/</url>
  <title>Family distraught after cat found with legs severed</title>
  <content>
A FAMILY has been traumatised by the death of their young cat, after the kitten was found with both front legs severed.

Sarah Mistelhorn's 9-year-old son found Lucy underneath their Stanwell home, in agony and with both front legs missing.

Too distraught to speak yesterday, Sarah's friend Skye Hanley told The Morning Bulletin the 9-month-old kitten was euthanised by a vet due to the severity of the injuries.

Skye said there was no blood trail on the property and no trace of the missing limbs.

She said the family was concerned when Lucy wasn't home on Sunday night as the cat spent the majority of her time inside and had been home Sunday morning.

They could not have imagined the horrific scene which awaited them Monday afternoon.

The family were told Lucy's injuries were possibly over 12 hours old, adding to her suffering.

"It's a horrible, horrible thing that has happened," Skye said.

"She was beautiful. She was just so friendly.

"She was black and white and had little socks on her feet.

"Her and Tibby (the family's second, older cat) just loved each other and played all the time. She was just lovely with all the kids."

The family are concerned Lucy may have been injured in a trap.

Steel jaw traps are illegal in Queensland, as they cause extreme pain and suffering to animals.

The incident was reported to the RSPCA, which will investigate further to find if an illegal trap was responsible.

Baby whale rescued on the Sunshine Coast
Up to $214,000 remains on table for refocused investigation
Tensions simmered over in restaurant hygiene dispute.
TEACHING at Nambour in the 1950s.
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skye</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skye Hanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morning Bulletin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tibby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
