<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410252553837693</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/asia/donald-trump-ready-for-war-with-north-korea-senator-says/news-story/5c74cfc9a1db51f99c2c0fabc0ac5ca4</url>
  <title>Donald Trump ready for war with North Korea, senator says</title>
  <content>
US senator says Trump ready for war with North Korea
0:31

9 News: Republican senator  Lindsey Graham says US President Donald Trump has told him he would go to war to destroy North Korea rather than allow it to develop a long-range nuclear-armed missile.

August 2nd 2017
an hour ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

North Korea launched a Hwasong-14 intercontinental ballistic missile, ICBM, on July 4, the first of two last month. Picture: Korean Central News Agency/Korea News Service/AP

AFP, Reuters

Share

DONALD Trump would rather go to war to destroy North Korea than allow it to develop a long-range nuclear-armed missile.
Influential Republican and foreign policy expert Lindsey Graham told NBC's Today Show the President had told him so himself and warned patience with the rogue state was running thin.
"There is a military option: To destroy North Korea's program and North Korea itself," he said.
Just this week, North Korean leader Kim Jong-un boasted that his country could now strike any target in the United States after carrying out its latest intercontinental ballistic missile test.

Republican Senator Lindsey Graham said Donald Trump has told him he would go to war to destroy North Korea rather than allow it to develop a long-range nuclear-armed missile. Picture: Brendan Smialowski/AFPSource:AFP
World powers have been trying to stifle Pyongyang's weapons program through United Nations-backed sanctions, but have failed to daunt the regime and Washington is growing frustrated.
Mr Graham said that if diplomacy, and in particular pressure from the North's neighbour China, fails to halt the program then the United States will have no choice but to take devastating military action.
"They've kicked the can down the road for 20 years. There will be a war with North Korea over the missile program if they continue to try to hit America with an ICBM," he said, describing his discussions with Mr Trump.
"He's told me that. I believe him. If I were China, I would believe him, too, and do something about it. You can stop North Korea, militarily or diplomatically.

US President Donald Trump said he would handle North Korea. Picture: APSource:AP
"I prefer the diplomatic approach. But they will not be allowed to have a missile to hit America with a nuclear weapon on top."

It come as Mr Trump told reporters at his second full Cabinet meeting that he would handle North Korea.
"We will handle North Korea. We are gonna be able to handle them. It will be handled. We handle everything," Mr Trump said.
The tough war of words is in stark comparison to Secretary of State Rex Tillerson who said the US doesn't want to topple the North Korean government.
"We do not seek a regime change, we do not seek a collapse of the regime, we do not seek an accelerated reunification of the peninsula, we do not seek an excuse to send our military north of the 38th Parallel," Mr Tillerson told reporters at the State Department.
"We are not your enemy ... but you are presenting an unacceptable threat to us, and we have to respond.
"And we hope that at some point they will begin to understand that and we would like to sit and have a dialogue with them."

US Secretary of State Rex Tillerson said the United States is not trying to topple Kim Jong-un's regime, but warned it must halt its nuclear missile program Picture: Paul J Richards/AFPSource:AFP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean Central News Agency/Korea News Service/AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>APSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul J Richards/AFPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindsey Graham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hwasong-14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Senator Lindsey Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations-backed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Smialowski/AFPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC's Today Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICBM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
