<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410776539857600</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/work-begins-on-114m-rebuild-of-braybrooks-aeroplane-park-after-it-was-destroyed-in-arson-attack/news-story/65c315b3f117528b9a080525a5e3023d</url>
  <title>Playground to fly again</title>
  <content>
CONSTRUCTION has begun to raise Braybrook's beloved Aeroplane Park from the ashes.
An arson attack just days before Christmas in 2015 burnt the popular playground to the ground and Maribyrnong Council is hopeful the new playground will be open before summer.
The new playground will keep the flight theme of the original playground and the council hopes the $1.14 million project will become a regional destination and a place for the community to come together.
Maribyrnong Mayor Catherine Cumming said the destruction of the original playground, which featured a large wooden aeroplane, was "truly tragic".
"It clearly held such a special place in the hearts of so many, including myself," she said.
"Over the last few months we've been liaising with the local community and working hard on plans to rebuild the playground and are thrilled that construction on this amazing new park has commenced.
"We are confident this new park will provide a stunning focal point for the local community; a place to come together to play, socialise and create memories."
Footscray designer BiGfiSh, which designed the original wooden aeroplane structure that was destroyed in the fire, has been commissioned to design and create key elements of the new steel aeroplane structure.
BiGfiSh's Chris Goff said his company set out to design a "unique and iconic" playground.
"Over the last few weeks we have been working on bringing the enormous metal wings to life and are thrilled with how they are coming together,"
Mr Goff said.
"It's been a lot like building a giant model aeroplane."
Along with the new playground, the rebuilt park will include exercise equipment, open lawn areas, a scooter and trike track, an upgraded community garden and a picnic area.
The State Government pitched in $205,000 to help rebuild the park.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braybrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Goff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maribyrnong Mayor Catherine Cumming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aeroplane Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footscray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maribyrnong Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BiGfiSh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BiGfiSh's Chris Goff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
