<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410561791489109</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/a-league/ffa-cup-mariners-boss-paul-okon-hails-preseason-clean-sheets-as-big-test-looms-against-blacktown-city/news-story/58d63796427a064bc5439ca5220fb658</url>
  <title>Mariners pre-season excellence faces big test</title>
  <content>
A YEAR ago the Mariners crashed out of the FFA Cup in a manner that cost the-then coach Tony Walmsley his job.
Now it's a measure of the new standards being demanded by Paul Okon that the Central Coast boss has one specific target for his team.
Okon's heavily remodelled Mariners travel to Blacktown City on Wednesday night for a round of 32 cup tie that could offer the same potential for embarrassment as their defeat to Green Gully 12 months ago.
But not only is Okon "curious" to see how his side copes with the pressure of being the favourites in a game for once, he wants one particular record maintained.
DARWIN HOPES:
So far the Mariners have played four games and won three in pre-season. However, the statistic Okon cares about is the zero goals conceded.
From a side averaging the concession of more than two a game for the past three years, that's a small but important start.
"We've had three wins and a draw in pre-season," Okon said.
"Results aren't important at this stage but we still haven't conceded a goal, which at this point is unheard of for us after 170-odd goals in three seasons, and more than 70 of them last season.
"It's an area where we know, if we're to be taken seriously, we have to improve on. We believe we're on that way, and we hope to continue towards that in the FFA Cup.
"There's only one cup competition, and it guarantees you - if you stay in it - more games to play. One of the issues is trying to find games to play in pre-season if you go out of the cup. So it's a step in the direction of where we want to go, and there's a little bit of expectation on us. I'm curious to see how we go with that."
Many of Okon's new signings will feature, including the likes of Tom Hiariej, Anthony Golec and Andrew Hoole, though Spanish striker Asdrubal won't be rushed into action as he plays catch up in terms of pre-season training.
Though the squad appears to have a stronger emphasis on experience, Okon was keen to emphasise that he retains a core of young Australians.
"We haven't replaced a young player with an older player," he said.
"We've still got six boys born 1997 or 1998 - when I was coming through as a young player, to have senior guys around me made me learn so much. I'm sure our younger boys will really appreciate the chance to play and train alongside not just experienced players but good professionals."
Mariners fans who make the trip should also get at least some sight of Daniel De Silva, the teen prodigy whom Okon hopes will become his No 10 after returning from abortive attempts to earn his stripes in Europe.
Okon confirmed De Silva's registration has been processed, after questions were asked about the apparent interest in him held by Italian club Roma.
"I didn't quite understand the noise around that," Okon said.
"I was always of the understanding that there were no issues, and in the end there weren't any. Daniel's available for selection; he's worked incredibly hard in recent months and though he's not at full 90 minute fitness, he's itching to get minutes.
"Whether that's from the start or off the bench we'll see, but at some stage hopefully we'll get to see him."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Walmsley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Gully 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okon</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blacktown City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asdrubal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Hoole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Hiariej</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Golec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Okon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariners</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARWIN HOPES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel De Silva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Silva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
