<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410733590183948</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/reignite-your-soul-at-the-next-peregian-originals/3207757/</url>
  <title>Reignite your soul at the next Peregian Originals</title>
  <content>
THE Hanlon Brothers - one of Queensland's finest soul, funk and reggae outfits - will headline the next Peregian Originals on Sunday, August 13.
The six-piece act from Burleigh Heads will round out an afternoon of super-talented musicians.
The Sunshine Coast's own Andrea Kirwin will be in fine form, bringing five supporting members to the stage.
Sydney touring act Billy Fox and the Coast's Favourite Son also feature on the afternoon program.
The four live acts will be at Peregian Beach Park from 1-5pm for the all-ages, family-friendly concert.
Peregian Originals is held on the second Sunday of every month, hosted by the not-for-profit group The East Coast Originals.
The East Coast Originals runs a number of live music events in small communities to support, nurture and develop the local arts and music scene.
Each Originals event depends heavily on the contribution of the local community through financial contributions, donations, volunteering of time and services and through active participation. I
f you would like to be a part of the Originals, visit
Baby whale rescued on the Sunshine Coast
Up to $214,000 remains on table for refocused investigation
Tensions simmered over in restaurant hygiene dispute.
AT Nambour State School, many pupils came to school by train.
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Maleny open day throws spotlight on theatre groups
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Social media erupted after she stepped out in the see-through top
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Kirwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Fox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanlon Brothers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Coast Originals</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burleigh Heads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Beach Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's Favourite Son</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
