<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410725000249201</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826499/warillas-flag-mission/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Warilla's on state grade one pennants finals mission</title>
  <content>
On target: Leif Selby will be in action for Warilla at the state pennants finals this weekend.

After 12 years between state titles, Warilla's former international Leif Selby is optimistic about avoiding another long wait.
Selby believes the pennants finalists have the ability to defend the crown they won last year, starting at St Johns Park and Cabra Vale bowling clubs on Friday.
One of four members who were part of their previous triumph in 2004, it was a nod to rivals Taren Point's ability to recently win three grade one finals in a row that makes him believe in their own cause.

"It's a long road to get there, but we believe we can do it," he said. "It would be huge for the club to win it two years in a row, it would be a great achievement. We've just got to get it right on the weekend, hopefully we can start well and go from there."

Warilla are drawn in Section Four, to play Port (Macquarie) City, Kingscliffe Beach and Maitland City.
Zone 16 counterparts Dapto Citizens will meet Raymond Terrace, Mt Lewis (Sydney) and Halekulani (Central Coast).
Wayne Crane, Erin Smith and Ted Clarke are the other three players from 2004 who captured the pennant again for Warilla last year.
But Warilla are also introducing some young talent into the pennants team.
Jesse Noronha has taken over from Selby as skipper, who has moved to the No.3 position, while teenager Toby Peters makes his state finals debut.
Selby won the 2012 world singles championship and silver at the Commonwealth Games in Delhi.
Peters is a rising star of NSW bowling and Selby said there was no hesitation to include him on the big stage.
"I've watched his progress as one of the juniors in my academy and he's become a really mature young player," Selby said.
"He's certainly worthy of the opportunity and it's a great opportunity, he'd have to be one of the youngest ever to play in the state pennants finals. It's been great for team morale."
The second and third rounds of the pennants finals will be played on Saturday, before the semi-finals start on Sunday morning.

The final starts at 1pm on Sunday. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John's Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Noronha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warilla</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erin Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabra Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto Citizens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raymond Terrace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Crane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Peters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selby</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted Clarke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingscliffe Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Section Four</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taren Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halekulani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leif Selby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
