<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411120137246527</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/bronte-hoarders-home-sells-for-3m-500000-above-reserve/news-story/33fa646fbfa1ddeb27485159f5694571</url>
  <title>Bronte hoarder's home sells for $3m - $500,000 above reserve - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
9 Blandford Ave, Bronte, sold for $3 million last night. Picture: Joel Carrett

THE Bronte home of the much-loved hoarder Ernie Towell sold for $3 million - $500,000 above reserve - in an exciting contest at the Double Bay auction centre last night.
The overgrown Federation home, jam-packed with building materials at , was snapped up by Kivan Derak, the managing director at technology firm Texel Global, who described himself as "one-man-band property developer".
When asked what he intended to do with the property, an excited Mr Derak said: "Have you seen it?

The view from the street in Bronte..

"The first thing I'm going to do with it is clean it up!
"It's got great views - I'm not sure what the council will let me do, but I'd like to build two nice houses on there."
Six bidders lined up for the overgrown 778sqm property, which, despite its condition, oozed potential because of the "dress-circle" views of the ocean.
Five of those put in bids - lots of them - during a frenzied auction in which it was difficult to absorb who was bidding what.

Not a bad view from the home.

Pointing out that the property was "not habitable" but a "rare development opportunity", auctioneer Andrew Cooley called for bids in the "early $2 millions".
However, he rejected the opening offer of $2 million, asking: "Can we make it $2.1 million?"
The bidder upped it to $2.1 million, and then it was off.
The next offer was $2.2 million. And increments rose in mainly $50,000 and $10,000 bids.
Belle Property agent Daniel Gillespie said the beneficiaries of the deceased estate - understood to be Mr Towell's friends and workmates since he'd never married - were pleased with the outcome.

The front door. Picture: Joel Carrett

"They're sad at the loss they've endured ... they're suffering from the pain of losing a friend but but they're very satisfied with the outcome," Mr Gillespie said.
The Royal Agricultural Society confirmed that Mr Towell worked as a storeman for 27 years. And between 2008 and early this year, he worked in the venue operations team before leaving in March due to illness.
The estate had already spent $30,000 removing the building materials to get a path up from the street to the back of the property.

Ernest Towell died in May of leukaemia,

Mr Towell, 69, who died of leukaemia in May, had spent a lifetime hoarding. Beyond the
"Danger, do not Enter" sign, the three-bedroom home was piled floor-to-ceiling with piping, timber offcuts, rusty paint tins and assorted junk.
Much of this was carefully labelled, indicating the date of collection.
There were also shelves of paintbrushes resting in water, tools in huge plastic containers, workman's clothes on hangers.
The lady who lived across the road, Thelma Hoad, 94, had known him all his life. "He got it from his father," she said.

The front yard. Picture: Joel Carrett

"He used to laugh about it, then it became compulsive. He'd load his car up - you couldn't get inside his house or his car."
She said he had another house "up the coast". "That house was jammed full ... and he did it with five or six cars up there, too.
"I used to say 'why?' and he'd say: 'I enjoy it'."

Dinosaur Designs' Louise Olsen and husband Stephen Ormandy, live nearby.

Mrs Hoad said Mr Towell's father "was never the same" after his years in the air force during WWII.
Mr Towell was much-loved in the street. Dinosaur Designs co-founder Stephen Ormandy and his wife and business partner Louise Olsen, lived nearby for 20 years.
"He had a lot of plans ... I always said: 'you're such an optimist, Ernie!' "Mr Ormandy said.
Former neighbour Angela Dorrfuss said: "He was nothing like those Bondi hoarders, who just collected rubbish," she said.
"They would have been a nightmare to have as your neighbour, but Ernie was just delightful.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie Towell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Ormandy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thelma Hoad, 94</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Agricultural Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Cooley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bondi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Designs' Louise Olsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texel Global</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belle Property</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Double Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Gillespie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela Dorrfuss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernest Towell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronte</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Ormandy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Towell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Olsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Derak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Carrett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WWII</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Towell, 69</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blandford Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gillespie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hoad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kivan Derak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
