<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651409994855794692</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/world/officials-donald-trump-has-fired-20170801-gxngdd.html</url>
  <title>Officials Donald Trump has fired</title>
  <content>
Up Next

Smelly water oozes into Niagara Falls

01:16

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Trump 'weighed in' on son's statement

The White House confirms the President had a role in his son's statement, in which he denied a meeting with a Russian lawyer was related to the 2016 presidential campaign.

﻿Anthony Scaramucci
The former New York financier was removed as White House communications director just 10 days after being named to the role. In that short time he electrified the internet with a profanity-laced interview with the New Yorker, in which he denounced White House adviser Steve Bannon. Scaramucci was fired, apparently, at the request of White House Chief of Staff John F. Kelly, according to two people with knowledge of the decision.Photo: AP
﻿
Sean Spicer

The White House press secretary resigned this month after six months on the job. He quit after Trump tapped Scaramucci to serve as White House communications director. Spicer, who quit with little warning, was not fired and said in an interview with Fox News Channel that the president wanted him to stay on. But Spicer, a devout Roman Catholic, had been subjected to a string of public slights by his boss, including being excluded from Trump's meeting with the Pope during a trip to the Vatican.
Reince Priebus

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Before Scaramucci's fall, Trump announced on a Friday he was replacing his chief of staff after months of speculation about Priebus's fate and a series of belittling and emasculating comments from Trump and other White House aides.
James Comey
When firing the FBI director in May, Trump deployed one his most trusted and longest-serving aides to carry out the task: bodyguard-turned-security director- turned director of Oval Office operations Keith Schiller. Schiller was sent to the Justice Department to deliver a letter notifying Comey of his firing. But the director was in California and learned of his dismissal from TV.
Corey Lewandowski
Campaign manager Corey Lewandowski had guided the campaign with the motto, "Let Trump be Trump". Trump had stuck with Lewandowski even after he was accused of roughing up a female reporter. He agreed to pull the plug in June 2016 only after an intervention from his adult children and son-in-law. Lewandowski was unceremoniously escorted out of Trump Tower in Manhattan by security after being notified of his dismissal.
Chris Christie
New Jersey's governor spent months leading the president-elect's transition team, pulling together policy papers and coming up with lists of potential cabinet members. But Trump decided he no longer required Christie's services in the days after his November 8 election. According to The New York Times, Trump gave chief strategist Steve Bannon the chore of telling Christie he was out.
Paul Manafort
Trump chose to fire his campaign chairman amid a steady stream of negative headlines about Manafort's foreign consulting work. He technically resigned from the position last August but Trump's son, Eric Trump, said in an interview his father was concerned that questions about Manafort's past were taking attention away from the billionaire's presidential bid.
Michael Flynn
Trump's campaign adviser-turned-national security adviser resigned in February following reports that he had misled Pence and other officials about his contacts with Russia. But Flynn's resignation wasn't voluntary. Trump later said that he'd fired Flynn, and blamed leaks from intelligence agencies and biased reporting from the "fake media" for forcing his hand.
Preet Bharara
The former leading prosecutor claims he was sacked by Donald Trump in March after refusing an order from the attorney general to resign. Mr Bharara, a 48-year-old US attorney for the southern district of New York, made a name for himself taking on Wall Street corruption, terrorism and political malfeasance.
Jeff Sessions, the attorney general, issued an order that all 46 Obama-appointed prosecutors resign immediately. Mr Bharara refused to resign and so was subsequently fired.
Walter Shaub  
The head of the US Office of Government Ethics stepped down in July before his five-year term was to end.
Mr Shaub, who also served during the administrations of Barack Obama and George W. Bush, had been an outspoken critic of Mr Trump over potential for conflicts of interest involving his business affairs.
He said: "In working with the current administration it has become clear to me that we need improvements to the existing ethics programme."
Michael Dubke  
The founder of Crossroads Media resigned as White House communications director in May. "The reasons for my departure are personal, but it has been my great honor to serve President Trump and this administration," said Mr Dubke, in an email to friends, reported by Politico.
Mr Dubke's resignation came amid criticism levelled at the White House over its communication strategy, in particular contradictions between the president and his press team. 
Sally Yates 
The acting US attorney general was fired by Mr Trump in January after she ordered Justice Department lawyers not to enforce Mr Trump's controversial immigration ban.
The president accused Ms Yates of having "betrayed the Department of Justice by refusing to enforce a legal order designed to protect the citizens of the United States."
Ms Yates, who was appointed by Barack Obama, said in an open letter that she is "not convinced that the executive order is lawful".
Sam Nunberg
The man behind many of Trump's earliest and most popular campaign ideas was pushed out of Trump's campaign in the summer of 2015 following a report that he'd posted racially charged material on his Facebook page. This time, Trump delivered the news to Nunberg directly over the phone.
AP, Telegraph, UK
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewandowski</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Niagara Falls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shaub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Manafort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obama-appointed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vatican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manafort</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Flynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preet Bharara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Politico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Schiller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spicer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flynn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dubke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George W. Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Dubke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nunberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schiller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walter Shaub</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Department</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News Channel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Comey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roman Catholics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John F. Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Office of Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Nunberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bharara</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November @ 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Yates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Spicer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Yates</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Christie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crossroads Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Lewandowski</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
