<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410570381423845</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:33</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/us-sports/michael-jordan-lavar-ball-nba-moron-dad-destroyed-by-his-airness-after-oneonone-boast/news-story/b2cfc971f53e5c73fef0fd7ffb40cc5c</url>
  <title>Jordan destroys NBA moron dad LaVar</title>
  <content>
LAVAR Ball claimed he would "kill" Michael Jordan one-on-one. His Airness has refrained from hitting back at the NBA loudmouth dad - until now.
"You got to understand the source. I think he played college, maybe?" Jordan told campers at his Flight School basketball camp.
"He averaged 2.2 points a game. Really?
"It doesn't dignify an answer but I'm a give it to you because you asked the question. I don't think he could beat me if I was one-legged."
There you have it. MJ would beat LaVar with one leg. Who would doubt the G.O.A.T.?
MJ roasts LaVar

LaVar has inexplicably risen to fame as the outspoken father of Los Angeles Lakers draftee Lonzo Ball. He is best known for costing his son a $27 million shoe endorsement deal by trying to launch his own Big Baller Brand, as well as making ludicrous comments about basketball luminaries like Jordan.
He also trashed Kyrie Irving for having a mother who died when he was four years old, has offended female reporters with misogynistic comments, and also delved into racist commentary about white basketball players.
Jordan also said during his response that he rated Lonzo as a good prospect and understood that all parents were proud of their kids, but added of LaVar: "No, he can not beat me and Kobe."
LaVar had responded to Jordan's comments seemingly within moments, as he has an open line to an enthralled US media.
"Look at everybody, man. Everybody used to say, 'You know, I think Wilt Chamberlain is better than Shaq; I think Oscar Robertson is better than LeBron.' Now the story is LaVar is better than Michael Jordan," Ball told The Really Big Show on ESPN 850 WKNR in Cleveland.
"C'mon, I didn't even play basketball in the pros and they're talking about me and Michael Jordan. That's what I'm talking about. He tells me he can beat me with one leg. Well, guess what: I can beat him with one hand. Now we both look like we out there like we can't play."
LaVar's initial Jordan boast came back in March, speaking to USA Today.
"Back in my heyday, I would kill Michael Jordan one-on-one. I would just back [Jordan] in and lift him off the ground and call a foul every time he fouls me when I do a jump hook to the right or the left," he said.
"He cannot stop me one-on-one. He better make every shot 'cause he can't go around me. He's not fast enough. And he can only make so many shots outside before I make every bucket under the rim."
LaVar played for Washington State in 1987-88, averaging 2.2 points and 2.3 rebounds per game before transferring to a smaller school in an attempt to get more playing time. Jordan averaged 35 points per game for the Chicago Bulls in the NBA that same season.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>KOBE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MJ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flight School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G.O.A.T</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Really Big Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN 850 WKNR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles Lakers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LeBron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar Robertson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jordan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaVar</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyrie Irving</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonzo Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cleveland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaVar Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago Bulls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Baller Brand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA TODAY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lonzo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilt Chamberlain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
