<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410106524946696</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:45</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/trump-white-house-real-dump-2017-8</url>
  <title>Trump to members of his New Jersey golf club: 'That White House is a real dump'</title>
  <content>
President Donald Trump reportedly told a group of members at his Bedminster, New Jersey golf club that the reason he frequented the golf property so often was because "that White House is a real dump."

The comment was reported Tuesday in a  which will appear in Sports Illustrated this week.

"Chatting with some members before a recent round of golf, [Trump] explained his frequent appearances: 'That White House is a real dump,'" Golf.com reported.

The publication wrote that the president is "often at his most unguarded among the people who pay for their proximity to him."

"Last November, the President-elect hosted a cocktail reception and dinner at Bedminster on the same weekend that he was holding interviews at the club with candidates for his cabinet," Golf.com reported. "At the dinner, Trump addressed the members of the club by saying, "This is my real group. You are the special people. I see all of you. I recognise, like, 100% of you, just about.'"

Trump has spent most of his weekends as president at Trump properties, whether it be his Mar-a-Lago, Florida resort, his New Jersey golf club, or his golf course in suburban Washington, DC. So far in his young presidency, Trump  40 days at one of his golf properties.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports Illustrated</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mar-a-Lago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President-Elect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump  40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
