<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410986993257944</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/rendezview/this-is-what-its-like-to-go-through-life-hating-your-body/news-story/8743147ea27379f6512c409b3ffecf7b</url>
  <title>This is what life is like when you hate your body</title>
  <content>
I know we're supposed to be all, "love your body whatever shape and size" but I can't be PC about this. I'm over my body.
Working out where this hatred has sprung from is a tricky one.
It may have been from watching my Mum diet her whole life, but I'm also over the blame-your parents-for-everything-wrong-in-your-life viewpoint, so that's not a credible argument for me.
Perhaps it was the steroids prescribed for a kidney problem which left me a fluid retentive puffy whale? Sure it affected my confidence as a kid but did that transcend to these weighty issues?
What about the yawn worthy comments from a bunch of zitty pre-pubescents with a knack for comparing my body parts to vegetables? "Hey carrot legs!" may have steered me away from healthy snacks but it can't be the whole reason.
Maybe it's the obsession I had with a total psychopath who'd haul me in front of school mirrors and tell me how disgusting I was and how no one would ever love me but him? Let's not give him the credit.
Maybe just maybe, it's all those things added together. Your formative years are a minefield where every word, decision or event can build upon another like a Jenga tower. Now I'm in my late 30s, with a humungous fear of mirrors, a love of chocolate coated peanuts and a skewed sense of self.
I know I'm going against the (whole) grain by exposing my truth when . I've watched the Dove ads. I've seen the "non airbrushed" celebrity shots. Self-love is so damn glittery.
Believe me I've tried. I've asked "acceptance" to the party multiple times but it never RSVPs. And before everyone asks why I don't just lose weight then, I've tried that too. The stretch marks prove it. The kilos go down, the kilos go up. Even at my lowest weight, acceptance was AWOL. Yes I was happier inside but still repelled by those wobbly bits only a good pair of Spanx could hide. I'm sick of failing with my healthy routines, sick of giving up because I see no change. One bad eating day and that's it, downward spiral into shame.
It doesn't help that my younger boyfriend eats whatever he likes. I've asked him to save the chocolate bars for his car ride home from work, away from my salivating lips but it rarely works. I can sniff out sugar. Soon enough we're in a fat-laden free-for-all in front of Netflix. Then I get angry with him, angry with myself and fall into a hole of despair.
I'm sad about the way I feel about myself. I feel like a narcissistic, indulgent, obsessive idiot. And I am obsessed. It's all-consuming. A quick trip to the hairdresser is torture as I'm forced to look at myself for hours on end, (hence my hair isn't a priority and my regrowth is often mistaken as balayage). A night out fills me with dread as I consider the technicalities of squeezing myself into skinny jeans without losing circulation. It's not uncommon to find me berating my wardrobe as it's strewn over the floor. "Yeah you, you can all just lie there and think about how you've made me feel today!"
This obsession is boring for me and boring to those closest to me, so I've learned to keep my feelings under wraps, to deal with my dark thoughts alone. On the outside I may seem like I have my shit together but my days always involve keeping myself out of group photos, bypassing my reflection in shop windows and positioning myself to full skinny effect in bed so my boyfriend isn't scarred for life.
I know it's not normal. I know there are more important matters in the world than Googling the fat contents of milk substitutes. I also know others face bigger struggles than I do but this is my struggle. And I doubt I'm alone.
My point? Sharing these universal fears and acknowledging we're all flawed and imperfect. Let's be honest about issues that affect us, no matter if that opens us up to judgment. It's silence that creates dangerous spaces.
Katy Moore is a freelance writer.
@whatktdidnextfw
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Googling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWOL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katy Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSVP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
