<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410686345542872</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/logan/logan-mayor-fends-off-claims-new-meeting-rule-gags-councillors/news-story/77faa8ec185d412d200180f2dd6b692a</url>
  <title>Mayor defends meeting rule</title>
  <content>
LOGAN mayor Luke Smith has defended a move to only allow items of general business to be raised if he has approved them prior to a council meeting.
He was responding after Shailer Park woman Paulette Oldfield lodged a complaint claiming the move "gagged" councillors.
Ms Oldfield said it was draconian and disrespectful and forced councillors to apply for permission in writing by the close of business the day before the council meeting.
"This is unrealistic and does not support an open, transparent and democratic process," she said.
"Your actions do not support a business that runs a democratic process."
Mayor Smith said councillors had "countless opportunities" to seek advice, make public statements and represent their communities every day.
"If some councillors believe the only opportunity they have to represent their community is once every three weeks via the general business item in a full council meeting, then they are not doing their jobs properly," he said.
"This is a simple process, common among other councils and boards, that is helping to keep our meeting efficient and is keeping state and federal party politics out of our council business."
However, Cr Jon Raven (Div 5) said he had never encountered general business being regulated in such a way in the private or public sector.
"Since being elected I can't recall any examples of non-council business that took more than a few minutes because we don't debate in general business we just raise matters that are important to our community," he said.
The complaint prompted mixed responses from councillors.
Cr Phil Pidgeon (Div 9) defended the move and said it was fair and prudent use of ratepayer funds to give all councillors and officers fair warning of items.
"Any councillor who has any questions they wish to raise in the public council meeting regarding any matter of council business has a right to file a Question on Notice," he said. "This is not to be confused with raising ad hoc general business items which requires notice prior to the meeting itself."
Cr Darren Power (Div 10) said the order was broken at Tuesday's meeting when Division 7 Cr Laurie Smith raised an impromptu item about increased traffic on a freight train line.
"You can only raise council business - no matters about other governments or matters outside the scope of council will be accepted by the chair (mayor)," Cr Power said.
"The spirit of general business at council is dying with only two general business items being brought up and with no debate occurring during committee recommendations, council is becoming irrelevant."
Division 1 councillor Lisa Bradley said the move curbed her freedom of speech.
"At Tuesday's council meeting, three councillors spoke in general business, there was no debate and one item was voted on without this matter put in writing before the meeting," she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 7 Cr Laurie Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Div 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Div 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shailer Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Jon Raven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Phil Pidgeon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Darren Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Bradley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulette Oldfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayor Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Oldfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Div 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Power</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
