<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410561791488981</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/heres-what-chinese-online-shoppers-like-to-buy-from-australia-2017-8</url>
  <title>Here's what Chinese online shoppers like to buy from Australia</title>
  <content>
Online shoppers in China have a high regard for Australian products, seeing them as safe and value for money.

Australia, seen by Chinese consumers as a place with a good lifestyle, resonates so much that most plan to buy something from the country in the next 12 months, according to a study.

More than 8 in 10 (84%) Chinese online shoppers say they are highly likely to buy at least one Australian product in the next year, according to research commissioned by FedEx Express.

The poll of 1,000 Chinese online shoppers, aged 18 to 44 years old in the cities of Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou and Shenzhen, shows Australian brands are already top of mind, with 81% having purchased at least one Australian product online in the past.

The Chinese online shoppers estimated that they have spent RMB$4895 ($940) on Australian goods over the last year.

Nearly two thirds (62%) of Chinese online shoppers like buying Australian-made because the way of life is appealing.

More than one third (36%) of Chinese online shoppers said the Australian goods are value for money and 32% believed they are safer than Chinese goods.

"Australian brands enjoy a high reputation among consumers in China," says Kim Garner, managing director, FedEx Express Australasia.

"With the China-Australia Free Trade Agreement and the emergence of online marketplaces connecting to consumers in China, it is becoming much easier for Australian businesses to do business with China."

In the survey, Australian dairy products were seen as world-class by 58% of Chinese online shoppers.

A fifth or more believe the same for health supplements and pharmaceutical products (39%), baby products (31%), skincare products (25%), fresh seafood and meat (24%), fresh fruit and vegetables (20%) and wine (20%).

Cosmetic and skincare products were purchased by 31%, followed by healthcare and pharmaceutical products (25%).

"Buying Australian products online comes down to trust," says Garner.

"This research indicates secure payment, authenticity and seller recommendations are more important to Chinese online shoppers than price and brand.

"It's important to have a world-leading product, but selling it through the right channels is also crucial."

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>FedEx Express Australasia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMB$4895 ($940</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Garner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shenzhen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-made</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guangzhou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FedEx Express</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China-Australia Free Trade Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shanghai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
