<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410557496521504</docid>
  <date>01/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/02/09/12/british-jihadi-threatens-new-wave-of-attacks</url>
  <title>'British' jihadi threatens new wave of attacks</title>
  <content>
A jihadi with a British accent has threatened US president Donald Trump and claimed ISIS is planning new attacks in the West in a new video.

The video, posted on social media, is believed to have been filmed in the Syrian city of Raqqa as Syrian Democratic Forces increase their stranglehold on the terrorist organisation's self-proclaimed caliphate.

Walking towards the camera from his position beside a machine-gun, the young jihadi addresses Trump.

"This is a message to the new pharaoh of today, Donald Trump!" he says.

He then warns of a fresh wave of attacks on Turkey and Italy.

"You may have your eyes on Raqqa and Mosul but we have our eyes on Constantinople and Rome,' he says, using the ancient name for the Turkish capital of Istanbul," he said.

"Bi Idhn Allah, Bi Idhn Allah (with Allah's permission). We will slaughter you in your own houses."

Related Articles

Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF) troops are slowly advancing through the outer suburbs of Raqqa, Islamic State's last major stronghold.

US-backed Syrian fighters have captured almost half of the Islamic State group's de facto capital. But the push into the city in northern Syria has slowed in recent weeks due to stiff resistance and large amounts of explosives planted by the extremists, a spokeswoman for the fighters and monitors said.

The assault on Raqqa by the Syrian Democratic Forces, a Kurdish-led fighting coalition, began June 6, backed by US-led coalition airstrikes and US troops advising the local forces.

Since then, the SDF has made steady advances from the eastern and western sides of the city, reaching the walled old quarter.

The fall of Raqqa would be a huge loss for ISIS, which earlier this month lost the Iraqi city of Mosul.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constantinople</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raqqa</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISTANBUL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraqis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mosul</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISIS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-backed Syrian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turkish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SDF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic State</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurdish-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bi Idhn Allah</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syrian Democratic Forces</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
