<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411120137246531</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/crime-and-justice/tamate-heke-on-trial-over-gateway-motorway-death/news-story/b1bb0f658dd811254663af5be79554ef</url>
  <title>'I hit him back. He fell on the road'</title>
  <content>
A SUPREME Court jury has been shown an emotional police interview in which manslaughter accused Tamate Heke describes the moment he hit Shane Merrigan and saw him fall into the path of an oncoming truck.
Heke, 38, has pleaded not guilty to manslaughter and an alternative charge of unlawful striking causing death and is facing day three of a trial in Brisbane today.
It is alleged he punched Mr Merrigan, 50, in the head and caused him to fall onto the busy Gateway Motorway and under the wheels of a garbage truck on December 1, 2015.
The jury is watching an interview with police recorded just hours after the tragedy unfolded.
Heke told police Mr Merrigan was tailgating him in the right-hand lane and was so close he "couldn't even see his bonnet".
He said it went on for a while before Mr Merrigan motioned for him to pull over at Eight Mile Plains.
Heke, who was supported by his younger brother during the interview, said they both got out of their cars and started arguing.
"He's pushed me twice. He took a swing," he said.
"He hit me in my face ... left-hand side.
"I hit him back. He fell on the road."
Heke's voice wavered and his brother rubbed his back as he said: "I tried to catch him".
"He fell on the road, the truck was coming," he said.
"I saw his head get squashed."
Heke said he got out of the car "to see what his problem was" and didn't know what he was thinking.
But his anger level was about five out of 10, he said.
The trial continues.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heke</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merrigan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateway Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Merrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eight Mile Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamate Heke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heke, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
