<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411244691299846</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/hospital-celebrates-70-years-in-nambour/3205734/</url>
  <title>Hospital celebrates 70 years in Nambour</title>
  <content>
IN 1947, private hospitals were few and far between.
When Dr Jim Trotter and his colleagues were unable to get private patients into appropriate beds at existing hospitals, they took matters into their own hands.
The doctors joined forces with nursing sisters Christine Oxley and Dorothy Ralston, and Nambour Selangor Private Hospital was born.
Last week staff at the hospital celebrated the institution's 70th birthday, with the official event held on July 22.
Chief Executive Officer at Nambour Selangor Private Hospital Sandra Moore said she was proud of the healthcare the team had continued to provide over the years.
"Our staff are excellent here, they really are the backbone of our care to the community and are very passionate about what they do," she said.
"(They) are quiet achievers, just out there caring for the community and making sure that when people are unwell and need healthcare, we are there for them.
"There is such a camaraderie and connection to our patients and the community... if they can just do one thing to make their patients' journey a little better, that is what excites them.
"Our 70th birthday is a wonderful opportunity to celebrate not only our success in providing healthcare but also to honour our forebears who had the vision to open a private hospital in Nambour which has continually provided a wide range of medical and surgical services, as well as an excellent Rehabilitation Unit."
The team at the hospital celebrated the birthday by decorating various departments and wards with hospital memorabilia spanning over the ages, along with a special birthday party luncheon and cake.
To mark the occasion, the surgical and medical wards at the hospital were also renamed to honour founding Nursing Sisters Christine Oxley and Dorothy Ralston in recognition of their contributions.
"It is important to recognise your forebearers," Ms Moore said.
"During the hospital's life we estimate that over 750,000 patients have been treated here at one time or another.
"It's not always nice for people to be in hospital, because they are sick and away from family, but we are here and we are always happy to have them when and if they need us."
'Teen fed burning hot sauce, punched in face and stomach'
"Nice deal if you can get it!"
More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Selangor Private Hospital Sandra Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rehabilitation Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Oxley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Selangor Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Jim Trotter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nursing Sisters Christine Oxley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorothy Ralston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Executive Officer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
