<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410939748616957</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/more-sports/future-of-australian-athletics-on-display-at-world-championships-in-london/news-story/78df7f61e2ef1d66ff875d59f0112c18</url>
  <title>Generation Next ready for world challenge</title>
  <content>
IT'S a young team with an eye to the future but Australian head coach Craig Hilliard is confident medals are still on the agenda.
The changing of the guard in Australian athletics is in full swing with a team of 62, the biggest which has ever been selected for a world championships, to compete in London.
Hilliard will again be relying on his core group of experienced stars including Sally Pearson (hurdles), Dani Stevens (discus), Jared Tallent (50km walk), Dane Bird-Smith (20km walk) and Kathryn Mitchell (javelin) to win medals.
But he's just as excited about the depth in the sport on the back of an impressive showing at last year's Rio Olympics.
"I never predict medals, it's an exercise in futility but on any given day between nought and five (could happen)," Hilliard said.
"In Rio we could have won five, we ended up with two but we missed three by very small margins. I would be happy if we got two medals at these championships.
"It's a big team, 62, certainly the largest team we have had going away but I think that is a plus and it shows some of the depth we have got moving on from Rio."
Australia had 40 debutants in Rio and 20 of them are back in this team plus another 17 new debutants which are headlined by 17-year-old's Riley Day (200m) and Ella Connolly (4x400m).
"So we have 37 athletes here who basically have had one experience of a major championships or none," Hilliard said.
"This is our next crop realistically in terms of the next four year cycle."
For many competing in London, the experience is critical ahead of next year's Commonwealth Games on the Gold Coast.
Hilliard has identified pole vaulter Kurtis Marschall and javelin-thrower Kelsey-Lee Roberts as dark horses for these championships.

"Kurtis has been competing well in Europe, he's a bright talent for the future," he said.
"It's a technical event so it's one where you can progress quickly and I would be happy with him getting through to the top eight this year and spring boarding from there.
"Kelsey-Lee Roberts is another who has stepped up to another level now and these are the athletes who just missed top eight last year.
"That's the next bridge for them and from there you start thinking. 'I can medal from here'. "
Hilliard is also buoyed by he return of Pearson who has missed the past two years because of injury.
"The door is open, there's a lot of American athletes who have run fast hurdle times but there will only be four here and the depth in that event has fallen away a bit," he said.
"I think if anyone saw the Diamond League (12.48 sec in London) it was pretty exciting. To get back to run the 12.40s was phenomenal, she basically skipped the 50s and 60s and said. 'Here we go'."
Pearson, the 2012 Olympic 100m hurdles champion, isn't returning to her role as team captain with Hilliard preferring to go with a large leadership group model instead of a stand-alone candidate.
On the injury front, long-jumper Henry Frayne is back on track after a hamstring problem while Tallent, the silver medallist in Rio, has had an interrupted preparation and isn't in the same shape as last year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathryn Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Hilliard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tallent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ella Connolly (4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis Marschall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dani Stevens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Bird-Smith (20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diamond League (12.48</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilliard</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Tallent (50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley Day (200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelsey-Lee Roberts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Frayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
