<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411244691299697</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/usain-bolt-time-to-say-goodbye/8766102</url>
  <title>Usain Bolt warns doping could kill athletics as he prepares for final meet</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Just in the unlikely case that the world of athletics did not know what they will be missing once Usain Bolt walks away in less than two weeks, the Jamaican superstar's final eve-of-race news conference has rammed home the message.
These events have become part and parcel of every global championship and though Tuesday's version in east London lacked the dancing girl razzmatazz of his Rio welcome last year, it scored heavily on nostalgia as every aspect of his stellar career was raked over anew.
As always, journalists and TV crews, about 400 of them from every corner of the world, packed every available space and strained their arms in desperation to get their question answered by the great man, who playfully castigated one half of the auditorium for not giving him an enthusiastic enough welcome.
Bolt, 30, is an old hand of course and rolled out all the familiar answers, but always with grace.
His proudest moment was winning the world junior title on home soil as a 15-year-old while his most satisfying performance was his 200 metres world record run in the 2008 Beijing Olympics, where he poured all his concentration into getting the mark he had always wanted, having earlier danced over the line when winning the 100m.
He explained how his motivation to keep putting his body through such a punishing regime was renewed each year by resetting his goals - with one often created for him by a casually "disrespectful" remark from one of his opponents.

He would also speak to the BBC about his concern that drugs could ruin the sport he loves, saying those who dope "must stop or the sport will die".
"Hopefully athletes will see what's going on and what they need to do to help the sport move forward," he said.
"Personally I think we were at rock bottom [following the McLaren report]. After the scandal on Russia I don't think it gets any worse than that.
"Over the years we're doing a better job, it's getting clean and we're catching up to a lot of athletes.
"There's an understanding that if you cheat you will get caught. Over time the sport will get better.
"I said a couple of years ago it had to get really bad, when there's nowhere else to go but up."
Bolt targeting two more wins to finish off

His target in London is clear: to sign off with a fourth 100m title and a fifth 4x100m relay gold, taking his world haul to 13 to add to his eight Olympic golds - and then head off to play football with his friends and have fun.
"I'm ready," he said.
"If I show up at a championships you know I'm fully confident and ready to go.
"I ran 9.95 in Monaco so it shows I'm going in the right direction. Going through the rounds always helps me and it's then about who can keep their nerve.
"It's go time, so let's go."
The London Stadium, where he successfully defended his sprint double in the 2012 Olympics, will rise to acclaim him when he settles into his blocks for the last time on Saturday night.
Then, other than the relay a week later, he will be gone, leaving the sport without the man who has been its focal point for a decade.
Tuesday's event included big-screen "farewell and thanks" messages from the likes of actors Samuel L Jackson and Idris Elba, former France footballer Thierry Henry, model Cara Delevingne and India cricket captain Virat Kohli, underlining his status as probably the world's most famous and arguably most admired sportsman.

Bolt, who turns 31 later this month, looked moved by the images, saying: "It's just brilliant that people in other disciplines respect what you do as they know the work you have to do."
British TV had screened his I am Bolt film on Monday night, which opened a window on the rarely seen battles he has had to go through to overcome so many injuries and was a testament to his willingness to work himself back into shape year after year.
He intends to stay close to athletics and is eyeing some sort of roving ambassadorial role, inspiring the world's youth to get involved in the sport.
Bolt's parents were on hand on Tuesday to present him with his final pair of spikes, a combination of gold to mark his career highs and the purple of his school, William Knibb Memorial, where it all started after his cricket coach suggested he try out for the track team.
"I didn't know I would be a world-record holder growing up, I had no idea," he said.
"So all I'll say now is, if you work hard, that anything is possible."
Reuters/ABC

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara Delevingne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLaren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel L. Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Idris Elba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Knibb Memorial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thierry Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beijing Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virat Kohli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters/ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
