<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411279051038804</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/get-ready-for-the-2017-chevron-city-to-surf-for-activ/news-story/0ac8455022b056ee595e87a12d9069d8</url>
  <title>Get ready for the 2017 Chevron City to Surf for Activ</title>
  <content>
SINCE 1975, the Chevron City to Surf for Activ has been a much-loved fixture on the State's sporting calendar, capturing the hearts and minds of thousands of people and raising much needed funds for Activ and other charities.
As Activ's flagship annual fundraising event, the Chevron City to Surf for Activ benefits people living with disability and their families in WA.
Funds raised through the generosity of the WA community enable Activ to provide services and support across the Perth metropolitan area and in the regions, where Activ continues to ensure that people living with disability have access to case management support, employment, recreation services and accommodation.
The series brings WA to life with a series of five events in Albany, Geraldton, Karratha, Albany, Busselton, and the flagship race from the Perth CBD to City Beach.
Whether you want to walk, run, race or roll, be a part of the 2017 Chevron City to Surf for Activ and Go The Distance.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karratha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chevron City</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geraldton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Activ</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Busselton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
