<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411236101364888</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/books/wordplay-when-a-poet-yearns-for-the-tools-of-his-trade-20170731-gxmq9b.html</url>
  <title>Wordplay: When a poet yearns for the tools of his trade</title>
  <content>
The poet doesn't trust computers. In a recent poem Les Murray confessed, "The computer scares me/its crashes and codes/its links with spies and gunshot ..."
That recent poem is The Privacy of Typewriters, since Les is a lover of "inky marching hammers/leaping up and subsiding". Despite the latest RAM revamp, the highest of high-res screen, the ample Wi-Fi capacity, the poet prefers "the spoor of botch,/whiteouts where thought deepened,/wise freedom from Spell Check ..."Photo: Pat Scala
So where was his beloved typewriter, I wondered, scanning the writer's bungalow. Walls of books started back - Lorca and Brodsky. A Solidarnosc medal from the people of Poland, a goshawk print, but no typewriter.
Indeed, the poet is bereft. Typically, Les composes his verse in longhand, converting his scrawl to the old-fashioned QWERTY, though lately the QWERTY is a WP since typewriters are hen's teeth. His last one carked it and he doesn't know where to find a replacement, even where to start.
The situation saddens the lyrebird too, the "tailed mimic" who stalks below the office window on Bunyah, the poet's own stamping ground. Crestfallen, the bird must depend on memory to revive the clack-clack of the keys, resurrecting Les in his typing prime.
I'd come to Bunyah to experience such details in the flesh, in the feather, in the candelabra of the dam's drowned trees. For the past five years Les has championed Winter Solstice, a public health event begun in Albury under the banner of suicide prevention. Depression, according to Les, is "the crowded loneliness", a terrible waste of energy. It's "shredded mental kelp marinaded in pure pain".

Poetry, thank God, remains one sanctuary Murray's black dog can't reach. Along with the privacy of typewriters, of course, but Bunyah has none. Still, the man's work litters the shelves and furniture, his images press on all sides of the bungalow: the mayonnaise trunks, the barbed-wire stanzas, the cormorants with "musket-hammer necks". To visit Bunyah is to relive the metaphors Les has been clacking for 50 years.
The plan was to invite the Bunyah man to the solstice, to read a few poems about the sickness he rarely suffers nowadays. But at 78, Les is less inclined to roam. Albury looms as lumbago trigger, so Albury decided to visit Bunyah instead. I joined a few solstice volunteers, driving to Les' birthplace between Taree and the ocean, to ask the poet to recite on film.
Which he did, graciously. For two days in his lyrebird lair, across paddocks, among his ancestral graves in nearby Krambach. Always in that hooped jumper his beloved Valerie knitted, Valerie Murray nee Morelli. In fact, it was the alphabet that had played cupid back in 1960, the Sydney Uni students meeting in a queue for German orals.
Nearing lunch in the cemetery, the diabetic poet craves sugar, the party making for nearby Nabiac for coffee. A place of wild fig in the Katang tongue, Nabiac sounds more like an acronym, but Les knows the cafes backwards. We choose a nook beside a collectables store. It's there, on a hunch, I rummage in the back room to find a pre-electric Brother of mushroom Bakelite.
O, what a delightful typewriter, Les types. The ink is pale but the poet is radiant. Later, heading back through Coolongolook, weaving the Murray oeuvre, we talk about ribbons and shift keys, the valley's dual rains - from the south's "Victorian silver" to the north's rain, "lightning-brewed in a vast coral pot".
I sense new work emerging as we move, a reborn alphabet to thwart the darkness, a bank of hammers leaping from their bed to strike fresh outpourings. Readers, like the lyrebird, can rejoice.
davidastle.com
twitter.com/dontattempt
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunyah</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morelli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winter Solstice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solidarnosc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QWERTY</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nabiac</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Krambach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolongolook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Privacy of Typewriters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bakelite</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albury</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Uni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Scala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valerie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spell Check</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wi-Fi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valerie Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
