<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411248986267277</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>http://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/deals-this-typing-tool-is-basically-a-personal-trainer-for-writing/</url>
  <title>Deals: This Typing Tool Is Basically A Personal Trainer For Writing</title>
  <content>
There's more to good writing than just knowing the difference between there, their, and they're, but keeping track of the rules of spelling and grammar can be daunting for most. That's where  comes in. This writing tool helps you communicate quickly and accurately across all your devices.

With Ginger Page, you can eliminate typos, slang, and grammatical mishaps to ensure you're writing with confidence. Using the sentence rephrase tool, Ginger Page lets you test out different ways of conveying your thoughts. Plus, if English isn't your strongest language, you can shore up your understanding of the essentials with the built-in personal trainer.

You can get  [$29 USD], three years for $65 AUD [$50 USD], or you can upgrade to a lifetime plan on sale for $91 AUD [$70 USD], saving 90 percent off the normal price!

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

All deals are carefully vetted to ensure relevance and value to Lifehacker readers. Commerce Content is independent of Allure Media editorial and advertising, and if you buy something through our posts, we may get a small share of the sale. Click  to learn more.

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

WATCH MORE: Tech News & Life Hacks

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifehacker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Typing Tool Is Basically A Personal Trainer For Writing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allure Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD [$50 USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ginger Page</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD [$70 USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commerce Content</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Hacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
