<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411248986267185</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/national/melbourne-weather-thick-fog-engulfs-suburbs/news-story/b72dac0b0816ec002b6f69976ec3081a</url>
  <title>Thick fog causes travel chaos</title>
  <content>
FLIGHTS have aborted landings at Melbourne Airport and forced to interstate airports as thick fog continues to blanket the city.
At least two flights have been forced to divert as heavy fog reduces visibility.
One of the planes, Virgin flight VA252 from Canberra, reportedly got down to 140m before it abandoned the landing and returned to the sky.
It circled near Werribee before diverting to Sydney.
A Capital Airlines flight from China was also unable to land on its first approach, before touching down almost an hour late.
Airservices Australia spokeswoman Sarah Fulton said three planes had been diverted from Melbourne.
"Two went to Sydney and one went back to Hobart," she said.
Conditions were set to improve soon, Ms Fulton said, but delays were expected.
Earlier reports the airport was closed were wrong, she said.
"In particular it is the domestic and smaller regional aircrafts that are being affected," Ms Fulton said.
"Most international aircraft have been able to arrive and depart the airport because they have more advanced technology."
Flight tracking website FlightRadar24 showed a number of planes in holding patterns over parts of Melbourne before landing or diverting.
Ms Fulton said it was common for this to happen in foggy conditions.
Passengers flying from Melbourne, or people heading to the airport to pick up arrivals, were urged to check with the airport or airlines before heading to Tullamarine.
The Bureau of Meteorology issued a road alert for the Melbourne area due to reduced visibility making conditions dangerous.
The State Emergency Service urged people to reduce speed and maintain a greater distance between them and the vehicle in front.
Motorists are also urged to turn on their headlights.
Bureau of Meteorology forecaster Dean Stewart said light winds and clear skies overnight had contributed to the thick fog.
"It's quite extensive across the Melbourne metro area," he said.
The thickness of the fog varied across the city with Melbourne Airport experiencing visibility as low as 200m, Mr Stewart said.
"It looks like the fog will last quite a while this morning before it turns into low cloud later in the day," he said.
There is also a frost warning for most areas of Victoria.
Once the fog lifts the sun will return with a top of 15C expected today.
Melbourne experienced glorious sunshine yesterday as it welcomed August.
The mostly sunny day reached a top of 15C and had Melburnians out and about catching warm rays.
The remainder of the week is also looking brighter with average temperatures of about 15C but showers forecast for the weekend.
Mr Stewart said August was expected to be a drier month than usual.
"There is an increased chance of below average rainfall across the state for August," he said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stewart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werribee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tullamarine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Emergency Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fulton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Airport</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FlightRadar24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Fulton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VA252</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airservices Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melburnians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
