<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651410991288225365</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Mining</source>
  <url>https://www.australianmining.com.au/news/aimex-chairman-sees-renewed-confidence-mining/</url>
  <title>AIMEX chairman sees renewed confidence in mining - Australian Mining</title>
  <content>
AIMEX chairman David Moult

Latest News

Working with natural resources means never knowing what will be around the corner.
So says David Moult, non-executive chairman of AIMEX: "It is safe to say that the mining sector has just come through one of the most difficult periods that I have ever witnessed in my 40 year career."
"The pace and diversity of this industry is why I chose to enter the mining sector in the first place. Mining engineering covers more aspects of engineering than any other engineering discipline around."
In 1998, Moult first joined Centennial Coal when it was a very small listed company with a market capitalisation of less than $20 million. Around the time of the takeover of Banpu in 2010, he helped grow Centennial Coal into an ASX S&P100 listed company with a market capitalisation of $2.6 billion.
He now holds the position of non-executive director of Centennial Coal Company Limited, and is the chairman of Coal Services, a director (and past chairman) of the NSW Minerals Council, chairman of the Australian Coal Association Low Emissions Technologies Board and a member of the University of NSW Education Trust Advisory Committee.
"Recent movements in the coal price has given the sector more confidence, particularly as prices level to a more sustainable position. It is encouraging to hear a more rational debate from the Federal Government in respect to the electricity generation mix, particularly as we move into a more carbon constrained economy," he said.
As prices level, Moult argues the industry is looking for opportunities to invest - making events like the Asia-Pacific International Mining Exhibition 2017 more important than ever.
"AIMEX provides an unparalleled opportunity for companies and industry professionals from across the region to connect face-to-face, discuss industry trends and generate new business leads," Moult said.
"For suppliers, it's an opportunity to showcase their latest innovations. For operators, it's a platform to see and discuss where mining equipment, technology and services is headed. For delegates, it's a change to meet with colleagues - new and old."
David Moult is the non-executive chairman for AIMEX. He has also been a director for Minerals Council of Australia, the NSW Freight Advisory Council, Coal Innovation NSW (CINSW) and the Australian Coal Association (ACA). In May 2014, through to project end in February 2015, David was also a member of the Minerals Industry Taskforce, tasked with providing a roadmap for the growth in the minerals sector within NSW.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Moult</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minerals Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovation NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minerals Industry Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CINSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coal Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Coal Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX/S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centennial Coal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Minerals Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Freight Advisory Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia-Pacific International Mining Exhibition 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Coal Association Low Emissions Technologies Board</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Trust Advisory Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIMEX</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Banpu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centennial Coal Company Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
