<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411283346006196</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/12/07/sam-dastyari-australian-story-abc</url>
  <title>Sam Dastyari Australian Story was in</title>
  <content>
The ABC has rejected claims an Australian Story episode about NSW Labor Senator Sam Dastyari amounted to nothing more than an "infomercial", arguing there is a public interest in the politician.
On Monday, Australian Story aired a profile on Dastyari, sparking criticism from MPs and other senators that it helped promote a book by the Iranian-born politician aimed at restoring his public image following high-profile scandals involving Chinese donors.
Crossbench senator Cory Bernardi dismissed the program as an "infomercial", suggesting to  the public broadcaster had been co-opted into a career rejuvenation mission for Senator Dastyari.
An ABC spokesperson said the episode, Playing with Fire, was a "balanced retelling of events, with voices from across the political spectrum".
"There is clear public interest in hearing Mr Dastyari's answers to previously unanswered allegations and questions about his conduct as a Senator. The idea for the story came up in a researchers' meeting when the donation scandal first erupted. The program then approached Mr Dastyari's media advisor about an interview.
"As is always the case, the timing of the episode was dictated by the scheduling needs of the program and the availability of Mr Dastyari and other interviewees."
The Communications Minister Mitch Fifiled has said he will be asking the ABC about the story.

Related Articles

"From memory, Australian Story have had profiles on half a dozen serving politicians over the last six or so years," Senator -Fifield said. "Given a number of colleagues have raised this -episode's content and its timing, I'll ask the ABC about the background to it."
Last year, it emerged Senator Dastyari had allowed Chinese donors to pay a $1,670 travel bill and another $5,000 bill.
Dastyari also reportedly expressed support for China over the South China Sea dispute - a view contrary to Labor policy.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iranian-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Story</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dastyari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Dastyari Australian Story</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communications Minister Mitch Fifiled</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dastyari</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor Senator Sam Dastyari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Dastyari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cory Bernardi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South China Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
