<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411326295679741</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/02/11/52/couple-who-defamed-wedding-photographer-ordered-to-pay-damages</url>
  <title>Couple who defamed wedding photographer ordered to pay $1.2m in damages</title>
  <content>
A US couple who waged an online campaign against their wedding photographer have been ordered to pay her more than $1.2m in damages.

Texas couple Neely and Andrew Moldovan "wrongfully attacked" photographer Andrea Polito in a smear campaign that went viral online and also made news headlines, a court found.

The Moldovans hired Polito to take the photos at their wedding in October 2014 but got into a disagreement with her over what they claimed were "unreasonable fees", Dallas News reported.

Weeks after the wedding the couple contacted Polito asking when their photos would be ready.

Polito reminded them they needed to pick a cover image for their album. The cover image carried an extra $120 fee, a condition outlined in the contract the couple had signed.

But the couple objected to the cost and after emailing them, Polito said she had decided to absorb the cost to keep her customers happy. But when she contacted them days later she found out they had already called several news organisations.

The couple also made "disparaging and defamatory statements" on social media and on wedding blogs, claiming the photographer "cheated" and "scammed people" and that their photos were being "held hostage".

Related Articles

Polito said her business, which she spent 13 years building, was virtually destroyed overnight.

The photographer went from booking 75 and 100 weddings a year, to just two.

"People knew me and my reputation," she told Dallas News.

"I've shot several Dallas elites. All the name calling, all the bullying ... I was humiliated."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Moldovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moldovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neely</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Polito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polito</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas News</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
