<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411373540320812</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/business/technology/livetiles-raises-11m-for-growth/news-story/23bd697fb3195342cac084ce0ecd6eda</url>
  <title>LiveTiles raises $11m for growth</title>
  <content>
ASX-listed software company LiveTiles says it's accelerating global growth plans, after landing $11 million from institutional and sophisticated investors.
The New York-based software firm, which has an office in Sydney, said it had wanted $8 million but raised $11m with strong demand from existing and new shareholders.
The shares were placed at 18 cents, a 14 per cent discount to the last trading price. The raise was led by Blue Ocean Equities.
LiveTiles said it will also launch a share purchase plan to raise up to $1 million.
"We're very pleased to have received such strong support from new and existing shareholders, with the success of this raise providing strong validation of LiveTiles' rapid growth to date and our plans for the future," co-founder and CEO Karl Redenbach said.
"Strong demand for LiveTiles' offering has seen us grow annualised subscription revenue by 293 per cent in FY17 to $4.0 million.
"This additional capital will allow us to accelerate investment in sales and marketing across all regions to take advantage of our very large addressable market and strong sales pipeline."
According to Mr Redenbach LiveTiles is growing at six times the industry average subscription software growth of 44 per cent, with the surging revenue following a senior recruitment boom at LiveTiles. In April the company added former Hewlett-Packard and Microsoft executive Doug Caywood and former Wal-Mart executive Kendra Bluhm to spearhead the US expansion.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LiveTiles</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doug Caywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendra Bluhm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wal-Mart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Redenbach LiveTiles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Karl Redenbach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FY17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hewlett-Packard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Ocean Equities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
