<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411364950386052</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/domain/domain-news/location-canberra/retail-tenants-sought-for-molonglo-valleys-first-shopping-centre-in-coombs-20170802-gxnnar.html</url>
  <title>First look at Molonglo Valley's first shopping centre</title>
  <content>
Molonglo Valley's first shopping centre in  is a step closer to fruition with  and health services.

Tenants could be moving in as early as the end of the year, according to Burgess Rawson Canberra managing director Guy Randell, who is seeking expressions of interest for the tenancies.

"There's no defined time but we're negotiating with a whole range of people," Mr Randell said.

"It could be open before the end of the year or early next year, but the intention is for [all shops] to open together."

The Coombs shopping centre will have 128 parking spots.  Photo: Supplied

The .

Two applications were knocked back, but they were given the green light in August 2016, after improvements were made to the original design.

Mr Randell said the shopping centre and health facility were both quality developments that would bring much-needed services to the Molonglo Valley community.

Burgess Rawson is in the process of sourcing an operator for the 1000-square-metre supermarket and other ancillary retailers.

A gastropub, cafe and hair and beauty services are among the tenants being sought.

The nine retail tenancies for lease range between 88 and 243squaremetres and offer outdoor dining options for cafes and restaurants. The site includes 128 car parks.

Expressions of interest are also being sought from health professionals for the adjacent health and wellbeing facility.

The Coombs health and wellbeing facility will include a medical centre. Photo: Supplied

The facility, which is due for completion at the end of the year, has a total of 11 tenancies and five are available for lease.

A medical centre, opthamologist and childcare centre have already been secured to anchor the site. It will also include a vet, pharmacy and community centre.

A childcare centre is one of the anchor tenants.  Photo: Supplied

A gym, dentist and other complementary health providers will complete the facility and serve 2600 residents across  and Coombs.

It will be the first shopping centre for .

The district will be delivered in stages over a number of years and the population is expected to top 55,000.

Quarterly house price report

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coombs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy Randell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Randell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burgess Rawson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molonglo Valley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burgess Rawson Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
