<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411373540320905</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/west-beaches/10-million-expansion-to-meet-new-student-demand-in-adelaides-west/news-story/0b337429818f49f1e3334e2c7caa9b5e</url>
  <title>$10 million school expansion in Adelaide's west</title>
  <content>
PLANS have been lodged for a $10 million building at Nazareth Catholic College's Flinders Park campus to help cater for more students.
The college has submitted plans for the building to Charles Sturt Council and the Development Assessment Commission.
Under the plans, a two-storey building with general purpose classrooms would be built on the southeastern section of the site.
The building would cater for 202 extra students and help with the inclusion of Year 7 students into the campus from 2019.
The school will have an extra 230 students once Year 7's move onto the campus.
Acting secondary principal Jeff Sochacki said if plans were approved, work would start later this year.
"The additional building works at our Flinders Park Campus will increase the learning area and provide creative and flexible spaces to meet the needs of our wide student population," Mr Sochacki said.
"There will be increased opportunity for group work, the provision of different functional spaces, furniture and the ability for increased collaborative student learning.
"The new spaces will have the ability to change within two minutes to go from a more conventional area to one open space that will cater for 200 students at a house meeting."
A decision on the plans from both planning authorities is expected later this year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development Assessment Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Sturt Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 7</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Sochacki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Park Campus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sochacki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazareth Catholic College's Flinders Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
