<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411330590647109</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/technology/us-expands-13bn-military-base-in-south-korea/news-story/4d4e9d39875722ae25be50c9d03888fc</url>
  <title>US gives North Korea 13 billion reasons to worry</title>
  <content>
THERE are top notch facilities, a water park, schools and shopping.
The supermarkets look like any other in the world and fast food outlets, sporting fields and nearby restaurants offer punters everything they could possibly want.
But this isn't any ordinary city or town, it's a state-of-the-art $13 billion US army base in South Korea.
Camp Humphreys, known as United States Army Garrison-Humphreys (USAG-H), is located near Anjeong-ri and Pyeongtaek metropolitan areas - and thanks to a huge expansion project it's bigger than ever.
Along with apartment buildings and playgrounds it also has an 18-hole golf course, three fitness centres, and a 48-lane bowling alley.
According to the , the US and South Korea have been in talks for 20 years about moving the military base from Yongsan, in the middle of Seoul to Pyeongtaek, a rural city 100km south of Yongsan.
The 8th Army moved its headquarters here last month, and there are now around 25,000 people based here.
Further works are due to be completed at the end of this year. Once done Camp Humphreys is expected to house more than 1000 families and 45,000 people.
Four new schools and a military hospital due are also due to be completed later this month.
On its , Camp Humphreys promotes itself as the "most modern facilities the army has to offer anywhere in the world."
But Colonel Scott W Mueller, garrison commander of Camp Humphreys, told the  it was much, much more.
Colonel Mueller said state-of-the-art communications technology and a more "hardened" site meant the site was better protected against a possible North Korean attack.
"Down here we're a little bit further from the action, and that helps buy us some strategic decision space should anything happen," he said.
Camp Humphreys has several US Army tactical and direct support units including the 2nd Combat Aviation Brigade, elements of the 1st Signal Brigade, 501st Military Intelligence Brigade and the 65th Medical Brigade among others.
A 2014 statement released by USAG Humphreys public affairs office said it is .
It is also the largest construction and transformation project in the US Department of Defense's history.
"By moving into less congested southern areas of the peninsula, the US Army will improve readiness and efficiencies, while further enhancing its partnership with local communities," it reads.
The move and expansion has been many years in the making.
According to a 2014 piece in , the relocation has faced multiple delays due to funding and construction problems. The move was due to be made in 2008, but was postponed twice, in 2012 and 2016.
It also highlighted how Camp Humphreys is a huge part of the military's plan to close dozens of US bases in and around Seoul and consolidate its footprint in regional hubs.
STATE OF THE ART BASE
Home to the Desiderio Army Airfield, Camp Humphreys also supports various army, transportation, and tactical units.
Speaking on a YouTube video in July last year, Colonel Joseph C Holland, commander, USAG Humphreys, said those living here can expect great living conditions.
"Over the several years we built a new instillation here at Camp Humphreys, it's been designed to be soldier, family and pedestrian friendly," he said.
"We have beautiful living, working and recreation facilities that will make serving in Korea a wonderful experience."
Families who live here can choose from three, four and even five bedroom furnished apartments with parking, and many homes are close to schools, shopping and eating facilities.
TENSIONS MOUNT
The expansion of the garrison comes as tensions across the Korean Peninsula remain high following two intercontinental ballistic missile tests last month.
Just last week North Korean leader Kim Jong-un boasted his country could now strike any target in the US after carrying out its second ICBM test.
Both tests sparked an angry response from US President Donald Trump who called on China to do more to stop its rouge ally.
Just today influential Republican and foreign policy expert  than allow it to develop a long-range nuclear-armed missile.
However Secretary of State Rex Tillerson said the US doesn't want to topple the North Korean government.
"We do not seek a regime change, we do not seek a collapse of the regime, we do not seek an accelerated reunification of the peninsula, we do not seek an excuse to send our military north of the 38th Parallel," Mr Tillerson told reporters at the State Department.
"We are not your enemy ... but you are presenting an unacceptable threat to us, and we have to respond."
- with wires

This video features Camp Humpheys, the $11bn US army base in South Korea and describes it's features.

Welcome to Camp Humphreys
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of the Art</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secretary of State</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desiderio Army Airfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yongsan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Humpheys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Combat Aviation Brigade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Military Intelligence Brigade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States Army Garrison-Humphreys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Army</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Signal Brigade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyeongtaek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USAG Humphreys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anjeong-ri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colonel Scott W Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Department of Defense</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Humphreys</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seoul</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colonel Mueller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colonel Joseph C Holland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USAG-H</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICBM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Humphreys</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rex Tillerson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medical Brigade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
