<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411455144700704</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/markets/currencies/undaunted-by-rba-bulls-see-aussie-rally-toward-us85-cents-20170802-gxnnw9.html</url>
  <title>Undaunted by RBA, bulls see Aussie rally toward US85 cents</title>
  <content>
It will take more than just rhetoric to tame Aussie bulls as the currency hovers near a two-year high.
Unless the Reserve Bank's willing to signal it's ready to cut interest rates, anyone betting on the Aussie has little to fear, according to National Australia Bank and Westpac.

Up Next

Apple jumps, Dow hits record high

01:14

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Aussie dollar strength in play for RBA

Sean Callow, senior currency strategist at Westpac, discusses his outlook for the Australian dollar and the US dollar.

AMP's Nader Naeimi, who made the right bet buying the Aussie about eight months ago, said he will only switch to wagering against the currency if it climbs closer to US85 cents. Eaton Vance Investment Management said the currency will probably approach that level if iron ore extends its rebound and the greenback goes on slumping.
The RBA warned on Tuesday that a rising local dollar is set to subdue inflation and weigh down growth and employment. HSBC Holdings is among those saying that was actually a fairly mild reaction, considering the Aussie has rallied about US4 cents since policy makers' previous meeting in July.

"It was a quite a neutral statement," said Naeimi, who heads a dynamic investment fund in Sydney at AMP Capital, which oversees $US120 billion. "If the Australian dollar pushes up toward US85 cents, then that would get the RBA more concerned."
He has started trimming his positions in the currency but won't start shorting it until it gets to about US85 cents.

The Aussie bought US79.54 cents at 11:30 am in Sydney, after reaching a two-year high of US80.66 cents last week. The currency has surged more than 10 per cent this year, hampering the central bank's efforts to guide the economy's transition to growth led by education and tourism instead of iron ore and coal. Governor Philip Lowe and his deputy, Guy Debelle, began to ramp up their rhetoric on the local dollar late last month.Photo: Glenn Hunt
The RBA maintained its forecast for the economy to expand around 3 per cent in the next couple of years after leaving its benchmark rate at a record low of 1.5 per cent. It will release its updated growth and inflation projections in its quarterly statement on Friday.
Swaps traders expect the RBA to hold rates through the first half of 2018, betting on a hike only in the latter part of the year. As a result, Australia's bond yield premium over Treasuries will likely narrow as the Federal Reserve tightens policy, Naeimi said.
"Interest-rate differentials will move further and further against the Aussie after another US rate hike, so a further appreciation in the Aussie will be self limiting," he said.
Australia's dollar is 16 per cent overvalued, the most among Group-of-10 currencies after New Zealand's, according to a measure of purchasing-power parity that takes into account consumer-price gains.
Leveraged funds raised their net Aussie long wagers about a week ago to the most since April 2016, according to the Washington-based Commodity Futures Trading Commission. That leaves the currency vulnerable should the US dollar rebound or if there's a spike in risk aversion, said Sean Callow, a senior currency strategist at Westpac in Sydney.
Westpac expects the Aussie to advance to as high as US81.50 cents, before retreating to the "high 70s."
"Today doesn't seem to be the day to call a high in the Aussie, with the RBA statement unthreatening," Callow said on Tuesday. "But big picture, we see the Aussie as stretched, well above fair value."
Eaton Vance continues to favour a stronger Australian dollar, in particular against the kiwi as the bigger economy outperforms and leads the RBA to run a more hawkish policy than the Reserve Bank of New Zealand, said Eric Stein, Boston-based co-director of global fixed income at the firm.
If the Australian economy slows and inflation is low though, the RBA will turn more dovish and will try to rein in the currency's strength, he said.
"If terms of trade keep going up, they will be OK with a stronger Australian dollar," Stein said. "They would be more concerned if there is a disconnect between the two."
Bloomberg 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$120</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy Debelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US81.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naeimi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSBC Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Callow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eaton Vance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>19</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington-based Commodity Futures Trading Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP's Nader Naeimi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US79.54</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Stein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US80.66</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eaton Vance Investment Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US $85</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor Philip Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
