<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411373540320844</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north/alert-as-cops-hunt-tradie-sicko-who-exposed-himself-to-teenage-girl-at-bundoora-bus-stop/news-story/54cd82c188a3473e676ee18d7e872c73</url>
  <title>Man exposes himself to girl at bus stop</title>
  <content>
A TRADIE creep who allegedly exposed himself to a teen girl at a Bundoora bus stop in broad daylight is being hunted by police.
Police said the alleged pest approached the victim at a bus stop on Settlement Rd, Bundoora about 2pm on Wednesday, July 26.
The man paced back and forth in front of the teen several times before stopping close to the victim.
She said he exposed his genitals and then started to rub them.
The man did not say anything to the victim, who screamed and left the area.
The man then ran down Settlement Rd before heading along Brownhill St.
Police patrolled the area after but were unable to find the man.
The man is described as caucasian, aged between about 16 and 19, about 175cm with a thin build.
At the time he was wearing an orange fluoro "tradie"-style hooded jacket without logos, dark blue workpants and dark work boots.
His clothing was also described as being very clean.
Detectives from Transit CIU are investigating and appealing for anyone who saw the man in the area at the time, or has other information, to come forward.
Anyone with information is urged to contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or submit a confidential crime report online at

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Settlement Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundoora</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transit CIU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownhill St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
