<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411364950386035</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:38</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/11/37/it-is-not-over-more-dominoes-to-fall-in-o-dog-cocaine-ring-claims-fbi-source-jackpot</url>
  <title>'It is not over': More dominoes to fall in O-Dog cocaine ring, claims FBI source 'Jackpot'</title>
  <content>
The high-rolling gambler who helped topple an international drug smuggling ring trafficking large shipments of cocaine into Australia claims a woman is the new target of the ongoing FBI-NSW Police operation.

R.J. Cipriani, an FBI source codenamed "Jackpot", told nine.com.au that despite dozens of arrests in Australia and the US, including a Californian cocaine kingpin, that "it is not over".

"There's going to be more people dropping," Cipriani said.

"One thing I can guarantee you, the feds didn't get everybody. I guarantee you there is more to come."

Cipriani identified a woman he claimed was now in the cross hairs of the FBI.

In 2015, Californian cocaine boss Owen 'O-Dog' Hanson and 21 associates in his violent illegal gambling and drug smuggling crew were arrested in the US, after a joint FBI-NSW Police operation.

At the same time, four men in Australia, including music promoter Andrew McManus, were arrested by Strike Force Fairlawn detectives.

Related Articles

McManus, who pleaded guilty to attempting to pervert the course of justice, and three men had been allegedly been linked to a suitcase stuffed with $702,000 that was discovered in 2011 by NSW Police in a Sydney hotel room.

NSW Police, investigating alleged drug trafficking between Mexico, the US and Australia, would later make a series of other raids in Sydney and Newcastle, including the arrest of a figure known as Dr Octopus 88.

Roberto Zalapa, a 31-year-old from affluent Sydney neighbourhood Potts Point, was the man behind the Dr Octopus alias, police claim.

As Strike Force Fairlawn gathered momentum, Rio Tinto executive, Bennet Schwartz, and a University of Newcastle business student, Craig Phelps, were accused of being part of an international drug syndicate.

A Blackberry mobile in Schwartz's possession allowed police to hijack the phone's messaging app to track down Dr Octopus, according to court records.

Last September, a Double Bay man named Jonathan Fagan, 31, was also caught by the Strike Force Fairlawn operation.

Police accused Fagan of smuggling up to 160kg of cocaine into Australia in 16 shipments, allegedly orchestrated by Owen Hanson's US operation.
Fagan's lawyer has said his client would be fighting all the charges.

Cipriani claimed some suspects in the US and Australia must be "flipping", pointing to the pattern of ongoing arrests.

"You've seen  this one and that one. Clearly there are people rolling on other people," Cipriani told nine.com.au.

"It is not over."

Cipriani, a high rolling US gambler known as Robin Hood 702, was used by Hanson in an attempt to allegedly launder huge sums of money in Sydney's Star City casino.

But, in 2011, Cipriani lost $2.5m over several days on the Star City black jack tables.

When he returned to Los Angeles empty handed, Hanson blew up and demanded Cipriani pay back the missing millions.

Cipriani refused, leading to months of intimidation and threats from Hanson's crew towards him and his actress wife, .

After his mother's grave was desecrated by an LA private investigator hired by Hanson, Cipriani made a call to the FBI.

In September 2015 Hanson and 21 of his US-based associates were arrested.

Hanson and all but one of those indicted have pleaded guilty to various charges involving illegal gambling, international drug running and extortion.

Kingpin Hanson faces a potential 20-year sentence when he appears in a San Diego court next month.

Detectives from the NSW Police Organised Crime Squad intend to seek Hanson's extradition once his sentence has been served.
FOLLOW:
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owen Hanson's US</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Potts Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fagan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Phelps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2015 Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Octopus 88</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O-Dog' Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Fagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schwartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Double Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberto Zalapa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McManus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R.J. Cipriani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennet Schwartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police Organised Crime Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O-Dog</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robin Hood 702</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Octopus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BlackBerry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI-NSW Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cipriani</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strike Force Fairlawn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Owens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Star City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McManus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
