<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411373540320925</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-02/deledio-came-close-to-giving-up-on-2017</url>
  <title>Deledio came close to giving up on 2017</title>
  <content>
Calf problems nearly saw Brett Deledio sit out the entire 2017 season

AT HIS lowest moments, Brett Deledio thought about writing off his debut season with Greater Western Sydney. 

Deledio was in sparkling pre-season form until he pinged his right calf in February, and had so many setbacks with it in the following months that he admits he "lost count", but it was when his 'good' left calf went in June that he truly contemplated flicking the bails for the year.

The 30-year-old said his wife Katie and young daughter Milla kept him sane, and the support of his family and friends back in Melbourne, his new teammates, and GWS medical staff, allowed him to see an end to his injury worries in 2017. 

Speaking ahead of his long-awaited Giants debut on Saturday against Melbourne, Deledio said he was a lucky man.

"Thoughts definitely did go through my head that maybe I'd be better off just cooling the heels for the rest of the year and getting it right," he said.

"But I've got an incredibly supportive family and a good bunch of friends, and I've leant on them quite a bit. 

"I've always looked at it like 'what other options have I got?' and we're a great chance to go a long way this year, so I wanted to give myself every shot to be a part of that.

"There was always that motivation so I never wanted to give up." 

More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
