<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411412195027209</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/business/aurizon-jobs-foreign-drivers-may-be-recruited-despite-recent-redundancies/news-story/af0afa8993fdc7397d49926698214251</url>
  <title>Foreign drivers may be recruited despite sackings</title>
  <content>
AURIZON could bring foreign train drivers to Australia, new Federal Government documents have revealed.
Aurizon's Western Australian subsidiary, Australia Western Railroad Pty Ltd, has been included in a list of new labour agreements released after calls for transparency of the visa system,  reports.
Reports suggest foreign workers could be offered permanent residency as part of the agreement.
Company-specific agreements can be made on a case-by-case basis where a "genuine skills or labour shortage for an occupation exists" and cannot be filled by Australian workers or other migration arrangements.
"Employers are required to have made recent, genuine efforts to recruit, employ or engage Australian citizens or Australian permanent residents," the government's website states.
Train drivers are not on the Federal Government's list of eligible skilled occupations for 457 visas.
It comes after Aurizon announced in June it would close its Rockhampton rollingstock workshop resulting in the loss of 181 jobs.
Another 126 workers are expected to lose their jobs at Bluff, Gladstone and Stanwell, including train drivers.
Aurizon has been contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurizon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stanwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aurizon's Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Western Railroad Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
