<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411322000712347</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/melbourne-airport-extreme-landings-caught-on-camera/news-story/70693b82a24b69052ba5741efe9adecc</url>
  <title>Planes battle wild winds at Tulla</title>
  <content>
LANDING a passenger jet is difficult enough.
Doing it in 100km/h winds would given even the calmest pilot sweaty palms.
Aircraft landing at Melbourne Airport were rocked around by wild winds on .
Footage on  shows the tough conditions that made landing at Tullamarine a challenge for commercial pilots and a frightening experience for passengers.
Amazing landings at Melbourne Airport.

Amazing landings at Melbourne Airport

Jetstar passenger Therese Allaoui told the Herald Sun she was stuck on the tarmac at Melbourne Airport for more than an hour on Saturday after returning from a holiday in Bali because of the winds.
"Everyone's pretty restless now and they've started handing out water and turned the entertainment on for free so people are occupied while it all happens," Ms Allaoui said.
"We were told that because of the strong winds, the planes haven't been able to refuel or unpack the luggage which is why we can't disembark the plane.
"The plane is bouncing around on the tarmac, it's almost like we're on a rollercoaster or some sort of theme park ride."
Gusts of up to 130km/h swept through the state on Saturday morning, prompting severe weather warnings as a strong cold front crossed the state.
The State Emergency Service received more than 800 calls for help.
Of the calls, 300 were for building damage.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Allaoui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Therese Allaoui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tullamarine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Emergency Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Airport</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
