<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411459439668210</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coasts-ultimate-one-stop-shop-for-custom-furniture/3207873/</url>
  <title>Coast's ultimate one-stop-shop for custom furniture</title>
  <content>
A TIRED old industrial building will soon be transformed into one of the Sunshine Coast's ultimate one-stop-shops for custom furniture and interior decor.
It's the dream of RAW Sunshine Coast owners Katie Bishop and Chris Rawlins, who have embarked on a journey to expand their burgeoning business operations into a central hub.
The business currently has a store in the Sunshine Plaza and an off-site workshop, however, RAW Sunshine Coast will consolidate operations into a large new premises located in the Maroochydore Industrial Zone.
The new location, at 23 Kayleigh Dr in Maroochydore, will house the business's custom furniture workshop, showroom and offices.
In a special twist, owner Katie Bishop said the new home also had the potential to include a space for a coffee shop.
"It's kind of been a bit of a dream of ours for the last three years," she said.
"We've been searching for a free-standing building to house all of our operations in one and finally something came up."
She said RAW would remain in the Plaza until the new home was established, which was expected to be open by the end of August.
She said work was well under way to create an inviting space for customers.
"It's a big industrial shed and it has needed a bit of love to bring it up to date," she said.
"It's really exciting to get it all back together and just to let people actually see our furniture we make in a real life setting."
Mrs Bishop said customers would also be able to explore RAW's full range of furniture, available timber and finish options.
She said a viewing window from the showroom into the workshop would also allow visitors to catch a glimpse of the furniture making process.
There had been plenty of interest from other businesses looking to set up at the new location according to Mrs Bishop.
"We've had several inquiries already and we've had enquiries from other business so we're trying to squeeze possibly two (retail) spaces in there to create a collective hub," she said.
To coincide with the opening of the new location, RAW have teamed up with a number of brands to give three lucky customers the chance to share in over $5,000 worth of interior decor products.
To enter, customers need to spend a minimum of $50 in one transaction at RAW Sunshine Coast (in-store or online) and place the entry form into the barrel. The competition runs from the July 28 to September 30.
Latest weather data points to big dry
SELANGOR Private Hospital has celebrated its 70th birthday.
"I'm absolutely heartbroken to hear the two humpback whales died."
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayleigh Dr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Bishop</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SELANGOR Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RAW Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Industrial Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Rawlins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Bishop</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plaza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
