<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411244691299714</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/euthanasia-illness-derails-campaign-of-highprofile-advocate-andrew-denton-20170802-gxnjob.html</url>
  <title>Euthanasia: Illness derails campaign of high-profile advocate Andrew Denton</title>
  <content>
The push for assisted dying in Victoria has been dealt a blow, with one of its most high-profile advocates, Andrew Denton, being forced to withdraw from the campaign to have multiple bypass surgery.
In what some proponents have described as a "disaster" as the euthanasia debate heats up this month, the TV personality has been diagnosed with advanced heart disease and will be required to undergo surgery shortly.

Up Next

Tent city inappropriate: Berejiklian

00:34

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Andrew Denton to 'light a fire' on euthanasia

'There are over 100 million people in the world who have full choice about what happens to them at the end of life. None of them Australians,' says TV Producer Andrew Denton.

The diagnosis means that the Go Gentle Australia director - who set up that organisation specifically to achieve law reform around the country - may be absent at a critical juncture: as Premier Daniel Andrews' bill for assisted dying is introduced and thrashed out in the Victorian Parliament.
However his office has played down concerns, saying his work towards voluntary assisted dying would continue under its campaign manager Paul Price, a former senior adviser in the Baillieu Liberal Government.

"The Go Gentle campaign continues in full force," Mr Price told Fairfax Media. "In the next weeks and months we will be marshalling the support of the more 75 per cent of Victorians who want voluntary assisted dying to become law."
Mr Denton set up Go Gentle Australia last year - almost two decades after watching his father die a slow and painful death from heart failure - in a bid to convince politicians to give terminally ill people the right to a physician-assisted death in strictly defined circumstances.

In that time, he has become one of the leading public faces of the "yes" campaign, appearing at community forums, across the airwaves, and alongside Health Minister Jill Hennessy to talk to delegates at Labor's state council.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But the debate is likely to intensify even further in coming weeks, when the bill on assisted dying is introduced in the Lower House, paving the way for the most heated policy fight Premier Daniel Andrews faces ahead of next year's election.Photo: Edwina Pickles
"It's terrible for Andrew [Denton], and a disaster for the broader campaign," said one supporter of the bill.
In a sign of that the battlelines have well and truly been drawn, leaders of the Catholic, Anglican, Lutheran, Greek Orthodox and Coptic Orthodox churches placed an open letter in the Herald Sun on Monday saying that assisted suicide represented the "abandonment" of the terminally ill and sent a "confusing message" about the value of life.
Right to Life has also stepped up its opposition, sending out leaflets in nine marginal electorates - which looked as though they came from the sitting MP in each seat - suggesting Mr Andrews was attempting to sanction suicide to "save healthcare dollars".
If you are troubled by this report, experiencing a personal crisis or thinking about suicide, you can call Lifeline 131 114 or beyondblue 1300 224 636 or visit  or
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coptic Orthodox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lower House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baillieu Liberal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwina Pickles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Jill Hennessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Denton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go Gentle Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifeline 131 114</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek Orthodox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go Gentle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lutherans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV Producer Andrew Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
