<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411592583656261</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-02/all-silent-on-leverdemons-trade-speculation</url>
  <title>All silent on Lever-Demons trade speculation</title>
  <content>
Jake Lever has reportedly met with Melbourne officials to discuss a trade

IN-DEMAND Adelaide defender Jake Lever has reportedly met face to face with Melbourne officials in recent weeks.

Lever has reportedly also attracted interest from Collingwood and the Western Bulldogs, while the Crows have tabled him an offer.

A Crows spokesman told AFL.com.au the club wouldn't comment on the reports about Lever's meeting with the Demons. 

"The club does not provide on-going commentary about contract negotiations and/or speculation in the marketplace," the spokesman said. 

The Demons also weren't prepared to comment about the ongoing speculation on Lever. 

Crows captain Taylor Walker said he hoped Lever would remain at the club. 

"We provide a culture and an environment that hopefully when he comes to make that decision, he chooses the right one and he wants to stay at our footy club," Walker said. 

Lever is off-contract at the end of this season, but as he's not a free agent, a trade would need to be agreed for him to land at his club of choice. 

The Crows also face a battle to retain promising forward Mitch McGovern, who booted a goal after the siren to secure a draw against Collingwood last weekend.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lever-Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEMAND Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
