<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411588288688925</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/pisasale-barrister-fined-contempt-court/3207890/</url>
  <title>Pisasale barrister fined for contempt of court</title>
  <content>
THE barrister who claims he asked former Ipswich mayor Paul Pisasale to carry $50,000 cash for a client, was today fined $4000 for a contemptuous remark he made to a magistrate.

Barrister Sam Di Carlo, while representing a client in a bail application last year, said to Brisbane Magistrate John Costello: "You don't do things according to law".

Chief Justice Catherine Holmes said in the Supreme Court today it was particularly reprehensible that the comments were made by a barrister with 26 years of experience.

"It was not just an unseemly insult to a judicial officer but an affront to the court he represents," Justice Holmes said.

Outside court, Mr Di Carlo said the fine was fair punishment, he had crossed the line in his conduct, he had apologised and had conceded his comment was contemptuous.

"I misbehaved on this occasion," Mr Di Carlo said.

The Attorney-General last year asked the Supreme Court to "punish" Mr Di Carlo for contempt of court.

Justice Holmes said the court was a democratic institution, an arm of government and courts played a role in democracy and needed to be given the respect due to them in that capacity.

She said prior to making the comment to Mr Costello, Mr Di Carlo had been distinctly uncivil to the magistrate in a previous bail application for the same client.

On the occasion of the contempt, Mr Di Carlo, had asked Mr Costello to stand aside from hearing the bail application.

After Mr Costello said he was adjourning the application until two days later, after a public holiday, there was an exchange and Mr Di Carlo said the words that amounted to contempt.

She said it implied that the magistrate did not apply the law according to his judicial oath.

Justice Holmes said while she acknowledged Mr Di Carlo was motivated by the perceived unfairness of his client being detained in custody, lawyers were obliged to behave with courtesy and respect.

Magistrate John Costello had written to the Attorney-General last year asking for her to consider prosecuting Mr Di Carlo for the comments.

The Chief Justice gave Mr Di Carlo three months to pay the fine.

In June, Mr Di Carlo claimed $50,000 in cash found on Mr Pisasale by federal police at a Melbourne airport was for a client of his.

The claim came a day after Mr Pisasale resigned as mayor after 13 years, citing ill health and two days after his home and office were raided by police.

Mr Pisasale was granted bail when he appeared in court on June 21, charged with extortion and two other offences relating to an alleged assault which he plans to defend.

Mr Di Carlo told The Courier-Mail the the money was for a settlement agreement for a Chinese client and that Mr Pisasale was acting as a friend by agreeing to carry it to Brisbane.

Tourist track takes toll with plenty of motorists caught out
Latest weather data points to big dry
SELANGOR Private Hospital has celebrated its 70th birthday.
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Magistrate John Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Di Carlo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pisasale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pisasale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Di Carlo</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-3.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Holmes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Justice Catherine Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Costello</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate John Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pisasale</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SELANGOR Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
