<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411493799407034</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/compulsory-literacy-and-numeracy-test-mooted-for-vce-students-20170801-gxn362.html</url>
  <title>Compulsory literacy and numeracy test mooted for VCE students</title>
  <content>
Victorian students may soon have to meet minimum literacy and numeracy standards if they want to leave school with a VCE qualification.
In what could signal the biggest shake-up of the high school certificate in decades, Fairfax Media understands that the state's curriculum authority is investigating a new compulsory literacy and numeracy test that students must pass before graduating.Photo: Rob Young
It is also examining whether students should have to achieve certain NAPLAN results in order to graduate with the VCE or its vocational equivalent, VCAL.
Industry bodies including the Victorian Chamber of Commerce and Industry are calling for the changes amid concerns that too many young people are finishing school with poor skills.Photo: Chris Hopkins
A similar model already operates in NSW and Western Australia.
In NSW, year 9 students must score in the top three of 10 NAPLAN levels in reading, writing and numeracy to pre-qualify for their high school certificate.

If they do not reach this benchmark, they have multiple opportunities between year 9 and year 12  to meet the standards via online tests.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The possible Victorian changes are being considered as new preliminary NAPLAN data, released on Wednesday, showed that the literacy and numeracy skills of Australian students had stagnated for the fourth year in a row.
Victoria continued to have high average achievements, and our year 3 students were the country's top performers in all areas of the test except for spelling.
Victorian students also topped the country in year 5 and 7 writing and numeracy.
In Western Australia, the new minimum standards have been credited with improving students' literacy and numeracy skills, boosting the proportion of students with top NAPLAN results and enhancing the reputation of year 12 qualifications.
But the changes have also been controversial - and have been blamed for turning NAPLAN into a high stakes test, discouraging students from staying at school, and triggering anxiety.
The Victorian Curriculum and Assessment Authority and Victorian Education Minister James Merlino refused to say whether they were considering minimum benchmarks for the VCE.
Their spokesmen said there was currently no proposal for new literacy and reporting arrangements as part of year 12.
"The introduction of any changes would involve extensive consultation with schools, principals and key stakeholders," they said.
Stakeholders have not yet been consulted but Fairfax Media understands that work is taking place inside the VCAA about what a proposal may look like.
Mr Merlino said that he was always looking at ways to improve student outcomes and the latest NAPLAN tests showed that Victorian students were "ahead of the pack".   
Australian Curriculum, Assessment and Reporting Authority chief executive Robert Randall said standards should be built into high school certificates, but it was up to the states to determine what they were.
"Discussions are going on with each of the relevant authorities about the importance of literacy and numeracy standards," he said.
"They are observing what WA and NSW have done and wondering whether they would do the same thing or adopt a different approach ... we should set expectations and standards and we should work with young people to achieve them."
Victorian Chamber of Commerce and Industry chief executive Mark Stone said minimum literacy and numeracy standards would lift the skills of school leavers with VCE qualifications.
This would help students move into employment or further study, and give employers certainty, he said.
"With minimum standards in place, business and employers would be assured that young employees with this qualification have achieved a consistent level of competency in literacy and numeracy skills," he said. 
Australian Industry Group head of workforce development Megan Lilly said businesses often raised concerns about the poor literacy and numeracy skills of school leavers.
"They are constantly commenting about deficiencies in their literacy and numeracy skills," she said.
"It can compromise safety. They might struggle with a simple calculation or measurement, and if you are talking about a production environment, that can lead to excessive wastage."
She supports the introduction of minimum literacy and numeracy standards in high school certificates, but said struggling students needed additional help reaching those benchmarks.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assessment Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Lilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Curriculum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Randall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCAA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hopkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VCE</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Chamber of Commerce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reporting Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merlino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Industry Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Curriculum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Education Minister James Merlino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
