<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411248986267212</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/tennis/serena-williams-i-suffered-racism-on-court-20170801-gxngvd.html</url>
  <title>Serena Williams: I suffered racism on court</title>
  <content>
Tennis star Serena Williams has revealed how she was a victim of racism, both on and off the court, and was told she could never accomplish her dreams because of the colour of her skin.
Williams, former world No 1 and winner of a record 23 Grand Slam singles titles, spoke out as she campaigned for equal pay after it emerged black women in the US are paid just 63 cents for every dollar a man makes.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
"I am in the rare position to be financially successful beyond my imagination. I had talent, I worked like crazy and I was lucky enough to break through," wrote Williams. "But today isn't about me. It's about the other 24 million black women in America. If I never picked up a tennis racket, I would be one of them; that is never lost on me."
In her essay - published in Fortune magazine on Monday, Black Women's Equal Pay Day - Williams urged: "Be fearless. Speak out for equal pay. Every time you do, you're making it a little easier for a woman behind you.
"Most of all, know that you're worth it. It can take a long time to realise that. It took me a long time to realise it. But we are all worth it. I've long said, 'You have to believe in yourself when no one else does'."
Williams, 35, who announced her engagement to Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian last December, is pregnant with her first child. She plans to return to competitive tennis next year.

She wrote: "Growing up, I was told I couldn't accomplish my dreams -because I was a woman and, more so, because of the colour of my skin.
"In every stage of my life, I've had to learn to stand up for myself and speak out. I have been treated unfairly, I've been disrespected by my male colleagues and - in the most painful times - I've been the subject of racist remarks on and off the tennis court."

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In 2016, Williams attacked inequality in tennis after Raymond Moore, who was then CEO at the Indian Wells venue in California, said women's tennis was riding on the coat-tails of the men's game. Mr Moore later resigned.
Earlier this year, Williams asked John McEnroe to "respect" her after he said she would "be, like, 700 in the world" if she played against men.
"The cycles of poverty, discrimination, and sexism are much, much harder to break than the record for Grand Slam titles," wrote Williams. "For every black woman that rises through the ranks to a position of power, there are too many others who are still struggling."
She explained that she has recently joined SurveyMonkey's board of directors and that its most recent findings showed 69 per cent of black women perceive a pay gap.
"Data doesn't lie," wrote Williams. "It just gives a number to the gap women feel every day."
The Telegraph, London
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raymond Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexis Ohanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serena Williams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Slam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williams, 35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John McEnroe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SurveyMonkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Women's Equal Pay Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
