<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411545339015353</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/fashion/70yearold-grandmother-with-phenomenal-figure-hits-out-at-critics-claiming-shes-had-surgery/news-story/3f1c64ccbd72ac21df0cd76d7cd95c58</url>
  <title>'I have maintenance like a car'</title>
  <content>
70-YEAR-OLD Carolyn Hartz - who made headlines around the world with her youthful looks - has hit back at online critics who believe her figure isn't simply the result of a sugar-free diet.
Ms Hartz spoke of how her lifestyle, mindfulness, exercise regimen and diet were all contributing factors to her figure.
But viewers weren't buying it, claiming she must've had some help.
"Her forehead can't even move," one viewer posted to Twitter.
"Who is this woman fooling?," another added.

Telling me that womans 70 & no had work done & its all down to quitting sugar nope im jst no buying it ....
Now, the grandmother-of-four has hit back at critics - claiming she has had maintenance "just like a car or house would".
"I have always said I have maintenance," Ms Hartz told news.com.au.
"Like a car or house would, the body needs repairs and maintenance.
"But that is my business ... I don't go around asking people what work they've done.
"I make my own decisions and I'm responsible for those. If people want to have their opinions on surgery or Botox, they can talk like that - that's their decision, not mine."

. The Perth local said her looks and figure were in part thanks to giving up sugar, after she was diagnosed as a pre-diabetic 29 years ago.
"I was a sugar addict," she explained.
"Sometimes I'd have half a cheesecake in the morning, and chocolate in the afternoon.
"I was in denial and I knew my addiction would catch up with me one day. So I changed my diet, but that's not 100% the reason I look good.
"It's to do with attitude, exercise, sleep, diet and meditation as well."
When asked if she'd had any cosmetic procedures, Ms Hartz denied to disclose - but said she "isn't opposed to anything anyone wants to do to their body".
"Whatever I do, it's my choice ... I am only responsible for myself," she said.
"Life is short. You need to be happy. I love being 70 and I don't read the comments people say."
After giving up sugar, Ms Hartz switched to using sugar alternative xylitol, which her company now imports. She wrote a cookbook, titled Sugar Free Baking, and now urges people to reject the sweet stuff from their diet.
She hopes her lifestyle and recipes will inspire people to make the same dietary change she did.
"I could see what the effects of diabetes two was going to do to me," she said.
"When you're frightened of something you should change, and I did because I didn't want to be unhealthy."
Speaking of her skincare regimen, Ms Hartz said she's been using products since she was 17-years-old.
"I never go to bed with makeup, and I've always used nightcream," she said,
"Ever since I was 17, I always used sunscreen.
"I don't sunbake, and I sit under an umbrella. I always wear a shirt and safety pin the collar to protect my neck.
"I exfoliate twice a week, and try to have a moisturising mask at least once."
"Even if you have good genes, you need to eat and sleep properly. It can't just be down to genes."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Botox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hartz</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YEAR-OLD Carolyn Hartz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sugar Free Baking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
