<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411545339015368</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/thesourcesa/full-set-of-penfolds-grange-up-for-adelaide-auction/news-story/ee36e2ec828a4bff1a8ed9a292fb4c81</url>
  <title>Full set of Penfolds Grange up for grabs</title>
  <content>
Watch rare footage of Penfolds Grange creator the late Max Schubert revealing how his revered red was born and what makes it so special. Thanks to Penfolds and Milton Wordley.

A RATE full set of Australia's most famous wine, Penfolds Grange, has been valued at more than $250,000 for its auction on Sunday at du Plessis Mile End rooms.
The set, pieced together over 25 years by an anonymous Adelaide building industry figure, is considered to be in pristine condition and contains 62 bottles stretching from 1951 to the latest release 2012 vintage.
The collection, posted on the du Plessis website on Monday night, has already attracted strong interest from more than six serious collectors, auctioneer Mark du Plessis said.
"They're keen because it is so hard to find a full set of Grange," Mr du Plessis said.
The early inquiries have come from Australian collectors but it's expected international interest will build before the auction date.
"We like to sell it in South Australia where the wine originates, and we'd like it to stay in South Australia," Mr du Plessis said.

Other Stories

"Penfolds Grange is not just an Australian icon, it's a South Australian icon.
"A set like this is of rare historical importance."
Details and photos of the set are available as Lot number 167
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plessis</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Schubert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penfolds Grange</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milton Wordley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plessis Mile End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
