<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411502389341804</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/rugby-league-world-cup-league-legend-darren-lockyer-backs-storm-centre-will-chambers-for-australias-campaign/news-story/f53ded8d5c429d47a1d9e1d0ddc9be18</url>
  <title>Lockyer backing Chambers for World Cup</title>
  <content>
Kangaroos' selector Darren Lockyer insists Territorian Will Chambers is a "good chance" of lining up in Darwin's Rugby League World Cup quarter-final.
Australia will play either Scotland, Samoa, Tonga or New Zealand in the NT on November 17, the first time they have done so in their 109-year history.
Lockyer said Chambers was likely to hold his place after impressing in Australia's Anzac test win over New Zealand in May.
"(Australian coach) Mal (Meninga) is a big fan of Will so he is a good chance of being there if he is fit," Lockyer told the NT News. "He was outstanding in the recent State of Origin series and he's coming from the Melbourne Storm, which is a good system.
"You'd expect Melbourne to go deep into the finals, so if Will is part of the squad I am sure he will want to play in front of his home crowd."
Lockyer - who holds the record for most Australian caps with 59 - said bringing a quarter-final to TIO Stadium was a fantastic initiative.
"For the people of Darwin it will be great to see the Cameron Smiths, the Slaters, the Cooper Cronks," he said.
"It's good that it's a quarterfinal but I just think the Kangaroos playing (in Darwin) is great." No matter the Kangaroos' opponent, Lockyer said he expected an open contest. "Whether it's Tonga, Samoa, New Zealand or Scotland, they are exciting to watch," he said.
"A lot of those players play in the NRL every year and they seem to be improving. I think the Kangaroos will obviously go into the game as favourites, but the fans will see a good brand of football."
Lockyer said the Kangaroos would use the disappointment of the 2008 World Cup - when they were beaten in the final by New Zealand - as a reminder they will have to be at their best.
"They will use it (2008) as a reference. It will be used to remind them that if we are not at our best, we will get beaten," he said.
"(Johnathan) Thurston is a big loss, he's been such a big part of that team for a decade and Matt Scott. You often get players at the end of the club season that need to have surgery, I'm sure there will be another few more that can't come, but whenever Cameron Smith is the captain I always know the team will play well, regardless of who's in the team."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Anzac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NOVEMBER 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockyer</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meningas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin's Rugby League World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territorian Will Chambers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Lockyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonga</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TIO Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
