<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411541044047968</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/moreton/new-free-bus-service-being-trialled-to-help-people-get-to-caboolture-markets/news-story/4a3eb77a5e971652a8cae7e34c3612cf</url>
  <title>New free bus service</title>
  <content>
A NEW free bus service will start in Caboolture on Sunday.
The service is being trialled to help more people get to the Caboolture Country Markets.
It will run from Morayfield Station at 8am, 8.45am, 9.30am with five minutes between stops. The return from the showground leaves at 10.15am, 11am, noon.
To the showgrounds the route is: Morayfield Station, Morayfield Shopping Centre, Caboolture Park Shopping Centre, King Circle, Caboolture Station, Caboolture Hospital and Caboolture Showgrounds.
From the showground the route is: Caboolture Hospital, Caboolture Station, Caboolture Park Shopping Centre, King Circle, Morayfield Shopping Centre and Morayfield Station.
The service is being run by Caboolture Show Society for the Sunday markets.
"We have a lot of people wanting to go to the market, but don't have a car," Caboolture Show Society secretary Michelle Goullet said.
"So we were thinking of ways to help them. Caboolture Bus Lines actually contacted us last year about this (service)."
The bus will have room for two wheelchairs and the service will be trialled for two months.
Caboolture Country Markets are held every Sunday, 6am-noon at Caboolture Showgrounds with more than 500 stalls. Visit caboolturecountrymarkets.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture Station</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morayfield Station</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morayfield Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture Show Society</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture Country Markets</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture Showgrounds</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture Park Shopping Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Circle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle Goullet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caboolture Bus Lines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
