<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411592583656265</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/woman-mauled-death-dog-boarding-kennel/3207884/</url>
  <title>Woman mauled to death by dog at boarding kennel</title>
  <content>
A WOMAN has been mauled to death by a dog in Perth.
Reports suggest the attack happened in Southern River, a residential suburb in the city's southeast. The woman is believed to be aged in her 50s.
The West Australian reports police got called to a property with boarding kennels for dogs about 1.30pm local time (3.30pm EST).
St John Ambulance officers declared the woman dead after she received life threatening injuries as a result of the dog attack.

Police statement on fatal dog attack at a boarding kennel in Southern River

Gosnells Council has seized the dog, reportedly a mastiff. PerthNow reports the death is not being treated as suspicious and a report is being prepared for the coroner.

News.com.au has contacted Gosnells Council for comment.
The tragic incident comes just weeks after a Melbourne man was attacked at a beach in Brighton East.
Cam McIntyre said he was lucky to be alive after dog, believed to be a labrador-rottweiler cross, attacked him and left him with a gash in his neck just millimetres from a major artery.

The dog bit his hand and neck and he was treated with 40 stitches.

Tourist track takes toll with plenty of motorists caught out
Latest weather data points to big dry
SELANGOR Private Hospital has celebrated its 70th birthday.
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosnells Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PerthNow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam McIntyre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SELANGOR Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern River</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
