<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411579698754196</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/brotherly-advice-shaped-zak-jones-sydney-swans-future-20170802-gxnp0a.html</url>
  <title>Brotherly advice shaped Zak Jones' AFL future</title>
  <content>
Melbourne co-captain Nathan Jones acted more as sounding board than spruiker during younger brother Zak's AFL contract dilemma.
In-demand hard nut Zak Jones ended months of speculation this week, signing a two-year contract extension with Sydney.Photo: AAP
Zak insists he never seriously considered shifting home to Victoria, in part due to the advice of Nathan.
"I've spoken to him a fair bit about it," he said at the SCG on Wednesday.
"We joked around with it a fair bit. He bounced a few things off me and told me what I've got to look at.
"I wasn't too sure but once we had those discussions, then I felt confident with what I wanted to do.

"Obviously it would have been great to play with my brother but I'm my own player."
Nathan has endured plenty of low points during his 235 games at the Demons; 22-year-old Zak has already featured in twice as many finals as his 29-year-old sibling.
But Nathan's commitment never wavered. The veteran pondered last month that "when you've invested so much of your life, physically and emotionally, why jump ship and bail out at the hardest point in time?".
Zak, who was drafted by the Swans in 2013, is eyeing a third straight finals campaign and didn't face quite the same dilemma.
But, like Nathan, the speedster spurned a multitude of suitors.
"I like being loyal to the team," he said, having been one of the Swans' most consistent players in a season that started with six consecutive losses.
"They're a loyal team to me. They drafted me and that's something big for me."
The Swans trained behind closed doors on Wednesday, when skipper Josh Kennedy was among a raft of players attempting to prove their fitness.
Kennedy was restricted by a tight hamstring during the club's loss to Hawthorn last week and would be sorely missed if he's unable to face Geelong in Friday night's crunch clash.
The midfielder warmed up with the main group then shuffled off to do some low-key handball drills before reporters were asked to leave.
The loss of Kennedy would be a big blow but Sydney's hopes of winning the all-important midfield battle in Geelong were boosted by Patrick Dangerfield's one-game suspension.
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak's AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennedy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak Jones' AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
