<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411493799407025</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/12/19/tony-jones-catches-up-with-subzero-on-melbourne-cup-winners-29th-birthday</url>
  <title>Melbourne Cup winner Subzero is a true Australian sporting hero</title>
  <content>
We often bandy around the term "heroes" in sport and most of the time the term is applicable.
Who could argue with the likes of Don Bradman, Wally Lewis, Leigh Matthews, Rod Laver, Dawn Fraser or Ian Thorpe being categorised as true heroes of Australian sport?
But there's another who can rightfully lay claim to such status.
An old grey bloke who reached the pinnacle of his career in the early 1990s, but it's been post career that he's become a standout in Australian sport.
1992 Melbourne Cup winner Subzero.
Now, "Subbie" might not have the track record of Phar Lap, but the impact he's had on the lives of Australians has been remarkable.
As those of the equine variety celebrate their birthdays this week, Subzero reached the remarkable age of 29 - that's around 83 in human years.

Related Articles

In many ways, Subbie would consider himself human.
Even in his dotage, the champ has a full calendar of visits to nursing homes, schools, hospitals and industry launches.
To see Subzero interact with humans is something quite remarkable and, often, quite moving.
I recall several years ago, Subzero visited a hospice for children.
One by one, with handler and best mate Graham Salisbury by his side, Subbie walked over to the ill children to offer comfort.
The smiles it brought to the faces of those children was something to behold.
Towards the end of the visit, a young girl, around 10 years of age, was brought into the lounge area where Subzero was holding court.
So ill was the girl, her bed was wheeled into the room.
She lay there as the big grey walked over to her - walked over, not led over - and lowered his head towards her.
This giant of an animal then rubbed his nose gently against the girl's face.
He knew this girl needed some special attention and as those in the room watched through glassy eyes, he stayed at her bedside as her face lit up.
It was a beautiful moment and it reinforced the view of many that this horse knew.
He knew.
It's just one example of the work he carries out.
The nursing home visits are among his most popular, a break from the long, lonely days faced by many of the elderly.
Some actually backed Subzero on that first Tuesday of November 1992, when he captured the Melbourne Cup for trainer Lee Freedman.
By the end of his career he'd won more than $2 million from his 48 starts which also included victories in the '92 South Australian Derby and the Adelaide Cup.
In retirement he became a clerk of the course, thriving in the race day environment and the chance to mingle with his growing number of fans.
He finished his official duties in 2008 when arthritis set in.
So bad had the condition become the following year, he was only hours away from being put down.
Incredibly, the big grey rallied and defied the odds, just as he did at Flemington on that magical day in 1992, to virtually check himself out of the veterinary hospital.
Subbie was going home. Indeed, Subbie was going back to work.
Within days, he was back on the float resuming his "duties".
In 2014, the racing industry honoured Subzero with induction into the Hall Of Fame.
Down the track, legend status surely beckons.
Not that it's necessary, most racing fans would consider the now 29-year-old a legend already.
And as for the little girl at the hospice who shared that precious moment with Subzero, she sadly passed away only days later.
Her father wrote to Graham Salisbury thanking him for the joy that Subzero brought to his daughter.
A touching tribute to a hero who continues to touch the lives of so many.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Laver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Matthews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Thorpe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawn Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Derby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flemington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phar Lap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Bradman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subbie</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Salisbury</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee Freedman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday of November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
