<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411583993721500</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/breaking-news/hsc-standards-improved-naplan-results/news-story/438b8e6fe80b38fefc3bb990d02ee917</url>
  <title>HSC standards 'improved NAPLAN results'</title>
  <content>
NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian has credited new minimum standards required for HSC candidates for the state's improved NAPLAN results.
NSW year 9 students have risen to first in the nation for numeracy and spelling, while overall the state's students ranked in the top three for all tests in all years.
"I'm pleased that the NAPLAN results have improved on last year and have put NSW at the head of the pack in a number of key areas across the nation," Ms Berejiklian told reporters at a high school in Sydney's south on Wednesday.
From 2020 minimum standards for literacy and numeracy are required for students to receive the HSC and the premier says that is the main reason NSW improved its performance this year.
"We don't apologise for making the standards higher," she said.
Ms Berejiklian also cited a targeted approach to improving underperforming schools as a reason for the 2017 result.
The strategy targeted schools and students who had not met previous expectations, providing resources to specific students, Education Minister Rob Stokes says.
He also defended the government's decision to enforce stricter standards on HSC candidates, arguing the extra work it required would help them into the future.
"We make no apologies for insisting at the end of 13 years of education. We want every child to be equipped with minimum literacy and numeracy standards to prepare them for life, to prepare them for the workforce," Mr Stokes said.
While scores in NSW were generally positive, Mr Stokes said he was concerned about grammar results in year 5 students.
"That's one aberration that I'm concerned about and I've already spoken to the education department about things we can do in relation to looking at those results."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stokes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HSC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Rob Stokes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
