<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411712842742032</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/aretha-franklin-reveals-results-of-drastic-weight-loss/news-story/a406dff20cd32aecf3e44a6ea952a844</url>
  <title>Aretha Franklin's dramatic weight loss</title>
  <content>
QUEEN of Soul Aretha Franklin is half the woman she used to be.
The Respect and Say A Little Prayer singer, 75, looked slimmer than ever in a new backstage picture that emerged on Instagram this week.
Franklin is currently midway through what she says will be her final concert tour, having battled undisclosed health problems in recent years.
"I am retiring this year," the star told a Detroit TV station in a telephone interview earlier this year. "I will be recording, but this will be my last year in concert. This is it."

Franklin  with fellow music legend Dionne Warwick, accusing her of making up a story that she was Whitney Houston's godmother, even though the alleged offence happened five years ago at Houston's funeral.
"She blatantly lied on me ... fully well knowing what she was doing," Aretha Franklin said in a phone interview.
Franklin addressed what she claimed was a "libellous" statement against her made five years ago at Houston's funeral. At the time, Warwick told funeral-goers that Franklin was there and introduced her, but then realised she wasn't in attendance.
When asked if she wanted an apology from Warwick, she said: "I don't care about her apology, at this point it isn't about an apology, it's about libel."
She added: "We've never been friends and I don't think that Dionne has ever liked me."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Say A Little Prayer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUEEN of Soul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aretha Franklin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dionne Warwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dionne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitney Houston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detroit TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Houston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
