<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411665598101229</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/media-and-marketing/advertising/domain-kicks-off-new-advertising-campaign-following-court-battle-with-rea-group-20170802-gxnmyq</url>
  <title>Domain kicks off new advertising campaign following court battle with REA Group</title>
  <content>
It's the catchphrase News Corp-backed REA Group desperately tried to stop rival property classifieds group Domain from using. But, with the legal battle lost, Fairfax-owned Domain is launching an ad blitz centred on 'Australia's #1 Property App'.
The new campaign is centred around 'Australia's #1 Property App' and will be pushed to more than 2000 outdoor advertising panels and will include television commercials, radio partnerships with Fairfax-majority owned Macquarie Radio, and online content series, such as the parody Avalon Now created by Domain in 2015.
Domain, which owned by Fairfax Media, publisher of The Australian Financial Review, used advertising agency DDB Sydney for the campaign.
The legal battle between Domain and REA began in February 2016 following Domain's advertising campaign featuring the phrase 'Australia's #1 Property App'.

REA was quick to sue, alleging Domain had breached consumer law. Of the seven advertisements published by Domain, while two were found to have made false or misleading representations, according to a ruling in the Federal Court in Melbourne.

The court ruled Domain can use the phrases 'Australia's #1 Property App' and 'Best Listings' - however Domain is stopped from using the 'Most Listings' phrase without a prominently featured source for that claim.
In June, Domain was ordered to pay 75 per cent of REA's costs, while REA was ordered to pay 25 per cent of Domain's costs.
However, Domain was awarded damages while REA was not.
REA was also ordered to pay Domain for the cost incurred to the Fairfax-owned property hub for cancelling, removing or changing advertisements that were subject to the court case and later found to not be misleading or deceptive by a judge.

Both Domain and REA are key pillars of growth for their respective publisher owners who are battling a digital advertising environment dominated by Google and Facebook.
Last week, , and increased REA's 12-month target price.
When Fairfax releases its full-year results in a fortnight it is expected to update investors on its plans to separately list Domain, keeping 60 per cent to 70 per cent of the company and giving the remainder to existing shareholders.
It comes after a months-long saga with two private equity firms looking to capture Domain by buying Fairfax.

TPG Capital had a proposal of $1.20 per share for Fairfax, valuing the company at $2.7 billion, while Hellman & Friedman had a non-binding offer of $1.225 to $1.25 per share, valuing Fairfax at $2.87 billion.
Both decided against lodging a formal bid at the deadline imposed by the Fairfax board at the end of June and the company cut off conversations with the pair.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avalon Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REA Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax-majority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friedman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax-owned</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TPG Capital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DDB Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rea</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hellman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's #1 Property App</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Listings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp-backed REA Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax-owned Domain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
