<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411502389341813</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/technology/science/space/nasa-set-to-test-detection-and-tracking-system-during-asteroid-flyby-in-october/news-story/e9d4a077ed0a125e6e2fce4d1f5e5ecc</url>
  <title>NASA set to test detection and tracking system during asteroid fly-by in October</title>
  <content>
Due to increases in technology, the number of asteroids detected has increased dramatically in recent years.
A TEAM of asteroid hunters who scan the skies looking for potentially hazardous near-Earth objects, asteroids and comets heading in our direction (or more specifically, within 48 million kilometres of Earth's orbit) are set to test a system that could save us all from a deadly impact.
At NASA, the Planetary Defense Coordination Office is responsible for the program which is effectively designed as a constant celestial lookout, while also planning and co-ordinating a response to any possible asteroid impacts.
And the US space agency is spruiking its work ahead of an October test which amounts to a practice run for intercepting incoming asteroids.
Lindley Johnson heads up the planetary defence office at NASA and says researchers have detected a vast majority of potentially hazardous objects in our celestial neighbourhood.
"After almost 20 years of searching, over 93 per cent of the near-Earth objects larger than one kilometre are already discovered. The focus is now on finding 90 per cent of those larger than 140 meters," he said.
"Almost 7,700 of these are now being tracked, but we believe there are still over twice that number out there to be found."
Not only is NASA hunting and monitoring asteroids and comets but it is also crafting ways to deflect or even blow them up if they come to close for comfort.
We're hunting for near-Earth asteroids, while also working on ways to defend our planet against them. See how:
"Asteroid impacts are predictable and preventable. If we can find them before they strike, we can precisely predict their paths and time of possible impact. And we now have the space technologies to divert them," Mr Johnson said in a NASA blog post.
And, of course, there's what NASA described as "the Hollywood option" made famous by the 1998 film Armageddon in which Bruce Willis saves humanity by drilling into the surface of an oncoming asteroid and detonating a nuclear bomb.

The real life plan is a little less dramatic than that, but would no doubt be a hugely ambitious mission if it ever came to pass.
"It involves exploding a device close enough to an asteroid that the super-heated surface material blows off, creating a powerful, rocket-like push," Mr Johnson said.
"Though quite effective if time is short, it would take a lot of co-ordination and approval not only within the US government, but also with the international community," he said. For obvious reasons, "this is a last resort measure."

There is no shortage space rocks in our neighbourhood.Source:Supplied
THE TEST RUN
NASA scientists are currently prepping for the moment  passes no closer than 6,800 kilometres from Earth on October 12.
The fly-by will help scientist test NASA's Asteroid Detection and Tracking Network, bolstering its ability to mitigate future threats.
Asteroid 2012 TC4 is estimated to be between 10 and 30 meters in size - slightly larger than the space rock that hit Earth's atmosphere near Chelyabinsk, Russia, in February 2013.
However it has not been seen since its 2012 discovery when it sped past Earth at about one-fourth the distance from Earth to the moon. It has been too distant and too faint to be detected over the last five years, NASA says.
"This is the perfect target for such an exercise because while we know the orbit of 2012 TC4 well enough to be absolutely certain it will not impact Earth, we haven't established its exact path just yet," NASA scientist Paul Chodas said last week.
"It will be incumbent upon the observatories to get a fix on the asteroid as it approaches, and work together to obtain follow-up observations than make more refined asteroid orbit determinations possible."

NASA's First Asteroid-Sampling Mission Lifts Off
1:42

NASA on Sept. 8 launched the first U.S. mission to collect and return an asteroid sample, in hopes of learning more about how the solar system coalesced and life came to be. Photo: AP

September 9th 2016
a year ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Technology - syndicated/

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindley Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Johnson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sept</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U.S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armageddon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Willis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Technology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracking Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA's First Asteroid-Sampling Mission Lifts Off</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Chodas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planetary Defense Coordination Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA's Asteroid Detection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TEST RUN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASA</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TC4</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelyabinsk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
