<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411712842741996</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/business/technology/xref-raises-fresh-funds/news-story/68c8d68caaa8cdad520d62ea8b42fd16</url>
  <title>Xref raises fresh funds</title>
  <content>
Xref Limited has raised $7.5 million in the market with investors taking a shine to the human resources technology company's software platform.
The equity injection comes via Xref issuing 12.5 million shares at 60 cents, a 1.6 per cent discount to its last traded share price.
According to Xref, the fresh funds will be used to expand the company's global footprint and a new marketing drive to bolster existing sales channels.
Xref CEO Lee-Martin Seymour said that the placement had received strong support from existing and new shareholders.
"We are building growth and scale, and have a great opportunity to expand in new regions and leverage channel relationships in those markets," he said.
Launched in 2011, Xref listed in February last year through a reverse takeover of King Solomon's Mines, raising $4m with an eye to raising its client list.
Xref's platform automates reference-checking, a critical piece of the overall hiring process, that involves collecting data from an employer, candidate and referee. The platform aims to not only save businesses time but also deliver better quality data and benchmarking to ensure better hiring decisions are made.
It's a pitch that so far has been picked up by the market.
Xref increased sales by 137 per cent in fiscal 2017 compared to the previous year and its customer base and retention levels have been growing steadily quarter-on-quarter. Sales for the full year came in at more than $4.1m, a year-on-year increase of 137 per cent.
The company reported record quarterly sales of $1.6m for the fourth quarter, more than double the $710,000 posted for the same period in fiscal 2016.
Xref's client list includes NBN Co, English Premier League champions, Chelsea Football Club, Xero, Caltex and Fitness First.
Company CTO Tim Griffiths said the platform was now scalable enough to facilitate easy entry into new markets.
"Our channel strategy allows us to on-board new clients without the need for a large sales team," he added.
The placement was managed by Bell Potter Securities. Settlement of the placement is expected to occur on August 7 2017 with new shares allotted on August 8.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xref</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 7, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell Potter Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caltex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xero</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CTO Tim Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Solomon's Mines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xref CEO Lee-Martin Seymour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xref Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitness First</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
