<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411721432676812</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/innovation/the-subtle-transformation-of-apple-from-phone-pioneer-to-fee-collector-20170802-gxnjtb.html</url>
  <title>Apple's future: More about fees, less about phones</title>
  <content>
Apple, the world's biggest company, has been undergoing a subtle transformation in recent years. From the maker of iconic devices, to... a giant fee collection vehicle?
The company's latest quarterly results, released on Wednesday morning Australian time, underscore this point.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Apple jumps, Dow hits record high

Stronger-than-expected sales of iPhones have driven Apple's quarterly revenue higher.

Apple signed off on a $US8.7 billion ($10.95 billion) quarterly profit on revenue of $45.4 billion. Investors liked the result. Shares were up 6 per cent in after-hours trading on the Nasdaq.  
Perhaps the most striking aspect of the result - or at least of what the company trumpeted - was record revenue from its  "services" division (think apps and content) of $US7.3 billion. That was up 22 per cent from a year earlier, a growth rate only beaten by "other", a catch-all used for its Apple TV, watch and accessories income. "Other", the company's smallest segment, posted revenue of US$2.7 billion. 

The iPhone 8 is expected to be announced in the next few months and will no doubt be a huge hit. But, since pretty much everyone in developed markets has a smartphone by now, whether Apple will be able to generate the levels of growth it achieved in the past remains an open question. 

That's why the company has, for a while now, been pinning its hopes on increased revenue from the content and apps that people use on its devices to power its future. 

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Services revenue eclipsed sales from iPads and Mac computers last year. It's now Apple's second-biggest earner behind the iPhone, and according to Credit Suisse, could account for 30 per cent of the company's profits by 2020.Photo: Bloomberg
But hang on! Apple is actually pretty terrible at making apps and content, isn't it?  
Well, yes. For years, people have raved about its devices, and moaned about its software. Its maps product is considered vastly inferior to Google's. Likewise its hyped streaming music service is considered well behind Spotify in terms of quality and usability. iCloud, its online storage service, has all sorts of problems. 
Meanwhile, Apple's first foray into original entertainment, a Shark Tank style reality TV show called "Planet of the Apps" featuring Gwyneth Paltrow, Jessica Alba and others, has been widely panned by critics. 

So how is Apple making so much money from all of this?  The answer is, at least in part, that it probably isn't. Instead, Apple is quite likely generating significant services revenue simply by taking a cut on apps and content made by other people. 
"The biggest problem with services is the complete lack of transparency," says Arnhem Investment Management portfolio manager Theo Maas. "Where the growth [in services] is actually coming from is a good question."

The company doesn't break down the composition of its services revenue. But we do know the company generally takes a 30 per cent cut on the subscription revenue generated from apps downloaded through app store.  
This is known as the ''.  It's hard to stomach for many (especially since Apple itself is criticised for not paying enough actual tax to governments in countries like Australia.) 
Some big app providers, such as Spotify, have gone to  to get around the Apple tax. Others, such as Netflix, have reportedly been able to secure . But most just grin and bear it. Apple has an installed base of more than 1 billion devices. Its users tend to spend more than those in rival smartphone ecosystems. For most, this simply is too big and lucrative a market to ignore. 
Interestingly, one app developed by Apple that has received largely positive reviews (although it's not widely available in Australia due to a dispute with the major banks) is Apple Pay. 
Perhaps that is not so surprising. In collecting huge sums from rival app makers through the 30 per cent "tax",  Apple is in some ways, itself becoming a gigantic payments processing vehicle.

Amazon makes the backend every startup uses. Microsoft makes Office 365. Google pretty much runs online advertising. just takes 30%.

That is amusing. Australia's banks are desperately trying to position themselves as technology companies - exhibit A being  about an "agile" transformation, whatever that means.
At the same time,  a significant part of Apple's business is becoming fee collection. You know, kind of a bit like a bank.  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US7.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office 365</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spotify</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shark Tank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple Pay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theo Maas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhem Investment Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gwyneth Paltrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iCloud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$8.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Alba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
