<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411455144700701</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/world-travel/europe/family-thrown-out-of-hotel-pool-because-their-burkinis-were-against-portuguese-culture/news-story/881157d99e6a031c1a28ee359f6c9324</url>
  <title>Family thrown out of hotel pool because their burkinis were 'against Portuguese culture'</title>
  <content>
Internet Pranksters Carry Out Burkini Ban Social Experiment on British Beach
3:03

A group of internet pranksters carried out a staged social experiment on a British beach in a video published on August 27, in which a "police officer" confronts a burkini-wearing woman and tries to forcibly remove it from her. A man and a woman from a group known as "Trollstation" played the roles in the experiment, which aimed to gauge public reaction to the burkini. Female onlookers at the beach came to the woman's aid, while others filmed, before the hoax was revealed. A French court this past week suspended a ban on burkinis that was imposed by a town in the country's south. Credit: YouTube/Trollstation

August 28th 2016
a year ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Family thrown out of hotel pool because their burkinis were 'against Portuguese culture'.

Amanda DevlinThe Sun

Share

A BRITISH family say they were left "humiliated" after being banned from wearing burkinis in the swimming pool while on holiday in Portugal.
Maryya Dean and her sister-in-law Hina claim they were told they "must wear a bikini to follow Portuguese culture" before being out thrown out by hotel staff.
The 36-year-old mum from Chessington, London also accused a maintenance worker at the pool in Albufeira of using her nine-year-old daughter, who was wearing a swimming costume, as an example of what she should be wearing.

Maryya Dean and her family were told they "must wear a bikini to follow Portuguese culture" before being out thrown out by hotel staff.Source:Facebook
"The man started making cultural references and said that Portuguese people wear bikinis and so should we," she told the Mirror Online.
"I was compared to my nine-year-old daughter who was told to stand up out of the pool to see what she was wearing which I found completely rude. I was told I should wear that to swim."
Ms Dean said the whole thing humiliating.
"We were embarrassed as we came out of the pool with four children and people were watching us like we'd committed a crime."
Ms Dean was on a week-long holiday with her four children, sister-in-law and other relatives when she was forced to defend her choice to wear a covered swim suit in the Algarve.
Her sister-in-law said the pair were wearing a three quarter length top and leggings, which were waterproof, for "religious, cultural, confidence and comfort reasons".

Burkinis is a type of modesty swimsuit for women which cover the entire body apart from the face.

A burkini is a type of modesty swimsuit that women often prefer for religious, cultural or comfort reasons.Source:istock
Last year many places in France banned women from wearing burkinis on the beach.
In May, Austria became the latest European country to make it illegal for women to wear burkas in public despite huge controversy.
MPs approved the ban on full-face veils among a series of measures aimed at integrating migrants - including compulsory language lessons.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda DevlinThe Sun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burkini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Internet Pranksters Carry Out Burkini Ban Social Experiment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryya Dean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube/Trollstation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Austria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Dean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirror Online</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chessington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Algarve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trollstation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portuguese</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
