<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411283346006237</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/beauty/face-body/celebrity-makeup-artist-hung-vanngo-on-the-biggest-beauty-mistakes-women-make/news-story/437f1377813963faff3a631f725badd3</url>
  <title>Celebrity makeup artist Hung Vanngo on the biggest beauty mistakes women make</title>
  <content>
Selena Gomez is one of makeup artist Hung Vanngo's most famous celebrity clients. He created this look for the premiere of her Netflix show 13 Reasons Why. Picture: Hung Vanngo/Instagram

Share

SCROLLING through Instagram in 2017, you could be forgiven for thinking elaborate glitter eyes and thick, heavy brows are the makeup trends everyday women want to wear.
But a quiet show of defiance against the over-the-top and gimmicky looks filling our feeds is currently taking place in the beauty world. Because really, who has time to  in the morning?
Leading the charge is celebrity makeup artist Hung Vanngo, who regularly paints the faces of some of Hollywood's biggest names.
Vanngo is famous for making women look like the most gorgeous versions of themselves - with glowing skin, a bold eye, a bushy brow - and little else.
are regularly treated to selfies from Kendall Jenner, Selena Gomez and Karlie Kloss, showing off Vanngo's handiwork.

A post shared by Hung Vanngo (@hungvanngo) on

A post shared by Hung Vanngo (@hungvanngo) on

"My aesthetic is making women more beautiful. It's really my thing," Vanngo told news.com.au in an interview to promote his new global artist ambassador role with Marc Jacobs Beauty.
"I appreciate all the artistic and fun makeup, but at the end of the day, every woman wants to look their most beautiful. That's really how I approach makeup nowadays in my work," he said.
Born in Vietnam, Vanngo migrated to Canada and moved to New York in 2006, where he assisted on fashion shoots before transitioning into event and red carpet makeup.
His client roster is impressive - think Katy Perry, Emily Ratajkowski, Ashley Graham and Jennifer Lopez - and their sultry selfies have earned Vanngo a spot among Instagram's most popular beauty accounts.

He's done celebrity makeup for the Met Gala, the Oscars and countless red carpet events, where his clients have one request: make me look beautiful.

A post shared by Hung Vanngo (@hungvanngo) on

So for those of us at home without Vanngo's talents, he says if we avoid making these five common makeup mistakes, we'll be on our way to Selena-worthy glam.
1.  Your foundation doesn't match your skin tone
"I think the most common mistake is definitely the foundation not being the right colour. I think that trying to match a shade is key," he said. Hot tip: ask the makeup counter for a sample and test it in natural light.
2. You haven't blended everything properly
"Blending the foundation and blending the makeup is key," he said. "It doesn't matter if you want to wear a heavy contour or an almost bare face. Everybody is different. But whatever your look, it needs to be well blended to look good."
3. You stick to boring, dull eyeshadow colours
"People should realise a little colour does give a very nice lift to the face. When the colour is too neutral, you look a little flat," he said.
"That's why I like to experiment with more colours. Of course I love brown, but I like more warm brown colours. I like to experiment. It gives so much life to the face that greys or nudes or taupes."
4. You only use your fingers, not brushes
"For blush and for lips you can use fingers, but for eyes, yes, [brushes are] essential. We [Marc Jacobs Beauty] just came out with three new eye brushes [The Crease, The Shadow and The Smudge]," he said.
"Those three are key for people to create a beautiful smoky eye. It's important because the position you cannot get from the finger."
5. You've just got too much makeup on
"Sometimes people have a little too much of everything. Do a strong eye or strong lip then a little less on the eyebrows," he said.
"I think if you put too much eye, too much lip, you have to balance it out. Where do you think is the focus? Pick one."

A post shared by Hung Vanngo (@hungvanngo) on

rebecca.sullivan@news.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smudge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hung Vanngo/Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Met Gala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Ratajkowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanngo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vietnam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reasons Why</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katy Perry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kendall Jenner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Lopez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selena Gomez</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netflix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karlie Kloss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selena-worthy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hung Vanngo</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Jacobs Beauty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
