<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411669893068532</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/13/37/melbourne-collision-divides-viewers-over-who-is-at-fault</url>
  <title>Collision on a Melbourne street divides viewers over who is at fault</title>
  <content>
Dashcam footage of a collision on a Melbourne street is dividing viewers - and the hosts of TODAY Extra.
The video, uploaded to Facebook yesterday, shows a P-plater attempting to merge lanes to pass a row of parked cars in Carnegie in the city's south-east.
Both cars appear to speed up as they cross the intersection before the P-plater attempts to merge into the right-hand lane, instead hitting the other car and coming to a stop.
The dashcam owner posted the video, blaming the P-plater for speeding up rather than slowing down to merge behind.
Debate has ensued as others have been quick to slam the driver for not slowing down to let the P-plater in.
"Technically the P-plater is in the wrong as it is not a merge but rather changing lanes... but this collision could have been avoided. The dash cam car identified early what the P-plater was doing and had ample time to slow and allow room for the car to change lanes," one Facebook user said.
 "The dashcam driver is in the wrong as the P-plater clearly was in front so they had right of way! Dashcam driver is supposedly meant to give way," said another.

Related Articles

The hosts of TODAY Extra were also left divided.
"You (the dashcam owner) are dragging along a main street trying to get ahead of the P-plater," co-host David Campbell said.
"Isn't it the rule that if you are in front, you are not at fault?" presenter Davina Smith asked.
"I would have thought the dashcam driver is right because that is the lane that has right of way and the P-plater on the left should slow down to merge behind her," co-host Georgie Gardner said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>P-plater</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davina Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Today Extra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgie Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carnegie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
