<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411807332023853</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/mick-fanning-to-ride-wave-of-mercedes-benz-ute-pop/3207909/</url>
  <title>Mick Fanning to ride wave of Mercedes-Benz ute popularity</title>
  <content>
HE'S been a world champion, ridden some of the globe's best waves and even wrestled a great white shark...but soon Mick Fanning will be wrangling a luxury Mercedes-Benz ute.
The surfing legend has been named a brand ambassador for Mercedes-Benz and it's new X-Class ute due in Australia next April.
"Sitting in the X-Class for the first time was a real thrill. As soon as I saw it I thought it has the style and design of a Mercedes-Benz and the power and versatility that I want in a vehicle," Fanning said
"I have a very active lifestyle and as a surfer it's pretty natural to have an interest in the ocean and the environment. Mercedes-Benz Vans have vehicles like the X-Class and Marco Polo Activity, which encourage people to get outdoors. I'm always trying to influence others to experience the thrill of nature. At the end of the day, I can't wait to throw my boards in the back and take it down the beach."
Mick Fanning has been named an ambassador for Mercedes-Benz and the X-Class ute.
Mercedes-Benz Vans Australia and New Zealand managing director Diane Tarr said Fanning was an ideal choice for Mercedes-Benz Vans and for the X-Class specifically.
"Australians are buying more utes than ever before, there were just under 191,000 utes sold here last year, representing 16 per cent of overall new vehicle sales," she said.
Mercedes-Benz will launch the new X-Class ute early in 2018.
"With this market growth, we believe there is a new kind of ute buyer, not only a tradesman who needs a ute for work but someone who is active and wants a vehicle that also supports their lifestyle.
"Mick perfectly embodies the Australian lifestyle that the ute has been designed for. Surfing is a sport which requires a vehicle that can get you to the ultimate surfing spots and also provides sufficient cargo space and towing capacity to take all your boards and wetsuits with you. The X-Class has been designed with the Australian landscape in mind so it can take you wherever the waves are, without compromise and with all the gear you need."
Mercedes-Benz will launch the new X-Class ute early in 2018.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz Vans Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fanning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-Class</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Fanning</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diane Tarr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Polo Activity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz Vans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
