<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411760087383056</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Asia Pacific Defence Reporter</source>
  <url>http://www.asiapacificdefencereporter.com/articles/1225/Luerssen-briefs-over-600-Australian-SMEs-on-SEA-1180-opportunities</url>
  <title>Luerssen briefs over 600 Australian SMEs on SEA 1180 opportunities</title>
  <content>
One of the world's leading shipbuilders, Luerssen, has shown more than 600 Australian small to medium-sized enterprises how they can benefit from the Australian Government's Offshore Patrol Vessel (OPV) project.

2nd Aug 2017

Luerssen briefs over 600 Australian SMEs on SEA 1180 opportunities

One of the world's leading shipbuilders, Luerssen, has shown more than 600 Australian small to medium-sized enterprises how they can benefit from the Australian Government's Offshore Patrol Vessel (OPV) project.

The international ship designer and builder has so far completed industry briefings in six cities, detailing how Australian businesses can tap into a lucrative global supply chain.

With its Australian partners ASC and Forgacs / Civmec, the 142-year-old company outlined the many subcontracting opportunities to flow from the OPV program, which will see a total of 12 vessels built in Adelaide and Perth.

Luerssen - which has exported more than 300 warships around the world - teamed up with its partners ASC and Forgacs / Civmec as well as its major subcontractors L3 Australia, Penske and SAAB Australia to hold the briefings in Sydney, Melbourne, Adelaide, Perth, Cairns and Darwin.

"The opportunities for SMEs across the entire country from the Australian Government's continuous shipbuilding program, include in the construction of the vessels, contributing supplies, in shipyard services, in future sustainment work and in supporting industries," said Luerssen Defence Managing Director Dirk Malgowski.

"In Germany we calculate that for every one job we create in the shipyard, four further jobs are created in other businesses."

"We see significant benefit in partnering with Australian SMEs, and opportunities for them to participate in a new era in Australian shipbuilding."

Newgate Communications Pty Limited
"We are a subcontracting company, it is in our DNA."

Luerssen told the industry briefings that it had been looking to establish a base outside of Europe to design and build warships for the export market.

"Hearing about the continuous shipbuilding program we saw the possibility to contribute to the creation of Australia's sovereign shipbuilding capability and to establish an export-led industrial base."

"Our decision to establish our local export-base here in Australia was in part because we knew of the strength of Australia's local industry and ability to deliver the services and supplies necessary for construction," Mr Malgowski said.

Luerssen is one of three shortlisted tenderers for the Royal Australian Navy's SEA1180 Phase 1 Offshore Patrol Vessel Project.

If selected by the Commonwealth for the SEA1180 program, Luerssen will be the designer and prime contractor for the entire program and will subcontract the construction work of the vessels to its Australian partners ASC and Forgacs / Civmec. Fully supported by Luerssen, ASC and Forgacs / Civmec will not only be executing the construction and completion work, but will also subcontract a large proportion of supplies and works to local industry.

"The ASC Shipbuilding and Forgacs joint venture is delighted to be supporting Luerssen in its bid for the OPV project," said Mike Deeks CSC, MD Forgacs Marine and Defence.

"We applaud Luerssen's approach in engaging local suppliers and subcontractors and recognise the importance of working with Australian companies to ensure a quality outcome for the Royal Australian Navy."

 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Civmec</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penske</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OPV</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASC Shipbuilding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian Navy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forgacs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian SMEs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luerssen</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aug 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Malgowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Deeks CSC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMEs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newgate Communications Pty Limited</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saab Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Government's Offshore Patrol Vessel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEA 1180</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>L3 Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MD Forgacs Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian Navy's SEA1180 Phase 1 Offshore Patrol Vessel Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luerssen Defence Managing Director Dirk Malgowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
