<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411755792415610</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/13/56/andrew-denton-diagnosed-with-advanced-heart-disease</url>
  <title>Andrew Denton diagnosed with advanced heart disease</title>
  <content>
Former TV host Andrew Denton is expected to undergo multiple bypass surgery after being diagnosed with advanced heart disease.

The illness means Denton will need to temporarily step back from his campaign to legalise euthanasia, Fairfax Media reports.

The 57-year-old TV personality has been a vocal proponent of euthanasia and set up the organisation Go Gentle Australia in order to campaign for law reform over the issue.

Denton quit his work in TV in order to devote himself to the organisation, 20 years after watching his dad die a slow and agonising death from heart failure.

Denton's ill health comes at a critical time in the euthanasia debate with Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews' bill for assisted dying set to be introduced in state parliament.

Go Gentle Australia's campaign manager Paul Price, a former senior adviser in the Baillieu Liberal government, moved to play down fears Denton's absence would set back their campaign.

"The Go Gentle campaign continues in full force," Mr Price told Fairfax Media.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baillieu Liberal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Denton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go Gentle Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go Gentle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gentle Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
