<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411712842742056</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/13/32/man-to-serve-just-three-months-in-jail-for-bashing-a-bus-driver</url>
  <title>Man to serve just three months in jail for bashing bus driver</title>
  <content>
A 30-year-old man will spend just three months in jail as punishment for the brutal bashing of a bus driver and a violent outburst on paramedics.
Liam Cooper Scorsese  pled guilty to seven charges from two separate incidents in Southport Magistrate Court.
It was a polite question over parking, in the heart of the Gold Coast, that sparked the violence in what the court found to be the most serious charge of assault.
Pulling into Cavill Ave in Surfers Paradise with tourists on board, the bus driver asked the occupants of an illegally parked car "Excuse me, Are you going to be much longer?"
The pair then abused the bus driver, dragging him down the stairs by the feet, before the onslaught of blows began.
And it didn't end there, dashcam recorded the two men hurling threats when the bus driver tried to call for help.
"Hey brother if you ring the f---ing police, I've got your number plate, I know exactly where you are."

Related Articles

Magistrate Andrew Sinclair, in condemning Scorsese's savagery, said: "It was you who dragged him off the bus" and "you who inflicted serious violence" to a man just trying to do his job.
"It took place in a very public place, in the centre of tourist mecca."
But that was not the only attack by the hands of Scorsese.
The 30-year-old also faced court over a frenzied outburst on three paramedics just four months later.
Emergency services were called after the man tried to stab himself and had to be restrained to a stretcher.
Scorsese was handed 18 months' jail, with parole in November, just three months into his sentence.
He was also ordered to pay a total of $3000 in compensation to his victims.
Outside of court his lawyer Ashkan Tai told 9NEWS his client is not a member of an outlaw motorcycle gang and "is very sorry for putting the bus drive through for what he did, from the very beginning he was always very remorseful".
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cavill Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scorsese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surfers Paradise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magistrate Andrew Sinclair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashkan Tai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport Magistrate Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Cooper Scorsese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
