<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411764382350361</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Motor Report</source>
  <url>http://www.themotorreport.com.au/65454/hyundai-rolls-out-smartsense-safety-across-entire-2018-santa-fe-range</url>
  <title>Hyundai Rolls Out SmartSense Safety Across Entire 2018 Santa Fe Range</title>
  <content>
has introduced a 2018 model year revision to its  large SUV range, trickling-down the advanced safety tech previously only available on high-grade models across the entire range.
Infotainment also comes in for a spruce up with the Elite and Highlander grades moving to a new Apple CarPlay and Android Auto-compatible 8.0-inch touchscreen system.

The four-variant range sees the entry level Santa Fe ActiveX priced from $40,990 plus on-road costs with a 199kW/318Nm 3.3-litre petrol V6 engine, six-speed automatic, and front-wheel drive.
The inclusion of Hyundai SmartSense adds forward collision warning, autonomous emergency braking, smart cruise control, blind spot detection, rear cross traffic alert, lane departure warning, and lane change assist. Hyundai has also added a larger 4.2-inch colour-instrument cluster display, power folding mirrors, side puddle lamps, a self-dimming rearview mirror, and an electric park brake.

Santa Fe Active X

The slightly more expensive Active adds the same key features from $41,850 plus on-road costs although the powertrain drops down to a 2.4-litre petrol four-cylinder engine and six-speed automatic. However the Active also includes standard all- wheel drive. A diesel Active is also available, again with a six-speed auto and all-wheel drive, plus a 147kW/440Nm 2.2-litre four-cylinder engine for $44,850 plus on-road costs.
Higher up the range the Elite and Highlander are diesel-only with the full suite of safety tech as well as the new infotainment system.

Santa Fe Highlander

Along with the updates and added tech, Hyundai has dropped the manual transmission option with the Active model, which bumps-up the price of entry slightly, although the auto-equipped Active 4x4 holds steady on price despite the changes.
Other standard features that carry over include a reversing camera, cloth seats and 17-inch alloy wheels on the Active, leather trim, heated front seats, 19-inch alloys, and dual zone climate control on the Active X, powered seats and tailgate, 18-inch alloys, stainless steel scuff plates, premium audio and satellite navigation for the Elite, and a panoramic sunroof, heated rear seats, HID headlights and LED tail lights for the Highlander.
Pricing

Santa Fe Active X V6 - $40,990
Santa Fe Active petrol - $41,850
Santa Fe Active diesel - 44,850
Santa fe Elite diesel - $51,990
Santa Fe Highlander diesel - $57,090
Manufacturer's list price, excluding on-road costs.
MORE:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai Rolls Out SmartSense Safety Across Entire 2018 Santa Fe Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highlanders</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple CarPlay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Fe Active X V6 - $40,990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Fe Highlander</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Active 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Active X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Fe Active X</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai SmartSense</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyundai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>santA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Fe Active</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santa Fe ActiveX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
