<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411721432676728</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/breaking-news/turnbull-in-a-bind-on-marriage-vote/news-story/5bc9c6ddd8099f0b1f7a5916bf56245b</url>
  <title>Turnbull coy on postal marriage vote</title>
  <content>
Malcolm Turnbull is dodging questions on holding a postal plebiscite on same-sex marriage as his colleagues bicker over the best way to resolve the issue.
The prime minister maintains he went to the election promising a plebiscite on changing marriage laws, but refuses to say whether a postal vote would fulfil this pledge.
His conservative colleagues are mounting the case for the postal option, while one of the government's most senior moderates has warned against crossing the floor in parliament.
Threats have been swirling around Mr Turnbull's leadership, the coalition agreement with the Nationals, and conservatives defecting to the crossbench should backbenchers force a vote in parliament to allow same-sex marriage.
Mr Turnbull is not ruling out a postal plebiscite nor offering his colleagues public counsel.
"I talk to my colleagues all the time and we often have discussions about policy issues, and they are best done privately in the party-room," he told reporters in Western Australia on Wednesday.
"I'm not going to get into a public debate about internal party issues and discussions."
West Australian senator Dean Smith is working on a marriage equality bill while his lower house colleagues Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson and Warren Entsch have been discussing options with colleagues.
But cabinet minister Simon Birmingham, a moderate who has long supported marriage equality, issued a caution.
"It's always been ... a right in the Liberal Party for individual members to exercise their conscience from the backbench if they choose," he told Sky News.
"But equally, it is, of course, a right that people should exercise carefully, with caution and with consideration for all of the consequences."
The Liberal Party is expected to thrash out the issue during a partyroom meeting next week when parliament returns from the long winter break.
Deputy Prime Minister Barnaby Joyce wants the Nationals brought in for that debate, despite suggestions Tony Abbott was branch-stacking when he did so while in power.
Tasmanian senator Eric Abetz - a staunch opponent of same-sex marriage who would vote against it even if a plebiscite showed support - warned it was a "grave matter" for any government to lose a procedural vote in the lower house.
Manager of Government Business Christopher Pyne - who's in charge of running the lower house - dismissed this as "complete rubbish".
Those MPs pushing for marriage equality argue they have discharged their duty to support a plebiscite and it's not their fault the Senate blocked the legislation.
But Minister Zed Seselja said that argument was nonsense, pointing to the government's persistence over workplace relations laws.
Queensland's Liberal National Party president Gary Spence voiced his disappointment late on Tuesday after the party's state conference passed a motion calling for a postal plebiscite.
"I am equally disappointed that members elected under the LNP banner have chosen to take a position that defies LNP policy and the wishes of the LNP's membership," he wrote to members.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Liberal-National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government Business Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Zed Seselja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Prime Minister Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
