<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411712842741977</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/good-news/2017/08/02/13/44/adelaide-man-wins-world-record-for-largest-bubble</url>
  <title>Adelaide man bursts record for the world</title>
  <content>
An Adelaide man now holds a world record for creating the largest indoor, free-floating soap bubble.
At 6am on a cool winter's morning in June, Graeme Denton set out to burst the previous Guinness World Record of 8.5m.  
"I thought it would be a fun project," Mr Denton, who also goes by the name Marty McBubble, said in a statement.
"It turned out to be harder than I thought."
Using a "supersize wand" made out of two 4m fishing roads and a long piece of string, Mr Denton dipped the wand into his "secret bubble recipe" at Lockleys Primary School in Adelaide amid cool temperatures and high humidity.
"That's why I did it at 6am when the humidity was at its highest point. The air was also very cool and slowed down the evaporation of the bubble, which ultimately leads to the popping," Mr Denton said.
To measure its size, Mr Denton enlisted the help of Professor Matt Roughan from the ARC Centre of Excellence for Mathematical and Statistical Frontiers (ACEM).

Related Articles

"They're mathematically interesting because they're what we call a minimal surface. The spherical shape that encloses the bubble has a minimum surface area because of the surface tension," Professor Roughan said.
The bigger the bubble gets, though, the more irregular the shape becomes - which  was the case with Mr Denton's giant bubble which evolved into something resembling "a huge sausage" from the side.
"We had to make sure we had a lot of measurements in the gym to compare the bubble against. We also had to make sure we knew exactly where the bubble was inside the gym in order to be able to correct that perspective distortion," he said.
"So I had to build a model to actually correct the camera perspective."
Professor Roughan's week of calculations showed Mr Denton's soap bubble reached 19.8m, shattering the previous record, which has since been verified by Guinness World Records.
Thanks to his efforts, the Adelaide professor has been passed on Mr Denton's "secret recipe" for perfecting giant bubbles - one he said he is not willing to share.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACEM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guinness World Record</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockleys Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Statistical Frontiers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marty McBubble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Denton</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Denton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARC Centre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Roughan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Matt Roughan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
