<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411850281697376</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/before-politics-there-was-long-hair-and-surfing/3206087/</url>
  <title>Before politics there was long hair and surfing</title>
  <content>
IN 1971, I left my hometown of Nambour to move to Brisbane to continue my education at university but the lessons I learned growing up on the Sunshine Coast and going to Nambour State High School have guided me since I left.
At Nambour High, I wasn't necessarily a straight-A student.
I was more of an "A student" with the emphasis sometimes on surfing, just one of the benefits of growing up on the Sunshine Coast.
But as a former treasurer, I want to put on the record that in addition to being a surfer, I also won the school's economics prize. You can't surf every day.
I've always owed my old economics teacher, Mr Huggins, a debt of gratitude for everything he taught me, especially as we faced down the Global Financial Crisis and kept Australia out of recession.
As well as many fond memories, we all have regrets about our school days. Mine is playing up in French classes and making life hell for my excellent French teacher Mrs Jones.

As a result, I never really did learn to speak French - something that would have come in handy at G20 Summits in Paris and Geneva.
There is something I did learn successfully at Nambour and that was the art of successful negotiation.
When I won the economics prize, the principal called me to his office and, looking at my surfie haircut, told me that unless I had it cut off for the award ceremony, the prize would be withdrawn.
So I had a choice: the hair or the prize.
At 17, the decision seemed obvious. I made a stand and chose the hair. Thankfully, the principal backed off.
The thing I'll always be grateful to Nambour High and the Sunshine Coast community for is that they didn't just give us an education, but also an education for life.
We had the freedom to learn and excel whilst being true to ourselves. We weren't forced into being something we weren't at too young an age. And we were able to discover and choose for ourselves the lives we really wanted to live.
No one gets pigeon-holed. Everyone gets respect.
A lot has changed about the Sunshine Coast since I left more than 40 years ago, but those same values and that spirit remains.
More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
Miriam Vale sergeant breaks down in court after charge read out.
One of the Coast's most innovative business hubs is thriving
BREAKING: Coast researchers find white spot in frozen foods section
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour High</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miriam Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Financial Crisis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G20 Summit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geneva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour State High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Huggins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
