<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411455144700716</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/home-garden/the-best-49-cents-youll-ever-spend-on-your-home/news-story/522b6ca05fe483a8bf77d2a93606079c</url>
  <title>The best 49c you'll spend on your home</title>
  <content>
IT'S the dream for any household appliance, decoration or accessory - cheap but still effective.
And that's why this bargain buy for under $1 is taking the internet by storm, .
It's IKEA's TEKLA tea towel, which sells here for just 49 cents (almost half the price it sells for in the US).
The 100 per cent cotton kitchen item can be re-purposed, according to thrifty online users, with some using it as a place setting napkin, while others turn them into curtains.
"They might not be the prettiest ... but they are the most useful"
While there are no reviews currently for the tea towel on the Australian site, the Swedish homewares store has plenty of happy customers Stateside.
According to posters, the cotton weave becomes more absorbent after a handful of washes, as opposed to many kitchen towels which can end up the other way around.
One mum says she has previously "cut them in half and used them to wash up babies after meals."
While another user says she keeps her greens fresher in the fridge longer by using this towel.
"I wet the towel and wring it out as thoroughly as I can, then wrap the greens in the towel and place on a refrigerator shelf," Dobemom wrote.
"The greens stay crisp quite a while this way. They might not be the prettiest towels in the kitchen, but they are the most useful."
One gym bunny confessed: "with the loop it comes in very handy at the gym to make sure only dry bottles get packed into the bag after one's shower."
Getting crafty
Many websites have worked out how to get crafty with the cheap cotton cloth to create a range of other things.
Blog Red Red Completely Red has a step-by-step instruction manual on turning the tea towel into little bags for kids toys.
While Martha Stewart's home styling website has advice on how to switch them up with a little dye, "making them pretty enough to use as napkins".
According to the Crafts Editor, Silke Stoddard, it's "as easy as running a load of laundry".
Meanwhile, blog Live Laugh Rowe has an easy way to turn the 65cm sheet into a curtain, albeit shorter than normal.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silke Stoddard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Red Completely Red</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martha Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dobemom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crafts Editor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swedish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IKEA's TEKLA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Live Laugh Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
