<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411850281697401</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/price-labels-aussie-golfers-key-to-cup-success/3207928/</url>
  <title>Price labels Aussie golfers key to Cup success</title>
  <content>
GOLF: Nick Price will be looking to Jason Day and Adam Scott to lead from the front at next month's Presidents Cup to break the International team's drought in the competition against the Americans.
The Australian stars have slipped down the world rankings and remain winless in 2017 but they remain the second and third best players on the International team behind Japan's Hideki Matsuyama.
Captain Price said both need to be at their best if his team is to taste victory for only the second time since 1998.
"The top five on our team haven't played their best in recent months," Price said ahead of this weekend's World Golf Championships-Bridgestone Invitational
"So hopefully they'll start really getting their games into shape now.
"There's so much to play for between now and the Presidents Cup. They just need that little bit of momentum going into that week."
Price and assistant captain Ernie Els are the only members of the extended 2017 Internationals team who have played on a winning Presidents Cup team.
The Presidents Cup takes place at New Jersey's Liberty National from September 26.
More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
Miriam Vale sergeant breaks down in court after charge read out.
One of the Coast's most innovative business hubs is thriving
SELANGOR Private Hospital has celebrated its 70th birthday.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey's Liberty National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Presidents Cup</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miriam Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie Els</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Golf Championships Bridgestone Invitational</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Hideki Matsuyama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SELANGOR Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
