<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411712842741973</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/rugby/michael-hooper-gets-nod-to-take-over-from-retiring-stephen-moore-as-wallabies-skipper/news-story/b0e6e346da13dc9ac036ba595cc99bb6</url>
  <title>Hooper relishing Wallabies captaincy elevation</title>
  <content>
AS expected, Michael Hooper has been appointed as the new full-time captain of the Wallabies following Stephen Moore's decision last week to step down.
Though Hooper has taken the role often in the last few years as Moore's deputy, the 25-year-old Waratahs flanker will lead the Wallabies into battle with New Zealand on August 19 for the first time as the official captain.
Hooper first captained the Wallabies in 2014 when Moore was injured, becoming the 82nd captain of the Wallabies and also the youngest ever skipper at just 22 years old.
The Manly junior was unveiled as the new captain in Sydney on Wednesday. His vice-captain was not named. That role is likely to be announced next week.
"It's a huge honour to just wear the Wallabies jersey, let alone captain the side. I'm extremely grateful to Cheik (Michael Cheika) but also to Steve (Moore) for all that he's done for me and the team," Hooper said in a statement.
"It's what you do in the jersey that's most important and I get another crack at showing what it means to me against New Zealand in Sydney in a fortnight.
"There are quite a few good young leaders in this team like Bernard (Foley), Adam (Coleman), Samu (Kerevi) and Allan (Alaalatoa), so we'll be working together to take this team to a new level.
"I'm really excited about what we can achieve in the next four months. It is a very special opportunity for all of us, and we'll be doing all we can to show that pride in the jersey," Hooper said.
Hooper has captained the Waratahs for the last two seasons, but also led the Tahs to their 2014 Super Rugby grand final win due to an injury to Dave Dennis.

Rugby: Stephen Moore has retired from international rugby. Check out this tribute put together by Kick and Chase.

Thank you Stephen Moore
"Michael always shows on the field how much he loves the gold jersey and that's why he is totally respected among the rugby players in Australia," Cheika said in a statement.
"His role as the leader of this team will also be about making the standards of the Australian rugby team the highest they can possibly be.
"Michael loves Australia and his record as a player speaks for itself but he's exactly the type of man we want see in rugby - connected to his school, a great club man at the grassroots, a passionate Super Rugby player and a proud Wallaby.".
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coleman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Dennis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Moore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Rugby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerevi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cheika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alaalatoa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
