<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411330590647093</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/good-news/2017/08/02/11/50/queensland-students-cut-of-their-ponytails-for-good-cause</url>
  <title>Queensland students cut off their ponytails for inspirational cause</title>
  <content>
Queensland student Charlotte Graves has been growing her hair since her last chop about eight months ago.
This morning, alongside more than 50 of her fellow students at St Margaret's Anglican School, she volunteered to snip off her ponytail live on The TODAY Show, lending a hand to those who have lost their own.
"I'm feeling really excited. We're all donating to a really great cause and I think we are all prepared to cut off our hair," Ms Traves told TODAY prior to the snip.
'The Ponytail Project' is an annual school initiative that started in 2015 when a former teacher and member of the parent community, Amanda Minotti, was diagnosed with breast cancer.
"Our students came to us and asked whether we could do this thing called' The Ponytail Project', where we cut off our ponytails - particularly to help out women who are suffering from chemotherapy or children who need wigs as a result - and raise funds for much needed cancer research," Principal Ros Curtis told TODAY.
"Many of these girls were taught by Amanda and she has a young family, so we are helping as best as we can to assist her young boys with their education."
Back in 2015, 21 students took part in making the snip.

Related Articles

In 2017, more than 50 students have now raised  for the Queensland Cancer Council and the Minotti family. 
"I think everyone is pretty excited - more excitement than nerves at the moment," student Bella Gray said as a local hairdresser made the snip.
All of the girls' hair will be donated to make wigs for those who have lost their hair due to a medical condition.
"I am so proud of the girls. This is something that is driven by the students themselves and the staff support them," Ms Curtis said.
"They are not at all worried. They just know this is for a worthy cause and they have been so motivated to increase the funding.
"I hope they are an inspiration for other students to do the same."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ponytail Project</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bella Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Margaret's Anglican School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Traves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda Minotti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ros Curtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Today Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlotte Graves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Cancer Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Curtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amanda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minotti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
