<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411712842741945</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/melbourne-mother-lives-in-fear-shot-in-gangland-dispute/8766996</url>
  <title>Melbourne mother 'living in fear' after revenge shooting in gangland wars</title>
  <content>
A Melbourne woman believes she was shot in the stomach as payback for giving evidence against her son, Rodney Phillips, who was sent to jail for arson attacks on the homes of the family of notorious gangland figure Carl Williams.
Leonie Stuart was targeted through her security door at her home at Glenroy, in Melbourne's north, in March.

"I've walked down (the hall), and next minute all I could see was this red laser light," she said.
"Then next all I heard was a big echo noise and I heard it again, and I'm holding [the spot] where I got shot.
"I managed to walk back to the kitchen. It was very painful. I've laid on the ground and I could feel I was slowly going out of it."
Victoria Police are appealing for information about the shooting and want to hear from anyone who saw a charcoal-coloured four-wheel drive or a motorcycle in Hubert Avenue, Glenroy on March 2.
"We don't know who the offenders are and we're appealing to the public for any assistance that can be provided," Detective Inspector Stephen Clark said.
"Clearly there will be people out there who know who has committed this serious offence and exactly why they've done it."
'I went against him' but no regrets

Ms Stuart's spleen was removed and she has a scar down the length of her torso.

Phillips pleaded guilty in March to multiple offences, including shooting a police officer and arson attacks on the homes of family members of gangland killer Carl Williams.

Phillips is believed to be part of a gang in Barwon prison, headed by Johnson.
Ms Stuart said she did not regret giving evidence against her son.
"I went against him in a matter of speaking. I was very honest about stuff I knew on the stand. I was being very honest because I'm not a person [who] lies," she said.
"When you're in prison, you don't like anyone to come forward with any information and in the eyes of my son, he never appreciated me doing anything like that."
Ms Stuart said she does not think her son would do anything like that to her.
"Someone might have took it into their own hands [to do it] behind his back," she said.
"I live in fear. I'm not afraid to talk today. It was on my own account. Some family members don't agree with me.
"I live in fear that's how I live now."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillips</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonie Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector Stephen Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenroy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barwon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Stuart</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carl Williams</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hubert Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
