<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411803037056508</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/preview-pelethronius-poised-to-continue-his-faultless-record-this-winter-in-the-coffs-harbour-cup/news-story/8259372069e55ef6f66da3c45d4c1355</url>
  <title>Preview: Pelethronius on song for Cup</title>
  <content>
WHEN David Pfieffer brought Pelethronius back into work this winter he never envisaged the five-year-old winning consecutive races at Randwick let alone starting favourite in a Coffs Harbour Gold Cup.
The in-form gelding is unbeaten in four runs this winter, including winning back-to-back Saturday races at Randwick at his past two starts.
On Thursday, Pelethronius will line up as a short-priced favourite in the $80,000 Coffs Harbour Gold Cup (1600m) and Pfieffer concedes he has already exceeded all expectations.
"Last prep he raced in a mile race at Randwick on Melbourne Cup Day and he ran midfield and I thought he went well," Pfieffer said.
"The jockey that day said he felt the track and that it was a bit too hard for him, so I targeted the winter with him thinking I will probably have a midweek class horse."
With low expectations, there's little reason Pelethronius' large group of owners have been quite boisterous after every win this campaign.
"(His owners) are having an absolute ball," Pfieffer said. "I didn't expect him to keep improving like he has but he was always a horse that needed time to mature.
"Now he has developed a good racing resume and he has had 13 runs for seven wins. It looks as if he might get to better than Saturday grade racing as well."
Pelethronius has drawn barrier 11 in the Coffs Harbour Cup but Pfieffer said it's not as bad as it looks on paper. "I know the four emergencies are drawn inside him and we're going to come into (barrier eight if there are no more scratchings) and I think that's good," he said.
"In a big field at a country track you don't want to be too close to the fence because you could be cluttered up. You could probably say you would rather be drawn 6-11 and you have that option of being one off the fence and then getting a bit of room in the straight.
"I know the track is rated a good 4 but with the winter tracks at the moment they all have a bit of cut out of the ground and he has proven he has great wet form.
"He has really stepped up to the plate this prep and could get himself to that next level."
Kerrin McEvoy will make the trip to Coffs Harbour to ride Pelethronius in another big positive.
Pelethronius was rated a $2.10 TAB favourite on Wednesday well ahead of Sofin ($7.50) and Mr McBat ($8), who ran the quinella (Mr McBat won) in the South Grafton Cup last start.
Meanwhile, Pfieffer will also saddle up Refuge Bay in the Class 3 Handicap (1200m).
The five-year-old mare is resuming on the back of two trials. "Her trials have been good," Pfieffer said. "She is probably best over 1400m but I expect her to sprint well fresh."HAWKESBURY
Sahara Emaar leads charge for Ryan
TRAINER Gerald Ryan has a leaning towards Sahara Emaar as the pick of his Hawkesbury runners on Thursday and warned he won't hesitate to scratch Albumin if the track is worse than a Soft 6.
Ryan looks set for a big day at Hawkesbury with Sahara Emaar, Albumin and Rosettas Whey all top chances in their respective races. Albumin (59kg) returns to the races after a solid two-year-old campaign and Ryan is just concerned about the weight he has to give his older rivals in the Class 1 Handicap (1100m).
"He is going to the races as fit as he can be first-up without having a race," Ryan said.
"But he is a young three-year-old giving five-year-olds 2, 3 or 4kg which always worries me at this time of the year. If it was 57kg to 54kg it wouldn't worry me but when it is 59kg to 57kg and 54kg I always worry about it. But there just wasn't another race to kick him off in, so we will see how he goes."
The Hawkesbury track was rated a Soft 6 on Wednesday with more rain predicted on Thursday.
"If it got any worse than a Soft 6 I will scratch him because he showed at Rosehill (last campaign) he doesn't handle it," Ryan said. "He has always shown ability and he went to the races off one trial and just got beat (on debut) and then he bounced back and won what has turned into not a bad maiden form race (at Rosehill)."
Sahara Emaar won a recent 900m Rosehill trial and will resume in the Maiden Plate (1300m). The four-year-old finished third to the talented Ghostly on debut and then was travelling like the winner second-up at Kembla before running off the track on the home turn and failing to finish.
"He has always shown good ability and he is a big horse and has always taken time," Ryan said. "He has been gelded now and I think that is why he might have run off the track.
"He hasn't shown any signs of it since and his trial was all right. He is probably a horse that will run 1600m on his ear and that is why he is running in a 1300m race first-up and he is not brilliantly quick. He has good form and put it this way, I always believed he was better than a midweek maiden."
Rosettas Whey rounds out Ryan's team in Race 7.
"She is honest and consistent and she doesn't seem to have a lot of luck," he said.
INSIDE MAIL
John Davis and Stephen Zammit analyses the quaddie legs at Coffs Harbour and Hawkesbury.COFFS HARBOUR (John Davis)
RACE 5 (2.35pm): CLASS 3 HCP (1200m)
9. Aristograts resumed in tidy fashion when a plodding fifth over a slightly shorter trip at Ballina last month. Proven second-up and the Dunn/McGuren combination is a powerful one. 1. Impregnable is used to lumping huge imposts. Stalked the speed before coming away to score at Ballina impressively last time. Obvious threat. 7. Menneke Belle faces her acid test this time after consecutive victories at Grafton in slightly weaker grade.
BETTING STRATEGY: Boxed quinella 1,7,9.
RACE 6 (3.10pm): DANIEL BAKER SPRINT (1200m)
Former Sydney galloper 14. Shotgun Roulette is normally effective in the early stages of her campaign but needs it firm under foot. Indicated readiness with a smart 1007m Taree trial last month on a soft track. Gets in under the limit weight and is worth an each-way ticket. 2. Free Standing found the class a fraction hot in the Ramornie Hcp at Grafton last month but cannot be overlooked following his dominant victory in the Country Championships over the autumn. Obvious threat. 8. So You Know did not have a lot of luck obtaining a run in the stretch at Moree last time. Normally thereabouts. Trifecta hope.
BETTING STRATEGY: SHOTGUN ROULETTE each-way.
RACE 7 (3.45pm): COFFS HARBOUR GOLD CUP (1600m)
2. Sofin has his hoof right on the till and bypassed Grafton Cup to be readied for this assignment. Rattled home to beat all but Mr McBat in the lead-up to last month's Grafton feature. Drawn to take beating. 14. Single Spirit met with ring support ($9 to $6.50) when an eye-catching second to Malleable in the Sawtell Cup at this venue last month. The mile trip is about as far as he wants but stays under notice. 1. Pelethronius is an imposing individual and made it four straight at Randwick last time, pouncing on the lead in the shadows of the grandstand to score running away. Can't knock, despite huge impost.
BETTING STRATEGY: SOFIN to win.
RACE 8 (4.20pm): BM60 HCP (1000m)
7. Supreme Girl led them up and stuck on solidly when a fighting second at this venue last time. Trained locally and drawn to go one better here. 14. Dream Starlet's wide gate sealed her fate when a handy fourth at the Gold Coast over an unsuitable distance last time. She gets champion apprentice Andrew Adkins in the saddle here and another look at the blinkers. 2. Go The Gantry has the speed to take up a forward slot and that has to be respected.
BETTING STRATEGY: SUPREME GIRL to win.HAWKESBURY (Steve Zammit)
RACE 5 (2.55pm): MAIDEN PLATE (1800m)
Two consecutive minor placings point to 11. Ultraman proving very hard to beat here. The Mark Newnham-trained gelding put up a strong performance at Gosford on July 11 and should be at peak now. After 24 tries for six placings, no one could begrudge 4. Mateship a win. The 6yo just missed at Goulburn last start and deserves to shed the 'bridesmaid' tag. 8. Chilli Beauty's third placing here on July 16 was a promising effort. Has each-way claims.
BETTING STRATEGY: Box trifecta nos 4,8,9,11
RACE 6 (3.35pm): MAIDEN HCP (1500m)
This looks an ideal race for 4. Sacred Edge, who has a 50 per cent place ratio from eight starts. Trained by Chris Waller, he was an excellent second at Warwick Farm last start and gets an extra 100m here. Also, the blinkers go off here. 5. Cool One was having only her second run when third here last time out. Much fitter now and is from the astute local stable of Garry White. 11. Manhattan Drive proved costly when runner-up at Cessnock on July 17 and can atone here without surprising.
BETTING STRATEGY: SACRED EDGE to win.
RACE 7 (4.10pm): CLASS 2 HCP (1400m)
There are a few handy types in this race, including 1. Bombardier, who won on debut before finishing runner-up over 1300m here on July 6. The additional ground will suit and he could cap off a big day for Mark Newnham, who has made a couple of gear changes on the 4yo. 8. Rosettas Whey is most consistent and very close to another victory. Ran a game third at Newcastle and will find the line strongly at the right end of this. 5. Chin Ups broke through in fine style at Gosford and another forward showing can be expected.
BETTING STRATEGY: BOMBARDIER to win; Box quinella nos 1,5,8.
RACE 8 (4.45pm): BM63 HCP (1800m)
The Kris Lees-trained 6. Labrooke was supported into favouritism at Newcastle on July 15, and finished on stoutly for third, giving the indication he was looking for something longer. He gets that here and looks very tough to hold out. Local 7. Letter To Juliette won a maiden here over 1500m and she too should find the 1800m of this event to her advantage. 2. Captain Manering was just collared at Kembla Grange on July 8 and will benefit here with a 4kg allowance for apprentice Aaron Williams.
BETTING STRATEGY: LABROOKE to win.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kembla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soft 6</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerald Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour Gold Cups</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrin McEvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Zammit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PLATE (1800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkesbury.COFFS HARBOUR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sahara Emaar</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosehill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McBat ($8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Race 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Pfieffer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MR MCBAT</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sawtell Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramornie Hcp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Girl</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Davis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosettas Whey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goulburn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Zammit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Waller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SACRED EDGE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Grafton Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BM60 HCP (1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pfieffer</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gantry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Refuge Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ultraman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sofin ($7.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dunn/McGuren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkesbury</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soft 6 I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PELETHRONIUS</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aristograts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour Gold Cup (1600</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juliette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bombardier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menneke Belle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maiden Plate (1300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coffs Harbour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HCP (1500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grafton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Adkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARK Newnham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HCP (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Newnham-trained</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sofin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SHOTGUN ROULETTE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HCP (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BM63 HCP (1800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Class 3 Handicap (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Class 1 Handicap (1100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labrooke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan Drive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DANIEL BAKER SPRINT (1200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chin Ups</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kembla Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kris Lees-trained 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
