<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411674188035947</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/senior-doctor-tells-coroners-inquest-it-was-an-error-to-have-both-stroke-specialists-on-leave-at-time-of-mens-deaths/news-story/84a01702099767738938daffe609f8b3</url>
  <title>Stroke doctor rostering an 'error' when men died: inquest</title>
  <content>
A DOCTOR in charge of the radiology roster at the Royal Adelaide Hospital has admitted it was an "error" to have both specialists on leave at the same time when two men died from strokes, an inquest has heard.
On Wednesday, RAH acting head of radiology Jim Buckley was the first witness called to give evidence in the inquest into the deaths of Michael John Russell and Leslie Robert Graham in April.
Mr Russell, 60, and Mr Graham, 87, died a week apart after being admitted to the Royal Adelaide Hospital when two stroke specialists were on leave at the same time.
Dr Buckley told State Coroner Mark Johns that he signed off both leave requests by two specialists - James Taylor and Rebecca Scroop - without realising it left "a window" when no one would be available for the 24/7 service.
"It was an error," Dr Buckley said.
"I had signed a form for Dr Taylor the previous year and then I was presented with a form sometime later by Dr Scroop and I inadvertently signed that.
"I didn't appreciate that Dr Taylor was on leave too."
Dr Buckley said he was made aware of the overlap - from April 18 to 22 - in March and had a meeting with both doctors to figure out a solution, which included tweaking their holiday plans and allowing a third consultant to cover some of the days.
He said the roster for the 24/7 specialist stroke service was "very fragile" because two doctors were required to cover such extensive hours.
"The INR (blood clotting test) roster often changed - it changed frequently," he said.
But he said a third specialist has joined Dr Taylor and Dr Scroop as part of the INR team as of this week to help with the workload.
"I know things have been very stressful for both (Dr Taylor and Dr Scroop) and have been for a very long time," he said.
"If one was overseas, it meant the other was on call day and night - it was an intolerable situation."
Dr Buckley said the need to get a third specialist was urgent given the number of procedures was increasing.
"It's an expanding area," he said.
But he told the inquest the new specialist would not be a fully active member of the team for up to seven weeks because she needed another 20 supervised procedures under her belt before she could be registered.
Following the deaths of Mr Russell and Mr Graham, The Advertiser revealed in May that Dr Scroop and Dr Taylor - both SA Medical Imaging radiologists - .
A review of the neuro-interventional radiology service called for a third specialist to be employed in 2013 - four years before the deaths.
On Tuesday, , saying he was a "wonderful man, a truly gentle soul".
"I am still struggling to comprehend why and how this happened to my dear Michael and how I am supposed to live my life without him" she said.
Last month,   but failed to address it before two patients died.
An email trail showed officials had admitted that the hospital's roster - which had just two specialists to supposedly offer 24/7 complex stroke care - "puts SA Health at extreme medico-legal risk and would be indefensible in the media".
Documents prepared for the coroner's inquest into the two deaths revealed:
OFFICIALS knew the rostering system contravened the industrial award and was contrary to a recommendation in a major review of services.
THEY were aware there was no contingency plan if one specialist fell ill while the other was on leave.
THEY privately conceded the roster of just two staff for a 24/7 service had been "severely stretched" for more than two years and that extra appointments were "a matter of urgency".
SUPERVISORS were aware both specialists would be away at the same time in April - a meeting was held with them to discuss it - but no contingency plan was put in place.
SA HEALTH was rebuked for claiming in the media that local graduates were about to increase numbers on the roster, when in fact no one is in training.
THE two specialists, interventional neuro-radiologists Dr James Taylor and Dr Rebecca Scroop, allegedly were "routinely" rostered off on Thursdays and often also on Wednesdays, despite the RAH supposedly being the state's 24/7 stroke centre of excellence.
DR Scroop sent an email revealing her anguish at the deaths, while noting it underlines the pressure of having just two specialists for the service.
The only other specialist in the state accredited to do the delicate procedure of suctioning a blood clot from the brain, Dr Steve Chryssidis, agreed to come in from his private practice and perform the procedure despite not being credentialed to work at the RAH.
Each time, this resulted in a delay of about two hours between the stroke being diagnosed and the procedure being performed.
Mr Russell's death was referred to the coroner but with no mention that there had been no specialist rostered on to do the procedure.
Mr Graham's case was only referred after Coroner Mark Johns read about the deaths in The Advertiser on May 13 and demanded details.
The inquest continues.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Russell, 60</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Scroop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Buckley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Medical Imaging</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Russell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Coroner Mark Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coroner Mark Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Steve Chryssidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie Robert Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Rebecca Scroop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Graham, 87</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Scroop</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Graham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael John Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Taylor</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr James Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Health</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
