<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411712842741962</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/brisbane-bus-drivers-threaten-strike-if-safety-requests-not-met/news-story/5a8182302062628203d0383b255eb3d6</url>
  <title>Progress - but more strikes possible</title>
  <content>
BRISBANE council bus drivers could strike again unless a seven-month industrial dispute is settled.
Rail, Tram and Bus Union members want a 3.5 per cent pay rise, improved safety measures and training, and better rosters for drivers, the union's secretary Tom Brown told an animated rally of about 300 people.
The union has been in "tense" discussions with Brisbane City Council. Mr Brown said at a meeting on Tuesday evening nothing was resolved, but progress was made.
"The progress was they were sitting down and talking to us and not packing up after two hours and going home as they were in the past," he said.
The RTBU will not budge from its demand for a 3.5 per cent pay rise. "We think that is fair and reasonable," Mr Brown said.
"For the time being we can talk about safety, we can talk about rosters, we can talk about fatigue, these things we can get settled ... there can be no EBA until the pay is settled."
A doubling of security guards across the network, increased safety training and guarantees of jobs for drivers assaulted at work were also high priorities for the RTBU, Mr Brown said.
Further talks are scheduled for Thursday and if they fail there could be more industrial action.
"I'm not prepared to rule out anything but we take it one step at a time," Mr Brown said.
Wednesday's work stoppage, the fourth in three weeks, also involved members from associated unions, including the CFMEU, in a show of solidarity Mr Brown said was unprecedented.
It was held between 10am and 2pm, deliberately outside peak hours, to ensure as many members as possible could attend, Mr Brown said.
The union had heard "nothing but support" from public transport users, he said.
- AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brown</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
