<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411884641436240</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/whats-on-tv-friday-august-11-20170802-gxnoty.html</url>
  <title>What's on TV: Friday, August 11</title>
  <content>
Never Been Kissed
Never Been Kissed (1999)
Eleven, 8.30pm
In modern America, the journeys that seem to interest people most are those of self-realisation. In Raja Gosnell's Never Been Kissed, 25-year-old Josie Geller (Drew Barrymore) returns to her old high school as an undercover journalist. Her first attempt at high school was a disaster, so going back is more about trying to exorcise the troubles of the past than writing a good article. Barrymore works overtime to generate fun and warmth, but whether you are ultimately charmed by the film may come down to the ending, a fantasy in front of a packed crowd and the television cameras of America, where a man says to a girl, "It took me forever to get here." This is a nod to American Gigolo's "It took me so long to reach you", based on the mistranslated English subtitles for Pickpocket's "what a strange path I had to take to meet you". Great concepts have a happy tendency of repeating. SM
pay Alfred Hitchcock's The Birds (1963)
Fox Classics (pay TV), 8.35pm
Forty per cent of the time I argue for Marnie as Alfred Hitchcock's masterpiece. The other 60 per cent I opt for The Birds. In a San Francisco pet shop, Mitch Brenner (Rod Taylor) flirts with the ice-cool Melanie Daniels (Tippi Hendren). The daughter of a media baron, she is careless about getting what she wants and that seems not to be Mitch. But he won't take no for an answer and drives up the coast to Bodega Bay, with two caged lovebirds on his passenger seat. Feathered creatures soon figure prominently, with seagulls drifting into shot from on high as a mysterious battle between humans and birds begins. Based on a Daphne Du Maurier short story, the film's subtexts are far more complex than many realised in 1963. Audiences were in fact bewildered by an ending that today is crystal clear and cathartic. Half a century late, the world has caught up with Hitchcock. SM

Never Ending Orgasm
ABC2, 9.05pm
For a program that features footage of dozens of women masturbating (we see them only from the neck up), this documentary is surprisingly dry. A pioneering Canadian study aims to investigate why it is that some women are "multi-orgasmic" (apparently defined as experiencing two to three orgasms per ''sexual event'') while others are "super-orgasmic", allegedly experiencing, sometimes, more than 100 orgasms in any one sexual encounter. It's unclear why such a study is necessary, but reportedly it's "still a mystery" to science. By the program's end, in which the world's leading sex scientists examine their subjects - including the obligatory tantric expert - orgasming on camera and even inside MRI scanners (one lucky Brit was flown all the way to the States to get off inside a machine - upsettingly for her, without her vibrator), it's still, partly at least, something of a mystery. KN
pay A New Prehistory
Discovery Science, 9.30pm
What killed the giant prehistoric insects? Three hundred million years ago, the skies were ruled by dragonflies whose wingspans stretched to 70 centimetres, while the millipede-like arthropleura grew 2.3 metres long and 50 centimetres wide. Until recently it was thought that falling atmospheric oxygen levels simply made arthropods' tube-based respiration unworkable at such scales. Now, however, things look more complicated. This unsensational French series combines serviceable CGI of ancient animals with the latest science to paint a more detailed picture. Recent research shows that the action of the giant dragonflies' flight muscles would have enhanced respiration, enabling such species to persist longer at lower oxygen levels than previously thought. The evolution of flying reptiles and flowering plants might have posed more pressing problems. The series' characteristically European focus on the actual subject matter - as distinct from the typical Anglophone preoccupation with empty hoopla - makes a refreshing change. BN
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marnie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglophone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barrymore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Barrymore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daphne Du Maurier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred Hitchcock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raja Gosnell's Never Been Kissed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kissed (1999</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melanie Daniels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tippi Hendren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ending Orgasm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleven, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birds (1963</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Science, 9.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Brenner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bodega Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Prehistory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV), 8.35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Classics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Gigolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CGI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josie Geller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC2, 9.05</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hitchcock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
