<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411893231370932</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/the-coolest-business-on-the-sunshine-coast-can-now/3207931/</url>
  <title>The coolest business on the Sunshine Coast can now be yours</title>
  <content>
HAVE you ever wanted to run your own cafe or bar? Do you constantly dream of leaving your day job in the dust and head out on the open road?

Here's your chance - the Sunshine Coast's cutest coffee caravan could now be all yours.

As the pitter patter of tiny feet draw closer for coffee aficionado Sarah Tanner, the soon to be mum of two is looking for someone to take on her business Hanalei Trading Co.

Hanalei currently offers coffee cart and bar hire, bar staff, and barista services on the Sunshine Coast, Brisbane, the Gold Coast, and Byron Bay areas all wrapped up in an insta-worthy caravan.

Mrs Tanner told the Daily that she hopes to hand over the reins to someone who has the time to give Hanalei Trading Co the attention it deserves.

"I'm pregnant and I already have a two-and-a-half year old," the Buderim mum said.

"I just don't have the time."

When the crew at Hanalei Trading and Co aren't on the road, Sunshine Coast coffee lovers can find them roasting beans in the Buderim area.

Although the cafe and bar caravan doesn't currently offer any food services, Mrs Tanner designed the custom-built caravan with the capacity to expand into food truck territory.

"The fit-out has been made so someone can just apply with council (for the food-handling permit)," Mrs Tanner said.

"We had ours custom built so it looks really flash.

"People love hiring it because of how awesome it looks.

"I have people getting in touch with me (to hire it) every day."

The caravan is the epitome of cool, and comes kitted out with everything you need to start your own venture - all you need is $80,000 and the courage to take the plunge.

The sale includes the caravan (and everything in it), the website, contracts with coffee and milk suppliers, and insurance.

Contact Sarah at hello@hanaleitradingco.com.au for more information.

More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
Miriam Vale sergeant breaks down in court after charge read out.
One of the Coast's most innovative business hubs is thriving
TOUGH choices for a future politican.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Tanner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byron Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Tanner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miriam Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanalei Trading Co</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanalei Trading</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanalei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
