<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411927591109714</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/bunnings-caught-up-in-massive-tradie-tax-fraud-amid-calls-for-abn-overhaul-20170802-gxnmz4.html</url>
  <title>Bunnings caught up in massive tradie tax fraud amid calls for ABN overhaul</title>
  <content>
Hardware giant Bunnings Warehouse has unwittingly become the centre of a massive tradie tax fraud, the chair of Treasury's Black Economy Taskforce says.
The fraud reveals the shaky "honour system" that underpins Australia's tax code.

Up Next

Officials Donald Trump has fired

01:43

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Bunnings bans some harassing tradies

It makes sense that a Bunnings store has banned some tradesmen, Sex Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins tells Jon Faine on 774 ABC.

Bunnings Warehouse's Australian Business Number is being used in more than 40 per cent of all ABNs quoted in the Northern Territory, according to Michael Andrew, the chair of Treasury's Black Economy Taskforce.
It is potentially costing taxpayers hundreds of millions of dollars in missed revenue.

Putting down the wrong ABN effectively allows an independent contractor or supplier to dodge paying tax on a transaction. With cash transactions especially, it is almost impossible for the Australian Tax Office to ensure tax has been paid correctly.
"We found out that more than 40 per cent of ABNs quoted in the Northern Territory were Bunnings, and when you start looking at that of course every tradesman goes to Bunnings," Mr Andrew told a CPA Australia podcast in July.

"They get an invoice, the ABN's up top, so people ask for an invoice or a valid receipt and they get the name of the company but they then get an ABN of someone else such as Bunnings.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The result of which is you can't trace where the money really went."
Mr Andrew was scathing of the ABN system, which he says is "not working". 
Eleven-digit ABNs are supposed to be unique identifiers of Australian businesses. The tax office uses them to track and audit how much tax businesses are supposed to pay.
But, said Paul Drum, head of policy at CPA Australia, it's very easy to circumvent the system - all you need to do is put someone else's ABN on an invoice.
If the business you've invoiced does not check the ABN is correct - many don't bother - then there is no way for the tax office to link the payment to you.
"In many ways it's become an honour system; it's based on the honesty of people," Mr Drum said.
"We're talking about fraud, which is an indictable offence, and the magnitude appears to be quite profound."
The Black Economy Taskforce released an interim report in March that recommends, among other things, the government consider a system to validate ABNs in real time. The final report is due to government in October.
Bunnings and the Treasury both declined to comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Faine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury's Black Economy Taskforce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Economy Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrew</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Tax Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Drum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Drum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Discrimination Commissioner Kate Jenkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings Warehouse's Australian Business Number</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleven-digit ABNs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bunnings Warehouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABNs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
