<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411897526338341</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/former-diddillibah-pupils-look-back-with-pride/3206132/</url>
  <title>Former Diddillibah pupils look back with pride</title>
  <content>
IT CLOSED five years before the Near North Coast became the Sunshine Coast but it held lasting memories for its former charges.
Past pupils and their descendants gathered in the park that was formerly the site of Diddillibah State School for a reunion earlier this year.
The event was held next to Diddillibah Hall to unveil a plaque commemorating the planting of two cork trees in the school grounds more than 100 years ago by students Lyle Preston and Colin Mackay.
One tree still survives but the second perished and was replaced in 2014 and continues to grow strongly.
Keith Campbell, grandchild of Colin Mackay, said the Diddillibah school had an amazing story.
"It all started in 1868 when land was first offered for selection in the area," he said. "A flourishing close-knit farming community grew quickly and it soon became apparent to the local families that a school was warranted.
"Henry Kiel had a 424 acre (171ha) property here and in 1884, he offered to transfer two acres to the Department of Public Instruction for the purposes of facilitating a school.
"The first provisional school began operating with about 20 students in 1885 with the building being completed using labour and materials supplied by the community.
"The first proper school building followed in 1889 - a large single-room building with a shingle roof and front veranda - again completed mainly by the local community."
When the local state member, Frank Nicklin, opened a new school building in 1938, special mention was made of many beautiful established shade trees, in particular the cork trees.
"I'm not sure if anyone knows for certain why the cork trees were planted," Mr Campbell said.
"It may have been to commemorate Arbour Day, or possibly to mark the end of the First World War, but they have remained a feature of the school and now park grounds for over 100 years.
"In the 1960s, the government in their wisdom began closing the smaller schools and in 1962 Diddillibah was closed.
"Students then had to continue schooling at Woombye.
"The school building was moved to the Cotton Tree Caravan Park where it still stands today. The church closed in 1968 and the building was moved to Coolum.
"The hall continued to be used extensively and be an important resource for the community. The park has continued to evolve into an important public open space."
More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
Miriam Vale sergeant breaks down in court after charge read out.
Turn your dream of owning a hip cafe or bar into a reality.
TOUGH choices for a future politican.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diddillibah State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Mackay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woombye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miriam Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diddillibah Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First World War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Nicklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arbour Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Kiel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyle Preston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree Caravan Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diddillibah</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Near North Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
