<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411893231370965</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/memories-of-school-days-flood-back/3206140/</url>
  <title>Memories of school days flood back</title>
  <content>
I WENT to Maroochy Primary and Maroochy High.
We walked home every afternoon to my parents' shop, Bill's Bait Bar, and spent a good part of my tuckshop money at the corner store on 1c lollies, once a week.
Mr Berry, Mrs Logan and Mr Dunk are just a few of the names of teachers I remember.
I remember how excited we all got when it was our turn to "ring the bell"! Riding our push bikes around Maroochydore.
Narelle Kither
I WAS school captain of Tewantin State School's Year 7 in 1986.
There was a uniform but it wasn't compulsory (except for photo day). Even shoes were optional, which was a complete culture shock for me, moving up from suburban Sydney in 1981.
We used to walk down to the river in Tewantin for swimming lessons where it was sectioned off especially, later moving on to the pool at Noosa High in Cooroy.
That was before the Noosa-Cooroy Range road and we would take the very steep and winding old road up, around and around the mountain in the old buses. It took forever.
Deciding which high school to send your kids to was easy back in the '80s: Noosa High, Coolum or St John's in Nambour - all there was up this end of the coast.
Velesia Page
I STARTED at Tewantin in 1974 in Year 7, arriving from Sydney. I couldn't believe how small it was.
We used to wear a uniform, if you could afford one, and we travelled to school on Bill Battalina's buses.
After Tewantin Primary, I went to Noosa District High and we got the school bus up the old range road. I remember it well because it used to make me sick.
I remember one day, Bill Battalina was sick of the kids smoking on the bus so he pulled up at the Timberwah Hall and wouldn't take anyone home until the culprits owned up. It wasn't me but after sitting there for quite some time, myself and a friend said it was us just so we could get going. I thought I wouldn't get in too much trouble but Bill had other plans for me and my friend. The bus finally got going when we got near the bus depot on Gympie Tce and Bill hit the brakes, took us off the bus and made us clean all the buses.
Frances Lane (nee McCafferty)
More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
Miriam Vale sergeant breaks down in court after charge read out.
Turn your dream of owning a hip cafe or bar into a reality.
TOUGH choices for a future politican.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa District High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frances Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy High</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie Tce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Logan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill's Bait Bar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tewantin Primary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miriam Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tewantin State School's Year 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa High</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tewantin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timberwah Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narelle Kither</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dunk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Velesia Page</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa-Cooroy Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Battalina</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCafferty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
