<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411755792415621</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/decade-of-naplan-testing-shows-little-improvement/8766902</url>
  <title>NAPLAN: a decade of testing sees little improvement, says UWA education academic</title>
  <content>
An education expert says 10 years of NAPLAN testing has only seen a marginal improvement in the reading, writing and numeracy levels of students across the nation.
More than 1.1 million students in years 3, 5, 7 and 9 sat the 2017 NAPLAN tests in May, and the preliminary results have been released today ahead of the final results in December.
The figures show WA had improved in 14 of 20 NAPLAN assessments - the highest of all the states and territories.
Senior lecturer in public policy and sociology of education at the University of Western Australia, Glenn Savage, said WA was actually one of the good news stories for NAPLAN.
"Over the last decade since NAPLAN was first conducted in 2008, Western Australia and Queensland have seen the greatest improvements," he said.
"But at the national level there has been a lot of stagnation, or what some would call a plateauing, of results, so not really a lot happening."
Mr Savage said year 9s in WA were above the national average on all indicators except grammar and punctuation, but there were concerns about years 3, 5 and 7 nation-wide.
"Australia has not been doing well on the international level, so if you look at the OECD's PISA [Programme for International Student Assessment] testing which is done across the world, we have been steadily declining against that since the year 2000," he said.
"The unfortunate thing is that even though there has been significant resources, significant investment and a huge amount of effort from people across the board, we're not seeing significant gains or improvement.
"So if I were a system leader of a policy maker, I would be concerned about that."
'Academics don't like NAPLAN, but parents do'

WA Education Minister Sue Ellery said academics might not like NAPLAN testing, but parents loved it.
"I think that is perhaps overstating what NAPLAN is," she said.
"It is a snapshot on one day in the year. It's a tool that teachers use, it's an important tool, but that is all it is.
"We can always do better and we shouldn't be resting on our laurels, we should be continuously striving to improve our educational outcomes and I know that is what teachers are doing in classes every day.
"Parents really want to be able to get in simple, easy to understand language how their children are doing and that is why it is not going away anytime soon, but it needs to be put into perspective, it is one tool, one way of measuring progress."
Writing skills of concern

Federal Education Minister Simon Birmingham described the national results as a mixed bag.

"We are seeing improvements in terms of reading skills, numeracy skills and particularly strongest in the earliest years of primary school, so that's encouraging and positive for the future," he said.
"But it is a worry that our writing skills in our school children appear to be going backwards and there is a trend there in the NAPLAN scores that is a particular concern."
Mr Savage said he expected NAPLAN testing would be more effective in 2018 when it moves to online testing.
He said students would sit the tests in May and schools and parents would get almost immediate feedback and adjust programs to implement changes.
He said under the current pen-and-paper tests, students sit the exams in May and do not get the final results until the end of the school year in December.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OECD's PISA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UWA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Education Minister Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Western</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Education Minister Sue Ellery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Savage</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Student Assessment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
