<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411936181044513</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828614/hunter-wary-of-nearest-rivals/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Hunter wary of nearest rivals</title>
  <content>
A fully fit Hunter United will be on guard for a revival from Eastwood-Ryde in their top-of-the-table Netball NSW Metro League division one clash on Thursday night.

Hunter United
Hunter defeated second-placed Eastwood-Ryde 50-41 in a rare close contest for the competition leaders, who are seven points clear of the field after 12 wins and a draw in 14 games this season.
While Hunter have maintained their form through an injury-hit period, Eastwood-Ryde have lost their past three games to sit equal on 18 points with Illawarra.
However, Hunter coach Traci Baber said form was difficult to read in the league. 
"You don't know what any teams' injuries, what their commitments or illnesses are, or whether premier league players are coming in or out, you just have to go into every game knowing it's going to be tough," Baber said. "We're expecting a tough game, especially with them coming off a loss, you always want to get whoever you play next and with us being the leaders, everyone wants to get us.
"We're just concentrating on ourselves and trying to finish as strong as we can."

Ellie McVey will miss the match because of work commitments but Hunter are otherwise full strength.

"I've got 10 healthy, fit girls at the moment and nine going down tomorrow night," Baber said.

"I'd say it's the first time I've got nine girls who could all play a whole game if I needed them to."

In another boost for Hunter United, their No.2 side, the Diamonds, ended the unbeaten run of division four leaders Inner Western Suburbs 48-43 on Monday night. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baber</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellie McVey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eastwood-Ryde</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netball NSW Metro League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Traci Baber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter United</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
