<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411334885614525</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/grandmother-becomes-social-media-star-dance-moves/3207804/</url>
  <title>Dancing grandma becomes instant social media star</title>
  <content>
SOMETIMES there is just no resisting the rhythm of the music - no matter your age!

An Irish grandmother has become an instant internet sensation after her impromptu dance moves went viral on social media.

Galway resident Caroline Fortune-Loughrey filmed her mother and another woman dancing to the hit song 'Despacito'.

But it was the elder of the two who stole the show, busting out moves that would shame many a frequent nightclubber.

However, even the best of us know when one dance move is one too many with Ms Fortune-Loughrey's calls for more quickly waved away.

Ms Fortune-Loughrey uploaded the video to Facebook on July 22 and it quickly caught viral fire after it was watched over 31,000 times and shared by 141 people.  

The video follows on from the three Australian bowlers who  that also became a viral hit.

SELANGOR Private Hospital has celebrated its 70th birthday.
"I'm absolutely heartbroken to hear the two humpback whales died."
'Teen fed burning hot sauce, punched in face and stomach'
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Fortune-Loughrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SELANGOR Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Despacito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fortune-Loughrey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
