<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411927591109720</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/south-sydney-rabbitohs-coach-michael-maguire-responds-to-of-burgess-twins-weight-criticism-20170802-gxns27.html</url>
  <title>Rabbitohs coach says he'll speak to former player about weight criticism</title>
  <content>
South Sydney coach Michael Maguire says he will discuss game plan and player weight criticisms from former Rabbitohs prop Mark Carroll with the man himself.
Carroll raised his concerns on Tuesday about the side's lacklustre performance, starting with the Burgess twins.Photo: Brendan Esposito
He said Tom and George Burgess must drop their playing weight - currently at 120 kilograms each - over the summer to re-invigorate their NRL careers.
"Personally, I wish they'd get down in size a bit. I reckon they should get down to about 115," Carroll told AAP at Fox League's Retro Round launch in Sydney.Photo: AAP
"They're just massive humans. They don't have to do weights and they'd still keep weight on.
"But the game these days is about pace, mobility, working on the inside."

Carroll said while Maguire's "a fabulous coach" his current roster needs an overhaul, and his playing style should be adjusted to the up-tempo game plans in vogue across the league because "attack-wise, Souths are poor".

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Maguire returned the friendly fire from the former NSW and Australian representative on Wednesday.Photo: Anthony Johnson
"I think everyone has their opinion and I have a lot of respect for Mark too but we do that internally and I'll talk to him about those sorts of different things," he said of the proposed clean-out.
"I'm very open with a lot of our great players that have played at the club.
"I think that, over time, is a part of what any club goes through but we'll review where we are and continually make changes where needed."
Maguire said comments about South Sydney needing to work on their attack next season were not unfamiliar.
"A lot of people ask me about this. I think our game plan is very similar to most teams but if we hang onto the ball and give ourselves the best opportunity with the ball then we'll be able to show a little bit more," he said.
"That's something that we've been challenged with right throughout the year.
"And if you give yourself an opportunity to get down the other end and complete your sets ... well people will probably see our attack in a different light."
As for any players needing to shed a few kilograms, Maguire seemed unfazed.
"I don't know where I could probably get kilos off them," he said.
"They've probably got one of the lowest skin folds in the competition so I'll have to have a look at that one."
AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carroll</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maguire</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Maguire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rabbitohs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox League's Retro Round</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Esposito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
