<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411583993721541</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826098/healthy-balls-of-bliss-for-school-lunchboxes/?cs=2388</url>
  <title>Food ideas: Cookie Dough Bliss Balls</title>
  <content>
Cookie Dough Bliss Balls

Recently I held a free workshop at the gorgeous new bulk whole food store in the heart of Wollongong, The Source. The workshop focused on home-made nutritious and delicious school snacks for kids that are free from nuts, dairy and eggs (the most common food allergies going around) in addition to being completely free from refined sugars and additives or preservatives which store-bought school snacks are typically ladened with.
One of the most popular tasters we gave out during the workshop to both adults and kids was these little bliss bombs of awesomeness which we have named our "Cookie Dough Bliss Balls". The combination of natural sweetness from the dates and coconut, the nutty taste from the oats and then added decadence of the cacao nibs, makes this treat a taste sensation. And not only do they taste amazing, they are also super awesome for our kids to have as a school snack as the combination of complex carbohydrates, fibre, healthy fats and the absence of any nasties means their blood sugars remain more stable throughout the day and they stay fuller for longer. Total winner on all fronts.
So for those that couldn't make it to the workshop, here is the recipe for you to make yourself and see how delicious they are. Once you have a made a batch you can eat them straight out of the fridge or you can freeze them to defrost over the course of the morning for school lunchboxes.
Enjoy!
Makes 14-16 balls
Ingredients:
2 cups rolled oats
10 medjool dates
5 tbsp water
3 tbsp shredded coconut
2 tbsp cacao nibs (or raisins or choc chips if you would prefer)
1 tbsp coconut sugar (optional)
1 tsp vanilla
Pinch of sea salt to taste
Method:
Blend oats in a high speed blender or food processor until you get a fine consistency, like flour. Add in shredded coconut and vanilla and process. Slowly add dates and water, and process until smooth consistency.
Remove dough from the food processor/blender and fold through the cacao nibs. Roll the dough into small round balls and store in the refrigerator or freezer ready to those school lunchboxes.

Recipe by Stephanie Meades, Life Wellness Co. Pty Ltd. For more whole food inspired recipe ideas, visit www.lifewellnessco.com or come in store at The Store, Wollongong every second Friday from 12 noon. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Meades</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cookie Dough Bliss Balls</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Wellness Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
