<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411970540783422</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/national-affairs/treasury/pm-puts-gst-onus-on-labor/news-story/9f4735901d931c48ab494d20d6fc067f</url>
  <title>'Start acting like PM' on GST</title>
  <content>
Malcolm Turnbull has put the onus on Western Australian Premier Mark McGowan to demand co-operation from his state and federal Labor colleagues ahead of the pair meeting to discuss the issue this afternoon.
Federal WA Labor MPs have meanwhile called on Mr Turnbull to stop blame-shifting and take action as Prime Minister to address the fact that the state only gets to keep 34.7 cents for every dollar of GST it raises.
Mr Turnbull said the status quo clearly didn't "pass the pub test".
"It certainly doesn't pass the test in any pub in WA," he said.
"I am the first prime minister to have acknowledged that there is a problem here.
"We are the first government, it began under my predecessor Tony Abbott, to provide in effect top-up funding to WA out of the federal budget to try to address some of this unfairness."
Mr Turnbull said his government had committed more than $1bn in top-up funding so far.
"But what we do need to get is a fairer distribution of the GST and one that's recognised as fair across the country, so we have the Productivity Commission examining the formula.
However, he said the biggest obstacles to changing the formula were Bill Shorten and his state Labor counterparts.
"New South Wales, Liberal state, has recommended a change to the GST formula. Don't take my word for it. It's there. They've made a submission to the Productivity Commission," he said.
"You've got the Western Australian federal MPs and senators made a completely wishy washy submission to the Productivity Commission which recommended nothing.
"Mark McGowan is the Labor premier of Western Australia. He's got to start standing up for Western Australia within the Labor Party.
"I've been making the case for Western Australia to the state Labor premiers. What's Mark McGowan doing? He should be able to have more influence with them. He should be able to have influence with Bill Shorten so I'm going to hopefully this afternoon, in the friendliest and kindest possible way, in the most helpful way, encourage him to put a bit of steel in his spine and have a go at Bill Shorten and get the Labor Party on board for what really needs to be a review of the GST so that all Australians will be able to say, 'yep that's fair, that's what we want to achieve'."
Federal WA Labor MP Tim Hammond said Mr Turnbull was the Prime Minister and needed to "start acting like one".
"He is the one with the power to get this changed and get it fixed and quite frankly it is just not good enough for him to swan in over here on only his second trip to WA in eight or nine months to suggest the answer to fixing the GST lies somewhere else," Mr Hammond told Sky News.
"The answer to getting the GST disparity fixed is right in front of Malcolm Turnbull's face and he and Scott Morrison both have the power to get this done and all they are doing here is shooting the blame home to anyone else except for themselves.
"The community is just not buying what it is the Malcolm Turnbull is trying to sell over here."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal WA Labor MP Tim Hammond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Productivity Commission</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal WA Labor MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hammond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
