<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411841691762701</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/mining/coal/yancoal-to-raise-3b-to-fund-coal--allied-deal-20170802-gxnmtw</url>
  <title>Yancoal to raise $3b to fund Coal & Allied deal</title>
  <content>
Yancoal believes it can extract as much as $140 million in synergies from its acquisition of Rio Tinto's Coal & Allied business, which will also bring a suite of new investors onto its share registry.
Yancoal announced details for its $US2.5 billion ($3.1 billion) capital raising on Wednesday. The raising, the largest on the ASX this year, will fund t
The Chinese company that owns the bulk of Yancoal, which is called Yanzhou, had previously committed to inject $US1 billion into the raising, and Yancoal has also secured $US300 million of equity from Swiss commodities giant Glencore, which
But Yancoal also revealed on Wednesday that it will bring in a number of new investors as part of the raising.

Chinese merchant bank Cinda Asset Management will join Glencore in taking up $US300 million in stock, while finance group Shandong Lucion Investment Holdings will take up $US200 million.

Coal group Shandong Taizhong Energy will take up $US100 million of shares, while mining and commodities group General Nice Development will buy $US50 million of shares.
The attitude of Yancoal minority shareholders, Noble Group and Senrigan Capital Group, towards the rights issue remains unclear. The pair will be heavily diluted through the deal.
Yancoal says the deal will make it Australia's largest pure-play coal miner, only behind Glencore and BHP in terms of annual coal production.
The company said the deal will result in synergies of between $120 million and $145 million, with the bulk of those savings - as much as $85 million - coming from procurement cost savings, such as the optimisation of equipment across the mines, and improved purchasing power.

Another $35 million in cost savings is expected to come from the elimination of duplicated corporate overheads, while Yancoal also says it can earn $25 million through the marketing of different coal blends.
The size of the synergies underline why Glencore, which initially lost the auction for Coal & Allied, was so keen to get a piece of the deal. Glencore has mines adjacent to HVO, so will be well placed to extract savings of its own.
Yancoal said demand for thermal coal would be underpinned by the push to build so-called super critical and ultra super-cricial power plants in Asia, which generate fewer carbon emissions but require higher quality coal.
The company expects the thermal coal price will be remain around $US69 a tonne to $US78 a tonne across the remainder of 2017, and says the push by Chinese regulators to monitor and potentially restrict the output of domestic coal producers should support prices.

Newcastle thermal coal is currently hovering around $U93 a tonne, having been as high as $US119 a tonne in November 2016.
Yancoal chairman Xiyong Li said the deal will "redefine our position within the global coal marketplace and strengthen Yancoal Australia for the future."
Brokers Morgan Stanley, JPMorgan and CICC are handling the deal, which has not been underwritten and opens on August 10.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$119</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Nice Development</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senrigan Capital Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shandong Lucion Investment Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U93</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yancoal</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xiyong Li</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HVO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JPMorgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto's Coal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cinda Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shandong Taizhong Energy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yanzhou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yancoal Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$300</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CICC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US78</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US69</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
