<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411979130718121</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/bombers-hold-off-on-watson-call-as-finals-beckon/3207941/</url>
  <title>Bombers hold off on Watson call as finals beckon</title>
  <content>
AFL: Don't expect Jobe Watson to join the growing list of players announcing their retirement just yet.
Essendon coach John Worsfold said "at this stage" a decision on the veteran midfielder's future wouldn't be made until the end of the season and he hoped any potential conversation about a possible send-off game would be thwarted by a finals appearance.
"Hopefully not, because you can't plan a farewell game in the finals, that's our aim," Worsfold said.
"You don't know when your last game is going to be.
"Ultimately at this stage I'll be sitting down with Jobe post season and talking about where we're at as a club, where he's at. That decision will be made on the balance of the whole season."
Watson has been a star for the Bombers since making his debut with the club in 2003, notching up 216 games.
Worsfold said he hadn't spoken to Watson about his form, which the coach had been "pretty happy with".
"I think he's working really hard," the Bombers coach said.
"He hasn't been best on ground every week but he's still helped us become a pretty competitive team."
Defender Patrick Ambrose is a chance to return for Saturday's crunch game against Carlton. Ambrose has recovered from quad injuries and has played two games in the VFL.
Forward Josh Green is available with Worsfold declaring "he's flying on the track".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Worsfold</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Ambrose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jobe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ambrose</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Worsfold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
