<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411931886077105</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4829105/searching-for-a-slim-hope/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Searching for a slim hope</title>
  <content>
Three-year-old William Tyrell went missing in 2014. Photo: Max Mason Hubers

The clock starts ticking the moment a missing person is reported to police.

Andrew Bourke
The battle is not only the physical aspect of searching, it's the emotional fight to keep hope alive.
Officers immediately create a profile; when the person was last seen, appearance, state of mind, medical needs, any drug or trauma issues, plus phone, social media, and money-access activity. The officer becomes the information and support lifeline for family, plus help if media is called in to spread the word for help.
This week, a joint operation between Griffth and Wagga police found a 37 year-old Wagga man safe and well in Narrandera, after he went missing for 27 hours. A process of elimination saw key places searched first.
Other cases, however, remain unsolved. Andrew Bourke hasn't been seen for six years. He disappeared in July 2011 after drinking with another person and allegedly driving his vehicle into the Tumut River. Did he drown? Was it an accident, or was he murdered? 
And while attention is always on supporting loved ones, police, too, become affected.
Cases such as  who was snatched outside his grandmother's house three years ago. He was last seen wearing a Spider-Man suit.

"There wouldn't be a police officer (working on these cases) who doesn't go home and say, 'Oh my God I'm going to give my kids a cuddle tonight'," Wagga police chief Bob Noble said.

"Police become very emotionally invested in finding these people, and it's a sense of pride that we solve the case."
Every year in Australia 38,000 people are reported missing, and while most are located fairly quickly, 1600 people are placed on the missing persons list.
What is changing is the use of more sophisticated technology. The question is, will technology advance to such a level that every missing could be found?
"Biometrics, facial recognition and CCTV are going through leaps and bounds and as scary as it might be, there will be a roll out of technology with that application," Superintendent Noble said. 

"But there will always be people that want to disappear, and you should ever underestimate the resourcefulness, and deviousness, even, of a person that wants to disappear."

Daily Advertiser
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spider-Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narrandera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 38,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Mason-Hubers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tumut River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superintendent Noble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Tyrell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Bourke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Advertiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Noble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
