<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411884641436164</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/green-guide-letters-the-readers-brickbats-and-bouquets-20170731-gxme71.html</url>
  <title>Green Guide letters: the readers' brickbats and bouquets </title>
  <content>
Look at moi

Going through my Green Guide this week I see with delight Kath and Kim are back, this time on Nine. I know it's all a bit old now, but at a time when we could really do with a laugh, I reckon Nine have hit on a great idea in giving them another run. Not so sure about the decision to put it on after the Hamish and Andy show though - all that's going to do is prove how unfunny the boys are in comparison.
Alex Duntish, St KildaPhoto: Rodger Cummins
Their goose is cooked

Nailed on the head Deb Hunt! My wife and I said exactly the same. We watched a previous series of MasterChef and were also disappointed with the outcome but thought we'd give it another go, though   we were   disappointed leading up to the end. Do they think  the viewers are so stupid as not to see it's a total farce! Gary, George and Matt really stuffed it with those scores. That's it. You've lost us forever now and I guess a few million others.
Malcolm Harrison, Preston
Selling out

I had the displeasure Sunday night to watch the free-to-air screening on Channel 7 of The Dressmaker. It was an absolute disgrace how many ads were presented during this screening and in inappropriate places. Also the aspect ratio of the film was all wrong. Channel 7 has done a disservice to the Australian film industry and  its viewers by presenting The Dressmaker so badly. It leaves little wonder why people are staying away in droves to free-to-air television.
Kevin Janner, Brunswick

On the boil

I just love Eggheads (ABC). The resident panel's knowledge is so egg-stensive. What incredible minds! Educational, entertaining and riveting viewing, if quiz shows are your thing. It tends to have an English bias on some questions, which puts us Australian viewers at a slight disadvantage. Australian television needs its own version; it would certainly be an improvement on what is currently on offer in this genre and might improve our minds?
Carolyn Garvey, Kingston
Fingers off the Pulse

Are the producers of Pulse, the new medical serial on the ABC really serious? God help anyone who landed in that chaotic hospital expecting reasonable treatment for whatever ailed them. It looked more like another dating options show than a serious medical drama. As one of the surgeons uttered mid operation: "Sex on toast."
Pamela Pilgrim, Highett
Reality check

I was looking forward to Pulse given I like good homemade drama and I liked the cast. I was very disappointed after the first screening but to give the show the benefit of the doubt I watched the second episode. Having worked in hospitals for 40 years, this  show does not resemble what happens in any hospital I have ever worked in. Apart from the fact  there are few staff portrayed other than doctors, the storyline is fanciful and ill-informed. This misrepresentation of reality matters for many reasons but my primary concern is it gives prospective health care workers a false image of what a career in health may look like.
Julie Sharrock, Ocean Grove
Short-changed 

I am a big fan of Sterling Archer, so I get annoyed when I record the show late at night to view later only to discover that some inferior program has been substituted. The networks seem to do this a lot, presumably to discourage people from recording, but all they achieve is to get us mad and eventually I abandon them altogether and get free DVDs from the library. I can wait!
Eric Peterson, Brighton East
Email letters, including your name, address and daytime phone number, to . Letters must be 75 words or fewer and may be edited. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brunswick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVDs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Harrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Sharrock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Janner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7 of The Dressmaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Guide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodger Cummins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sterling Archer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolyn Garvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deb Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterchef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St KildaPhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Peterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pamela Pilgrim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Duntish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ocean Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
