<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412013490456957</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/lifestyle/arts-and-entertainment/art/mossgreen-makes-push-into-contemporary-art-with-uk-sale-20170802-gxnjgz</url>
  <title>Mossgreen makes push into contemporary art with UK sale</title>
  <content>
by
Peter Fish

Mossgreen is shedding more than a dozen staff and has sold its premises, but chief executive Paul Sumner says it is business as usual at the Melbourne-based auction house, which continues to line up sales at a frenetic pace.
Sumner says the staff restructure reflects the firm's increasing focus on single-owner collections and higher value lots following its expansion in recent years - including the merger with the Charles Leski stamp auction group in 2013 and the takeover of New Zealand's Webb's last year.
He says the job-shedding involves mainly internal support staff, though one specialist left of his own accord.
As for the sale of its premises, a refurbished cinema in Armadale that was once the home of Sotheby's, Sumner says the firm leases the building, as it does all its premises. "The new owner is someone we know well," he says.

Supplied

As well as holding regular mixed-vendor sales of paintings and decorative art, Mossgreen specialises in frequent single-owner auctions of pictures, furniture, classic cars, stamps, rare books and Australiana. "We've now got more single-owner collections than we've ever had," says Sumner.

It is also pushing into the market for contemporary art - an area Sumner sees as ripe for development.
Players scramble

It thus offers a point of difference to other players in the rarified market for the priciest artworks, where a handful of operators including Sotheby's, Deutscher and Hackett, and Menzies, scramble for big-ticket works to offer.
But Mossgreen can also steal a march on the leaders - as it did with its landmark sale of the $7 million collection of Dr Peter Elliott in Sydney two years ago.

 Upcoming is a sale of contemporary art from a wealthy British collector, to be held in Melbourne on September 17. It might seem counter-intuitive to offer a UK collection in Australia, but about half the artists featured are Asian and some have had exposure in public galleries here.
They include Indian artist Jitish Kallat, whose work has been shown at Sydney's Museum of Contemporary Art. Kallat's Collidonthus from 2007, resembling a life-size skeletonised car, has a pre-sale estimate of $130,000 to $200,000. Other notable inclusions are China's Zheng Fanzhi whose Sky No 7  is $900,000 to $1.18 million, and Fang Lijun, whose triptych 2007.6.7, is listed at $650,000 to $920,000.
Cohen sale

Sumner admits there are few significant collectors of high-value contemporary art here, but the firm has been doing extensive marketing: "There hasn't been an auction like this in Australia. It's very left field," he says.

"[But] in the eyes of the UK we're seen as a safe way of selling art into China, with our strong legal and banking systems. We've done a lot [of business] in China." 
Although Mossgreen does not name the owner of the UK collection, it has been identified by Britain's Daily Telegraph as being from the prominent entrepreneur Frank Cohen, who is known as the "Saatchi of the North" because of his appetite for art.
It seems that Cohen, 74, an entrepreneur who graduated from collecting cigarette cards to owning five warehouses full of contemporary art, is running out of space and wants to cut back.
Ariadne controversy

Meanwhile, Mossgreen has put noses out of joint by using Streeton's tiny 1895 masterpiece Ariadne to attract works for its October art sale. Its ads extol the fact that it sold the work for $500,200 compared with an estimate of $200,000 to $300,000. That was in June 2014.
But of course the buyer at that sale, a prominent Sydney art dealer, then sold Ariadne to the National Gallery of Australia for more than twice as much - a cool $900,000 - and next Ariadne's image was all over London promoting the Australian Impressionists exhibition at the National Gallery, its appearance at such a prestigious show adding even more to its status.
As well as possibly leaving the original owners of the painting, a Darling Point family, feeling a bit short-changed, it hardly seems to reflect great credit on the original estimate of its value.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Museum of Contemporary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky No 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mossgreen</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Streeton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fang Lijun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Gallery of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kallat's Collidonthus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Zheng Fanzhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hackett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cohen, 74</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Peter Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jitish Kallat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand's Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Sumner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australiana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sotheby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sumner</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Fish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Leski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armadale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saatchi of the North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ariadne</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutscher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Gallery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Impressionists</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
