<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411841691762688</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/west-coast/sam-mitchell-busts-his-own-big-myth-confirms-his-preferred-foot-to-kick-footy-with/news-story/980c1a88849a81dd275187f355cb05ef</url>
  <title>Retiring Eagle busts his own biggest myth</title>
  <content>
THERE'S not much the footy world doesn't know about Sam Mitchell - except to say for certain what his preferred kicking boot is.
So the man himself put any doubts to bed on Wednesday during his retirement presser.
Mitchell announced he would  at the end of this season after a decorated AFL career, which included four premierships, a Brownlow Medal and five Hawthorn best and fairests.
After thanking family, friends, teammates, coaches and even the media, Mitchell was asked if he was a left or right-footer.
SAM MITCHELL WILL BE ON FOX FOOTY'S AFL 360 TONIGHT FROM 7.30PM (AEST)
It's a conundrum many have debated over the years due to Mitchell's ambidextrous nature. Few players have kicked on both feet with equal preference and performance.
But Mitchell said his kicking versatility stemmed from an interesting string of events during his early teenage years.
"As a kid, I started off as a left-footer, but I had to change my technique," Mitchell told reporters.
"I was one of those kids that dropped the ball with two hands, so I spent a year changing my technique when I was about 13 or 14.
"In the middle of that, I had a coach that thought I was a right-footed and yelled at me for kicking on my left. He thought I was 'lairising'.
"So I did two things. One I became a right-footer and two I got a dictionary and tried to figure out what lairising meant.
"So I became I right-footer at the age of 14."
By foot, Mitchell never had the penetration of a Jason Johannisen, but his ambidexterity was one of his greatest weapons.
His ability to mark the ball, stop on the mark, assess his options then disposed by hand or foot - either left or right - has kickstarted many Hawthorn and, later, West Coast scores over the years.
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Johannisen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAM MITCHELL WILL BE ON FOX FOOTY'S AFL 360 TONIGHT FROM 7.30PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
