<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412056440130733</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/carnegie-sale-tops-16-million-amid-demand-from-developers/news-story/e84c715b12f11cffd730cb824ea8ef4d</url>
  <title>Carnegie sale tops $1.6 million amid demand from developers - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
sold for $1.63 million on July 22.

A property held by one owner for decades has sold for a hefty seven-figure price at auction, after a buyer was prepared to pay more than $1.6 million purely for its land value.
Woodards Carnegie agent Benjamin Dax said the price for the 618sq m property at , was a very significant result for land value in the suburb.
"It was really strong, given it wasn't a conventionally shaped block," he said.
Mr Dax said at more than $2630 per square meter, the site was a good indicator of what land value was now worth in that area.
"I think it's the new benchmark for that type of site," he said.
The July 22 auction attracted solid competition, Mr Dax said.
"The auction went for half an hour, and there were three very keen bidders," he said.
Mr Dax said two bidders seeking home sites vied for the property, but a bidder interested in its development potential came out on top. He said the hammer fell at $1.63 million, soaring past hopes.
"We expected it to be in the $1.2 million-$1.3 million range," Mr Dax said. The result had delighted the family who had owned the property for many years, he added.
Mr Dax said competition for land with development potential was strong, as there was little available.
"It's hugely popular because there's not a lot of it," he said.
SEE SUBURB PROFILE:
Earlier in July, a Carnegie home went under the hammer four years from when it last did, with very few details unfolding differently this time - except for the sale price.
The home at  sold for $1.26 million on July 8 but its last sale, in April 2013, netted $756,500, CoreLogic records show.
Mr Dax said the property had not been renovated, and had the same agent, marketing campaign, sale type and auctioneer each time it was sold. The more than $500,000 price gain was purely down to the market, he added.
"It was in identical condition; they hadn't done a thing," Mr Dax said. "It's a perfect indicator of the growth we've seen in Carnegie."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dax</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 22</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodards Carnegie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Dax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUBURB PROFILE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carnegie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
