<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412099389804236</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/sa-racing/double-vision-for-jockey-krystal-bishop-trainer-greg-lesnikowski-as-new-era-kicks-off-at-morphettville/news-story/dfc3824a0031520c6dfec785948a8084</url>
  <title>Double vision as new era kicks off</title>
  <content>
GREG Lesnikowski and Krystal Bishop have combined to claim a small chunk of South Australian thoroughbred racing history at Morphettville.
Wednesday's Morphettville card was the first South Australian race meeting to be broadcast on free-to-air TV after the commencement of a landmark media-rights deal between Thoroughbred Racing SA and Racing.com.
Bishop rode the Lesnikowski-trained Xaarian to win the opening race under the new seven-year deal, the vision streamed into homes on Seven West Media's Channel 78.
"Yes, I've got the first winner with Racing.com and I'm leading the trainers' premiership, too," Strathalbyn-based Lesnikowski joked, the race also the first of the 2017-18 SA racing season.
Xaarian, having just his seventh start, certainly showed enough to suggest Wednesday's win in the Holdfast Insurance Maiden (2025m) wouldn't be his last.
The four-year-old gelding, on the third line of betting at $4.40, settled just off the pace then proved too strong in the straight, bullocking clear to win by two lengths. The Greg Dunn-trained Midrada ($91) fought on for second, two lengths clear of the favourite Unflynnching ($2.50), who loomed as the winner on the home turn but only battled in the run to the line.
"He went super today," Bishop said. "We've done a lot of work with him and finally got everything right. He's settling beautifully and I think there's more to come."
Lesnikowski and Bishop didn't have to wait long to return to the winner's stall, with four-year-old mare Hilumiere prevailing two races later.
It was the fourth city double for Bishop, 24, whose career has been hampered by a string of injury issues.
Lesnikowski, who has only had 40 runners this year, is already halfway to matching his winning tally from last season.
"I was hopeful we might get a double but you don't want to get too carried away," he said.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilumiere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lesnikowski</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishop</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holdfast Insurance Maiden (2025</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven West Media's Channel 78</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Dunn-trained Midrada ($91</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Krystal Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathalbyn-based Lesnikowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unflynnching ($2.50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREG Lesnikowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thoroughbred Racing SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xaarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lesnikowski-trained Xaarian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday's Morphettville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphettville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
