<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412056440130748</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-02/bee-projectto-protect-horticulture-from-impact-of-varroa-mite/8767470</url>
  <title>Pollination project: Hunt for best working bee</title>
  <content>
Bees have long been a critical element to the productivity of farmers, the difference between a bumper crop and financial loss.
Now protecting pollination-dependent crops from disaster will be the focus of an Australian first, $10 million research project led by the Rural Industries Research and Development Corporation (RIRDC).
With about 65 per cent of Australian crops relying to some extent on the introduced European honeybee to fertilise flowers for fruit, better understanding of the industry and threats facing producers is crucial.
RIRDC project manager Paul Blackshaw, who based in Rutherglen, Victoria, said the project would focus on protection from pests and diseases.
He said there was also a side benefit of being able to increase profitability and productivity for industries that rely on bees.
Multiple scares involving colonies of Asian honeybees, which carry the parasitic varroa mite have left beekeepers and the industries that rely on their pollinating services worried mass bee deaths could occur,'' Mr Blackshaw said.

"We've got very strong biosecurity measures in place, but the concern is varroa mite is possibly going to enter Australia."

"This project is hopefully getting on the front foot to make sure the industry is prepared if that event occurs."
Researching alternatives to European honeybees should the varroa mite devastate wild bee populations is another element of the RIRDC project.

Tetragonula carbonaria, a native bee, has been identified as a successful pollinator for many crops.

Tetragonula carbonaria, a native bee, has been identified as a successful pollinator for many crops.

Supplied: University of New England

"A part of this project is to look into what native pollinators are in existence," Mr Blackshaw said.
"We tend to always think bees, but other insects like butterflies and flies are also native pollinators as well as some of our native bees."
Mr Blackshaw said better vegetation management could be key to encouraging native insects to provide pollination in orchards and paddocks.
Native options

Dr Mark Greco, from Charles Sturt University in Wagga Wagga, has been investigating native bee management for nearly three decades.
In the past he has used medical scanners to study bee behaviour and potential environmental influences on their important work.
Dr Greco said the stingless native bee Tetragonula carbonaria, found in subtropical and coastal Australia as far south as Bega, could be an effective pollinator for crops.
"From trials we have discovered the native bees will effectively pollinate capsicum crops in our greenhouses here," Dr Greco said.

Dr Mark Greco has been researching the behaviour of native stingless bees.

Dr Mark Greco has been researching the behaviour of native stingless bees.

Supplied: CSU Media

Macadamia farmers have also found success in pollinating their trees with the stingless bees.
Dr Greco said native bees small size meant they were immune to infestation by the varroa mite.
"They are about the size of a mosquito, the varroa mite is about half the size of the native honeybee, so it's way too small to act as a host."
Research roll-out

Four sub-projects delivered by Australian National University, The University of Adelaide, University of New England and University of Sydney will be funded to under the RIRDC scheme.
Work has already started assessing pollination deficits in apple orchards and investigations into the blueberry and raspberry industries.
Mr Blackshaw said building on those existing strong relationships between researchers and key horticulture industries was important to provide on-farm feedback about pollination.
"They're playing a really important role there, as well as the extension and the delivery of the key messages to the industry once they become a bit clearer."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIRDC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rutherglen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Sturt University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Greco</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bega</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rural Industries Research</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of New</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Blackshaw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CSU Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Blackshaw</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Mark Greco</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tetragonula</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagga Wagga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
