<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412060735098071</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/opal-aged-care-managing-director-accused-of-bullying/8738394</url>
  <title>Opal Aged Care boss Gary Barnier accused of bullying complaining patients' relatives</title>
  <content>
Accusations of bullying have been levelled at the managing director of one of Australia's biggest nursing home chains. He also offered money after one family complained about the abuse and death of their loved one.

In a two-part investigation by 7.30, members of two families say they felt intimidated by senior managers at Opal Aged Care, a company half-owned by Australia's AMP.
In the most disturbing case, a Victorian man - who prefers to be known only as Graeme - said the company's managing director, Gary Barnier, offered him $10,000 after his mother's death.
Graeme's mother, Beryl, was blind and diabetic. She had been a resident at Opal Lakeside for four years.
In December last year, she had extremely high blood sugar readings. Two doctors recommended she go to hospital but staff failed to send her. She was eventually rushed to hospital where she died on December 11.
Graeme called Mr Barnier, trying to find out why staff ignored the advice.
"And he started to turn, 'You can't threaten me and, you know ... take it to court," Graeme said.
"And then [he] goes, 'I know you are hurting, I can see you are hurting'. And this is all via the phone, 'So, mate, as a token gesture from me to you, I'll offer you $10,000'.
"What is that for?"

Mr Barnier denies he bullied or intimidated Graeme.
"I say that's absolutely not the case and I had another person in the room who has taken down the conversation," he told 7.30.
"What I can say is Graeme was very distressed."
But Mr Barnier admits offering $10,000 to Graeme to assist him financially because he was emotionally distressed.
"At the time it was my personal judgement that it was appropriate, given the particular circumstances that he raised with me," Mr Barnier said.
Beryl's death is being investigated by the coroner.
'He started to yell at me'

In another case, Helen Hardy said Mr Barnier had a "screaming match" with her, suggesting she "see a psychiatrist" when she complained about an Opal care worker who hit her 84-year-old mother across the head in 2013.

Police charged the worker with assault but the case was dismissed when the worker produced two statutory declarations from co-workers saying she hit June Johnston across the head because she saw lice.
"This person had produced two stat decs to say that she was hitting lice off my mother's head. She got away with it," Ms Hardy said.
Ms Hardy wrote to Mr Barnier, who called her.
"It basically went: 'What more do you want me to do?'," Ms hardy said.
"'I've sacked the woman. If you've still got a problem you need to see somebody and get some counselling. You need to see a psychiatrist and I can organise that for you'.

"And he started to yell at me, 'Don't you dare talk to me like that. Don't talk over the top of me'."
Mr Barnier said he did not recall any conversation with Ms Hardy but said it was possible others from Opal offered assistance, "in the event that they express distress to actually get them some help".
"I have no recollection and I don't believe it [the conversation] ever happened," he said.
Mr Barnier said he does not know why two people said they were intimidated by manner.
"I can't explain that," he said.
"I can only tell you what I firmly and honestly believe, that I offered that money in good faith to assist him [Graeme] with the things that he raised with me. And that there was no screaming match [with Helen] at all."
Opal Aged Care was previously called Domain Principal, and owned the  in 2011.
Drug-addicted nurse Roger Dean set the home alight because he had stolen prescription medication.
Another Opal home in NSW made news recently after .
Unchecked pressure sores led to death

In another case, Danny Selir died at an Opal nursing home after 12 weeks, partly due to necrotic pressure wounds.
Mr Selir went to Opal Leamington on Queensland's Gold Coast in 2015 for respite care following a stroke. After three months he was admitted to hospital with gangrene in his foot and in his buttocks due to extensive pressure sores.
His daughter-in-law, Yvonne, went to the home demanding answers. It denied the pressure sores had occurred there.

"I said, 'What do you mean it didn't happen here?'," Yvonne said.
"She said, 'No it wasn't like that when he left here', 'So you're telling me that in a 10-minute ride in the ambulance, from Leamington to the Golf Coast University Hospital, gangrene happened?' And that's when she asked us to leave."
Mr Selir died the next day.
Mr Barnier said Mr Selir presented to the nursing home with some necrotic wounds but they worsened while at the home.
"On the care documentation that I've seen, some of those wounds stayed the same, some slightly improved and others, frankly, got worse," he said.
He said Mr Selir had received attention but acknowledged staff "did not do enough for him."
This story is the first in a two-part 7.30 investigation to be aired tonight and tomorrow.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opal Lakeside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Barnier</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Selir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opal Leamington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domain Principal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Barnier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's AMP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Dean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hardy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yvonne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golf Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Selir</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Hardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leamington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opal Aged Care</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opals</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beryl</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
