<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411583993721505</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/star-recruit-brett-deledio-says-he-has-something-to-prove-to-his-gws-teammates/news-story/c45606900bdfc975ca1d981b69d8a858</url>
  <title>Deledio: 'I've got a point to prove'</title>
  <content>
GIANTS star recruit Brett Deledio says he still has something to prove to his new teammates despite an illustrious 243 game career at Richmond.
Deledio will play his first game for GWS on Saturday in Canberra against Melbourne after missing the entire season to date with a series of calf injuries.
"I probably do (have something to prove)," Deledio said.
"I want to show them (my teammates) I came up here for the right reasons and I can still play the game and offer something.
LIDS RETURN: '
COMING BACK:
They're an exciting bunch of blokes to play with hence the yellow boots, I have to try and fit in with these young bucks. I'm just excited to get out there with them I've watch them from afar."
The 30 year old said his time at GWS has been the most frustrating part of his career to date and revealed he had lost track of the number of times he re-injured his troublesome calf muscles.
"I have lost count," Deledio said.
"Overall I've had a nick in the calf about eight or nine times. They've never been huge just tiny things that set you back a couple of weeks at a time. That's the most frustrating thing you can probably deal with a big tear and know you're out for a certain amount of time, but the little ones I've tried to get the ball rolling too quickly and hence another setback."
Deledio has played two games in the NEAFL for the Giants reserves and shared the same hotel as his former team when they played the Gold Coast Suns reserves last weekend.
"I felt like I was on an interstate trip with the Tigers running into so many people I knew. It was good to catch up and the support from them and on social media have been greatly appreciated and kept me going through the darker days."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
