<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412056440130728</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/15/09/win-for-conservationists-in-nsw-mine-fight</url>
  <title>Win for conservationists in NSW mine fight</title>
  <content>
Conservationists have had a big win in their fight against a NSW Central Tablelands mine extension which they claim would pollute a major tributary of Sydney's water supply.
The NSW Supreme Court on Wednesday upheld not-profit group 4nature's appeal against the extension of Springvale coal mine, which would prolong the operation near Lithgow by 13 years.
Three judges unanimously found the 2015 approval for the mine extension was invalid, as the Planning Assessment Commission (PAC) made errors in assessing the development's effect on water quality.
Orders would ordinarily be made declaring the development consent invalid and setting it aside, the written judgement said.
But given the consequences for mine operator Centennial Coal and coal users, the court will hear further submissions before making such orders.
Environmentalists say the mine extension would dump polluted water into the Coxs River, a major tributary of Sydney's main water supply.
4nature spokesman Andrew Cox in a media release on Wednesday said the group wanted to find a reasonable resolution.

Related Articles

"We are willing to sit down with the government to find a way that honours the intent of the judgment while addressing immediate safety and job concerns," he said in a statement.
The NSW government in a statement said they would closely review the court's decision.
A spokesman said that until orders were given, the Springvale mine could continue to operate and supply the Mt Piper coal plant under PAC's 2015 development approval.
The underground mine has 437 employees and contractors, and produces up to 5.5 million tonnes of coal each year, according to Centennial Coal.
The company in a statement said it had maintained all issues were addressed during the "protracted and exhaustive" approval process.
"While the court decision is obviously disappointing, we have prepared for this outcome," said Katie Brassil, Centennial Coal's executive general manager of external affairs.
"A range of options have been identified and we will now proceed to implement these options to seek to ensure Springvale can continue operating without disruption."
Colong Foundation director Keith Muir said the decision enabled Springvale mine's plan to be "reset" so waterfalls and streams were protected, as well as drinking water catchments.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coxs River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Central Tablelands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keith Muir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAC's 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Piper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centennial Coal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lithgow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Brassil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Assessment Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colong Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springvale</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
