<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412103684771616</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/stage/melbourne-stage/david-williamsons-credentials-review-pervasive-misogyny-spoils-an-ambitious-tale-of-two-australias-20170802-gxnrjs.html</url>
  <title>David Williamson's new play Credentials spoiled by pervasive misogyny</title>
  <content>
THEATRE
CREDENTIALS ★★★
David Williamson
La Mama Courthouse
Until August 13
For La Mama's 50th anniversary, our most successful playwright, the semi-retired David Williamson, returns to the theatre that launched him.Photo: Supplied
The theatre has, like the nation, transformed since Williamson gave up engineering to take up the pen 50 years ago. Yet his appeal has remained constant.
There's his talent for portraying Australian types and voices. Williamson's following gets the frisson of recognition (his contemporaries do especially) when he holds a mirror to them.Photo: Supplied
And if a changing world can make that mirror into a funhouse distortion - the sequel Don Parties On pandered to the Boomers, while insulting the crap out of their children - that's a defect Williamson attempts to remedy in Credentials.
Heroic Chrissie (Kayla Hamill), a paramedic with a bleak past, looks like losing the job she loves and does superbly well, when her boss Stephen (Geoff Paine) discovers she faked her qualifications. This frames the action, as Chrissie's harrowing backstory is done in flashback, counterpointed by Stephen's travails with his neurotic wife (Nell Feeney) and spoiled daughter (Yvette Turner).

It's a tale of two Australias - the rich, urban, educated elite and the impoverished underclass with no way ahead - that spans the perils of privilege and the despair of drug addiction. It might be billed as black comedy, but is too troubling (despite some funny dialogue) for the label.
Credentials displays a pervasive, disconcerting misogyny. The dodgy phallocentrism of Chrissie's boyfriend Rick (Zak Giles Pidd​), has a realism we shouldn't shy away from. As Chrissie descends into her Sydney circle of hell, an even worse bloke (a bikie drug dealer with an overdone private-school voice from Matt Furlani) rears his head.Photo: Supplied
Ultimately, though, it isn't the brutalisation and demeaning of Chrissie - awful to behold - that's a turn-off, but the shallow caricature of privileged women. It's as if they are twisted into knots of gender stereotype, merely to prove what a long-suffering husband and father Stephen is.
And Mack (Paul Bongiorno) gives the subplot an icky Pretty Woman twist, which, as with the predictable finale, suggests that all the women - even the toughest - need to be saved by men.Photo: Supplied
Well, no one expects Williamson to be woke. And Credentials nonetheless still has meat for actors to sink their teeth into, with director Tom Gutteridge marshalling strong performances - particularly from Hamill, Paine and Giles Pidd.
Any new Williamson play attracts wide interest, and this is a better, riskier, and more ambitious work than anything he's written recently.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak Giles Pidd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chrissie</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Furlani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Giles Pidd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Bongiorno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Gutteridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Paine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Williamson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kayla Hamill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Williamson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yvette Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Mama's 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nell Feeney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pretty Woman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Mama Courthouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Parties On</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
