<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412099389804232</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/police-appeal-to-find-dylan-slingsby-in-connection-to-assault-car-theft-20170802-gxntxc.html</url>
  <title>Police appeal to find Dylan Slingsby in connection to assault, car theft</title>
  <content>
Photo: Queensland Police Service
Queensland Police are appealing for public assistance to find Dylan Slingsby, who they believe will be able to assist with their investigation into a car theft and violent assault on the Gold Coast.
Officers have been on the hunt for a man who assaulted a woman and stole her luxury car at Southport in the early hours of Wednesday morning.
A 54-year-old woman drove her Mercedes-Benz sedan into an underground carpark of an apartment building on Marine Parade, when she saw a man trying to enter a locked stairwell.
Police said she challenged the man, who then punched her in the face a number of times before driving off in her car.
The woman was taken to the Gold Coast Hospital and treated for serious facial injuries.
The car was later found by police at Coolangatta, and a man who was in the car was taken into police custody.
That man was assisting police with their enquiries, and police believe Mr Slingsby may also be able to assist.
Police warned members of the public who see Mr Slingsby not to approach him, and instead call police immediately.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Slingsby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolangatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Slingsby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes-Benz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Parade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
