<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411364950386027</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:38</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/mining/glencores-coal-chief-fires-up-on-energy-costs-20170801-gxnhrp</url>
  <title>Glencore's coal chief fires up on energy costs</title>
  <content>
Glencore's head of coal Peter Freyberg is set to launch an attack on "irresponsible" state governments announcing emissions reductions and says Australia may need to delay its Paris climate commitments.
Speaking at a luncheon in Sydney, Mr Freyberg says states need to spell out the true cost of their targets on power prices and jobs.
He also sounded a warning about the "rhetoric" around battery storage, which he says can do little to help power-heavy industry.
"The much heralded proposed renewable lithium battery storage in South Australia of 129 megawatt-hours would power one aluminium smelter here in New South Wales for a grand total of 7.7 minutes," Mr Freyberg says in notes released in advance of his address.

He says that energy policy trends have increasingly made electricity unaffordable for heavy industry in NSW and Queensland, evident in the 5 per cent drop in employment in manufacturing in the 12 months to February 2016.

"We urge policy makers to be honest about the costs and carefully consider the consequences of all available policy options because the flow on impact to future investment is very real," says Mr Freyberg, continuing
He singled out Queensland's target of reaching net zero emissions by 2050, saying the government should spell out just what plants will have to shut down, how many jobs will be lost, and what electricity prices will be for households as a result.
Mr Freyberg said that Glencore was among a number of heavy industry players that have been clear they need to "consider their future in Australia" because of soaring energy prices and uncertainty around future supply,
At Glencore's copper refinery in Townsville and its mining and smelting operations at Mt Isa, gas and power are critical inputs, he said, pointing to the risk the plants will close and move offshore, with no hope of returning.

"As a major Australian producer and consumer of energy whose annual electricity bill is around $400 million, Glencore is very concerned," Mr Freyberg says.
"We are ready to assist in finding an effective and lasting solution to the current energy crisis."
Mr Freyberg said the recent Finkel Review on energy security does little to provide any confidence for future investments, pointing to "unanswered questions" in the modelling on assumptions used for the country's industrial base and on policy recommendations on energy affordability.
He calls for the priority to be placed on addressing the energy crisis and on putting the country on a "least-cost pathway" to reducing emissions without sacrificing growth.

Mr Freyberg called for support to replace baseload power generation and for the removal of the renewable energy target and state-based targets. Heavy penalties need to be imposed on generators guilty of anti-competitive market behaviour.
Heavy industry needs to be exempted from clean energy policy if it is to continue to operate in Australia, he adds, saying that Australia may need to consider delaying meeting its Paris emissions reductions targets in order to prioritise energy security and economic growth.
 Mr Freyberg also reiterated support for coal as "one of the few energy sources capable of supplying secure and reliable baseload energy for Asian economies."
He said the future for coal underpins  one of two coal businesses Yancoal is buying from Rio Tinto.

Mr Freyberg also uses his address to slam the CFMEU's industrial campaign against a number of Glencore coal sites. He says the union is trying to "grab power" and is returning to 1970s tactics, where "gutless bully-boys abuse and intimidate those who want to work and those that don't want to have anything to do with their so called national campaign."
﻿

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yancoal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Isa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Freyberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Freyberg</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
