<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412056440130701</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/australian-holidays/australian-adventures/tigerair-has-dropped-a-huge-flight-sale-but-be-aware-of-the-caveats/news-story/5946ef085b148674f9adaf3e3a1d3b69</url>
  <title>Tigerair has dropped a huge flight sale but be aware of the caveats</title>
  <content>
Want Cheap Airfares? Let the Airline Plan Your Trip
4:56

What's the latest trick to find a cheap fare? Book a trip to somewhere, just about anywhere, but let the airline decide where you're flying. Scott McCartney has details on Lunch Break.

September 3rd 2015
2 years ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Travel - News.com.au/

Tigerair has dropped a huge flight sale but be aware of the caveats.

Share

PLANNING a cheeky Aussie getaway? Listen up. Tigerair has just dropped a huge flight sale where you could bag a return flight for the same amount as a 7/11 coffee.
The "Pay to Go, Come Back for $1" promotion commences at midday AEST today and runs until midday AEST Saturday 5 August, or until sold out. And it applies to all 23 domestic routes in the Tigerair Australia network.
However, you have to get in quick because there are just 13,000 tickets included in the sale and Tigerair Australia spokesman Joel Dwyer expects these to be snapped up real fast.
"We are proud to be able to fly more people for less and we're sure people will grab the opportunity to take an affordable holiday early next year with both hands," he said.
That's the other catch, the sale fares are only available for travel between late January and late March 2018. So you're only in luck if you were planning on a domestic getaway early next year.
And like all sale fares, it doesn't include optional extras such as checked-in baggage, travel insurance and reserved seat selection. You'll have to be prepared to pay extra if you require any of those services too.

You could bag a return flight for just $1 with Tigerair as a part of their new promotion. Picture: Shae BeplateSource:News Corp Australia
Some of the more popular routes advertised are Melbourne-Sydney, where you can snag a seat for $79. There are 2000 seats reserved for people travelling on this route as a part of the promotion between 30 January-21 March 2018.
On the Brisbane-Melbourne route, there are 1500 seats reserved for $109 if you are travelling between 30 January-21 March 2018.
And for Gold Coast-Sydney, Tigerair has reserved 1200 seats for $59 for bargain-hunters travelling between 30 January-22 March 2018.

A full list of routes, prices and the number of seats reserved can be found on the  website.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airline Plan Your Trip</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST Saturday 5 August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Come Back</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott McCartney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January-22 March 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane-Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Travel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shae BeplateSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigerair Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January-21 March 2018</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheap Airfare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigerair</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lunch Break</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast-Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
