<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411369245353417</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Tech Guide</source>
  <url>http://www.techguide.com.au/reviews/elgato-eve-review-smart-products-control-home-ease/</url>
  <title>Elgato Eve review - smart products to control your home with ease - Tech Guide</title>
  <content>
Related Articles

Do you want to create a smart home? Elgato has released the Eve range of products that can be placed around your house and easily connected so you can have complete control.

These Eve products all work with Apple HomeKit which means they're easy to set up and will integrate with Siri on your iPhone so you also have voice control.

The Eve devices you set up in your home can all be seen monitored through the companion Eve app.

From here you will be able to also see more detailed information about each particular product which can be grouped into different rooms of your home.

Apart from the convenience they offer, the information they provide can be used in a variety of ways.

The products can be automated with timers or triggered when you return or leave your home.

Users can also set rules to trigger various scenes. For example, you might set a rule that when you pass one of the sensors a lamp will turn on.

And if you are using Siri, you can say "I'm leaving" as the trigger to turn all your devices off.

All the Eve devices are powered by long lasting batteries so there is no complicated installation.

They also connect directly to your network which means there is no need for an additional bridge or hub.

Adding Eve products to your home network is remarkably simple.

Once the batteries are placed inside the device, simply open the Eve app or HomeKit app and click the "Add Accessory" option in the settings.

It will then instantly detect that device and ask you to aim your iPhone's camera to capture the code on the side of the device. That's it.

You can then rename the product and assign it to a particular room in your home.

HomeKit can be viewed on all Apple devices including iPhone, iPad and the latest Apple TV so you monitor and control from anywhere.

Elgato's suite of Eve products include:

EVE ENERGY - $84.95

This is a switch and power meter so not only will you be able to turn connected products on and off, you also be able to see how much energy they're using.

Users can enter the price per kilowatt they are paying so I can monitor the current cost and projected cost of running that product.

Using Eve Energy also means your device has voice control through Siri.

EVE WIRELESS ROOM SENSOR - $139.95

The Eve room sensor can tell you three things - the room temperature, humidity and air quality.

The on-board sensor can analyse a volatile organic compounds (VOC) to help improve your comfort.

This information could be used with the other Eve products.

For example, when the Eve room sensor reaches a certain temperature, it could tell the Eve Energy switch to turn on the fan it might be attached to.

You can also ask Siri to tell you the temperature, humidity and air quality.

EVE DEGREE - $129.95

The Eve Degree is a small, sleek device that displays the current temperature or humidity and can be tracked within the Eve app.

It can be used in a variety of locations in your home whether it's monitoring the right temperature for your tropical plants or the Shiraz in your wine cellar.

EVE MOTION SENSOR - $84.95

The Eve device detects movement whether you're entering or exiting a room to trigger connected accessories with your presence.

One scenario would be the lights turning on when the Eve motion sensor detects you entering your home again.

And it can also turn them off when you're leaving.

EVE DOOR AND WINDOW SENSOR - $69.95

This two-part device can be easily installed on a door or window to let you know when they're open or closed.

Apart from seeing the current state of the door window, users can also take advantage of this information to trigger other actions.

For example, when the Eve sensor detects a door opening it may activate the Eve Energy switch to turn on a lamp, a fan or any other connected device.

EVE WEATHER OUTDOOR SENSOR - $84.95

This is your own personal weather station which senses temperature, humidity and air pressure at your place.

All that data is accessible within the Eve app or Apple's HomeKit app or you can just ask Siri to tell you.

VERDICT

The Elgato Eve range of smart home accessories is perfect for anyone who wanted to make their home smarter but just didn't know where to start. The Eve products are easy to set up, easy to organise and easy for you to take control.

Rating - 85%

85
%

PROS: Easy to set up and control, HomeKit compatible, control with Siri, easy automation, excellent Eve app.

CONS: Some accessories are expensive, runs on batteries which will need replacing.

VERDICT: The Elgato Eve range of smart home accessories is perfect for anyone who wanted to make their home smarter but just didn't know where to start. The Eve products are easy to set up, easy to organise and easy for you to take control.

User Rating:   Be the first one !

Related Posts

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EVE WIRELESS ROOM SENSOR - $139.95</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EVE DEGREE - $129.95</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eve Energy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EVE MOTION SENSOR - $84.95</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shiraz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elgato</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EVE DOOR AND WINDOW SENSOR - $69.95</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siri</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HomeKit</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VOC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EVE ENERGY - $84.95</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Add Accessory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eve Degree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elgato Eve</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EVE WEATHER OUTDOOR SENSOR - $84.95</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple's HomeKit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CONS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
