<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412146634445169</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/city/sala-artists-paint-adelaide-celebrities/news-story/ef0332df1c033bd7af2ea13061f5c735</url>
  <title>Famous faces on show</title>
  <content>
In the spirit of this month's South Australian Living Artists (SALA) Festival, we've asked six local talents to paint, draw (and, in one artist's case, carve) half a portrait of a recognisable Adelaide face. We've been left gobsmacked after each canvas delivery from the artists - and it's motivated us even more to get out and see the other exhibitions happening in town this month. We suggest you do the same. Perhaps start with this one?
Teresa Palmer
Who: Actress
Artist: Mariana Mezic
Photo by: Frazer Harrison/Getty Images.
How they met: "I've never met her but Teresa contacted me for this because she had seen my art on Instagram," Mariana says.
The process: "When I work, I usually go for faces that have a lot of detail but this photo was quite bland because all the shadow had been taken out of her face. My solution to make it more my own work was to add the shading - it's a pencil drawing with some watercolour. I glued the paper over a wood block and poured resin over it. It's such a good process; I'm going to use it bloody all the time now. I used to do it years ago so I knew what the process entailed, but it's just made my work pop. The glossiness of it really brings the colour out. It took maybe a couple of hours. I've got four kids, I've gotta get s*** done! After I had my fourth, I learnt a process I could do very quickly. I don't think about anything, I just go, 'I've got to do it - do it.' And then I stand back."
Teresa says: "I chose Mariana as I had noticed that my good friends Lucy and Kane Cornes followed her on Instagram. I started looking at her art and I was completely blown away by how unique it is. It's very cutting edge, it pushes boundaries and feels both mystical and forward-thinking at the same time. I was actually just hoping she would say yes because I'm such an admirer of her work. I'm so grateful that she agreed to do it. I think the piece is exquisite and very vibrant, the direction she chose is so bold and left of centre. I really appreciate the energy behind it and I'm just floored by her eye, she is incredibly gifted."
Visit @marianamezic_artist on Instagram
Eddie Betts
Who: Adelaide Crows player
Artist: Pat Cassar
Photo by: Eddie Betts (Eddie wanted to have a bit of fun with this so took a selfie).
How they met: Eddie was happy for The City to choose an artist so we had a look on Instagram for inspiration. After some thorough searching, we came across emerging artist Pat Cassar, whose intense, moody paintings attracted us immediately. The 2016 Adelaide Central School of Art graduate and founding member of Floating Goose Studios happily obliged when we pitched the idea to him, though he did admit he wasn't a football fan. "But when I heard it was Eddie Betts, I looked him up and realised I was familiar with him as a person," Pat says. "I read about the (racism) controversy he was in and I do admire him."
On the process: "When I saw the toothy grin I was like, this is portrait painting kryptonite. Teeth descend into your mouth and are not as flat as they appear, and you need to really illustrate that, so trying to get it as accurate as possible was very important. I definitely needed to look him up online to get a sense of who he was, and once I saw all the images of him I realised the smile was actually very important because he does smile a lot. I found it endearing to look into him as a person and try to capture him. I'm not really a portrait painter so doing a face this big was new to me. I do a lot more figurative work, but this was a nice challenge to take up. I learnt a lot doing so. My biggest hope when doing a portrait like this is the person will see it and will go 'wow, you've captured something of me nobody has really seen before'.
Eddie says: "It looks pretty good, doesn't it? I'm a pretty happy, relaxed person and I think the artist has done well to capture that. I look forward to seeing what the other paintings look like at the exhibition."
Visit @p.cassar_artist on Instagram
Kelly Vincent
Who: Dignity Party representative in South Australian Parliament (the youngest woman ever elected to an Australian parliament and the first Australian to be elected on the platform of disability rights)
Artist: Megan Roodenrys
Photo by: Chris Parkhurst
How they met: "I met Kelly two or three years ago - her media adviser Anna Tree used to go rowing with my sister," Megan says. "When Anna got the role and I used to have cafes (such as Ginger's and The Flinders St Project, in which Megan constructed that epic wooden spoon installation) she was looking for function support and asked me and my partner if we were interested in that. We got to meet her, I really appreciated the work she was doing and I liked her as a person. I did a large portrait of her for the Archibald."
The process: "Half of the photographic image is underneath. I liked the idea of putting the square of the photograph with the circular portrait - and because it's a circle, I made it spin. I thought that was like a symbol of political life - I'm sure she often feels like her head is spinning. It's an oil painting and took about six hours. I had some fun with it."
Kelly says: "Megan was introduced to me by a mutual friend and painted an amazing, but very humbling, portrait of me that was entered into the Archibald Prize. I'm happy to say we've become friends; I greatly admire her talent. It's always hard to comment on a photo or painting of yourself, but I think Megan's captured the moment. It's from a photo taken in the Legislative Council."
More information on
Megan Roodenrys at richmondroadstudios.com.au
Duncan Welgemoed
Who: Africola owner and head chef
Artist: Marieka Hambledon
Photo by: Marieka Hambledon
How they met: "Duncan and I have been friends for a number of years, meeting through acquaintances at events and dinners - and obviously dining at his restaurants," Marieka says. "I approached Duncan early last year and asked if he would be my subject for the 2016 Archibald Prize which is where the mutual respect of each other's work really intensified."
The process:
"On the night of our photoshoot for this SALA piece, Duncan was exhausted. We had to find a white wall to shoot against for this concept - which found us piled into the disabled toilets at Africola. I asked Duncan to do a series of poses for me, and one was based around the 'rock-star' style life he was leading. He would hate me using that word but it's kind of true. He rolled his eyes at me as usual when I ask him to do silly stuff, but he complied. I think the result is perfect. It really shows the juxtaposition between the exterior self - the intense 'rock star chef' life - and the internal tired, yet determined, man we can see within the eyes. I think that's why I love painting Duncan, there is so much going on in his eyes.
The (acrylic) painting took me 30 hours. I can't paint small. This size (601mm x 915mm) is probably the smallest I go. I work with a tiny brush that is like a pin prick and to go any smaller just doesn't allow me to develop the detail. My style is all about how abstracted realism can be. How the physical world is just a bunch of particles put together to create something whole - how things may seem perfect from afar but up-close the illusion becomes clearer. I achieve this by using tiny painted dots - similar to pointillism and impressionism but manipulated to achieve realism. I chose to paint Duncan in black and white because this suited the intensity of him that I was trying to capture. For me, I'm very much about the human experience. "
Duncan says: "Marieka is one of my favourite artists; her work is dramatic and intricate. She is extremely talented and super humble. The piece she has created captures me in my dishevelment, leaning against bathroom tiles, waiting for service and/or death. It's a pretty accurate depiction."
mariekahambledon.com
Tilda Cobham-Hervey
Who: Actress
Artist: Fletch
Photo by: Larry Busacca/Getty Images
How they met: Tilda was happy for us to choose an artist, so we went with a recommendation from artist Donovan Christie and approached oil painter Michael "Fletch" Coard. Fletch, the son of former Home & Away actor Dennis Coard, was more than happy to paint a portrait of someone in the acting industry, having been around it since he was a kid.
The process: Fletch decided to shift his focus to the left of the canvas so the artwork could "stand alone". He also ditched his usual style of painting (which involves etching with a palette knife) for a more traditional style. "It's just because she's got such beautiful, smooth features," Fletch says, "There are no real wrinkles or things to make texture with, so it ended up quite porcelain - she is striking looking. I very much painted outside my comfort zone with this one. I generally pick old, textured faces but I really enjoyed trying something I wouldn't normally."
Tilda says: "Fletch has such incredible attention to detail. It is amazing to see the photographic image in conjunction with the painted portrait. I am really impressed by the outcome and I can't wait to see what he goes on to do next."
More information on Fletch at facebook.com/fletchart3 and on Instagram at @fletch_cuts
Hilltop Hoods
Who: Hip-hop trio
Artist: Donovan Christie
Photo by: Nicole Reed
The artist: Donovan Christie. is a self-taught painter and screenprinter who is crazy for hip-hop, and the genre influences a lot of his work - whether he's listening to it or painting his favourite rappers.
He told The City: "I grew up in a home of hip-hop, heavily influenced by my older brother and the older kids from around the way.
It was only natural that my love for rap music lead me down the path of graffiti which transitioned me to start painting on canvas.
In my opinion, Hilltop Hoods set the bar for Aussie hip-hop. The Calling, in particular, was quintessential Hoods and was the soundtrack to my generation's adolescent years.
You couldn't go to a house party in the '90s to late 2000s and not hear Hilltops blasting out of the 4000 watt, in-house sound system."
The process: "I took a rather simple approach to painting this piece. I was given the reference image and after a few tweaks on Photoshop to adjust their head heights, I cropped the image and sketched it to canvas, then got busy with the paints."
Donovan has a SALA exhibition of old shopfronts called Business as Usual at Studio Bowden until August 13. Visit donovanchristie.com
Visit our office foyer at 31 Waymouth St to check out the portraits up close. It's one of the 660 exhibitions popping up in Adelaide as part of the SALA Festival, which runs throughout August.
Visit salafestival.com
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilltop Hoods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sala</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donovan Christie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tilda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frazer Harrison/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Africola</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Roodenrys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Parkhurst</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SALA Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Studio Bowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Coard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hip Hop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floating Goose Studios</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larry Busacca/Getty Images</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waymouth St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Central School of Art</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariana Mezic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legislative Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marieka</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Tree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders St Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teresa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tilda Cobham-Hervey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archibald Prize</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teresa Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Cassar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mariana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncan Welgemoed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Reed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncan</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Living Artists</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly Vincent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archibald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kane Cornes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dignity Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photoshop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marieka Hambledon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
