<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412060735098064</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/whats-on-tv-sunday-august-13-20170731-gxm2m3.html</url>
  <title>What's on TV: Sunday, August 13</title>
  <content>
Little Boy Blue
Seven, TIME TBCOccupation NativeYou Are HerePhoto: Supplied
Little Boy Blue is a brilliant British drama based on the true story of the murder of 11-year-old Rhys Jones. In 2007 Jones was on his way home from footy practice when he got caught in the crossfire between teen gangsters. He was shot in the neck and died. The case rocked Liverpool, and this sensitive and beautifully-made miniseries explores the impact on the family, and on the city, as well as the painstaking investigation lead by detective inspector David Kelly. Heartbreaking but never exploitative, Little Boy Blue hits all the right notes, creating a powerful rhythm that rises and falls - sometimes hectic, sometimes achingly subdued - and although it's impeccably researched is far more interested in the emotional aspects of both the crime and the investigation than in the procedural detail. The performances are also terrific. Sinead Keenan and Brian O'Byrne are excellent as Rhys' parents Mel and Steve, both grappling to cope in their very different ways, but it's Stephen Graham (This Is England, Boardwalk Empire) as DSI Kelly who's the standout, perfectly balancing professionalism, ambition and compassion. Keep the tissues handy. MH
pay Three Days of the Condor (1975)
Fox Classics (pay TV), 8.30pm
In Sydney Pollack's elegant paranoia thriller, Three Days of the Condor, Joseph Turner (a never-better Robert Redford) looks for hidden political messages in foreign-language books. One day, he returns from lunch to find everyone in his office dead. Fleeing from a devilishly clever hitman (Max Von Sydow), Turner kidnaps a bystander, Kathy (Faye Dunaway), and heads for the hills. Apart from the relentless tension, there is a refined intelligence to the film craft, a striking visual beauty and the reassurance of fine actors treating every line with respect. The only moment that troubled some viewers four decades ago was the stylised conversation between Turner and Kathy in her apartment, after he notices her photographs are devoid of people. Viewed again, this is simply another example of the sensitivity and insight the late and much-missed Pollack brought to his love stories. He was one of Hollywood's finest. SM

You Are Here: Occupation Native
NITV, 8.30pm
One of the great things about this series of docos by and about Indigenous Australians is their cheek. They're kind of angry (with good reason, as these stories demonstrate) and they're often very sad (ditto) but they're also wry and funny - perhaps as powerful a way as any of highlighting the absurd disconnect between commonly accepted Australian history, and the actual one. This sprightly piece from Trisha Morton-Thomas (with a bit of help from Black Comedy's Steven Oliver) tackles that history head on, taking us from Cook and the First Fleet to the present day, and retelling the story from the locals' point of view. The journey is fascinating, sometimes heartbreaking, but also, weirdly, a lot of fun. MH
pay Climbing the Property Ladder
 LifeStyle Home, 9.30pm
It's surprisingly fascinating viewing as ordinary people take big risks in pursuit of big rewards in Britain's Brexit-rattled property market. First-time house-flipper Cate is in her 50s and needs some serious cash if she's to retire in her 60s. Her idea is to do up an old, dilapidated council house in South Manchester. The catch? The place is so rundown as to be unlivable, so no bank will lend money on it. Cate will plonk down a £15,000 ($25,000) deposit and then spend £30,000 doing the place up in the hope that a building inspector will deem it habitable. If he doesn't, she could lose everything. Complications arise when Cate suddenly finds herself in hospital having a hip replacement. In London, meanwhile, young Andrzej shells out nearly £250,000 for a tiny, rundown bedsit. The series wisely eschews sensationalism, letting the tension build naturally. BN
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trisha Morton-Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian O'Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MH</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sinead Keenan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Boy Blue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Days of the Condor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Occupation Native</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Von Sydow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrzej</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy Blue</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Pollack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Redford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Comedy's Steven Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TIME TBCOccupation NativeYou Are HerePhoto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DSI Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Three Days of the Condor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boardwalk Empire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Fleet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhys Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Manchester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cates</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Faye Dunaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home, 9.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pollack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV), 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Classics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Ladder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain's Brexit-rattled</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NITV, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
