<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412146634445209</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/tasmania-fish-farm-expansion-earmarked-for-north-west/8767052</url>
  <title>Fish farm expansion earmarked for Circular Head region in Tasmania's north-west</title>
  <content>
The Tasmanian Government has said it is expecting strong community support for the introduction of fish farming to the state's far north-west.
Offshore areas around Circular Head and King Island have been identified as possible "grow zones" in the Government's yet-to-be released Sustainable Salmon Industry Growth Plan.
Primary Industries Minister Jeremy Rockliff said it was an enormous opportunity for the area.
"This is a region that values resource-based industries, values agriculture, values the fishing industry, values aquaculture and I know values jobs in rural and regional Tasmania," he said.

Mr Rockliff said a strong regulatory framework was in place to make sure the state's natural resources were looked after.
"There is resource for everyone, tourism and aquaculture can, have done and will continue to co-exist," he said.
Petuna Aquaculture has been granted an environmental monitoring permit to explore future salmon farming near Three Hummock Island.
Petuna's acting chief executive, David Wood, said the expansion would result in about 50 jobs in the region.
"Apart from the jobs that would be be created we are taking about an investment of tens of millions of dollars to establish a farm," he said.
Mr Wood said the company would work with the local community to ensure any new development had a social licence to operate.
"Realistically, there is a lot of work to be done in terms of looking at the environment, looking at the growing conditions, looking at the community needs and concerns," he said.
"We think it's three years before you see fish in the water."
Circular Head mayor Daryl Quilliam said with the impending  jobs were needed in the region.
"Fishing has always been an important industry for Circular Head ... further development would be really good for us," he said.
"Some will need to be re-trained to do these jobs."
Expanding the salmon industry to the state's north west comes as .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sustainable Salmon Industry Growth Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Three Hummock Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daryl Quilliam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petuna Aquaculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAVID WOOD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Circular Head</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Industries Minister Jeremy Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petuna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
