<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412099389804228</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/20-years-on-the-dreaming-that-kept-stuart-diver-alive-20170802-gxnti4.html</url>
  <title>Flashback: The dreaming that kept Stuart Diver alive</title>
  <content>
First published in The Sydney Morning Herald on 4 August 1997
Lying on his back in a terrifying concrete coffin for 65 hours, a freezing Stuart Diver escaped into a hallucinatory state. In the pitch black, deep in water, covered in mud and with no room to move, his mind roamed, travelling the world.Photo: Dallas Kilponen
With him for part of his surreal trip was his new friend, Paul Featherstone, one of the State's most highly trained paramedics.
Beside him was his wife, Sally, pinned by a concrete slab when the landslide hit their ski lodge last Wednesday night.Photo: Mike Bowers
Sally, a reservations manager at the Thredbo Alpine Resort, is believed to have died instantly in the collapse but Stuart, in a desperate attempt to help her, had tried to lift her head clear of water pouring down a steep slope from an underground spring.
Nearly drowning himself - he propped himself on his elbows to lift his mouth and nose above the muddy water - he spent the next 65 hours, wearing only boxer shorts, holding his wife's hand until he was rescued about 5.20 pm on Saturday.

"When he first saw the sky he just looked up to me and said 'that sky's fantastic'," said Mr Featherstone, who was the lifeline to the 27-year-old ski instructor.
Last night, Stuart, recovering in Canberra Hospital, attributed his remarkable survival to the prayers and support of well-wishers and rescue crews.Photo: SMH
Propped up on pillows, with oxygen tubes coming from his nose and a cage surrounding his frostbitten feet, he said the help had been "overwhelming".
"I'd just like to thank everyone who was involved in my rescue, the fire brigade and all the rescue services along with the medical teams at Thredbo and here in Canberra and all the people who prayed for me and gave me so much support over the last couple of days.
"It's been overwhelming and I don't think I'd have made it through without the involvement of all those people. It's been fantastic, and thanks very much."
His father, Stephen, tried to recall his first brief words to his son while he was still trapped in the ruins of Bimbadeen lodge: "I can't remember my exact words - something like, 'It's dad here' or words to that effect.
"When he first saw the sky he just looked up to me and said 'that sky's fantastic'."
Paul Featherstone, paramedic

"It (his voice) was very croaky. But once again I honestly couldn't tell you what, but he just said, 'I'll see you' or something."
Mr Diver said there were still some fears about frostbite - his son's right foot was looking good after treatment but there was some concern about toes on his left foot.
"He's tough, yeah, very resilient. He's got a very strong, strong willpower and strong mind. And he loves a joke."
In a thick Scottish accent, Mr Diver told how he and his wife, Annette , arrived in 1965 as "ten quid migrants" and had eventually settled in Melbourne.
Mrs Diver said: "I always thought he was fantastic ... he's now even more fantastic."
An emotional Mr Featherstone, who spent 11 hours comforting and providing medical treatment to Stuart from a tunnel above him, also praised him for his incredible willpower and "strength of spirit".
"He's a remarkable person ... the fact that this young fellow was super fit was probably the main reason he survived."
When rescuers found Stuart, and spoke to him for the first time, he had no idea how long he had been trapped.
He was disorientated and had lost all sense of time - for three days he did not know whether it was day or night.
He told Mr Featherstone, a member of the NSW Ambulance Special Casualty Access Team (SCAT), that he repeatedly lapsed into dream-like states and thought he was dreaming when he heard the rescuers call for him.
"One of the first things he said was how glad he was to see someone," he said. "He had been hearing people working in the area for a while.
"He said that to pass some of the time what he did (was) he travelled the world. He put himself into places which obviously he had a lot of fun and excitement in and had a good appreciation for."
Mr Featherstone said he had to gain Stuart's trust and knew he had to find topics to discuss which would be interesting and would keep his mind focused.
"Being in Thredbo and being a ski instructor he obviously loved the area and the environment he worked in.
"So I kept painting pictures of what it was really like out here and we just had a classic day ... talking about the snow on a nice, sunny, crisp clear day. I kept promising him that 'this afternoon you'll be out and we'll have a look at it together'."
Other more exotic locations were also discussed, as was the tragic event that brought them together - the landslide three days earlier - but not in detail.
Nineteen people, including Stuart and his wife, were in Bimbadeen staff lodge when a loud explosion shattered the peaceful resort about 11.30 pm.
"He thought actually the house had been bombed," Mr Featherstone said. "He had already surmised that his building had been written off."
Within seconds, Stuart found himself alive but trapped under a mountain of rubble, entombed in what his rescuers would later call his "concrete coffin". Sally lay beside him in the darkness.
He was able to move his arms, and lift his legs slightly, but he could not raise his head. The concrete slab was inches above his face and it was "kissing his chest".
Several times he had to prop himself up on his elbows to avoid drowning from rising water which was "rushing" into the cavity. On one occasion the water reached his lips before it subsided.
"What he would do is lift his head, quite remarkably, and put it up against the slab above his head and suck in the air," said Mr Featherstone.
"It was totally dark and muddy. When the water subsided he was laying in cold mud and he did this for 63 hours and was able to keep a good frame of mind."
First published in The Sydney Morning Herald on 4 August 1997
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Divers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1997</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thredbo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Ambulance Special Casualty Access Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Featherstone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bimbadeen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Featherstone</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Diver</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Morning Herald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thredbo Alpine Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Kilponen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Diver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Bowers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
