<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412146634445196</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/street-watch-bail-breacher-busted-doing-115kmh-on-peninsula-link-police-hunt-stolen-black-bmw/news-story/ef722a9b2dde204657eb31d901944826</url>
  <title>High cost of love for speeding bail breacher</title>
  <content>
Love could end up costing a man his freedom after he was caught speeding and in breach of strict bail conditions while on his way home from his girlfriend's house. The 29-year-old Docklands man was booked doing 115km/h on Peninsula Link at Carrum Downs at 4.45am on Tuesday, August 1. He also allegedly tested positive to drugs and was found to be on three counts of bail, one of which was only granted the day before at Frankston Magistrates' Court. The bail conditions prohibited him from driving, using drugs and leaving his home residence between 9pm-6am. The man was remanded.
MORNINGTON
A black BMW stolen more than a month ago is still being driven around the region and police want help tracking it down. The car was stolen from a residential property in Mornington on Monday, July 10. If you've seen the car (pictured) please phone Mornington Peninsula CIU 59781400 or Crime Stoppers 1800 333 000.
Three motorists tested positive to drugs or alcohol in less than three hours on Thursday, July 27. The first driver was pulled over on Moorooduc Highway by Somerville Highway Patrol at 8.12pm after trying to avoid a booze bus by doing a U-turn. The 39 year old Frankston man allegedly blew 0.078 and is likely to lose his licence for six months. At 9.50pm on the same night a Hastings man, 46, was pulled over on Main St Mornington and allegedly tested positive for drugs on a preliminary oral fluid test. Police said the man then refused to the secondary test. He also refused a similar test on July 5. He will face Frankston Magistrates' Court at a later date. About an hour later at 11.pm a Mornington man, 36, was arrested driving a stolen car in the Tanti Estate. He was taken to Mornington Police Station where he also tested positive to methamphetamines. He will face Frankston Magistrates' Court at a later date.
MORNINGTON PENINSULA
A man who failed to turn up to court to face assault charges could be on the Mornington Peninsula. Police are asking people to keep an eye out for Matthew Beveridge, 28. He is 170cm tall, with a thin build, blue eyes and light brown hair. If you see him phone Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
Two warrants have been issued for the arrest of a man wanted for stealing a car, resisting an emergency worker and assault. Luke Goode, 38, is known to spend time on the Mornington Peninsula and police want the public to let them know if they see him. He is described as being 180cm tall, of medium build with blue eyes and light brown hair. If you know where he is please phone Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrum Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Goode, 38</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>U-turn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers 1800 333 000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula Link</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula CIU 59781400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somerville Highway Patrol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moorooduc Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Beveridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanti Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hastings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main St Mornington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
