<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411253281234648</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/brisbane-city-council-workers-rally-against-enterprise-bargaining-agreement/news-story/c5778af952f8f5c9ea065b5d5676f7dc</url>
  <title>Workers rally against Brisbane City Council</title>
  <content>
WORKERS will rally against the Brisbane City Council's proposed enterprise bargaining agreement at King George Square on Wednesday.
Services Union Secretary Neil Henderson said the midday rally was arranged coincide with members' lunch breaks so they would not lose pay but could still send a message to the council.
The city's bus drivers are striking today.
Mr Henderson said there had been "tiny flickers of movement" in the negotiations but their core concerns remained the same.
Brisbane City Council's offer includes a 2.5 per cent increase each year until the agreement expires in 2020 and a $400 signing bonus.
Mr Henderson said members wanted a higher pay rise to reflect current and expected future productivity increases and keep up with cost of living for the life of the agreement.
"I think ratepayers should pay for the services they get and they get good services ... I think the ratepayers of Brisbane get very good service in all of their endeavours," he said.
Lord Mayor Graham Quirk said the offer met community standards and negotiations with the union had "come a long way".
"I'm disappointed that the union leadership are taking this down another track, I don't think it's in step of the majority of employees in the council, who simply want to continue to serve the people of this city," he said.
"We will see what response they (the union) get today," he said.
Mr Henderson said the dispute was about more than pay but members held an array of different roles and demands varied.
Members are in the middle of industrial action, where they voted to and put a ban on answering emails indefinitely.
Brisbane City Council has been contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Henderson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Union Secretary Neil Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
