<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411541044047972</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/business/banking-and-finance/rate-hikes-could-worsen-mortgage-stress-in-mining-areas-genworth-20170801-gxniu5.html</url>
  <title>Rate hikes could worsen mortgage stress in mining areas: Genworth</title>
  <content>
﻿
Rising home loan interest rates may push mortgage stress further into "elevated" territory in mining regions and other parts of the country with weak labour markets, mortgage insurance giant Genworth says.Photo: Louise Kennerley
The insurer on Wednesday said a higher proportion of home owners in Queensland and Western Australia had fallen behind on repayments, and this contributed to a 34.7 per cent slide in its profit.
While NSW and Victoria performed much better, mortgage delinquencies also edged up in the two largest states, with the insurer saying job losses in Victoria's manufacturing industry had hit some customers.

In a sign it does not expect an improvement in these trends anytime soon, the company noted that economic conditions had "moderated" and it expected mortgage stress to remain high in mining regions.
Chief executive Georgette Nicholas noted that overall mortgage interest rates remained low, allowing many households to pay down their loans ahead of schedule, giving them a "buffer" against financial shocks. Yet she added that recent increases in mortgage rates - targeted at customers with interest-only loans - could put more stretched borrowers at risk.

"The recent re-pricing, and continued re-pricing of mortgage books by lenders does pressure the serviceability of loans in a low-rate environment, and could cause additional stress in areas where they are already impacted by lower employment," Ms Nicholas said on a call with investors.
Over the year ahead, Ms Nicholas said Genworth expected house prices to "moderate", as a result of the regulator's crackdown on interest-only lending, and the recent rate hikes.

Genworth, which has a 30 per cent share of the mortgage insurance market, is experiencing trends that may also affect the major banks to some degree, although the lenders are less exposed.
Mortgage insurers sell cover to banks to help shield lenders from default by riskier borrowers or those with smaller deposits.
Omkar Joshi, portfolio manager at Regal Funds Management, said Genworth's results suggested there were no signs of improvement in mortgage stress in mining-heavy areas.
Yet major banks would be less affected by these trends than Genworth, which insures higher-risk loans with a loan-to-value ratio above 80 per cent.
"The trends are getting worse, but they are much more negatively affected by Queensland and Western Australia than the major banks," Mr Joshi said.
Earlier on Wednesday, Genworth reported profits slumped 34.7 per cent to $88.7 million in the first half, as the insurer was affected by rising delinquency costs and falling premium revenue, because banks have cut low-deposit lending.
It reaffirmed guidance for its gross written premium revenue to fall by 10 to 15 per cent this year, while it also expects a wider loss ratio - claims as a proportion of its revenue from premiums.
It also said it would launch a $100 million share buy back, equal to purchasing about 6.5 per cent of its issued stock, which helped drive its shares 4 per cent per higher to $3.14 shortly after midday.
UBS analysts said that although key drivers of profit were under pressure, news of the buyback could improve sentiment towards the stock.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Omkar Joshi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgette Nicholas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Nicholas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Joshi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Kennerley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genworth</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regal Funds Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
