<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412107979738937</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/real-estate/queensland/home-ownership-among-young-queenslanders-a-distant-dream/news-story/1e139ea1fd715bcd3750f33139854e8a</url>
  <title>Home ownership among young Queenslanders a distant dream - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Home ownership among young Queenslanders has dropped dramatically, according to HILDA survey. Picture: iStock.

HOME ownership among young Queenslanders has dropped dramatically, meaning an increased likelihood of Millennials paying rent well into their retirement.
New statistics from the Household, Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia (HILDA) survey show the number of 18 to 39-year-olds owning a home outside of Brisbane has fallen 17 per cent - from 38.2 per cent in 2002 to just 21.1 per cent in 2014.
Sydney was the only place in the country with a larger decline in the home ownership rate.
In greater Brisbane, only 29.8 per cent of young people own a home.

Nationally, average mortgage debt among young people almost doubled over the 12 year period - jumping from $169,201 to $336,586.
In the six months to April 2017, a Roy Morgan survey found regional Queenslanders had a median outstanding mortgage of $224,000 - the highest of all country areas in the nation - while homeowners in Brisbane had an average mortgage debt of $229,000.

The home ownership dream is becoming a distant memory for young Australians.

The HILDA survey also found a third of young homeowners weren't paying down their debt, which was increasing every year.
Report author Professor Roger Wilkins said he was shocked at the figures.
"I had to keep double checking it because I though it must be wrong," he said.

"You tend to think of people buying their house and then paying off their loans over time, but for many that just isn't happening.
"You have to wonder whether these young homeowners who aren't paying down their mortgages, will have paid off their loans by the time they retire."
The findings also revealed young people are living with their parents for longer.
The HILDA survey tracks more than 17,000 people in 9500 households.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iStock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roy Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
