<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412150929412592</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/accused-dangerous-driver-has-no-memory-from-before/3207978/</url>
  <title>The missing seconds before horror Bruce Hwy fatal</title>
  <content>
PAUL Gerard Crimmins can't remember the final seconds before he swerved across the Bruce Hwy and ploughed into an oncoming car in a horror five-car smash that killed a Noosaville man and severely injured three others.

Mr Crimmins had never, in his entire 40-year driving history, earned as much as a speeding ticket, the Maroochydore District Court heard yesterday.

But the retired former banker is accused of dangerous driving causing death and grievous bodily harm after a horror Bruce Hwy crash at Bells Creek on November 27, 2015.

Dashcam footage from Mr Crimmins' vehicle was played in court on Tuesday, detailing the moment the 59-year-old Lennox Heads man suddenly veered to the right, across the northbound lanes, through the median strip and into oncoming highway traffic.

The Nissan Patrol collided head-on with a silver Landcruiser, killing driver Graeme Warren and severely injuring his wife Dianne Warren.

Mr Crimmins and his wife Gail Crimmins also sustained severe injuries, and were in hospital for about 28 days and 25 days respectively.

Yesterday Mr Crimmins took the stand to give evidence, and during cross-examination crown prosecutor Mark Whitbread questioned whether Mr Crimmins was drowsy after the long drive from their Lennox Heads home.

Mr Crimmins had stopped for several hours at Petrie for lunch, had one light beer and one mid-strength beer, but blood samples taken in hospital after the crash were found to have zero blood alcohol content.

Mr Whitbread probed Mr Crimmins on his memories before the crash.

"I've asked myself that a thousand times, I just can't remember," Mr Crimmins told the court from the witness box.

Mrs Crimmins also had difficulty remembering the moments leading up to the crash, and Mrs Warren sustained trauma-induced amnesia, the court heard.

Mr Crimmins has made admissions to causing the crash, but Mr Whitbread told the jury the difficulty was deciding beyond reasonable doubt if Mr Crimmins was driving dangerously.

More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
Child taken to hospital after being hit by car while leaving school
Turn your dream of owning a hip cafe or bar into a reality.
STUDENTS are always ready to get back together.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lennox Head</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Whitbread</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Whitbread</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Landcruiser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Crimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gail Crimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nissan Patrol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAUL Gerard Crimmins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bells Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dianne Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Hwy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Crimmins</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
