<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411412195027160</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/technology/uber-drivers-secretly-colluding-to-cause-price-surges-wringing-more-from-customers/news-story/5831ee5ee7f1d8c2ce2fa284f2ba78b2</url>
  <title>Uber drivers 'gaming the system'</title>
  <content>
UBER drivers are gaming the system to spark price surges that allow them to charge customers more, damning new research claims.
According to  academics who interviewed employees from the ride-sharing company in London and New York and analysed 1012 posts discovered drivers were gathering in secret to play the company's algorithms.
Drivers in the same area co-ordinated to log out of the transport app so that their cars dropped off the list of available rides, The Times reported.
This causes an increase in surge pricing with fares potentially rising to several times the normal rate.
A team from Warwick Business School and New York University cited one conversation on an online forum where a London driver reportedly said: "Guys, stay logged off until surge." A second driver replied: "Why?" "Less supply high demand = surge," the original poster said.
Another driver said: "Uber will find out if people are manipulating the system."
The original driver added: "They already know cos it happens every week."
Researchers told The Times drivers' behaviour was understandable as a response to Uber's "management by algorithm", where drivers rarely interact with company bosses.
Uber told The Times the research was based on comments by drivers that were in many cases untrue.
Uber Australia has also been contacted for comment.UBER BOSS QUITS
In June, Uber boss Travis Kalanick resigned as chief executive amid shareholder concern over the company's "toxic culture".
Mr Kalanic stepped down in response to pressure from shareholders, but will remain on the board of the firm, according to reports.

His resignation comes after a review of practices at the firm, which exposed scandals including complaints of sexual harassment and bullying.
The 13-page report criticised how the company's "hustlin'" culture had encouraged "poor behaviour", with illicit drugs and alcohol were being used at work events, and a lack of clear policies to combat inappropriate behaviour.
"I love Uber more than anything in the world and, at this difficult moment in my personal life, I have accepted the investors request to step aside so that Uber can go back to building rather than be distracted with another fight," Mr Kalanic said in a statement.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kalanic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Business School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBER BOSS QUITS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Kalanick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uber</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
