<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411583993721528</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/environment/consent-for-polluting-coal-mine-in-sydneys-water-catchment-invalid-court-finds-20170802-gxnkrr.html</url>
  <title>Consent for polluting coal mine in Sydney's water catchment invalid, court finds</title>
  <content>
Environment groups say they have scored a "massive victory" against coal mining in Sydney's water catchment area after the should not have been granted to a mine near Lithgow.
Centennial Coal's Springvale mine was granted a 13-year extension in 2015 by the Baird government, even though the mine was discharging millions of litres of untreated waste water directly into the Coxs River.

Up Next

Man arrested over 'Sydney plane bomb plot' released without charge

02:15

More NSW News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

NSW refunds Shenhua $262m for mining licence

The government's buyback of Shenhua's coal mining exploration licence on the Liverpool Plains has diminished the project's long-term value says local landowner Tim Duddy.

The river is the second largest source of water for the Warragamba Dam, which supplies most of Sydney's drinking water.
4Nature, an environment group, challenged the extension's approval, arguing it was in clear conflict with the 2011 State Environmental Planning Policy requiring any development in the catchment to have a neutral or beneficial effect on water quality.

The Appeals Court result on Wednesday overturned , and now requires the parties to determine the mine's fate.
"The parties agreed that given the consequences for the current operations of the respondents and the users of the coal supplied by the mine, the Court should hear further submissions before making such orders," the judgment said.

"This is a massive win for the community," 4Nature spokesman Andrew Cox said.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It was a serious test - it shows you cannot just make up your own rules."Photo: Centennial Coal
Fairfax Media has sought comment from Centennial Coal and the NSW government.
Springvale mine supplies nearby Mount Piper power station, and supporters of the mine have said in the past that the power station - which supplies about 15 per cent of the state's electricity - may cease operations without the coal supply.Photo: Wolter Peeters
Sue Higginson, principal solicitor for the NSW Environmental Defenders Office, said the decision would have an impact on future coal or other developments across the catchment.
"It sets a really good precedent," Ms Higginson said.
Centennial Coal was left in a conundrum because it would now have to show it could operate with a neutral or beneficial effect on water quality, she said.
The NSW Environmental Protection Authority was among the agencies that had raised objections to the mine's extension because of the high salinity and other contaminants - especially compared with background levels - of its waste water.
In the past, the mine supplied the waste water to the nearby Wallerawang power station until it shut down.
Without a treatment plant of its own, the mine discharged the waste directly into the Coxs River. The pollution, of up 19 million litres a day, would amount to about two-thirds of the flows at the discharge point.
Centennial has had a poor environment record, including allowing about 2300 tonnes of coal material to discharge into the Wollangambe River and the World Heritage area of the Blue Mountains in 2015.
, a record penalty for a single prosecution.
"It's an operator that has not shown a strong commitment to the environment," Mr Cox said, noting the company's underground mines were also "destroying endangered upland swamps" in the region.
"For years, Centennial Coal ... had known about the need to limit pollution from the mine entering the Coxs River," Chris Jonkers, a spokesman for Lithgow Environment Group, said. 
"Instead, the miner delayed tighter discharge rules that were due to start on July 1, 2017." 
Kevin Muir, director of the Colong Foundation, warned the government against trying to change the law, saying it would be vilified if it tried that route.
"You mean you are going to allow pollution in the drinking water - how could you?"
The company now needs to negotiate and bring forward a water treatment plant that currently has consent to be built "off in the never-never", he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coxs River</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Environmental Defenders Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Jonkers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallerawang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollangambe River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Piper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Higginson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Environmental Planning Policy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Duddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Appeal Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool Plains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centennial Coal's Springvale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CENTENNIAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warragamba Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Higginson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centennial Coal</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lithgow Environment Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Muir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shenhua $262</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shenhua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lithgow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolter Peeters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colong Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springvale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Heritage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Environmental Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
