<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412228238824916</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/whats-on-tv-saturday-august-12-20170802-gxnow5.html</url>
  <title>What's on TV: Saturday, August 12</title>
  <content>
Supervet
​SBS, 5.30pmOne Day
Always a rollercoaster of emotions - including, usually, genuine horror at the graphic surgery scenes - Supervet, aka Professor Noel Fitzpatrick, manages to make even the most mundane of stories of his animal patients engaging - like tonight's cat Black Beauty who needs jaw reconstruction after being hit by a car, which, in the scheme of things in this genre, is not all that fascinating or nail-biting. Tonight he also performs some hardcore - and, one imagines, extremely costly - surgery on an Irish setter, Casey, who has a tumour in his front leg, and Staffordshire bull terrier Pearl, who is not just a loved pet but also a therapy dog - her owner Karen suffers from nocturnal epileptic fits and Pearl has the ability to sense these coming and wakes Karen's carer before the seizures take hold. But Pearl is getting on and has developed arthritis in her knees. Professor Noel performs the necessary surgery but Pearl's recovery is far from straightforward. But Supervet is not one to give up on a patient, and Pearl's story tonight takes place over several months. KN
pay Decline and Fall
BBC First, 8.30pm
Evelyn Waugh's satirical comedy springs to marvellous life once more, buoyed by a terrific little cast. Perhaps the most unexpected pleasure is Jack Whitehall's hitherto unsuspected capacity for restraint - he dials things down about 11 notches from his aggressively grating turns in things like Bad Education and Fresh Meat. It's the 1920s and hapless theology student Paul Pennyfeather (Whitehall) is expelled from Oxford on an unjust charge of indecent behaviour. In a stroke of luck of sorts, he lands a job for which he is manifestly unqualified - fifth-form teacher at a crumbling private school in Wales. There his biggest problem isn't the principal (David Suchet), the principal's daughter (Game of Thrones' Gemma Whelan), or even the menacing London criminal (Stephen Graham) - it's the fact that he falls for a student's mother (Eva Longoria) who might just have murdered her husband. Piercing and funny. BN

Crazy, Stupid, Love. (2011)
7Flix, 8.30pm
Cal Weaver (Steve Carell) can't move past the fact that his wife, Emily (Julianne Moore), wants a divorce. He slouches in a trendy bar, annoying anyone he can with his indulgent self-pity. Jacob Palmer (Ryan Gosling), a supremely confident womaniser, decides that the only way to get any peace is to offer Cal a few tips on life. What follows is a crash course on how to dress snappily and the ways to treat women as beddable objects. Intercut with Cal's sexual (mis)adventures is Jacob being pursued by a young woman (Emma Stone) on the spirited rebound from disappointment. In a series of Feydeau-like misunderstandings, this relationship (like others) seems headed for the rocks, all of which makes for good comic fodder. The cast is wonderful, even if directors Glenn Ficarra and John Requa seem unable to decide if Cal is a hero and whether Jacob's life lessons should be applauded or shamed. SM
One Day (2011)
7Flix, 11.00pm
After the commercial success of her anti-love story, An Education (2009), a film I regularly pray I hadn't seen, Danish director Lone Scherfig chose to make an anti-romcom, One Day. Its much-hyped twist is that it looks at the relationship of Emma (Anne Hathaway) and Dexter (Jim Sturgess) over two decades by focusing only on July 15 each time (though it cheats naughtily on the couple's first date, going well into the 16th). It is a frighteningly constricted conceit and shouldn't work, but it does. Novelist and scriptwriter David Nicholls re-imagines, in a modern world, Thomas Hardy's famous raging at fate, and the difficulty of lovers in finding the precise moment when happiness is possible. Nicholls knows his Hardy well, having previously adapted Tess of the D'Urbervilles for television. Hathaway is good as the ugly-duckling Emma, a wayward accent excepted, while Sturgess is riveting. SM
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julianne Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Sturgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS, 5.30pmOne Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staffordshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flix, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pennyfeather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fresh Meat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Whitehall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Carell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urbervilles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Noel Fitzpatrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supervet</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Gosling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Suchet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Hathaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gemma Whelan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feydeau-like</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Requa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eva Longoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education (2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evelyn Waugh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cal Weaver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Day (2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lone Scherfig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC First, 8.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oxford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hathaway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Beauty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dexter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tess of the D</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Ficarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Nicholls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearl</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Hardy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flix, 11.00</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bad Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Noel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Palmer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sturgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
