<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411407900059812</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/richmond/dane-swans-unique-brownlow-medal-advice-for-dustin-martin-after-patrick-dangerfield-ban/news-story/447a653929c0d80e7ebcc68d07f44838</url>
  <title>'Get a club suspension': Swan's advice for Dusty</title>
  <content>
WITH Patrick Dangerfield now officially ineligible to win this year's Brownlow Medal, Richmond's Dustin Martin has surged to outright favouritism.
And great mate - and 2011 Brownlow winner - Dane Swan has provided the superstar with some, well, unique advice to ensure he walks away with the AFL's biggest individual honour in September.
Dangerfield's one-game ban for his tackle on Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer means the medal will be Martin's "to lose", according to Swan.
Speaking from under an umbrella next to a Moroccan pool - just seconds after ordering a pina colada in French - while on a European holiday, Swan said Martin should "put the cue in the rack" to ensure his name goes down in footy folklore.
"If he's watching this, I'd say mate you've got enough votes now that you're probably a mile in front of everyone else. So my advice would be to put the cue in the rack," Swan said via a sportsbet Facebook video.
"People remember Brownlow Medallists, they don't remember premiership players. I couldn't tell you one Melbourne premiership player, I couldn't tell you one Carlton premiership player, I couldn't tell you one St Kilda premiership player - couldn't tell you one Collingwood premiership player.
"But I can tell you that Jim Stynes, Chris Judd, Robert Harvey - they've all won Brownlows. Couldn't tell you a premiership player for any of those sides, even from mine.
"But I know who the last Collingwood player to win a Brownlow was."
With tongue firmly planted in cheek, Swan even recommended Martin try to get out of playing the final four games of the home and away season.
"Mate, I'd fake an injury," Swan said.
"If I were you, sore hammy, rest up until finals and if you don't want to fake an injury, go out on a six-day break - or something like that - get yourself a club suspension and you can't put yourself in harm's way. Nothing wrong with that."
"Good luck and I'll make sure I'm home for Brownlow Medal night."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Swan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moroccan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Stynes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond's Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Judd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medallists</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
