<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411541044047940</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/health/andrew-denton-heart-disease-diagnosis-star-requires-bypass-surgery/news-story/9f3dc7d5c68d076a5db33e8db857d9a0</url>
  <title>Andrew Denton diagnosed with heart disease</title>
  <content>
ANDREW Denton has been forced to pull out of a campaign to legalise euthanasia after being diagnosed with advanced heart disease.
The news is a huge blow for the 57-year-old, who must now undergo multiple bypass surgery.
Denton's diagnosis comes as Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews is set to introduce a bill for assisted suicide in parliament.
The TV personality's absence from the campaign has been described as a disaster by advocates,  reported.
Denton has been a vocal advocate of voluntary euthanasia in recent years and told the National Press Club last year how the will was there for Australians to support assisted dying laws.
He accused prominent Liberal Kevin Andrews and Labor figure Tony Burke of being part of a from being reintroduced in the country.
The broadcaster said the forces behind the repeal of NT-assisted death laws by the John Howard government in 1996 - and the subsequent removal of the right of territories to create such laws - "were still in play".
Denton, gave up his media role five years ago to advocate the cause and is the director of Go Gentle Australia, the organisation set up to achieve reform across the country.
The Victorian bill on assisted debate has sparked strong debate in the state with church leaders arguing it will undermine confidence in doctors and amount to the government endorsing suicide.
Catholic Archbishop Denis Hart and Anglican Archbishop Philip Freier are among a group of Victorian religious leaders who signed a joint letter published on Monday, rejecting the push for assisted dying legislation.
A cross-party committee of MPs last year recommended Victoria come up with a bill to legalise assisted dying and the government plans to introduce it for debate before the end of the year.
Premier Daniel Andrews said he expected "robust debate", but wants it to be respectful.
"My own conscience tells me that this is a change that needs to be made," he said earlier this week.
Mr Andrews changed his mind on assisted dying after watching his father die from cancer.
- with AAP
Readers seeking support and information about suicide prevention can contact  on 13 11 14 or.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Press Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglican Archbishop Philip Freier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Denton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT-assisted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic Archbishop Denis Hart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go Gentle Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Kevin Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
