<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412279778433321</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/why-our-lifeguards-are-the-best-in-the-business/3207837/</url>
  <title>Why our lifeguards are the best in the business</title>
  <content>
BEACHGOERS are in safe hands with Sunshine Coast lifeguards walking the walk when it comes to their abilities in the ocean.
Lifeguard supervisor Anthony King may have hit 43 years of age but that hasn't diminished his capacity to take on some of the world's most challenging waves.
While the Coast wallowed in near-flat surf conditions last weekend, he headed south, throwing himself multi overhead barrels after earlier this year slotting himself into some of the best waves Teahupoo has to offer.
Alexandra Headland lifeguard Shane Bevan, a former professional surfer, has also shown he's no slouch out of the tower, teaming with his brother-in-law Shane Blake and Myles Blackwell for a top-five finish in the 53km Molokai to Oahu SUP teams' race.
And part-time lifeguards Lachie Landsdown (6th men's prone division) and Lincoln Dews (6th men's open SUP) were also well in the hunt during the gruelling open ocean race.
King admits to going through a bit of a mid-life crisis but said while he remained fit he wanted to keep pushing himself in big waves.
"I've reached a financial situation where I can afford to go on strike missions chasing waves," he said.
"The missus is starting to get a bit sick of it. Every morning I get up, have a cup of coffee and look at the charts."
A delayed trip to Tahiti to surf its infamous Teahupoo big wave break in May was followed by a trip to Cronulla's Voodoo left hander made possible through other surfers he had met overseas.
"They said next time we get waves we'll take you surfing," Anthony said of the trip.
"I'm doing it while I still can. I'm enjoying myself and I love it. There's no waves here. I could go mentally insane."
He says the massive Voodoo left hander in the main photo didn't look as big from where he was, describing it as "pretty solid" rather than nominating a height.
"I would have liked to have been further back. The first wave I got was better, I got barrelled," Shane said.
Back home for a week's work with the waves still small his eyes are already scanning the charts frothing about a building swell in Bali that could see Outside Corner at Uluwatu turn on.
And always on the radar Fiji's famous Cloudbreak left hander off Tavarua Island that can get huge and perfect.
There are also other breaks, closer to home, with the potential to turn on in the right conditions.
To keep fit for the job and his spare time pursuits Anthony trains in the pool once a week, does breath enhancement sessions at Noosa and does surfing oriented sessions under Kerry Knightley at the Ocean Performance Centre in Maroochydore.
"They're all my age or older," Anthony said. "Everyone's looking for the strength and flexibility to keep surfing."
Tourist track takes toll with plenty of motorists caught out
Turn your dream of owning a hip cafe or bar into a reality.
Coast researchers closing in on prawns behind white spot devastation
STUDENTS are always ready to get back together.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tahiti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ocean Performance Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teahupoo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cloudbreak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerry Knightley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Blake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lincoln Dews (6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Outside Corner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Molokai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oahu SUP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla's Voodoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myles Blackwell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tavarua Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluwatu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Bevan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachie Landsdown (6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
