<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412279778433332</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/fire-chief-quits-for-vic-environment-role/news-story/1eb0b0aa9d650f2dbc99dc2569ed0770</url>
  <title>Fire chief quits for Vic environment role</title>
  <content>
Metropolitan Fire Brigade acting chief Paul Stacchino is leaving for another government job, not because of ongoing issues with Victoria's fire services, says the state's premier.
Mr Stacchino announced on Tuesday that he quit the fire job, less than a month after the brigade lost chief executive Jim Higgins.
It's the latest in a line of resignations and sackings at Victoria's fire services, the MFB and Country Fire Authority.
"As I understand it he's heading off to another job within the Victorian government," Premier Daniel Andrews told reporters on Wednesday.
"He's going to work in a senior position at the (Environmental Protection Authority)."
The premier shrugged off suggestions the move was prompted by ongoing issues over the pay agreements and structure of fire services.
"He's made his own choice," Mr Andrews said.
"This is a senior person who is going to do another senior role in another important part of the Victorian government.
"We've got some reforms to make in fire (services) so we are ready and set up for the decades to come, not looking back and pretending the things that worked in the '50s are fit for purpose in 2017."
On Tuesday, acting CEO Russel Eddington said Mr Stacchino had "helped steer the organisation through some challenging times" but did not provide a reason for the departure.
The Victorian government is trying to merge the MFB with paid firefighters from the CFA to create Fire Rescue Victoria, in a bid to circumvent federal laws preventing a controversial union pay deal being signed.
Mr Stacchino raised his concerns about CEO powers at a Fire Services Bill Select Committee in July.
"What will be the concern for me in the office of chief officer is that the new Fire Rescue Victoria will not have within its governance structure a board, a CEO or a chief officer," he told the committee.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire Rescue Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stacchino</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MFB</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environmental Protection Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Russel Eddington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Fire Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Stacchino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Daniel Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metropolitan Fire Brigade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Higgins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fire Services Bill Select Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
