<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411502389341777</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/more-sports/joe-ingles-credits-quin-snyder-for-refinding-enjoyment-in-basketball-is-hoping-to-take-another-leap/news-story/6c9f5391fac5516e5d1937aef61b797e</url>
  <title>How Ingles</title>
  <content>
JOE Ingles thought he was a finished product.

A basketball player reaches his or her prime around the age of 27, and that was how old Ingles was when he was given his first shot in the NBA.

"I was probably at a point where I thought I was who I was gonna be, I guess," Ingles told foxsports.com.au.

But, that wasn't all.

Ingles had reached a point in his career where he just wasn't enjoying basketball anymore. Sure, he'd just come off a Euroleague Championship with Maccabi Tel Aviv, but the joy for the game - at least, in a professional capacity - was slowly dwindling.

Then, he arrived in Utah, where head coach, Quin Snyder, and eventually assistant coach, Zach Guthrie, entered his life and career.

"You know, I was talking to (my wife) Renae about it the other day," Ingles said.

"A lot of (my improvement) comes down to Quin 're-finding' my enjoyment in it. I think in Europe, I lost that a little bit. I always had it with the Australian team, that was never a question but those last couple of years in Europe, it was slowly fading.

"It took Quin to give me a lifeline after the Clippers and really support me and help me, and care. The time and effort he put in originally, then when Zach came on board. I owe those guys a lot."

Snyder, who, like Ingles, has been with the Jazz since 2014, is widely regarded around the NBA as one of the most effective player development coaches, and Ingles is one of his star pupils in that regard.

Ingles entered the NBA as a 6'8, crafty wing, who could effectively run the pick-and-roll and make the odd three-pointer. Two years later, Ingles has emerged as one of the most efficient shooters in the league, as well as an impressive defender; with the extent of the leap the most surprising to him.

"I think there's always things you can get better with and stuff like that," Ingles said. "A lot of credit (for my leap) goes to them they've taken and the care, the effort they've put into helping me."

A chance for yet another leap isn't out of the question, given the Jazz's volatile off-season.

The team's star, Gordon Hayward, signed elsewhere - Ingles described the reaction to his now-former teammate's departure as: "Utah, and the people in Utah, thought the world was ending when Gordon left. They thought the sun wasn't gonna come up the next day" - and a trade was made for a pure point guard in Ricky Rubio.

Ingles has already taken a step up from average shooter to sharpshooter and hopes to make even more of an improvement, even as he edges closer to the age of 30.

"Hopefully more sharper-er sharpshooting," Ingles joked.

Ingles excited by 'huge' news

"With our team now, there'll be different roles for everybody, so I'm going to take all of the opportunities I can. I still feel like I've got things I can improve and get better, and obviously Utah does, too, giving me four years (on my contract).

"I owe them for supporting me and backing me with this deal, and I obviously don't want to let them down. So, I'm ready. I can go back now and play. I'm pretty excited to get back into it. I'm excited about our team and the year, and excited for myself, just to get out there again.

"Hopefully my role keeps getting bigger and expands, and, if it does, I feel like I'm ready to take that on."

With no real 'go-to scorer' on this Jazz team, Ingles may have to increase his offensive burden. The Australian wing pointed to Rodney Hood as someone who can make the most of the opportunities at the wing spot, and called on the entire team to step up and make the most of the opportunity.

The addition of Rubio, a former teammate of Ingles, is also an indication of the style of play the Jazz may continue to move toward.

During the 2016-17 season, the Utah Jazz was the most international team in the league, featuring seven players born outside the United States, representing five other countries. With Rubio in the picture, as well as the signings of Jonas Jerebko and Thabo Sefolosha, that number is set to increase to eight players born outside the US.

Ingles and Rudy Gobert had already brought that international flavour to the team's core and even the addition of Ekpe Udoh - who was born in Oklahoma but is coming off an impressive stint with Fenerbahce - will contribute to the 'Euro' style of play that the Jazz will be looking to improve on.

"It'll be really cool," Ingles said of the potential of the Jazz's unique roster.

"What helps with that is obviously Quin knowing Europe and having coached in Europe; knowing how to play those guys and the style of play.

"We don't play a typical style, anyway. It'll probably get more funky, now that we lost a couple of Americans and got back a couple Euros. Now, it's on us to sort that out and still be a good team."

After spending the 2016 off-season as a part of the Australian Boomers' Olympic campaign, Ingles' 2017 has been relatively quiet.

He's been able to spend most of his time in Australia, taking care of his young twins, Jacob and Milla, while also completing his restricted free agency quite quickly; doing his best to avoid the drama of the intense off-season that surrounded him.

"Now that the dust is settled on that whole situation, it's an exciting opportunity for our guys that are still there," Ingles said.

"I can't wait to get back there."

***

Olgun Uluc covers basketball for Fox Sports Australia. Twitter:

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Hood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rubio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ekpe Udoh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maccabi Tel Aviv</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Ingles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonas Jerebko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Hayward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olgun Uluc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thabo Sefolosha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Boomers' Olympic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles' 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingles</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quin Snyder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Euroleague Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zach Guthrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Utah Jazz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clippers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Rubio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rudy Gobert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fenerbahce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SNYDER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Renae</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
