<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411240396332325</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/brightons-blair-athol-hits-market-with-eightfigure-price/news-story/4019be9d8abfacc2c46a7c41d8a2ca5c</url>
  <title>Brighton's Blair Athol hits market with eight-figure price - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
The facade of 5 Leslie Grove, Brighton, changes with the seasons.

AN ICONIC Brighton property with a history spanning more than 140 years has hit the market.
And it comes with an impressive price tag too.
The sprawling house known as  , is believed to date back to 1870.
JP Dixon Brighton agent Jacqueline Maggs said the six-bedroom home on 372sq m has price hopes of more than $13 million.
According to sales records, it last sold in 2013 for $7.52 million.
"It really is a landmark property in Brighton," Ms Maggs said.
"It's certainly one of the largest land holdings, and feels like a country estate in the heart of Brighton."
Ms Maggs said the property was keenly watched by property pundits.

5 Leslie Grove, Brighton, from when it last sold, with verdant vines and trees.

A conservatory features in the main residence.

SUBURB PROFILE:
Brighton Historical Society records reveal the home was built in 1870 for William Campbell, a squatter.
Its illustrious history grew from there. In the early 1900s, it's believed to have been owned by the Menzies hoteliers, owners of The Menzies Hotel in Melbourne's CBD, which was demolished in 1969.
Luminaries including the likes of Mark Twain, Herbert Hoover and Alexander Bell are believed to have been guests at the hotel.

The pool house provides self-contained accommodation.

In more recent times, the home has been owned by several top executives, according to JP Dixon Brighton director Jonathan Dixon.
Former Tabcorp and Southcorp CEO Ross Wilson purchased the property from Just Jeans founder Craig Kimberly in 1994 for $2.95 million.
It is understood he initially declined an offer of $2.25 million.

A glass-tiled pool and floodlit tennis court are provide outdoor amenity on the 3372sq m allotment.

Ms Maggs said the current owners have renovated the property since purchasing.
If the home's price hopes are realised, it would set Brighton's price benchmark for 2017.
26 Cosham St is this year's top recorded sale in Brighton, CoreLogic sales records suggest.
The five-bedroom home on 2100sq m sold for $9.95 million in January.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Just Jeans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqueline Maggs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Kimberly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzies Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Maggs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Twain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie Grove</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southcorp CEO Ross Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JP Dixon Brighton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Dixon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton's Blair Athol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton Historical Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cosham St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICONIC Brighton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herbert Hoover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
