<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412198174053457</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-02/how-do-the-dees-replace-hogan</url>
  <title>How do the Dees replace Hogan?</title>
  <content>
Is Cam Pedersen the man to step in for Jesse Hogan?

MELBOURNE has been forced to replace Jesse Hogan more than once this season, and will have to do so again as it tries to lock down a finals spot in the last month of the premiership season.

Hogan has been sidelined indefinitely after having a plate inserted to help repair the broken collarbone he suffered against North Melbourne in Hobart last Saturday.

After a disjointed first half of the season, the young forward was just starting to find some of his best form, having kicked four goals in the past two weeks.

Now, the Demons will have to forge a path forward without their spearhead and rejig a forward line that has not scored more than 100 points in a game since round 13.

The two prime candidates in line to replace Hogan are Cam Pedersen and Sam Weideman. But who to choose? AFL.com.au runs the rule over who should be considered for a senior recall for Saturday's game against Greater Western Sydney at the UNSW Canberra Oval. 

The case for Cam

Unlucky in many eyes to lose his spot in the senior team two weeks ago, Pedersen's main asset his versatility. The experienced utility performed strongly as an under-sized ruckman during Max Gawn and Jake Spencer's time out of the team, relishing the responsibility that was presented. The big man was not as consistent in other roles when Gawn made his return in round 14, and was dropped after Melbourne's loss to Adelaide in round 17. Pedersen has been playing mainly as a forward in the VFL in recent weeks, and has kicked three goals in the past fortnight. Pedersen will provide a contest and ensure the ball comes to ground inside forward 50, while relieving Gawn in the ruck when the big man tires.

What about Weideman?

The second-year forward is tracking nicely for a recall after much-improved form in the back half of the season. Weideman was named as Casey's second-best player against Coburg on Sunday after kicking three goals from 20 disposals and pulling down nine marks in a standout display that made him the most influential big man on the ground. The 20-year-old, pick No.9 in the 2015 NAB AFL Draft, is continuing to work on various aspects of his game, holding his position in the contest and refining his leading patterns, and continues to find greater consistency. The young forward kicked five goals in the first half (six in total) in a dominant game against Box Hill in late June to underline his talent and future prospects.

The verdict

Replacing Hogan's presence will not be left to one player, but it is understood Melbourne is leaning towards selecting Weideman over Pedersen. Weideman represents a key part of Melbourne's future, and the club is keen to expose the youngster, who has kicked six goals in nine matches across his career, to as much senior football as they can early in his career.

Finding a replacement for Hogan isn't the only change Melbourne will make this week, with Nathan Jones and Bernie Vince to return for the game against the Giants.

Rookie elevation Corey Maynard is also firming to make his senior debut against GWS, after a tremendous run of form in the VFL.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coburg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Spencer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB AFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie Vince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNSW Canberra Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Weideman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Hogan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam Pedersen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gawn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Maynard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weideman</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hogan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pedersen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
