<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412236828759617</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Ipswich Queensland Times</source>
  <url>http://www.qt.com.au/news/knights-go-on-attack-for-final-2017-bpl-games/3207968/</url>
  <title>Knights go on attack for final 2017 BPL games</title>
  <content>
IF only the Ipswich Knights had held the middle part of this season together. They could be challenging to play finals football.

However, having already accrued more points than last year in the Brisbane Premier League competition, the Knights are finishing this season strongly.

Preparing for Thursday night's BPL catch-up match against Grange Thistle, the Knights have climbed to ninth place on 23 points with six wins and five draws.

Most importantly, they haven't lost a match since a 2-1 victory over Mitchelton on June 16.

With three matches remaining, Knights head coach Danny Wilson is aiming for at least four points to complete a productive recovery for the Bundamba-based club.

"The guys have turned it around,'' he said.

Among the players he's been pleased with in recent weeks is club newcomer Elliot White. He played a more attacking role and scored two goals in the Knights' 3-2 win over Logan last weekend.

"He's starting to develop his game,'' Wilson said, glad how White has seized his opportunity.

"We've brought players in over the last couple of weeks and they've definitely stepped up and held their own so it's very positive for the club.''

Wilson was also pleased to see Dan Liddy come on as a substitute in the first half last weekend after more than a month out with injury.

But the coach's brother Lucas is still in doubt for Thursday night with a left ankle injury.

The catch-up game follows the Knights Reserve graders losing 2-1 to Grange Thistle on Tuesday night.

Thursday night's BPL game was scheduled to avoid some junior carnivals being staged over the weekend.

Game day
Brisbane Premier League: Thursday (7.30pm) - Ipswich Knights v Grange Thistle at Eric Evans Oval.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BPL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Liddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange Thistle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday (7.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich Knights</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliot White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Premier League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Evans Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundamba-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knights Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchelton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
