<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412228238824890</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/prime-minister-malcolm-turnbull-tours-albany/news-story/ddf12e7b07394ce02c71aba752258bbc</url>
  <title>PM thanks troops who have 'kept us free'</title>
  <content>
PRIME Minister Malcolm Turnbull has visited the National Anzac Centre in the south coast town of Albany, hailing the service of Australian troops who have "kept us free".
"It's a reminder of the sacrifice and service of the men and women who served over a century ago in the First World War and the Anzacs of today who serve today to keep us free," Mr Turnbull said.
The visit to Albany this morning with the member for O'Connor Rick Wilson included a community morning tea and a visit to the Albany Senior High School, where Mr Turnbull urged students to set their "horizons high" as they embarked on their careers.
Ahead of a meeting with WA Premier Mark McGowan tonight, Mr Turnbull ramped up pressure on the Labor leader to pursuade other states to support changes to the GST formula.
"You know what, Mark McGowan now has a big opportunity and a responsibility to take this up with Bill Shorten and the Labor states," he said, saying the Labor states of Victoria, South Australia and Queensland were the biggest opponents to change.
The Prime Minister then dodged questions about the potential for the government to hold a postal plebiscite on same sex marriage, insisting he was upholding an election commitment by opposing a free vote on the issue.
"If there is a vote, obviously our proposition was there would be a free vote on same sex marriage in the parliament if the Australian people approved of it in a plebiscite. That was our policy," Mr Turnbull said.
"So there was a condition precedent as the lawyers might say for that. Now that has not been satisfied, and the reason for that is because of the opposition of the Labor Party and for no other reason."
Mr Turnbull, who has expressed frustration that the issue is distracting from his week-long tour of WA would not say if he had sought to discipline MPs agitating for a free vote.
"I speak to them more regularly than I do even with distinguished members of the press, so you can imagine how often that is," he said.
"I talk to my colleagues all the time and we often have discussions about policy issues and they are best done privately in the partyroom. I'm not going to get into a public debate about internal party issues and discussions here."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany Senior High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First World War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Anzac Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Connor Rick Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
