<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411244691299758</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/cloud-but-slim-chance-of-rain-as-big-dry-continues/3207850/</url>
  <title>Cloud but slim chance of rain as big dry continues</title>
  <content>
THERE appears little relief on the horizon with the Sunshine Coast's bone-dry July likely to extend through August and into the start of spring.
The latest Bureau of Meteorology data shows the Sunshine Coast received only a third of its average annual July rainfall after a particularly dry summer.
July brought Queensland its highest temperatures on record with Kowanyama reaching 35 degrees on July 19.
It follows a June rated the second-driest in recorded history in Queensland.
BOM forecaster David Crock said temperatures remained warmer than average for the Sunshine Coast with no really strong signal of significant rain on the horizon.
He said a strong system developing stretching from Cairns to Rockhampton may extend further south but was unlikely to reach below Wide Bay.
Maroochydore's August average rainfall is only 80.5 mm.
The Coast's minimum temperature remained above 10 degrees overnight ahead of an expected maximum of 22 degrees on a mostly sunny day with light winds.
Thursday is expected to be partly cloudy with just a slight chance of rain and light winds with a maximum temperature of 23 degrees.
Friday will be warmer still, topping 25 degrees on another partly cloudy day with no more than a hint of rain and with winds staying light throughout.
Saturday is expected to be cloudy early with a medium chance of rain early ahead of a sunny afternoon on a day where the temperature will reach 24 degrees.
Sunday is expected to be mostly sunny, on a day that winds will remain light with a 24 degree maximum and the possibility of late showers.
Monday will see temperatures continue to climb, reaching 26 degrees during what is meant to be the depths of winter with light winds.
'Teen fed burning hot sauce, punched in face and stomach'
"Nice deal if you can get it!"
More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wide Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kowanyama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Crock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore's August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
