<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412236828759613</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/naplan-results-2017-qld-data-for-all-schools/news-story/6925e875d56d08fff30651440f8137cb</url>
  <title>New faces in top NAPLAN results</title>
  <content>
THE 2017 NAPLAN results for Queensland schools are in.
Queensland has posted some of its best ever , but writing skills remain a major problem, especially for older students.
Scroll down for Queensland schools data
A snapshot of how each Queensland school went in this year's NAPLAN tests has some new faces among the top performers.
The Queensland Curriculum and Assessment Authority today released raw NAPLAN data for schools achievement in Years 3, 5, 7 and 9 across the five different test areas.
Analysis by The Courier-Mail shows Fairholme College in Toowoomba recorded strong results with its Year 5 students coming in second highest across reading, writing, spelling, grammar and numeracy.
Fairholme College said it was particularly happy with the results of its boarder students who have been part of a project to reduce homesickness.
The project has involved both academic and boarding staff travelling to the properties and towns of its girls.
Although private schools dominated the top levels, several state schools have maintained good results especially in the earlier years.
Visiting Musgrave Hill State School in Southport today, Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk and Education Minister Kate Jones congratulated the 240,000 Queensland school students in Years 3, 5, 7 and 9 who completed the National Assessment Program - Literacy and Numeracy (NAPLAN) test in May.
"I'm pleased to say that our students have recorded some of their highest scores since NAPLAN testing began in 2008," Ms Palaszczuk said.
"My Government has employed more than 3095 extra teachers and teacher aides to improve education in Queensland state schools.
Ms Palaszczuk said Queensland's 2017 NAPLAN results confirmed the long-term trend of lifting literacy and numeracy outcomes across the state.
"This is great news for students - and for Queensland, as we know our students will be armed with the numeracy and literacy skills needed to exceed in future educational and vocational pursuits," she said.
Individual schools would receive their students' NAPLAN results from today and would begin to distribute these to parents and carers soon afterwards.
The current results are based on preliminary data with the final national report due in December.Queensland NAPLAN data 2017
The data shows the average scale score of students at each school, as provided by the Queensland Curriculum & Assessment Authority.
Raw scores are transformed into scale scores that allow comparison of students between year levels and in the future, across years. Higher scores indicate higher performance.
Viewing these tables on your mobile? Flip to landscape for optimal reading.
The Courier-Mail app users can also view the data by .
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assessment Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December.Queensland NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's 2017 NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairholme College</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Kate Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Musgrave Hill State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Assessment Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Curriculum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
