<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412232533792236</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/lister-ballerina-covered-by-betoota-advocate-mural-20170802-gxnltj.html</url>
  <title>Lister ballerina covered by Betoota Advocate mural </title>
  <content>
Underneath the freshly-painted mural of a satirical article on the "hideous street art" in Brisbane is a dancing ballerina in a pink tutu, created by prominent Australian street artist Anthony Lister more than two years ago.
Artist Scott Marsh finished his Betoota Advocate that joked coral bleaching was low on Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk's list of priorities compared to the rise of graffiti.Photo: Supplied
The large-scale mural painted over a range of graffiti, including a ballerina created by internationally renowned artist Anthony Lister, whose artworks have fetched upwards of $15,000.
Marsh was given permission to paint on the wall by the bar's manager and said he had called Lister himself to make sure it was ok to go ahead with his artwork.Photo: Google
"I know Anthony and I gave him a call and let him know, he was happy for me to do something over the top of it," he said.
"I spoke to him afterwards and he said 'good work, great work'.

"I think he is in the same kind of mind frame about what is going on with the Great Barrier Reef and the Adani mine as well, he was pretty happy with it."

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Lister was approached for comment.

A post shared by Anthony LISTER (@anthonylister) on

Marsh told Fairfax Media on Tuesday he was a "massive fan" of the Betoota Advocate's work.
"People walk past and think it's hilarious because they know Betoota is satirical, but other people do fall for it and say they can't believe Palaszczuk would say something like that, which I think is even more funny," he said.
"I think that speaks volumes for the opinion of Premier Palaszczuk and her government."
calling for "graffiti zones" for street artists to cut their teeth and hit out at Brisbane City Council for charging suspected vandals with 5260 offences in 2016.
"It [the fines] is money made off the backs of bored children," he said.
"It's embarrassed me to be in skate parks and not see people activating their space ... creatively, through street art, graffiti, public art, whatever you want to call it."
It was not the first time Ms Palaszczuk's support of the Adani mine was targeted by Marsh's street art.
In May, he Finding Nemo, in protest of the mine's impact on the Great Barrier Reef.
Sydney-based MarshKanye Loves Kanye  last year.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Barrier Reef</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Lister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finding Nemo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marsh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betoota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based MarshKanye Loves Kanye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betoota Advocate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
