<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412279778433317</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/east/smaller-block-snares-big-figure-in-doncaster-east/news-story/16d0a8dbfc38dce4e0fd8a68bf795bd8</url>
  <title>Smaller block snares big figure in Doncaster East - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
, sold for more than $1.2 million on July 29.

A DONCASTER East house's 511sq m allotment might have been on the smaller side for the suburb.
But that didn't stop it reaping a sum close to those usually seen for larger allotments.
Philip Webb Doncaster East auctioneer Robert Groeneveld said he'd been happy with a $1.225 million result at  on July 29.
"You wouldn't generally expect that much for a smaller block," Mr Groeneveld said.
"A few have sold nearby recently for around $1.35 million, but the block sizes were about 780sq m."
Mr Groeneveld said the house was particularly appealing because of its position in the Millgate Park Estate.
"Two bidders turned out on the day, one who wanted to live in the home, and one who wanted to build a new home on the site," he said.
"Both commented on the lack of quality homes on the market currently."

The open-plan zone opens to an expansive outdoor entertainment area.

SUBURB PROFILE:
He said the home passed in at $1.2 million, but sold shortly after in post-auction negotiations.
Mr Groeneveld added that buyers today were looking at anything that was neat, tidy, and presented well.
Doncaster East's median house price rose seven per cent to $1.23 million across the 12 months to April.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Groeneveld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millgate Park Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Groeneveld</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Webb Doncaster East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doncaster East</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
