<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412271188498497</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/blogger-has-to-pay-wedding-photographer-us1-million-after-ruining-her-business/news-story/c79cd9aad169b0362382248dcc40a92b</url>
  <title>Takedown over $125 costs blogger $1 million</title>
  <content>
A BLOGGER has been ordered to pay $US1.08 million ($AU1.2 million) to a wedding photographer after creating a media sensation over images of her special day.
Last week, a Dallas County jury ruled in favour of the US photographer Andrea Polito, agreeing that she had been the victim of a deliberate takedown.
Polito was hired by Neely Moldovan, who maintained a blog called "A Complete Waste of Makeup" to photograph her wedding in 2014.
But the arrangement soured when Moldovan objected to paying an $US125 ($AU157) for a "cover" as part of an album of high-resolution photos.
Moldovan and her husband objected to paying the fee because they had already paid thousands for the album.
While Polito said she tried to resolve the conflict and even apologised and offered to cover the cost of the album, she instead found herself at the centre of a media frenzy after Moldovan decided to contact a local television station complaining that Polito was "holding their photos hostage".
According to Polito, the negative publicity ruined her photography business, amid accusations that she "cheated" and "scammed" people.
"People knew me and my reputation. I've shot several of the Dallas elites," Polito told The Dallas Morning News. "All the name-calling, all the bullying ... I was humiliated."
The Moldovans posed for camera crews alongside empty photo frames to drum up sympathy and outrage over their situation but Polito said the couple was told about the extra charge from the beginning.
"She basically didn't read her paperwork or contract," Polito told the Washington Post. "She just couldn't understand why she couldn't have her high-res images. It's in bold in our contract."
Almost overnight, Polito's business was destroyed and she had to move out of a studio she'd maintained for 10 years.
Polito sued the Moldovans and the court was also shown messages that the blogger sent to someone saying "we are hoping that our story makes the news and completely ruins her business".
The Moldovans also encouraged further outrage with posts on social media.
Andrew Moldovan appeared to "like" a comment from someone who purported to be a former customer of Polito and wrote, "She gave me AIDS. Photos were okay".
The Moldovans blamed fake profiles for the offending "likes" but that was ultimately proved false.
Last week a jury ruled that the Moldovans had defamed Polito and her business, and had conspired to do so.
The photographer was awarded more than $US1 million in damages.
Although it's unclear whether the couple will challenge the verdict or actually have the money to pay up, Polito said she was just glad that her name had been cleared.
"For two and a half years I walked around my daughter's school feeling ashamed and embarrassed," she said. "They know I've won now."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$125</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Moldovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moldovan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas Morning News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Polito</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AU157</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AU1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dallas County</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Complete Waste of Makeup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neely Moldovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.08</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Polito</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
