<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412271188498458</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/wa-news/woman-killed-by-a-dog-south-of-perth-20170802-gxnn2l.html</url>
  <title>Woman killed by dog at southern Perth boarding kennel</title>
  <content>
A woman in her 50s has been killed by a dog at a licensed kennel facility in the Perth suburb of Southern River.
The incident occurred on Tuesday afternoon.Photo: Gary Warrick
Police were called to the property in Southern River, which also serves as a canine boarding kennel, at about 1.30pm.
Sue Lopicich, who owns the facility on Terrier Place, received life threatening injuries from a dog and she was declared dead by St John Ambulance officers.
Her death is not being treated as suspicious and a report will be prepared for the coroner.
The City of Gosnells said its rangers received a request from the police to attend the property to collect a dog, which was preventing officers from accessing the body of the woman.

"As a result, the City is currently holding two dogs that were taken from the property," the council said in a statement.
"The adult, male dogs, one a bull mastiff and the other a Staffordshire bull terrier, are being held at the request of police.
"An investigation is being conducted by the police and the City is waiting to hear further from them.
"The dogs are microchipped and registered to the owner of the property.
"No previous complaints have been made to the City about these dogs."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staffordshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrier Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Lopicich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern River</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Gosnells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GARY WARRICK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
