<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411248986267269</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/this-brisbane-house-sold-for-less-than-a-onebedroom-unit/news-story/85852ed00636a9b4adbee1f9f1708285</url>
  <title>This Brisbane house sold for less than a one-bedroom unit - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
This Brisbane home has sold for less than the price of a one-bedroom unit

YOU snooze, you lose.
This two-bedroom cottage on 710sq m of land at was looking for "offers over $310,000" - and has just gone unconditional for $320,000 - a figure less than its most recent land valuation for rates assessment.

The home has flaws, but the price can't be beat.

It's also below the $330,000 asking price for this one-bedroom, 60sq m unit at
- an apartment one-twelfth the size of the Deagon home's land.

For $10,000 more than Blackwood Rd, Deagon, you could have this tiny one-bedroom unit in the city.

The Deagon property included a work shed and covered car accommodation, and there was potential to improve, according to Ray White sales consultant, Catherine O'Keefe.
"All the interest I had had been from renovators, which actually surprised me, because I thought most of the interest would be from people wanting to knock it down," Ms O'Keefe said.

The property provided for a large flat lot in a gentrifying street.

Ms O'Keefe said gentrification in Blackwood Rd, and more widely across Deagon, was well underway.
"There are actually about five new houses in that street," she said.
"Deagon is an absolute cracker of a suburb. It's got three train stations that you can walk to, so it doesn't matter where you are in Deagon, you can walk to a train station," Ms O'Keefe said.
"And the bikeway that goes right across Brisbane, it actually goes down Blackwood Rd."
Some buyers might have been turned off by the train line to the rear, but at just 15km from the CBD, this had to be one of the most affordable and commutable homes to hit the market in Brisbane this year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms O'Keefe</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deagon</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine O'Keefe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blackwood Rd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
