<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412193879086125</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/net-tightens-on-prawns-responsible-for-white-spot-/3207981/</url>
  <title>Net tightens on prawns responsible for white spot outbreak</title>
  <content>
RESEARCHERS are closing the net on the source responsible for the white spot disease outbreak which wiped out millions of south-east Queensland prawns.

The University of the Sunshine Coast's Aquaculture Genetics Research Group has been methodically eliminating possible causes of the outbreak and have struck on one theory.

They also found similar close relationships between imported Chinese samples in retail and those reported from mainland China, although the precise retail strain is somewhat different from the Logan strain.

Assoc Prof Knibb said with more time they were fairly confident further testing could narrow down the precise linkages between all three points, the Logan River, retail and China.

Meanwhile the present picture and links demonstrate a clear potential pathway of introduction of white spot in Australia.

Assoc Prof Knibb said a large proportion of recreational fishermen and women used retail prawns as bait now, and white leg shrimp would've also been sold in any supermarket.

He said his team had "systematically" negated arguments by the federal biosecurity authorities that white spot entered Australia other than via retail prawns as bait, including theories it had already been present, or had been introduced in infected prawn farm feed.

He said raw prawns contaminated with the disease and used as bait could've entered Logan River farm intakes, or crabs which had eaten contaminated prawns could have also entered the farms and spread the disease.

Assoc Prof Knibb was confident with more testing they could further narrow down the overseas source of the outbreak.

"The net is tightening around the suspect, definitely," he said.

In March Agriculture Minister Barnaby Joyce told the ABC there was "no direct link between prawns at a retail level and the white spot outbreak".

Even so, importation of uncooked prawns was suspended after the outbreak, but Assoc Prof Knibb and his team have found white spot still present in cooked and frozen "processed" foods containing prawns in 14 of 15 samples purchased from two Coast supermarkets (after importation of raw prawns was banned).

"We don't know if the detection of white spot in frozen products means the virus is infective, but this is a question that needs to be tested," he said.

"In any case, it means these prawns were once infected with a living virus, and we cannot guarantee that processing will always be conducted in a way that kills the virus."

Seven prawn farms on the Logan River tested positive for the virus earlier this year, shutting them down for 12 months, and the virus has also been found in wild prawns in Moreton Bay.

One of those was Gold Coast Marine Aquaculture, which lost 25 million black tiger prawns after it was forced to de-stock when the contamination was confirmed.

General manager Alistair Dick said the outbreak had cost his company about $14 million.

They're now in the midst of a 12-month shutdown as a result of the outbreak.

He had no doubt raw, imported prawns carrying the virus and used as bait were to blame.

"There's been a number of expert reports," he said.

"The government's been using plausible deniability.

"The only evidence is based on raw imported prawns as being the source of the infection."

He said reports of proof of freedom had shown it was an exotic disease, so any suggestion white spot disease had already been present was "absolute rubbish".

"You can't have it both ways," Mr Dick said.

The Australian Prawn Farming Association life member and research and development panel member said he'd handed a series of government reports and surveys over as evidence to a Senate Inquiry into the outbreak.

Mr Dick said those documents had shown a rise in the use of imported raw prawns as bait about a decade ago.

He was frustrated at the approach to biosecurity, arguing education was not enough to prevent further spread of the disease, and he also questioned why imports had resumed before the Senate Inquiry had wrapped up.

The Daily has approached Biosecurity Queensland and the Federal Department of Agriculture and Water Resources for comment.

More than 700 cast votes for region's most popular vet clinic
Lost seconds before head-on highway crash
Child taken to hospital after being hit by car while leaving school
STUDENTS are always ready to get back together.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Prawn Farming Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's Aquaculture Genetics Research Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assoc Prof Knibb</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Department of Agriculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate Inquiry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Marine Aquaculture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair Dick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biosecurity Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March Agriculture Minister Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan River</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
