<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412318433139613</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/sophisticated-traveller/tali-wiru-a-fourhour-culinary-adventure-overlooking-uluru-20170720-gxevry</url>
  <title>Why fine dining at Uluru is good enough for this top chef</title>
  <content>
by
Amelia Lester

This is a special feature in association with Ayers Rock Resort.
How does one of Australia's most acclaimed chefs mark the occasion of his silver wedding anniversary? For Peter Gilmore, of Sydney's famed Quay and Bennelong restaurants, and wife Kath, a last-minute reservation at the corner bistro wouldn't cut it.
Instead, the couple travelled 3000 kilometres to a restaurant without a roof, where meals are cooked in a tent and dinner doubles as the most spectacular show on earth. The evening they chose is called Tali Wiru, which means "beautiful dune" in the local Pitjantjatjara language, and it's a four-hour culinary adventure which just happens to overlook Uluru.
"We had both always wanted to see it," Gilmore says. "[Tali Wiru] seemed like a very good reason to go." His is a sentiment a lot of Australians - including me - can relate to, and, like Gilmore, I was awed by the experience when I went earlier this year.

Kristine Harvey

Created by  in 2014, Tali Wiru takes place on a remote dune reached by minivan or, for extra knock-your-socks-off glamour, a half-hour helicopter ride. Voyages' Karena Noble, who accompanied me to dinner, explained this location is strategic so that diners can better appreciate the scale of the landscape, which is sometimes hard to grasp up close to the rock.

As the sun set over the horizon, I saw what she meant. We observed not only Uluru's famous metamorphosis through various moods of red, orange, pink, violet and indigo, but also the dramatic transformation of the scrubby eternity around us. (The golden dusk light here means you will never take a better selfie.)
The meal, which emerged, improbably, from under a tarp on an adjacent dune in five meticulously crafted courses, was a dazzling showcase of indigenous ingredients. Gilmore was similarly awed during his own anniversary dinner: "I was super impressed that in a remote spot the team could offer such a high standard of food and choice of dishes."
A word on those choices. You will have three for each course, paired with an Australian wine, and while I'm sure the Moreton Bay Bug with pickled muntries (or native cranberries) is a fine entree, the pressed wallaby I selected was delicious. The texture was akin to pulled pork, or especially unctuous rillettes, and the fermented quandong alongside was a perfectly tart counterbalance.
Between courses, Tali Wiru chef Robert Havel brought over slices of finger lime to try. It had flesh like caviar and a sharpness missing from limes I know. Later he introduced our group of 20, who had come from all over the world, to sea blight, a coastal green, and rosella petals, used to make ruby red domes of petit gateaux, served with Tasmanian ice wine.

Supplied

By then, with only a quarter moon, it was almost pitch dark. Havel explained that, for his people, constellations such as the Emu are seen not through the points of the stars but in the space between them, and distinct shapes began to emerge above us.
I was there as a journalist, stealing poor Karena's food all evening, and yet it still felt like one of the more romantic nights of my life. So what did the couple who have been married for 25 years think? The Gilmores loved it. "I took away more of an understanding and appreciation of Australia," Peter said. "It was truly memorable."

Supplied

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay Bug</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilmore</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karena Noble</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amelia Lester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayers Rock Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Havel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pitjantjatjara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Havel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristine Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Gilmore, of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tali Wiru</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
