<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412361382813204</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/east/mitcham-youngster-anthony-jordan-wants-to-represent-australia-at-the-paralympics-in-running-or-long-jump/news-story/bddfac24c3d4704348e8caa41e6a3e75</url>
  <title>No hurdles for Anthony</title>
  <content>
ANTHONY Jordan won't stop running and jumping until he can pull on the green and gold for Australia at the Paralympics.
Eleven-year-old Anthony, of Mitcham, is a keen cricketer and plays football for the Vermont Eagles, but it is athletics where he is beginning to make a name for himself
Anthony was born with a congenital arm abnormality, leaving him with a shortened left forearm and no fingers or thumb on his left hand.
But that added challenge has only spurred him on.
The youngster qualified for the 2016 School Sport Australia National Track and Field Competition in Sydney last year where he came fourth in both the 100m and 200m sprint finals, and received bronze medals for long jump and the 4x100m relay.
Anthony said he was eager to compete at the national competition again this year should he qualify as he believes he can now run faster and jump longer than ever before.
"At Sydney I ran the 100m in 15.12 seconds and I think I'm faster than that now," Anthony said.
"I broke my personal best in long jump at training recently as well.
"In Sydney my long jump record was 3.53m, but a few weeks ago I beat that by almost 30 centimetres and jumped 3.80m."
Anthony said his dream was to one day represent Australia at the Paralympics, like his hero Madeleine Hogan.
Hogan, an Australian javelin bronze medallist at the 2008 Beijing and 2012 London Paralympics, was also born without the lower half of her left arm.
She also competed at the 2016 Rio Paralympics.
"Maddy's got even less of an arm than me, so to see her do so well is pretty inspiring for me," Anthony said.
His mum, Angela, said he loved training at the Doncaster Athletics Tracks and had recently registered for the Little Athletics Junior Development Squad.
"Anthony believes in equal opportunity for all kids who love sport," Ms Jordan said.
"He cheers on his teammates whether it be at track and field events, cricket or football.
"Anthony understands that winning is not everything - it's the effort you put in that counts.''
Anthony has been nominated for a Whitehorse Leader Local Sports Star award, presented by Sportsmart, SportsTG and Gold104.3.
For more stories and to nominate, visit
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitehorse Leader Local Sports Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Paralympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Athletics Junior Development Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paralympic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>School Sport Australia National Track</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony, of Mitcham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Field Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vermont Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Paralympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold104.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANTHONY Jordan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doncaster Athletics Tracks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madeleine Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SportsTG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sportsmart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
