<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412361382813164</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/latest-news/trump-cautious-on-n-korea-force-expert/news-story/42010559317d6c9db0ea4a5586d68687</url>
  <title>Trump 'cautious' on N Korea force: expert</title>
  <content>
The chances of Donald Trump using military force to interrupt North Korea's missile program are low, says a respected foreign policy expert.
Lowy Institute executive director Michael Fullilove says the US president has so far shown himself to be "cautious" about the use of force.
Even in the case of Syria's chemical weapons, the president endorsed a Tomahawk missile strike which was a classic tool for "signalling something without taking big risks".
"I think probably the chances of Mr Trump using military force to try to interrupt the (North Korean) programs are low," Dr Fullilove told the National Press Club on Wednesday.
He said it was likely US military officials would give Mr Trump the same advice given to previous presidents - that the risks and costs of such action vastly exceed the likelihood of success.
"It is risky because North Korea is unpredictable. It is nuclear-armed. It has chemical weapons. It has thousands of artillery pieces pointed at Seoul.
"The likelihood of success is low because the North Korean programs are dispersed, they are mobile, they are partly underground, they are mysterious."
However he warned there were other ways conflict could arise on the peninsula such as the North Koreans mounting an attack on South Korea or Japan.
And, given Mr Trump's personality, there could arise "questions of honour and prestige and face" in which the president could decide to make an aggressive move.
Dr Fullilove said the US administration appeared to have shrunk its interest in Asia to the issue of North Korea's nuclear weapons and missile programs.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Press Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tomahawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Fullilove</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N. Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowy Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seoul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Fullilove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
