<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411970540783365</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/terrorsuspect-has-been-released-without-charge/news-story/efe8f45af0238d74bb5ba86b77b5dbef</url>
  <title>'Endured days of intense questioning'</title>
  <content>
A SYDNEY man arrested over a terror conspiracy to bring down a plane and then released without charge is shocked to have been associated with the allegations, his lawyer says.
Abdul Merhi, 50, was one of four men taken into custody on Saturday when five Sydney properties were raided by NSW and federal police.
Authorities became aware of an alleged plot to "bring down" a plane using a homemade device and detained the men without charge under terror legislation. Mr Merhi was released about 7pm Tuesday and his solicitor, Moustafa Kheir, said he endured days of intense questioning.
"It's a very serious allegation to have against you," he told AAP today. "There's a lot of stress associated there, and not knowing, and he was shocked that he was being questioned.
"It's just unfathomable that he would be associated with anything like this." Mr Merhi's family was also in shock and his life had been "turned upside down", Mr Kheir added.
"He just wants to go back to as normal life as possible now." Mr Kheir said he would review the actions of police.

My client Abdul Merhi has been released without charge. Tough few days, but he's relieved the truth is out. I will review police action.
"A lot of information was divulged, including his identity," he said. "That's caused a lot of damage to him. We want to review all the information police had and what basis they had to do what they did." The three other men can be detained until Sunday evening under the terror legislation.
Police have spent days rifling through properties in Lakemba, Wiley Park, Punchbowl and Surry Hills in the search for evidence.
"This investigation remains ongoing, and further information will be provided at an appropriate time," a joint statement from the AFP and NSW Police said today.
Etihad Airways confirmed it was helping Australian authorities with the investigation, amid reports the arrests were made after a tip-off from foreign intelligence services.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kheir</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Airways</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merhi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moustafa Kheir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
