<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412365677780521</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/afl/more-news/will-langfords-kiss-afl-may-need-to-step-in-says-lions-legend-simon-black/news-story/00e7be4e20b60d551a60ff989df9d2f0</url>
  <title>AFL may need to act on kissing: Black</title>
  <content>
IT was the "bizarre" act that might be deemed workplace harassment anywhere but the AFL, and Brisbane Lions legend Simon Black says the code may need to stamp out kissing if it becomes a ploy.
Black's comments follow Hawthorn midfielder Will Langford twice going into kiss Sydney Swans veteran Jarrod McVeigh last weekend.
McVeigh made it clear he did not appreciate the first kiss that Langford planted on his cheek.
When Langford went in for a second time, McVeigh shoved him in the face and gave away a free kick to the Hawk.
The incident caused a stir and even Langford's former teammate and now Melbourne defender Jordan Lewis said he'd be "filthy" if it was done to him.
"As a player, if that was to happen to me, I'd be filthy," Lewis told AFL 360 on Tuesday night.
Richmond forward Jack Riewoldt, who also appeared on AFL 360, said it was "bizarre".
"For mine it's a bit of an invasion of your own personal space" he said.
Black, one of the most highly decorated AFL players, said he would feel uncomfortable being kissed once, let alone having an opponent try it again.
He said he never experienced it during his playing days and the only two previous incidents he could recall was Hawthorn skipper Luke Hodge planting one on Sydney's Lance Franklin in the 2014 Grand Final.
The other was when Melbourne's Allen Jakovich kissed his brother Glen, who was playing for West Coast, in 1993.
He said it could get out-of-hand in the same way jumper punching became fashionable before it was finally reeled-in this season and deemed worthy of suspension.
"It's a bit weird. It's one out of the box and you'd certainly feel uncomfortable," he said.
"It's a cheeky ploy which makes players uncomfortable. If it becomes a serial thing the AFL may need to step in but it's a bit early to crack down on it."
Griffith University Employment Relations and Human Resources professor Michael Barry said Langford's actions would be deemed inappropriate at any place of work but the sporting field which has its own set of rules.
He said players are expected to antagonise and "get under the skin" of their opponents and kissing would be seen in that light although it was not a great publicity tool for the code.
"The commentary around this and its accepted it's not a good look. It's a kind of form of intimidation which is seen as part of the game."
Neither the AFL nor Hawthorn responded to questions asking if Langford had been counselled and whether the practice of kissing opponents was reportable or deemed harassment.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffith University Employment Relations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Black</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod McVeigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McVeigh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Barry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Langford</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Will Langford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Allen Jakovich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GLEN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Riewoldt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL 360</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
