<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412060735098096</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/movies/now-showing/atomic-blonde-review-charlize-therons-pained-vulnerable-star-performance-20170802-gxns3l.html</url>
  <title>Atomic Blonde review: Charlize Theron's pained, vulnerable, star performance</title>
  <content>
FILM
ATOMIC BLONDE
ATOMIC BLONDE ★★★ 1/2
MA General release (115 minutes)

Up Next

Trailer: Romper Stomper

01:21

More Trailers Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

02:54
Trailer: Atomic Blonde

Trailer: Atomic Blonde

An undercover MI6 agent is sent to Berlin during the Cold War to investigate the murder of a fellow agent and recover a missing list of double agents.

Up Next

Trailer: Romper Stomper

01:21

01:21
Trailer: Romper Stomper

Trailer: Romper Stomper

The original 1992 film that tells the story of the downfall of a neo-Nazi group in blue-collar suburban Melbourne.

Up Next

Trailer:
It

02:23

02:23
Trailer: It

Trailer:
It

The new adaptation of Stephen King's iconic work. In Derry, Maine, seven friends come face-to-face with a shape shifter, who takes the form of an evil clown who targets children.

Up Next

Trailer:
Kiki, Love to Love

01:52

01:52
Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Trailer:
Kiki, Love to Love

Director Paco LeA³nas vibrant new comedy follows a collection of lovers through a series of intertwined stories, delivering an outrageously provocative take on what can happen behind closed doors.

Up Next

Trailer:
Thor: Ragnarok

02:25

02:25
Trailer: Thor: Ragnarok

Trailer:
Thor: Ragnarok

Imprisoned, Thor must battle a former ally and race against time to prevent goddess of death Hela from destroying his home.

Up Next

Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

01:54

01:54
Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Trailer: Kiki, Love to Love

Set in Madrid, ordinary couples with real passion investigate their own sexuality through five intertwined stories.

Up Next

Trailer: A Monster Calls

02:26

02:26
Trailer: A Monster Calls

Trailer: A Monster Calls

A boy who is experiencing trauma from his single mother's terminal illness seeks the help of a tree monster.

Up Next

4 Corners: Pumped

00:30

Trailer: Atomic Blonde

An undercover MI6 agent is sent to Berlin during the Cold War to investigate the murder of a fellow agent and recover a missing list of double agents.

David Leitch's Atomic Blonde, based on the graphic novel The Coldest City, injects some serious glamour into a big Hollywood movie. This is a film where glamour is the whole point, albeit glamour of a paradoxical, hardboiled kind.
Charlize Theron plays the blonde of the title, MI6 operative Lorraine Broughton, who arrives in West Berlin at the end of the Cold War on a mission about a stolen piece of microfilm and a fellow agent (James McAvoy) gone rogue.
The details of the plot don't matter; what counts is the vibe. Leitch grooves on everything about this setting - the cloudy skies, the lounging punks, the graffiti on the Berlin Wall, and the absence of digital technology that makes the whole world somehow more immediate than the one we know today.
This immediacy is a mixed blessing for Lorraine and the other spies, who are often subjected to spectacularly brutal violence. The fight scenes are in the neo-classical manner of John Wick, which Leitch co-directed with Chad Stahelski. In these scenes the camera stays distant enough to let us appreciate the stunt work, yet still seems caught up in the action, as if it were an obstacle the characters could collide with at any moment.
The film resembles an advertisement, and sometimes literally is one, with Lorraine showing a decided fondness for a certain brand of vodka. It's also a lot like a fashion shoot, Theron looking like a rock'n'roll ice princess in the tradition of Nico and Debbie Harry; other free-associative cultural allusions range from the Queen and Bowie songs on the soundtrack to a clip from the Russian science fiction classic Stalker.
This reliance on quotation helps explain why Atomic Blonde lacks the gravity and melancholy a director like Michael Mann can achieve in an equally abstract genre context. The casual yet explicit treatment of Lorraine's love affair with another woman (Sofia Boutella) is something new in American pop culture, but this relationship is never as emotionally central as it should be. Similarly, the ending feels as if Leitch shot three or four options, then picked the safest and least interesting.
But none of this can take away the fact that in between this film and Mad Max: Fury Road, Theron has become one of the major action stars of world cinema. Again, her appeal depends on a paradox, which the whole film is built around: her ability to seem at once coolly unreachable and physically vulnerable.
The vulnerability registers in tiny but crucial moments, like the hoarse, pained cough she gives when lying prone on the floor - not a sound you'd be likely to hear from James Bond, but one you or I might well emit if we suffered a fraction of the damage Lorraine does here.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coldest City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hela</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorraine Broughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debbie Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thor</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATOMIC BLONDE ★★★ 1/2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Berlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mad Max</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leitch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Bond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monster Calls</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romper Stomper</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lorraine</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MA General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Derry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paco LeA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cold War</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ragnarok</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sofia Boutella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Mann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atomic Blonde</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James McAvoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Leitch's Atomic Blonde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trailers Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fury Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Stahelski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MADRID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MI6</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiki</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Wick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
