<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412236828759576</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/frankston-street-watch-police-use-capsicum-spray-to-subdue-man-after-langwarrin-crash-homeless-humpty-set-on-fire-on-foreshore/news-story/a5be6360cb767706e6c585cf343e3983</url>
  <title>Angry tailgater gets spray from police</title>
  <content>
LANGWARRIN
Police used capsicum spray to subdue a man after he became aggressive following an accident on McClelland Dve, Langwarrin, on July 27, about 11.15am. Police allege the man in his late 30s was riding a motorcycle and tailgating a vehicle when he crashed into it as it turned into the industrial estate. He allegedly struggled with Ambulance officers and police subsequently using capsicum spray and handcuffing the man. The man was wearing a helmet without a facial covering when the accident occurred. He was taken to The Alfred hospital to be treated for suspected head injuries.
FRANKSTON
CFA units put out a fire at a humpy-style shelter used by a homeless person near Frankston foreshore on July 31, about 6.30pm. Police said no-one was in the shelter at the time of the fire. They believe local youths have been using the shelter as a place to meet and smoke cigarettes.
Police have thanked the public and media for help identifying a Frankston man involved in a serious accident. Investigators have confirmed the pedestrian to be a 28-year-old Frankston man. The man continues to receive treatment in hospital and the investigation is ongoing. He crossed into the path of a west bound Jeep and was struck by a vehicle on Cranbourne Rd. on July 27 at about 11.10pm. He was flown to the Alfred with serious head, chest, pelvis and leg injuries, where he remains.
CARRUM DOWNS
A man will face court after a hammer was alleged used during a robbery at Carrum Downs 7-Eleven, Amayla Cres, on July 29 at about 7.30am. Police allege the man entered the store, produced the hammer and fled with an amount of cash. They arrested a 19-year-old man, from Frankston North, in nearby bushes at short time afterwards following a tip off from residents. He is due to face court soon on robbery related charges. Information to Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
HASTINGS
A man in his 40s was assaulted after an intruder entered his home in Thomas Place, Hastings, about 8.35pm on July 31. The man was stabbed in the right shoulder and lost several teeth after being punched in the face repeatedly. The intruder fled and the victim was taken to Frankston Hospital. The investigation is ongoing.
BAXTER
CFA units put out a fire after a stolen Nissan Navara was set on fire after being dumped off Golf Links Rd, Baxter, on August 1 just before 7pm. The fire was contained to the vehicle's cabin, however, it was effectively destroyed. Information to Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrum Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nissan Navara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrum Downs 7-Eleven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baxter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeep</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LANGWARRIN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hastings</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amayla Cres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cranbourne Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golf Links Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McClelland Dve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
