<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411541044047976</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/hundreds-of-council-employees-walk-off-the-job-to-battle-city-hall-20170802-gxnofu.html</url>
  <title>Hundreds of council employees walk off the job to battle City Hall</title>
  <content>
Strike action has spread beyond Brisbane's bus drivers, with council employees from eight other departments fighting City Hall for a better work environment.
On Wednesday hundreds of council employees rallied on King George Square at noon.Photo: Ruth McCosker
The calls of protest attracted attention from City Hall security personnel, police and the occasional tourist - but little response from inside City Hall.
One protester, who identified himself as a bus driver, stood at the front of the crowd of about 400 and called out "Graham Quirk, come out and talk to your workers". Photo: Belinda Hogan-Collis - Queensland Services Union
The only immediate response was the closing of all but one door and an increase in security.
The Services Union, the Australian Manufacturing Workers Union, the Electrical Trade Union, Professionals Australia, the Plumbers' Union, the Australian Workers Union, the CFMEU, the Rail, Tram and Bus Union and the Transport Workers Union are all involved in the council's Enterprise Bargaining Agreement negotiations and fighting for improvements to safety and working conditions.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

RTBU assistant secretary Tom Brown said all unions involved in the EBA attended to protest the council's delay in delivering the agreement.
"We've been negotiating [the EBA] for seven months now and we've gotten nowhere until industrial action was applied for," he said.
"Now we see people making slow process."
Mr Brown said an agreement had to be reached, but currently discussions between unions and the council were tense and ended in handshakes and no deals.
"Eventually the pay has to be settled, there can be no EBA until the pay is settled."
Union-member bus drivers went on strike between 10am and 2pm on Wednesday and Mr Brown would not rule out more strikes.
"I'm not prepared to rule out anything, but we take it one step at a time, we take our action and then we gauge our response."

Hundreds of union workers outside City Hall to fight for a better EBA. One is yelling "Graham Quirk come out and talk to your workers"

Australian Workers Union Queensland acting branch secretary Steve Baker said the EBA negotiations had left council workers angry.
"Our members and the general workers within the council feel that they've been ripped off."
CFMEU assistant secretary Andrew Sutherland said action from the unions was gaining momentum. 
"We're going to stand shoulder to shoulder and we're going to fight the council," he said.
More EBA talks would be held between the council and the unions on Thursday.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Workers' Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belinda Hogan-Collis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Union-member</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Sutherland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enterprise Bargaining Agreement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bus Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Manufacturing Workers' Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plumbers' Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professionals Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Workers Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brown</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth McCosker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Electrical Trades Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EBA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Workers Union Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RTBU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
