<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411669893068576</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/meeting-between-robert-boinga-bob-prudhoe-and-yarra-ranges-council-postponed/news-story/c9406ea7ea452bddb20372a30a31c423</url>
  <title>Sculpture house meeting deferred</title>
  <content>
A MEETING to discuss the safety of a Warburton sculpture house has been postponed.
Owner Robert "Boinga Bob" Prudhoe and Yarra Ranges Council were due to meet today to discuss the council's safety concerns about the Tibetan-themed house, which has become a major arts and tourism attraction in the town.
Mr Prudhoe, 77, has lived in the house for more than 20 years.

The council's social and economic development director Ali Wastie said the meeting was postponed until next Tuesday because one of Mr Prudhoe's project advisers could not attend.
She said both parties wanted him to be there.
The meeting will still be at Mr Prudhoe's property.
The property's ageing and "dilapidated and unsafe" structure has been an increasing concern for the council, which engaged a structural engineer in March to determine the work needed to meet its building code and regulations.
The recommendations included fencing off certain sections of the house until they could be rebuilt, and removing sections that were fire-affected and deteriorating.
Mr Prudhoe, who is awaiting hip surgery, told the Leader last week the council was aware he couldn't "physically or financially" carry out any repairs and he would feel "unfairly victimised" if he was told to demolish his house.
The community has rallied around Mr Prudhoe, starting an online fundraising campaign.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Prudhoe, 77</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Ranges Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Prudhoe</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tibetan-themed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boinga Bob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prudhoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warburton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Wastie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
