<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412322728106968</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/driverless-bus-to-be-trialled-at-sydney-olympic-park-20170802-gxnp4e.html</url>
  <title>Driverless bus to be trialled at Sydney Olympic Park</title>
  <content>
Workers at Sydney's Olympic Park will be among the first to use a driverless shuttle bus as part of a two-year trial of autonomous vehicles launched by the state government.
The first stage of the trial starting later this month will involve tests and safety checks of the shuttle bus in an off-road environment at Newington Armoury near the former Olympic village. The vehicle will run autonomously on a pre-programmed route.Photo: Supplied
The trial will be extended next year to roads at Sydney Olympic Park where office workers and other members of the public will get a chance to ride the driverless vehicle.
Transport Minister Andrew Constance said the trial would showcase the government's bigger vision for a technology-enabled transport future in NSW.Photo: Jessica Hromas
"The ultimate goal of the trial is to find the best way to harness the next generation of driverless technology and how to make it work for NSW while also answering questions about how it can improve safety and reliability," he said.
Roads Minister Melinda Pavey said the government wanted to use the trial to develop systems that would allow automated vehicles to be connected to traffic lights and other transport infrastructure, and to the public through devices and applications.

"There is still some way to go before automated shuttles become common place on Australian roads, but as a government we are ready to take the next step and from here all sorts of possibilities open up for transport in NSW," she said.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The NRMA, which is involved in the trial, said the use of autonomous vehicles on the state's roads could save thousands of lives, and reduce crashes and injuries.
The motoring group's chairman, Kyle Loads, said experts had predicted that fully autonomous vehicles could be commercially viable within a decade.
"Autonomous vehicles will bring about tremendous changes in the way we move, with the potential for improved safety and less congestion on our roads," he said.
Driverless bus trials , with the vehicle travelling down a pre-programmed route along the Western Australian capital's foreshore.
The $250,000 bus is capable of carrying 11 people at a top speed of 45km/h and read traffic lights and sense other vehicles. 
A driverless  in January with passengers being transported between popular tourist spots along the city's harbour. 
So far more than 3500 passengers have taken a trip on the bus, although some have expressed surprise that it's still operating under the control of a human driver.
The South Australian government has also of driverless buses at Adelaide Airport and Flinders University. 
The NSW government's Joint Standing Committee on Road Safety held a public inquiry into driverless technology in 2016 to explore whether it would lead to fewer accidents and reduce the road toll.
It recommended trialling the technology and establishing agreed benchmarks for safety.
- With AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roads Minister Melinda Pavey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Standing Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Andrew Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Road Safety</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Hromas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Loads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newington Armoury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
