<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411248986267196</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/warren-entsch-gay-and-lesbian-couples-deserve-marr/3207852/</url>
  <title>Warren Entsch: Gay and lesbian couples deserve to marry</title>
  <content>
IN 2004, when the Parliament made the decision to amend the Marriage Act to exclude gay and lesbian Australians, I stood and told the Liberal Party Room that I didn't understand why we needed to do this.

Hadn't gay and lesbian Australians been through enough? Why did we have to kick them on their way out the door? To me it didn't make sense. Denying any Australian equal status and the same level of dignity is in my mind completely un-Australian.

When the discussion from the Party Room hit the media, I was labelled in one article as a "fiercely heterosexual, Far North Queensland, crocodile-farming, bull-catching Liberal". The question was asked; how could I be an active supporter of gay rights?

The response from those early articles was overwhelming - not so much from the gay community but rather the family and friends of gay Australians. They pointed out that if someone of my background was prepared to support their gay relative or friend, they wanted to come out in support too. I realised at that time the strength of my advocacy.

"I'm absolutely heartbroken to hear the two humpback whales died."
'Teen fed burning hot sauce, punched in face and stomach'
"Nice deal if you can get it!"
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Party Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party Room</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Far North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
