<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411927591109737</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828025/updated-accused-firebug-granted-bail/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>UPDATED: Accused firebug granted bail</title>
  <content>
INFERNO: Kurri Kurri residents observe the smoke from bushfires on January 18. Picture: Simone De Peak

ACCUSED firebug Craig Tamlan Lambkin and his older brother, retained NSW Fire and Rescue firefighter Joshua Lambkin, have been charged over lighting three fires at Kurri Kurri, Loxford and Chinaman's Hollow during a heatwave in January. 
 
The blaze quickly raged out of control and forced the evacuation of homes and the Kurri Kurri Aquatic Centre. 
He was charged with intentionally cause fire and be reckless as to its spread and initially refused bail in Maitland Local Court. 
But after spending about two months in custody, Mr Lambkin was granted bail in the Sydney Supreme Court in March after a supporter agreed to post a $10,000 surety. 
On Tuesday, after an investigation by Strike Force Hingerty detectives, Craig Lambkin and his 28-year-old brother Joshua Lambkin were arrested and charged with multiple counts of intentionally cause fire and be reckless as to its spread. Joshua Lambkin, a retained NSW Fire and Rescue NSW firefighter, was also charged with concealing a serious indictable offence of another person. 
The charges relate to bushfires at Chinaman's Hollow, Hart Road at Loxford and McLeod Road at Kurri Kurri between 1.40pm and 2.14pm on January 18 this year, a day when the temperatures reached 38 degrees.
Joshua Lambkin was granted conditional bail by police to appear in Cessnock Local Court on September 6. 
"Fire & Rescue NSW has been advised that a retained (on-call) firefighter from Abermain has been arrested on arson-related charges," a Fire and Rescue NSW spokesman said.
"The retained firefighter has been suspended."
Meanwhile, police applied for a detention application in relation to Craig Lambkin, seeking to return him to jail.
Court documents show the registrar denied the application because a breach had not been established and continued Craig Lambkin's existing bail.  
EARLIER REPORT:

DETECTIVES have arrested two brothers - including an on-call Fire and Rescue NSW firefighter - over bushfires in the Coalfields.
Joshua Lambkin, 28, was arrested on Hall Street, Weston, and charged with four counts of intentionally causing a fire and concealing a serious indictable offence of another person.

The charges relate to fires on January 18 at Chinamans Hollow, Loxford and Kurri Kurri.
He will front Cessnock Local Court on September 6.
Mr Lambkin's brother, Craig Tamlan Lambkin, 27, will face further charges after being arrested on Tuesday.

Craig Lambkin was charged with an additional three counts of intentionally causing a fire and was refused bail.

He was already facing a charge in relation to a blaze that raged out of control between the Kurri Kurri cemetery and swimming pool on January 24.
The arrests come after the establishment of Strike Force Hingerty, which was formed in the wake of the bushfires, which ran over several weeks and threatened property.
In a statement Fire and Rescue confirmed that the retained Abermain firefighter had been suspended.
"Fire & Rescue NSW (FRNSW) has been advised that a retained (on-call) firefighter from Abermain has been arrested on arson-related charges," a spokesman said.

"The retained firefighter has been suspended.

"This is an ongoing matter for NSW Police and it would be inappropriate for FRNSW to comment any further at this time."

Strike Force detectives are continuing their investigations into the cause of the fires.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Tamlan Lambkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lambkin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abermain</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 18</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 6</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McLeod Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FRNSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Lambkin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hart Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Fire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joshua Lambkin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock Local Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri Aquatic Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Tamlan Lambkin, 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joshua Lambkin, 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rescue NSW</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strike Force Hingerty</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone De Peak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinamans Hollow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Loxford</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
