<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412365677780649</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/moreton/animal-rescue-charity-gets-reprieve-after-being-asked-to-pay-300000-for-road-upgrades/news-story/e5ecaa5a03ed3601e5a96d841b540333</url>
  <title>Animal shelter wins reprieve</title>
  <content>
A STATE Government -request for the Farm Animal Rescue sanctuary at -Dayboro to pay $300,000 for a turning lane from Dayboro Rd into the sanctuary is on hold for the time being.
FAR founder and president Brad King said the group had been advised the Government was going to appoint an independent assessor to look at the issue.
"We are still waiting to see the terms of reference and identity of the assessors," he said.
Mr King thanked the community for the 17,000 signatures of support on an online petition and asked that -advocacy efforts such as -letters and phone calls to ministers be suspended pending the outcome of the assessment.
"While we are not prepared to declare victory, this is a significant step forward," Mr King said. "Your support of this petition has been heard by the Queensland Government and we -believe the future looks a -little brighter.
"In this light, we have suspended the delivery of the petition.
"Clearly they are aware of your support and are working to resolve this dispute."
FAR is a registered charity, sheltering more than 60 animals rescued from abuse, neglect and cruelty, including pigs, goats, cows, fowls, ducks and sheep.
It would have had to ban visitors to the premises if it was forced to pay for the turning lane.
"While we have not yet agreed to terms of reference or the identity of the assessors, we believe that this is indication that Government accepts that their decisions require additional scrutiny," Mr King said.
"At this time we ask that advocacy efforts other than the circulation of this petition, such as letters and telephone calls to Minister's offices and other initiatives be suspended pending the outcome of this assessment."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr King</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farm Animal Rescue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayboro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayboro Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
