<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412318433139636</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/melbourne/crazy-horse-paris-comes-to-melbourne-for-the-first-time/news-story/d99e7760d7e673ccff6e97dcedd1c5fb</url>
  <title>Paris glitz and entertainment</title>
  <content>
IN the glitzy underground world of Crazy Horse Paris costumes fit into shoe boxes, Louboutins line dressing room walls and women dance onstage clothed in nothing but lights.
It has been the 'go-to' evening entertainment for Parisians and the world's biggest stars for the past 65 years.
Beyonce, Elvis Presley, Madonna, President John F. Kennedy, Elizabeth Taylor, Judy Garland, David Bowie, Cyd Charisse, Marlon Brando, and Kylie Minogue are a few who have walked the halls.
Balenciaga, Christian Louboutin, Dita von Teese, Salvador Dali, Paco Rabane and Roberto Cavalli have designed and entertained there.
Now, Australian audiences have the first chance to peak behind the red velvet curtains and see what the fuss is about when Crazy Horse Paris hits town.
Inspired by the endless theme of femininity, Crazy Horse Paris uses light, sound, choreography and fashion to stretch the limits of burlesque in glamorous, kooky, and breathtaking ways. Think Ziegfeld Follies and the Rockettes, but more classy and a lot more French.
Crazy Horse Paris chief creative officer Andree Deissenberg described the show as highly aesthetic.
"It's about lines and curves, the body being art and art being the body. It's about certain heels and not others, certain wigs and colours and not others," Deissenberg says.
"We have very specific ways. The make-up, the costumes, the style, the choreography, the body language, how you move on stage."
These specific ways are heavily influenced by the who's who of fashion. Perched under the shadow of the Eiffel Tower on George V, Crazy Horse Paris' neighbours include Yves Saint Laurent, Givenchy and a host of the hottest new fashion designers. Balenciaga was the first to design the costumes and Christian Louboutin designs the shoes.
Then there is the nudity. From military-like pop-art formations to sensual silhouettes accentuating female forms, 10 statuesque dancers weave through the stage with athleticism and grace more often than not covered only in lights. But this isn't about sex, it's about art, says dancer Enny Gmatic.
"It's a difficult show to explain, the art of nudity where women are dressed in lights," Gmatic says.
"People always smile at you saying 'oh lights, right'. But when you see the show it's a piece of art put in movement.
"Here, the woman is on the pedestal. Women are jewels, the stage is our jewellery box, and the lights are there to make the jewels as magnificent as they can be."
Dancer Gloria di Parma was at first taken aback when her dance teacher suggested the Italian ballet dancer audition but once she saw the show she understood the discipline of the style and felt empowered by the artistry.
"When you see the show you forget about the nudity and become focused on so many other things going on," Di Parma says.
"There's no other show in the world to compare it with."
Behind the scenes it's women responsible for making the jewels sparkle, too. Floor after floor, the building is filled with stylish, vibrant women working together with the cast of over 40 female dancers. In fact, men are a rare sight in Crazy Horse Paris headquarters. Two thirds of the staff are women, especially those in leadership positions. In addition to Deissenberg's artistic leadership, the production manager, in-house costume designer, stage manager, communications, and sales manager are women.
"Women, women, women, women. It's women who drive the business and who are our audience," Deissenberg said.
For 55 years Crazy Horse Paris was permanent in Paris with only locals and tourists getting an inside look, but Deissenberg changed that once taking the reigns, instigating "relentless activity" touring globally.
The Australian tour marks Crazy Horse Paris' true arrival at the other side of the world.
"It's chic debauchery," Deissenberg says.
Crazy Horse Paris. Palms at Crown. August 8-20. Bookings: ticketmaster.com.au
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberto Cavalli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PARMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gloria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ziegfeld Follies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parisian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Minogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yves Saint Laurent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Givenchy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Horse Paris</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marlon Brando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockettes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy Garland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvador Dali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Di Parma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eiffel Towers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyd Charisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enny Gmatic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Bowie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louboutin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Louboutin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paco Rabane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President John F Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gmatic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George V</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madonna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dita</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beyonce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crazy Horse Paris</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andree Deissenberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balenciaga</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elvis Presley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deissenberg</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
