<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411279051038833</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828230/gags-puts-club-before-cup/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Gags puts club before cup</title>
  <content>
FOCUSED: Dane Gagai insists the best way to earn a place in the Australia squad for the World Cup is to finish the season well for the Knights. Picture: AAP

DANE Gagai has learnt never to be satisfied. Ever. 
For the past three years, the Knights centre has shared an Origin dressing room with champions. Johnathan Thurston. Cameron Smith. Greg Inglis. Future immortals.
Gagai was watched their every move. How they prepare. The standards they set. Their burning desire to improve. Nothing is gifted. Everything earned.

Gags puts club before cup

exit
"You are never perfect," Gagai said. "I can assure you that all the great players, do the same thing. Cameron Smith and Johnathan Thurston, they are always looking to improve their game. They are at the elite level and they are still finding ways to get better."
Gagai confirmed in June that he had signed a three-year deal at Souths from 2018. Since then, the Knights have secured Aidan Guerra, Shaun Kenny-Dowall, Connor Watson, Tautau Moga and Herman Ese'ese. They had already tied up Cowboy Kalyn Ponga. The biggest game-changer is the likely takeover of the club by Wests. But the 26-year-old harbours no regrets about his move.

"It is great that Wests has jumped on board," Gagai said. "I'm really glad that has happened. Also a few key signings. The future is looking bright. I made my decision and that is it."
Before next season, is the World Cup. Given Gagai's heroics for the Maroons - he was awarded the Wally Lewis medal for player of the series - he could be forgiven for looking ahead to the 14-team tournament. 

That is where the Origin experience and influence of the Maroons great kicks in.

"It is something every footy player dreams of; representing your country," Gagai said. "You get in those reps side by performing for your club. I was fortunate enough to go through the Origin period. Now that is behind me, my focus is back on the Knights. If I was thinking about anything else, I'd be letting these boys down."

A quad injury hindered Gagai's chances of selection for the Kangaroos' successful Four Nations campaign at the end of last season, with outsides back Josh Ferguson, Valentine Holmes, Justin O'Neil and Josh Mansour getting the nod. Holmes and Ferguson with retained for the Anzac test in May. O'Neil was 20th man. Mansour tore the anterior cruciate ligament in his knee at Four Nations.

Gagai, in three games for the Knights since the Origin decider, has scored a try, carried the ball an average of 140 metres and topped the tackle busts. It would seem only injury could deny him a coveted Test jersey.

"I just want to finish the year off on a high with the Knights," Gagai said. "For me it is just about getting back here and doing my job."

If Gagai, as expected, is named in Australian squad, he is likely to encounter plenty of his Newcastle teammates.
Mata'utia brothers Sione and Peter were members of the Samoan team which went down to England in May. Saifiti twins Daniel and Jacob have represented Fiji for the past three seasons and were two of the Bati's best in a loss to Tonga mid year. 
Shaun Kenny-Dowall has 29 appearances for New Zealand and along with Danny Levi is in the frame.
England- bound prop Mickey Paea has played 12 tests for Tonga, the last of which of 2013.
Joe Wardle could feature in the England, as could reborn halfback Trent Hodkinson, who qualifies through his father.
Daniel Saifiti, who has been the Knights most consistent forward, is excited at the prospect.

"For the mid-season test, all the Fiji boys bonded so well as soon as we got into camp," Saifiti said. "Straight after it, Jacob and I we were talking about the World Cup. There will be a few Knights involved. It will be good for all of us to get experience and play against good teams. I have never played against Australia, New Zealand and England. I can't wait to play against them. It will be good for our development." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroons</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tautau Moga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sione</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Inglis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Gagai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DANIEL Saifiti</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mansour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Hodkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferguson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan Thurston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aidan Guerra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cowboy Kalyn Ponga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor Watson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Mansour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herman Ese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentine Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Nations</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bati</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mickey Paea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiji</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin O'Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Wardle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saifiti</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gagai</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Kenny-Dowall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Levi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tonga</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
