<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411626943395108</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/federal-politics/political-news/all-im-asking-for-is-to-have-a-bloody-vote-liberal-mp-warren-entsch-20170802-gxnomk.html</url>
  <title>'All I'm asking for is to have a bloody vote': Liberal MP Warren Entsch has had enough</title>
  <content>
Warren Entsch has had enough.
The long-time Queensland Liberal MP has called out colleagues for "ratcheting up the bullshit" over a push for a free vote on same-sex marriage, without having "the balls to actually put their names to it", while daring the LNP to dis-endorse him over his views.

Up Next

Tent city inappropriate: Berejiklian

00:34

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Same sex marriage division

Coalition MPs are considering crossing the floor to make sure same sex marriage is legalised in Australia, and conservatives are unimpressed.

A civil war has broken out within the government following Liberal senator Dean Smith's announcement he had drafted a private members' bill for same-sex marriage that could be put to the Parliament as early as this month.
Four Liberal MPs, including Mr Entsch, Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson and Trent Zimmerman have indicated they could cross the floor on the issue. That's sparked a rush of condemnation from more conservative MPs, who have switched to pushing for a postal plebiscite. The on-going debate has led to reports from government MPs, speaking anonymously, that those attempting to force a free vote could face pre-selection challenges.

"I read about that, I read about threats from the Prime Minister, I read about the Prime Minister calling me and Dean and - all information comes from anonymous sources," Mr Entsch said.
"They haven't got the balls to actually put their names to it.

"And all fairness and accuracy, the Prime Minister has not called me. Not at all. His office hasn't called up.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"These guys spread this sort of nonsense; they get personal on this sort of stuff.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
"And if they had the balls like we had, to stand up and state our position and be accountable of it - then it goes to the level of individual that they are."
Queensland LNP president Gary Spence  to supporters on Tuesday, expressing "disappointment" that "members elected under the LNP banner have chosen to take a position that defies LNP policy and the wishes of the LNP's membership", in what is being seen as a warning shot to Queensland MPs Mr Evans and Mr Entsch over their public support for a free vote.Photo: Andrew Meares
Mr Entsch said he was "disgusted" with the letter - and rang Mr Spence to tell him so.
I think it is [a threat] a veiled threat," Mr Entsch said.Photo: Alex Ellinghausen
"I am disgusted with it and I reminded him I am a Liberal, I am not an LNP member in the national parliament and there are lots and lots of [resolutions] that go through the state, which are different to the federal resolutions and - which one do you take?
"They are there as a guide. They are not there to lock you in and if we wanted that, we would have joined the Labor Party.
"I just said to him [Gary Spence] that I think it is particularly galling that this sort of message goes out to members who have only been around for a short time - it does intimidate them and I think it is wrong, it is absolutely wrong," he said.
There were better ways to handle the debate, Mr Entsch said, particularly given how long Australia had been having it.
"All I am asking for is to have a bloody vote," he said.
"Many of my colleagues have asked for that and I have accommodated, or facilitated their right to have a vote, even though I might have voted on the other side, I gave them the opportunity to have a vote out of respect.
"I am not asking them to change their vote, I am not asking them - they can abstain! I am just asking to have a vote and I think whatever the outcome of that vote I am more than happy to abide by that decision."
Mr Turnbull has not ruled out holding a postal plebiscite as a way of deciding the issue.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Spence</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland LNP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Liberal MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland MPs Mr Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ellinghausen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
