<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412447282160692</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/work/at-work/record-660000-fine-for-former-fruit-market-operator-who-paid-afghan-refugee-as-little-as-350-an-hour/news-story/b8fef159d851783e66765c284d6288d4</url>
  <title>Record $660,000 fine for former fruit market operator who paid Afghan refugee as little as $3.50 an hour</title>
  <content>
The worker was underpaid a total of $25,588.

Share

THE former owner of a Melbourne fruit market has been slapped with a record $660,000 penalty for paying an Afghan refugee as little as $3.50 an hour.
The worker was also not provided with the required meal breaks, despite sometimes working more than 12 hours a day, according to the Fair Work Ombudsman.
Abdulrahman Taleb, who owned and operated the Sunshine Fruit Market in Sunshine, has been fined $16,020 and his company Mhoney Pty Ltd has been fined $644,000 in the Federal Circuit Court.
It's the largest penalty ever achieved as the result of Fair Work Ombudsman litigation. The previous record was held by a NSW  and even "kill" foreign workers.
The court found Mr Taleb deliberately ignored warnings about required pay rates and did not pay the worker any wages for weeks at a time in early 2012. He was later paid a flat rate of $10 an hour to a maximum of $120 per day for moving and stacking fruit and vegetables.
Under the General Retail Industry Award 2010, he should have been paid hourly rates of about $17 for normal hours, up to $35 on weekends and up to $43 on public holidays. He was underpaid a total of $25,588 for two two-month periods of work in 2012 and 2013.
The refugee, who spoke little English, initially came to Australia as an asylum seeker and spent time in detention before being granted Australian residency and released in late 2010.
"[The worker] was a vulnerable employee in that he was a recent arrival to Australia and totally lacked fluency in English, and could reasonably be understood to be most unlikely to be aware of any entitlements at law," Judge Philip Burchardt said.
"The underpayments were so significant that the total not paid to [the worker] was, in relative terms, enormous for such a short time. Furthermore, for some of the time [he] was simply not paid at all.

"I accept the submission of the [Ombudsman] that the way it worked out was that [the worker] was paid wages of between $3.49 and $9.29 per hour. This was an egregious underpayment. It gave the respondents an unfair advantage in the competitive retail industry."
Fair Work Ombudsman Natalie James said the record penalties "highlight how seriously the courts take unlawful behaviour which involves workers being taken advantage of and stripped of minimum wages and entitlements".
"We have no sympathy for employers, as in this case, who arrogantly ignore direct advice from my agency about their wage obligations and exploit vulnerable members of the community in order to obtain a commercial advantage," she said.
The Court ruled that Mr Taleb will be personally liable for back-paying the worker more than $6500 if his company fails to do so.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furthermore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General Retail Industry Award 2010</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Philip Burchardt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Work Ombudsman Natalie James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mhoney Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Taleb</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ombudsman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Fruit Market</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Circuit Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Ombudsman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdulrahman Taleb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
