<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412447282160652</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/james-sicily-trails-only-alex-rance-as-afls-most-prolific-interceptor-20170731-gxm8va.html</url>
  <title>James Sicily trails only Alex Rance as AFL's most prolific interceptor</title>
  <content>
James Sicily has been the AFL's second-most prolific intercept player since he moved to the back line, only narrowly trailing Richmond champion Alex Rance. 
Sicily - who moved into the Hawks' back line in round 14 after playing the first part of the season as a forward - has had 55 intercept possessions between rounds 14 and 19, according to Champion Data. 

Up Next

Sam Mitchell retires

02:57

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

Rance is the only player in the AFL to have had more intercept possessions (58) than Sicily in the same period. 
Sicily is also leading Carlton's Liam Jones, the former Bulldog who has stunned the AFL with his performances in the Blues' back line since round 12, and Essendon's Michael Hurley. Photo: AAP
Sicily had nine intercept possessions in the Hawks' win over Sydney on Friday night, a game high. He also took three intercept marks. 
Intercept possessions are defined as any possessions that break an opposition ball-movement chain. They also include intercept marks (marks taken from an opposition kick).

Overall Hawthorn have scored 56 points from Sicily's intercept possessions between rounds 14 and 19, the most in the AFL.

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Sicily also ranks No.1 in the league for intercept marks (25) over the period, eighth for disposals inside the defensive 50 (59) and equal first for most contested marks inside defensive 50 with St Kilda's Jake Carlisle (7). Photo: AFL Media
The 22-year-old's transformation has come at the same time as the Hawks have surged into finals contention. 
After beating the in-form Sydney on Friday night Alastair Clarkson's side sit 12th on the ladder, only six points out of the top eight.
To make the finals the Hawks are likely to need to win all their remaining 2017 clashes against Richmond, North Melbourne, Carlton and the Western Bulldogs.
Hawthorn was in crisis after six rounds of the 2017 season. They had one win up until that point and only three more before their round 13 bye. 
But since the break they've won four of six games (Adelaide, Collingwood, Fremantle, Sydney), drawn one (GWS) and lost one (Geelong). 
The turnaround in form has been remarkable, as has the coaching effort by Clarkson. 
Moving Sicily and Jack Gunston into the back line have been critical moves in the Hawks' revival given Ben Stratton, Grant Birchall, James Frawley and Josh Gibson have missed large parts of the season through injury and form. 
Cyril Rioli, Paul Puopolo, Jaeger O'Meara and Jonathon Ceglar are also out and have been for much of the season. 
On the impact of Sicily's intercept possessions, an AFL opposition analyst told Fairfax Media it was crucial in the Hawks' post-bye revival. 
"Intercept possessions have always been gold. Hawthorn highly value it because they lose contests in the middle of the ground," he said. 
"It would correlate with Hawthorn's scoring chains starting out of the back half. The fact that they lose midfield contests and clearances a lot means they can rely on intercepting.
"If you know you're poor in an area of the ground or you're not heavy on contested ball players you can set up to intercept ... that's why Gunston and Sicily are pretty important to them playing as defenders."
The analyst also said Hawthorn's small forwards played a crucial role in helping the team capitalise on interceptions. 
"Hawthorn play pretty high so they try and get numbers back to support the defence and then 'slingshot' you," he said. 
"Their small forwards, like Luke Breust, then become pretty important in giving them a link from defence to attack." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyril Rioli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda's Jake Carlisle (7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathon Ceglar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Rance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Puopolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clarkson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sicily</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jaeger O'Meara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Liam Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champion Data</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Stratton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Frawley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Birchall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Sicily</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Gibson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gunston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Breust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Gunston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alastair Clarkson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon's Michael Hurley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
