<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411669893068581</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/gateway-motorway-road-rage-heke-merrigan/8758772</url>
  <title>Brisbane road rage death: Fatal punch thrown after 'tailgating, cursing', court hears</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

A man accused of punching another driver who fell into the path of an oncoming garbage truck says he lashed out after being tailgated and cursed at on a busy Brisbane motorway.
Tamate Henry Heke has pleaded not guilty to the manslaughter of Shane Merrigan, who was hit by the truck at a busy merge on the Gateway Motorway at Rochedale in December 2015.
A police interview with Heke recorded on the night of Mr Merrigan's death was played to the jury in which he told officers he was driving home from a 12-hour shift.

"A car came up tailgating me," Heke said in the video.
"I moved into the left lane, he moved into left lane ... he was pulling hand gestures."
When asked by Detective Senior Constable Benjamin Henderson how close the motorist was driving, Heke replied: "I couldn't even see the bonnet."
He told officers he did not know what Mr Merrigan's problem was, expect that maybe he was going too slow.
The court heard both men pulled over to the side of the busy motorway.
"He got out of his car, he was cursing at me, I was cursing at him," Heke told police.
"He took a swing, he slapped me on my face.
"I hit him back, he fell on the road.
"I tried to catch him."

'A jab to make him back off'

Heke was originally charged with murder, but that was dismissed and replaced with manslaughter and unlawful striking.
The New Zealander described the punch as a "jab" in the interview and told police Mr Merrigan had hit him first.
"What did you mean to happen when you threw that punch?" Senior Constable Henderson asked.
"Just for him to back off," Heke replied.
Senior Constable Henderson asked: "Did you want to be in a physical fight with him?"
Heke replied: "No."
Heke has chosen not to give evidence at his trial.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heke</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Senior Constable Benjamin Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merrigan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gateway Motorway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Merrigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tamate Henry Heke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constable Henderson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rochedale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
