<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412442987193333</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/motorsport/formula-one/nico-hulkenbergs-jab-at-kevin-magnussen-wannabe-verstappen/news-story/58c7988a8fa5383fc5e896daeeaeed12</url>
  <title>Nico Hulkenberg's jab at Kevin Magnussen: 'Wannabe Verstappen'</title>
  <content>
Magnussen tells Hulkenberg to 'Suck my balls honey'
0:36

Formula 1: Magnussen tells Hulkenberg to 'Suck my balls'.

July 31st 2017
2 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/Motorsport/

Kevin Magnussen is a 'Verstappen wannabe', according to Nico Hulkenberg.

Share

THE Hungarian Grand Prix gave us a selection of cringe-worthy encounters as drivers stood over their own kin to get ahead.
Red Bull had a weekend to forget after young gun Max Verstappen rammed into Daniel Ricciardo on the first lap, sending the Aussie spirraling out of the race with a puncture.
"Someone hit me. If that's who I think it was, that's f***!" Ricciardo yelled as he stopped in the middle of the track.
Then it was Kevin Magnussen and Nico Hulkenberg's turn to swap barbs.
The two drivers' rivalry reached tipping point as Magnussen thwarted his older opponent with a "ruthless" play late in the race.
Hulkenberg found himself stuck behind 11th-placed Magnussen in the closing stage, having dropped back with a slow pit stop then caught up quickly on fresher tyres.
With nine laps to go, Hulkenberg attempted a pass around the outside of the tight Turn 2 left-hander but was forced onto the grass in a move that earned Magnussen a five-second time penalty.
During the post-race television interviews, Hulkenberg approached Magnussen and sarcastically commended him for being "once again the most unsporting driver".
Magnussen replied: "Suck my b****, mate."

Speaking to NBC after the spat, Hulkenberg said: "I congratulated him for being the most unsporting driver of the whole grid once again. When it comes to racing, he's just nasty."
From there, the drivers' spat seemed to be over until the Belgian Grand Prix later this month.
But with more than three weeks between now and lights-out at Spa, it appears the Hulk wants to keep his rival busy.

Kevin Magnussen is fuelling a lot of top-tier F1 banter.Source:Getty Images

Nico Hulkenberg thinks Kevin Magnussen is a Verstappen wannabe.Source:Getty Images
.
"I wish there were as many people talking about the race," he said. "At the moment we have different challenges in Formula 1 than the balls of a wannabe Verstappen.
"I'm not the kind of guy to curry favour with the public after the race, and I don't need to insult someone. If I have a problem with somebody, I go ahead and say what's on my mind."
Hulkenberg said such rivalries are what bring fans to the sport, claiming "sensitive" drivers exploding at each other added to the fun of high-speed racing
"But the fans are happy about seeing a sport in which competition is being lived and somebody is speaking his mind," he said.
"This is the fun thing about F1, especially with hot-headed sensitive people.
"With Kevin it's like having a little brother. You know he is not able to defend himself in any other way. Therefore, it's easy to take his remarks with a smile on your face."
MERCEDES' 'PERFECT' MOMENT

Cute.Source:Getty Images
Newly appointed Mercedes driver Valtteri Bottas had a lot to think about when joining forces with the unpredictable Lewis Hamilton for the 2017 season. But he was reassured he'd made the right choice after a telling gesture over the weekend.
Hamilton wowed fans at Hungarian Grand Prix after allowing Bottas take back third place on the final lap, sacrificing his own place on the podium and recurring the Finn he had the respect of the former champion.
"It was a perfect example of what you can do when you have that trust, when you have that respect within teammates," he told Motorsport.com.
"The team can really rely on both of you to try things like this today. It's only going to get better."
Bottas admitted he was worried they would run out of time to do the switch as they rapidly approached the line.
"I think when it was two laps to go I asked: 'When are we going to do the swap?'" he said.
"The team said that I just have to get a bit of a gap to Max and we'll do it at the end, and so we did. I was trusting the team. They told me at the beginning that if I let him go and he can't do it, we'll swap. When the team say something like that, it's going to happen.
"Max was not far behind with a fresh set of tyres, so that made it even more tricky. We managed to do it in the end. I'm really glad."

It could have very easily been Hamilton on the podium.Source:Getty Images
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perfect Moment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magnussen</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Getty Images</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hulkenberg</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Ricciardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Formula 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turn 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valtteri Bottas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Verstappen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Magnussen</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Verstappen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hulks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hungarian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgian Grand Prix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bottas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricciardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nico Hulkenberg</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
