<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412404332487013</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/nsw-racing/barry-humphries-adds-star-power-to-lowkey-warwick-farm-meeting/news-story/84f07dfcdb0c59f858d2ab0254ace783</url>
  <title>Humphries out of luck on trip to Farm</title>
  <content>
COMEDIAN Barry Humphries has been cast in a supporting role as his wife attended her first horse racing meeting as an owner on Wednesday.
The international comedy star accompanied wife Lizzie Spender in the Warwick Farm mounting yard to watch Dante Rossetti, a three-year-old she part-owns, make his debut.
THURSDAY PREVIEW:
It was a dream come true for Spender, who grew up in London wishing of owning a hobby horse and being fascinated with racing. But for Humphries going to the races was a new experience.
"My wife loves horses, she rescues horses from the outback, some beautiful brumbies and I've come around to them," he said.
The 83-year-old doesn't describe himself as a betting man but admitted to having a flutter on his wife's $61 outsider. "I gamble on myself and I always win but anything else not so lucky," he joked.
His statement proved to be on the money. Dante Rossetti, trained by Gai Waterhouse and Adrian Bott, led from the gate but faded in the straight to beat one runner to the finishing post.
Meanwhile, some advice from her boss Gai Waterhouse convinced Rachel King to stand down from riding for the day following an early fall at Warwick Farm.
The apprentice jockey took a tumble just past the winning post after her mount in the first race, Puppet Master, was tightened up between Piracy and second- placed Ah Mah Haha.
King had no more than grass stains on her silks and told stewards she remained keen to take up her two remaining rides. But a chat with Waterhouse changed her mind.
"On Gai's recommendation, she didn't want me to keep riding for the rest of the day, just to make sure I'm right for the rest of the week," King said. "I was a little bit winded when I first got up but I feel fine. "Gai said when things like that happen it can snowball a bit so you're better off to step down and concentrate on the rest of the week."
She had two more rides at Warwick Farm and will be back in action at Hawkesbury on Thursday, where she has two bookings.
A stewards' inquiry into the race, won by the James Cummings-trained Piracy, is expected later on Wednesday.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>THURSDAY PREVIEW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Farm</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cummings-trained Piracy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dante Rossetti</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Humphries</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawkesbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waterhouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Humphries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gai Waterhouse</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gai</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Bott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ah Mah Haha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lizzie Spender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
