<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412404332487024</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/sydney-swans/sydney-swans-firebrand-zak-jones-vows-to-play-hard-despite-suspension-threat-20170802-gxnr08.html</url>
  <title>Swans firebrand vows to play hard despite suspension threat</title>
  <content>
Sydney firebrand Zak Jones says he will not be tempering his aggression despite being on the brink of an untimely suspension.
The Swans' commitment to playing "on the edge" was borne out of necessity after their terrible start to the season and although they are back in the premiership race it has not come without cost.Photo: AAP
Superstar forward and Jones are walking the tightrope with the match review panel after being fined twice this season. A third financial sanction for a classifiable offence would result in a one-match suspension irrespective of how minor it was.
The threat hangs over them for the rest of the year as a suspension would not reset their record. The cost of any ban would be magnified if it was to fall in September, though every game for the Swans is crucial if they are to keep their place in the eight.

Hawthorn star Luke Hodge fell victim to the rule this week when he unsuccessfully challenged a one-match ban for a strike on Sydney's Tom Papley. In isolation, the hit was worthy of only a fine but as Hodge had two priors he had to miss.
Jones has already felt the wrath of the MRP when he was rubbed out for a game for . He later .

However, he insists he will not change the way he plays.
"You're definitely aware how close you are to the line - a lot of players do push the line a bit but that's football," Jones said.
"You have to play hard and you can't shirk away from a contest. It's big to play on the line, I think every club wants their players to play on the line.
"We play on the line and we play a hard brand of contested ball."
Jones is off the market after signing a two-year contract extension that ties him to the Swans until the end of 2019.
The speedy 22-year-old has made big strides in the past two years to become a regular first-choice player for the red and the white.
There had been several Victorian clubs courting Jones, whose brother Nathan plays with Melbourne.
"I've spoken to him a fair bit about it. It would have been great to play with my brother," Jones said. "I'm my own player and I want to be my own player."
Jones said he wanted to be loyal to the club that secured him with pick 15 in the 2013 draft.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
