<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412404332486988</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/16/19/future-is-now-for-driverless-buses-in-sydney</url>
  <title>Future is now for driverless buses in Sydney</title>
  <content>
Young people could soon no longer need a drivers licence with Sydney's first driverless vehicle trial on the way, the NSW Minister for Transport has said.
The two-year trial will take place around Sydney Olympic Park, with a fully-automated shuttle transporting 12 passengers in and around the precinct.
"Today we drive our cars but the reality is, cars will soon drive us and while we are not there yet, we need to be prepared for this change and we need to stay ahead of the game," Minister Andrew Constance said.
The "Smart Shuttle" runs off a mixture of Telstra's 4G and 3G Network, wireless networks and laser technology.
The technology is heavily encrypted to defend itself from cyber-attacks, and sensors around the vehicle can detect pedestrians and obstacles which forces the vehicle to stop.
"There is still some way to go before automated shuttles become common place on Australian roads," Minister for Roads Melinda Pavey said.
"But as a government, we are ready to take the next step and from here all sorts of possibilities open up for transport in New South Wales," Minister Pavey said.

Related Articles

The National Roads and Motorists' Association (NRMA) hopes that in a decade with more driverless cars on the road, accidents and deaths will dramatically decrease.
"94 percent of accidents are caused by human error. Drug driving, drink driving and speeding. In the future that will be no more." NRMA President Kyle Loades said.
Legislation has been introduced to parliament to allow an exemption for this trial to take place.
The government is hoping to see this driverless technology rolled out into the public transport network too.
"The state is going to see its first fully automated driverless train in 2019," Minister Pavey said.
There are still issues being worked out around insurance, liability and the commercial viability of these kind of vehicles taking over manually driven vehicles on our roads.
"We can't stop doing good things with the fear of the unknown," Minister Pavey added.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smart Shuttle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra's 4G</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Motorists' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>G Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Roads</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRMA President Kyle Loades</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roads Melinda Pavey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Andrew Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Pavey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
