<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412447282160741</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/retail/surfstitch-shareholders-back-chairman-but-legal-battles-continue-20170801-gxnbjd</url>
  <title>SurfStitch shareholders back chairman but legal battles continue </title>
  <content>
SurfStitch's second largest shareholder and spurned suitor Crown Financial Group has lost its bid to unseat the company's chairman, Sam Weiss, amid an increasingly bitter legal battle.
Shareholders in the embattled online surf and skate retailer overwhelmingly voted on Wednesday against Crown Financial's proposal to remove Mr Weiss from the board.
Proxies received before the extraordinary general meeting requisitioned by Crown showed that only 10.87 per cent of shares voted were in favour of the Crown proposal and 88.9 per cent against.
Only 8.22 per cent of shares voted in the poll taken during the EGM were in favour of the resolution. The outcome of the poll raises questions about whether Crown, which owns 10.3 per cent, voted its shares at all or voted against its own resolution.

Louie Douvis

Crown, led by managing director Kim Sundell, had claimed SurfStitch's performance since Mr Weiss' appointment had been catastrophic and his tenure had been marked by board dysfunction, inconsistent strategy, ongoing losses, the sale of assets at significant losses and the decimation of the share price.

"There was fraud going on inside the company that you were aware of," Mr Sundell told the EGM.
"(The board) knew about the wrongdoings of previous directors and the wrong doings (of advisers), which I find staggering, and you try to demonise us about your failings. Since you've been involved the company has lurched from bad decision to bad decision," Mr Sundell said.
However, the board rejected Crown's assertions and advised shareholders to vote against the proposal, saying Mr Weiss's removal would be detrimental to the company.
SurfStitch said Mr Weiss and other new directors were all appointed after a series of events which led to big writedowns and operating losses and which triggered litigation with Crown, two class actions and an ongoing ASIC investigation.

Mr Weiss also defended his performance, saying he agreed to join the board at the behest of worried shareholders and had dealt with the challenges created by the legal actions, a failed content deal with Crown and other missteps by previous management "to the best of our abilities."
"I was under no illusions about the degree of difficulty of the task ahead," Mr Weiss said.
"The contested contracts (with Crown) and the manner in which they were handled and communicated prior to June 2016 link all of the significant challenges now faced by the company. The current board, led by me - each of us, including our CEO, appointed after the relevant periods and events associated with the contested contracts - continue to manage these challenges to the best of our abilities," he said.
"In the face of the adversity the contested contracts have caused ... the board continues to do everything in its power to preserve value where possible in our businesses."

Mr Weiss also defended the fact he does not own shares in SurfStitch. "Since the day I've been involved I've had privileged information that has precluded me from spending a dollar on shares. That continues today."
Mr Weiss told The Australian Financial Review that settling the class actions was a priority for the company, which is also considering selling more assets.
Proxy adviser CGI Glass Lewis had also advised shareholders to vote against the Crown proposal and questioned the publishing group's motivation in calling for Mr Weiss's removal.
The Crown group launched legal action against SurfStitch last year over the failed content deal agreed with former chief executive Justin Cameron, who resigned abruptly last April after the first of a series of profit downgrades.

SurfStitch is defending Crown's claims and has countersued, alleging Crown affiliates were involved in alleged breaches of statutory and directors duties by Mr Cameron, including the content deal.
SurfStitch shares were suspended in May after losing two-thirds of their value in 12 months, falling from 20¢ to 6.8¢, a fraction of their December 2014 issue price of $1 - cementing the company's reputation as the worst float for many years.
Crown acquired its 10.3 per cent stake after SurfStitch announced in June last year the reversal of $20 million in revenues associated with the content deal.
Crown stepped up the pressure on SurfStitch last October, making a conditional 20¢ a share takeover offer, but it was rejected by the board.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Weiss</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sundell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CGI Glass Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SurfStitch</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Financial Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Sundell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EGM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Financial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Weiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
