<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412442987193313</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/donald-trump-says-boy-scouts-speech-was-greatest-ever/8767466</url>
  <title>Donald Trump: Boy Scouts reportedly unsure who told President speech was 'greatest ever'</title>
  <content>
The Boy Scouts of America have reportedly said they are unaware who told Donald Trump his controversial speech to thousands of members was "the greatest speech that was ever made to them".

Key points:

Trump attacked "fake news" and political rivals in address to Scouts
Head of Boy Scouts issued apology "to those in our Scouting family who were offended"
President said day after speech that Scouts "loved it"

Last week, the  that included attacks on "fake news", political rivals, Congress, former president Barack Obama and a threat to sack his Health Secretary.
The tone of the speech attracted widespread criticism and prompted chief Scout executive Michael Surbaugh at the weekend to offer his "sincere apologies to those in our Scouting family who were offended by the political rhetoric that was inserted into the jamboree".
"That was never our intent," he said.
"The invitation for the sitting US president to visit the National Jamboree is a long-standing tradition that has been extended to the leader of our nation that has had a Jamboree during his term since 1937. It is in no way an endorsement of any person, party or policies.
"We sincerely regret that politics were inserted into the Scouting program."
Despite the Scouts' apology and widespread criticism of the speech, a transcript of an interview Mr Trump gave to the Wall Street Journal the day after the address reveals the President claimed the Scouts "loved it".
He rejected journalist Gerard Baker's characterisation of the response to the speech as "mixed".
"They loved it. [Laughter.] It wasn't - it was no mix," he said, according to the transcript released by Politico.
"I got a call from the head of the Boy Scouts, saying it was the greatest speech that was ever made to them, and they were very thankful."
When asked by Time Magazine about the message to Mr Trump, the organisation said it was not aware of any call from the national leadership team.
"The chief Scout executive's message to the Scouting community speaks for itself," Scouts told Time.
Scouts ready for 'political' speech, prepared guidelines

Last week,  and had given adult staff "stringent guidelines" about how to react to the US President's rhetoric.

External Link:

Donald J Trump Facebook post about address to Scouts
"Do I wish the President hadn't gone there and hadn't been political? Of course," he said last week.
"Anyone knows his speeches get highly political - we anticipated that this could be the case."
The guidelines given to staff reminded them, "chants of certain phrases heard during the campaign - [e.g. 'build the wall,' 'lock her up'] are considered divisive by many members of our audience, and may cause unnecessary friction between individuals and units".
"Please help us ensure that all Scouts can enjoy this historical address by making sure that your troop members are respectful not only of the President, but of the wide variety of viewpoints held by Scouts and Scouters in the audience," the guidelines said.
former US presidents traditionally avoided making highly political statements in their speeches.

External Link:

Former US president George W Bush addresses Scouts in 2005

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street Journal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy Scouts of America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Surbaugh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scouters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Politico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Jamboree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George W. Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boy Scout</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerard Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Secretary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Time Magazine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald J Trump Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scout</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
