<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411373540320876</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/forget-the-selfie-rachel-griffiths-speaks-out-against-slavery-20170802-gxnmf3.html</url>
  <title>Rachel Griffiths wants Australians to dump the orphanage selfie</title>
  <content>
While most Australians are familiar with her work on screen, Rachel Griffiths has been chipping away at another project for years: helping to dismantle the modern day slave trade. 
On Wednesday, the Academy Award nominee fronted a Senate inquiry urging politicians to legislate a modern day slavery act. 

Up Next

Alanis Morissette to tour Aus

01:18

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Entertainment news highlights

Bitchiness on The Bachelor, Dr G Yunupingu's marvelous career, talk shows take on Trump's transgender ban, fans' anger at Australian Ninja Warrior and Ringo and Paul back together again.

"It's the right time," she told the federal MPs. "Please, seize this moment." 
During the hearing, the 48-year-old pleaded with federal MPs to cast aside their differences and ensure Australia becomes a world leader when it comes to cracking down on the 45 million people around the world living a life of servitude. Photo: JOE CASTRO
Griffiths is the patron of Hagar, a charity that has helped rescue more than 15,000 women from the modern day slave trade.
She cited the recent travel ban on convicted paedophiles as an example of how Australia can make fast, practical changes to its laws to help children in places as far flung as rural Cambodia.  

"Unfortunately, human rights has become controversial," she said. "We're often distracted by human rights issues as reported in the tabloid press about a prisoner not getting soft enough toilet paper. The number one human rights [issue] in the world today is trafficking and slavery and we have to disrupt it."
In particular, Griffiths called on businesses to examine their supply chains and for the federal government to ensure it didn't procure goods and services from places that abused human rights.Photo: JOE CASTRO
She said there is an immense focus on sex slavery because of its salacious nature, but forced labour is in fact the most common form of modern slavery and the second most widespread crime around the world.
The Muriel's Wedding star also called on Australians to put an end to the orphanage "selfie moment".
"Vulnerable children should not be visited without training," she said. "I have nothing for respect and compassion for the empathy of others. [But] we know in developed countries institutions are not the place for children to grow up."
Griffiths said most orphanages operating in South East Asia are not registered, which puts the children at significant risk. 
"Unfortunately it can feel good to have 50 children come and hug you and you could walk away thinking you've done good," she said. "If you really analyse the facts ... that's not true."
However, the actress remains optimistic Australian's attitude to overseas orphanages will change over time. 
"I don't expect anything to happen fast, but sometimes cultural change can be enormously swift," she said. "Marriage equality is, I think, a really great example in generational change happening quickly. I grew up not using the word slavery except in a historical context, and that's [now] changed."
The parliamentary inquiry into modern slavery is due to submit its interim report in September. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Griffiths</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambodia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Academy Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hagar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffiths</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr G. Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitchiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muriel's Wedding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JOE CASTRO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-east Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alanis Morissette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
