<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412279778433190</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/business/wine-grape-prices-hit-their-best-level-in-eight-years-in-a-boon-for-our-growers/news-story/0b9292a0305846555c41d161c6f0a26c</url>
  <title>Grape growers toast a bumper harvest</title>
  <content>
WINE grape prices have hit their best level since 2008 putting almost another $80 million in the pockets of South Australian growers.
The Australian wine sector posted its third consecutive increase in crush and the average purchase price of winegrapes for this year's harvest, according to the National Vintage Report 2017.
Importantly demand and supply are also in balance, with a surge in exports soaking up the extra grape production.
The figures released yesterday show estimated the national crush at 1.93 million tonnes - an increase of 5 per cent from the 2016 vintage - and the national average purchase price increased by 7 per cent $565 per tonne - the highest since 2008.
The total estimated value for the 2017 vintage was $1.22 billion, an increase of 13 per cent from $1.08 billion in 2016.
In South Australia the estimated value of the crush was $658 million in 2017 compared with $581 million in 2016, Wine Australia figures show.
The average purchase value per tonne across the state increased by 8 per cent from $631 in 2016 to $680 per tonne in 2017.
The higher value of the SA crush reflects the higher value of varieties such as shiraz, cabernet sauvignon and chardonnay in SA.
Wine Australia chief executive Andreas Clark said, "the increases reflect excellent seasonal conditions in many regions as well as the growing demand for Australian wine, both in export and domestic markets.
"Pleasingly, the figures from the National Vintage Report indicate that the supply and demand for Australian wine is in balance.
"An additional 93,000 tonnes were crushed this year, which produces approximately an additional 65 million litres of wine.
"This is in line with increased demand for Australian wine: in 2016-17, exports increased by 50 million litres, and domestic sales increased by 12 million litres in 2015-16, a total of 62 million litres.''
Winemakers' Federation of Australia chief executive Tony Battaglene said: "There is a cautious optimism being echoed across the Australian wine sector.
"Export value overall has been on the rise and it is great to see the consecutive increases in exports matched by the increases in key vintage figures.''
Reflecting the success, particularly in China, of South Australian and Australian reds, 12 per cent of red wine grapes were purchased at $1500 per tonne or above in 2017, while 71 per cent were purchased at below $600 per tonne.
"Shiraz was the biggest driver in the overall increase in the average purchase price as the share of shiraz purchased at A and B grades increased from 13.3 per cent in 2016 to 15.5 per cent in 2017, which is double the proportion from five years ago,'' the Report says.
The report can be found .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shiraz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andreas Clark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Vintage Report 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China, of South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Vintage Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Battaglene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
