<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411279051038793</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/offers-flood-in-to-save-highbury-alpacas-handed-eviction-notice-by-tea-tree-gully-council/news-story/4a3a15d32c298b94d991701279584568</url>
  <title>Offers rush in to save evicted alpacas</title>
  <content>
TWO Highbury alpacas handed an eviction notice by the local council are now spoiled for choice for a new home, with more than 100 offers coming in from animal-lovers across the state.
The NorthEastern Weekly revealed yesterday Highbury resident Jodi Hume had to find a new home for Leonardo and Theodore after Tea Tree Gully Council said they had to go.
Offers have been rolling in from everywhere, from Mt Pleasant, Mt Compass, Mt Lofty, Murray Bridge, Hahndorf, Golden Grove, even "Bob" from the Flinders Ranges in Victoria.
Ms Hume said her phone had been running hot over the past 24 hours.
"We have offers pouring in," she said.
"I've had more than 100.
"I've had to charge my phone twice, I've had so many messages, it got drained.
"All these strangers contacting me through (Facebook) Messenger, it's been full on.
"I was drowning in names yesterday, I was overwhelmed.
"Not even local people - people in Strathalbyn, Mt Gambier, far and wide."

Police investigate former SA Anglican Archbishop Ian George, patient numbers heading in the wrong direction leading up to the hospital move, two alpacas looking for a new home, an unexpected visitor explores Port MacDonnell.

Beloved pets told to alpaca their bags
In a further twist, Ms Hume was hopeful of getting a further extension from the council after a personal visit from a staff member yesterday.
She said the council was due to pick up the alpacas this week, but held out hope of taking her "boys" to a new rental.
"I have to provide proof I'm looking for a new place," she said.
"A council officer visited me yesterday - he's on my side."
She said she was thrilled with the response so far from fellow alpaca owners.
"I felt desperate and hopeless last week," she said.
"I just want to thank everyone, it's been an amazing thing to see how much people care."
The council has been sought for comment.
The NorthEastern Weekly has received nearly 20 inquiries about the two alpacas over the past 24 hours.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hume</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NorthEastern Weekly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port MacDonnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Bridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tea Tree Gully Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Anglican Archbishop Ian George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Ranges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonardo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Gambier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hahndorf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Highbury</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodi Hume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Compass</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Lofty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Theodore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strathalbyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Pleasant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messengers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
