<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411279051038809</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/02/11/48/rare-roman-silver-found-by-teen-goes-on-display</url>
  <title>Silver hoard found by Scottish teen shows Romans bribed their foes</title>
  <content>
A rare haul of Roman silver discovered by a teenage metal detection enthusiast in Scotland during his "first proper find" is going on display.
David Hall unearthed the hoard of ancient metals in a field in Dairsie, in the county of Fife, in 2014, when he was aged 14.
The hacksilver - silver objects hacked into pieces to make bullion - were probably used by Roman soldiers to bribe rebel Picts while legions marched through Scotland, experts believe.
David, 16, told the BBC he had only been using his "low end" metal detector when he found the silver.
"It was quite a boring day," he said.
"I was at a rally with 103 metal detectorists and we were looking in three fields and nothing had come up.
"All of a sudden I found a few bits of silver and I showed it to a friend who said it was Roman and after that we found another 200 pieces on the first day."

Related Articles

Archaeologists believe the find shows the feared Roman army relied on bribes and diplomacy in dealing with hostile native tribes as well as pure force.
David said: "This was really my first proper find."
Experts have reconstructed four Roman vessels from more than 300 fragments, as well as examining how they had been cut into packages of bullion.
They believe the silver came to Fife as a gift or payment from Rome.
Dr Fraser Hunter, principal curator at National Museums Scotland, said: "New archaeological evidence is rewriting our understanding of Roman frontier politics, and silver was a key part of this".
"It's a fascinatingly complex picture that shows interaction and realpolitik, with the Romans changing their approach to deal with different emerging problems, and local tribes taking advantage of Roman 'gifts'. The Dairsie hoard is internationally significant.
"It's the earliest evidence for a new phase of Roman policy in dealing with troublesome tribes, using bribes of silver bullion in the form of hacked silver vessels."
The collection will go on display at the National Museum of Scotland in Edinburgh in October.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Museum of Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romans</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Museums Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David, 16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fife</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edinburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Picts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dairsie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Fraser Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
