<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412447282160676</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/athletics/canberra-javelin-thrower-kelseylee-roberts-feeling-mentally-refreshed-ahead-of-london-athletics-world-championships-20170628-gx01t9.html</url>
  <title>Classic case of chalk and cheese for Kelsey-Lee Roberts</title>
  <content>
Canberra javelin thrower Kelsey-Lee Roberts is coming off the toughest year of her career but it's a classic case of "chalk and cheese" leading into the athletics world championships.
Roberts has thrown, equalled, and bettered her personal best over the past month, a mark that now sits at 64.38 metres after a phenomenal outing at the London Diamond League.Photo: Matt King
The 25-year-old is feeling mentally refreshed ahead of the London world championships in August and primed to make up for the heartbreak of her disappointing Olympic debut in Rio.
At the end of a major event each year, Roberts sits down with her coach Mike Barber and maps out a plan for the road ahead, and everything has fallen into place in the lead up to the world championships.
Now she just has the London Diamond League on July 9, and hopefully another tournament to follow, before she sets her sights on a world title.
"I'm in a completely different space to this time last year, it's almost no comparison," Roberts said.

"We look at last year and take what we can out of it and make sure we don't do it again. In terms of my preparation to a major it's chalk and cheese, completely different and a completely different mental state."
Roberts' struggles in Rio reduced her to tears but she has already firmed as a genuine gold medal chance at the Gold Coast Commonwealth Games next year.
Instead of dwelling on the toughest year of her career, she learned from it and has bounced back to near career best form.
"It always comes with its learning experiences. I don't wish anyone to have to go what I had to last year just to learn from it, but it's what we do as athletes," Roberts said.
"We push our bodies to the limits and sometimes we push them over. That's what happened last year. I think we've been smart by learning what we did wrong, not making those same mistakes again and not getting caught up in that same process.
"I think that was the biggest thing about last year, was learning where we did go wrong and making those changes so we don't repeat it. I think we've done that really well.
"I guess it just reinforces the fact that we're doing things the right way and the process is working. I'm in good health at the moment so if we can just keep it going, I know there is more to come."
Roberts' preparations for the world championships have kicked off with a bang with some "quality training" in Germany tacked on to a handful of wins in Finland.
There's always a few things that signal the start of a big tournament for Roberts - getting around teammates new and old, and getting her hands on a brand new green and gold uniform.
But she still has some time up her sleeve before things really ramp up for her second world championship event.
"At the moment it's still reasonably quiet, we still have a little home and training as per normal so nothing has ramped up too quickly yet," Roberts said. 
"I had a pretty successful domestic season, I peaked at nationals and got the qualifier there. But to go away after nationals, do some more work, then come out and throw a PB closer to worlds, it's a nice thought that you're doing things right and you're on the right track."
Now she just has to "keep this process rolling".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast Commonwealth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Diamond League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberts</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Diamond League.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelsey-Lee Roberts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Barber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
