<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411283346006136</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4827802/teen-flees-after-being-grabbed-by-man-police/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Teen flees after being grabbed by man: police</title>
  <content>
Police are investigating after a child was approached at Flinders.
A 13-year-old boy was walking in a car park at Flinders Fields, on Burrinjuck Avenue, about 5.30pm on Tuesday. 
Police have been told a man got out of a vehicle, approached the boy and offered him a lift.
The boy declined but the man continued to approach him and grabbed him on the shoulder.
The boy was able to break free and run home where he informed his parents of the incident, police said in a statement.

Lake Illawarra police were notified and searched the area for the man without success.
Officers want to speak with a man who may be able to assist with inquiries.

He is described as being 60 to 70 years old, with a large build, balding with hair only on the sides and back of his head. He had pale skin and a moustache.
The man also had a tattoo of a bird with a flower in its mouth on his left hand and was last seen wearing a black leather jacket, blue jeans and brown boots.
His vehicle has been described as an older model black SUV, with yellow and black number plates, which had grey panels on the lower half of the vehicle and roof racks.
Anyone with information is urged to contact Lake Illawarra police or Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
SAFETY TIPS

Police have encouraged parents to discuss the 'Safe People, Safe Places' messages with their children, including:

Make sure your parents or another adult you know knows where you are at all times.
Always walk straight home or to the place you are walking to. Walk near busier roads and streets, or use paths where there are lots of other people.
Know where safe places are - a shop, service station, police station, library or school. If you are ever frightened, you should go to one of these places and ask them to call the police.
Learn about safe adults you can look for and talk to if you need help - police officers, teachers at school, adults you know and trust.
Don't talk to people you don't know and never get into a car with someone you don't know. If a car stops on the side of the road and you don't know the person inside, do not stop.
If you are scared and can use a phone, call 000 and tell them you are scared.
If someone tries to grab you, yell out, 'Go away, I don't know you'. This lets other people know you have been approached by someone you don't know.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Fields</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burrinjuck Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Safe People</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
