<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412447282160675</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/malcolm-turnbull-faces-backlash-from-under-40s-locked-out-of-housing-grattan-20170802-gxnqgt</url>
  <title>Malcolm Turnbull faces backlash from under 40s locked out of housing: Grattan</title>
  <content>
Plunging under-40s home ownership could spark a youth rebellion like the one that , Grattan Institute chief executive John Daley says.
The Household Income and Labour Dynamics Australia survey revealed the .
The trend was apparent across income, education and vocations, but was markedly worse for groups on the lower rungs of the income, education and vocational pecking orders.
British voting support diverged wildly according to age group in the general election held in June, with under 45s swinging overwhelmingly behind Labour and voters 55 and above swinging strongly behind the Conservatives.

Grattan Institute/Ipsos/Mori/Lord Ashcroft polls/ FT

Mr Daley said he had never seen an election "in which age was the dominant cleavage" and the outcome was at least partly due to "this general feeling that the combination of tax settings and supply is not working for us".

40-year-old 'Corbynistas'

"We think it's the 25 year old Corbynistas but it's 40 year olds as well. You can afford to lose the 25-year-olds - you can't afford to lose the 40 year olds," Dr Daley said.
Labor proposes winding back negative gearing and capital gains tax concessions on investor housing to curb runaway house price growth, which Roger Wilkins, the director of the HILDA survey, says is the biggest obstacle to young people buying homes.
Shadow Treasurer Chris Bowen said the government "continues to put investors buying their fourth or fifth property ahead of young people trying to buy their first home" and worsens the problem of falling home ownership "in another example of how the Turnbull Government continues to promote and defend inequality".

SAM MOOY

"Their disregard for Australians trying to buy their first home shows they just don't care about growing intergenerational inequality," Mr Bowen said in a statement.
"They repeat the discredited claim that reform of negative gearing and capital gains tax concessions would raise rents. They need to be called to account for this weak defence of unfair tax concessions that favour property investors, distort the housing market and keep home ownership beyond the reach of a whole generation of renters.
Tackle Nimbyism

Dr Daley said Labor's policies of curbing negative gearing and capital gains tax concessions for housing investors - policies the Grattan Institute also backs - would do a bit to help to ease house price growth and increase supply available for owner occupiers.

But he said the biggest thing governments could do to curb house price growth would be to change planning laws to increase supply and density in the middle suburbs, because local governments and NIMBY (not in my backyard) residents had conspired to prevent any material increase in density in those suburbs for over 30 years.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grattan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIMBYism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Chris Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Household Income</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grattan Institute/Ipsos/Mori/Lord Ashcroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mooy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Daley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grattan Institute</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corbynistas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NIMBY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
