<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411841691762684</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/02/14/14/father-shot-in-cold-blood-over-an-old-dispute-oceans-away-from-new-york</url>
  <title>Father 'shot in cold blood' over an old dispute oceans away from New York</title>
  <content>
A decades-long dispute between neighbours in China ended in the merciless murder of an elderly father on the streets of New York City.

Wu Long Chen, 45, was today sentenced to 40 years to life over the killing of 68-year-old Ying Guan Chen in Brooklyn last year,  reports.

As New York detectives dug into the bizarre murder case, they discovered Ying was gunned down because of a bitter property feud that stretched back 20 years.

At the time, Wu's extension to his home in China had caused a fractious disagreement with his elderly neighbour.

It led to one of Ying's sons allegedly assaulting Wu, according to The New York Post.

Remarkably, decades later, Wu found himself attending a wedding reception alongside the victim in Brooklyn during December in 2015.

Damning security footage showed Wu following the older man down the street after the reception.

Related Articles

Wu pulled a gun and began firing, shooting Ying in the head, chest and arm, before his weapon jammed.

Ying stumbled into a Popeye's Chicken fast food restaurant yelling for help and later died.

Police captured Wu in Texas as he tried to escape across the border to Mexico.

"This was a particularly egregious and senseless murder - an elderly man who had done nothing wrong was shot in cold blood over an old dispute an ocean away of which he had no part," said Acting Brooklyn District Attorney Eric Gonzalez.

Wu was found guilty and given consecutive sentences for murder and a weapons charge.

(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wu</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Acting Brooklyn District Attorney Eric Gonzalez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wu Long Chen, 45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ying Guan Chen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROOKLYN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Texas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Popeye's Chicken</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ying</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
