<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412442987193345</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828704/rugby-player-jailed-for-supplying-cocaine/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Rugby player jailed for supplying cocaine</title>
  <content>
JAILED: Dylan Heins playing for The Waratahs in June. He has been sentenced to serve at least 18 months in jail for supplying cocaine.

HE was a promising young rugby player, the son of a former police officer, who started using cocaine, fell in with a criminal syndicate and began supplying drugs and collecting debts. 
The dramatic downfall of Dylan James Heins, 25, was outlined in Newcastle District Court on Wednesday as the former Newcastle representative rugby player was jailed for a maximum of two years and nine months, with a non-parole period of 18 months. 

He had pleaded guilty to supplying an indictable quantity of cocaine - 83.8 grams with a potential street value of $50,000 - and knowingly participate in a criminal group. 

JAILED: A forlorn-looking Dylan Heins leaving the old Newcastle courthouse after being granted bail in July, 2015.
Heins started using cocaine at 21, but it wasn't until about six months before his arrest in July, 2015, that the drug "insidiously" took hold of him. He made drug deliveries and collected cash for high-ranking syndicate members Taha Eldarwich and Kirk Lawton in exchange for cocaine. 

When asked during a sentence hearing last week why it was that someone like him - someone who grew up in a supportive, law-abiding family, who got a good education and who was gifted opportunities to play rugby overseas - got involved in the criminal group, Heins' replied: "personal use".  
Then on July 21, 2015, his involvement in the Hunter's drug underworld reached its peak. Directed by Eldarwich to send three ounces, or 83.8 grams, of cocaine via Australia Post to an associate in North Queensland, Heins decided he didn't want to post the parcel himself.
He had no idea he was under surveillance - the dogged detectives attached to Strike Force Rupas - when he handed the parcel off to co-offender Steven Thomas Terry in a car outside Charlestown Square.

Terry was captured on CCTV as he strode into Charlestown post office and posted the express parcel. 
On Friday, after two years on conditional bail, Heins surprisingly asked that he be taken into custody. 

Cognizant of the inevitable, he was keen to start his sentence early. 
He re-appeared on Wednesday; his suit from last week long gone, replaced with a green prison-issued sloppy joe. 

His barrister Paul Rosser, QC, sought to paint a picture of a young man caught up in the midst of addiction and the "pseudo glamour" of the drug supply world. 
"Insidiously it got hold of him to a point where he didn't realise how dependent he was on it," Mr Rosser said. "He didn't realise much impact it was having on his life. "No doubt there was a certain glamour in it. "No doubt that getting his supplies for free... was attractive to him. "I think that's all dust and ashes now." 

Heins will be eligible for parole in January, 2019. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strike Force Rupas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HEIN</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rosser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan James Heins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Thomas Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Rosser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eldarwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirk Lawton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taha Eldarwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Heins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21, 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
