<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412284073400717</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-02/no-panic-with-nakia-say-cats</url>
  <title>No panic with Nakia, say Cats</title>
  <content>
Injuries have restricted Nakia Cockatoo to just 10 games this year

GEELONG will not succumb to the temptation of trying to find a quick fix to Nakia Cockatoo's injury issues after he suffered his third hamstring strain for the season last Saturday night.

While those offering solutions to the 20-year-old's current woes have not been backward in coming forward, Cats football manager Steve Hocking told AFL.com.au that no-one at the club, despite their disappointment at the latest setback, was panicking.

Hocking said the first step was to ensure Cockatoo overcomes his current injury, with late-season games and finals still a possibility for the electrifying forward.

The next phase, when the season ends, would be to map out a pre-season that builds Cockatoo's body to make it stronger when he explodes from a stoppage like he did against Carlton before grimacing as the string went.

"It's about building his resilience so he can sustain that level of force and that level of output over a period of time," Hocking said.

"A full pre-season will help that."

Hocking understands why people outside the club want to offer advice and help.

Everyone has seen the explosive and scintillating talent Cockatoo possesses during his 31 senior games.

They know his ability to accelerate from low to top pace is unique, and want to see more of it.

And many see the way Hawthorn rebuilt Cyril Rioli, changing his running style when he had soft tissue problems so he could accelerate and decelerate when fatigued without being injured, and wonder whether Cockatoo sits in the same boat.

Hocking said such a course of action was not part of the discussion at Geelong at this stage, although nothing was ever ruled out.

He described Cockatoo as a fluent athlete with quite a different running style to the Hawthorn speedster.

"Because it works for Cyril doesn't necessarily mean it applies to Nakia," Hocking said.

"You just have to isolate it to what each person needs, and we have confidence the staff will get on top of that.

"If our team comes and says there has to be some modifications made to his running, obviously we'll consider all of that, but that is certainly not part of the discussion at this point."

Hocking said the frustration that some supporters feel needs to be tempered because hard-headed, logical decision-making is required rather than knee-jerk reactions that only serve to make the issue bigger than necessary.

"It's certainly not 'Project Cockatoo'. We've got to be really clear on that," Hocking said.  

"That is starting to develop around him and growing its own life, and there is no need for that in our view."

Hocking said its worth remembering that Cockatoo did not play a lot of football before he arrived at Geelong, and more pre-seasons would benefit the youngster physically as well as building his understanding of his body.

The Cats also know that players who suffer a hamstring injury during the year are more vulnerable to hurting it again, hence their cautious approach when he missed five games before returning against the Blues.

That doesn't mean every stone at Simonds Stadium isn't being turned over to ensure Cockatoo is being set on the right path.

"The big thing for us is we just don't want to let him down," Hocking said.

"We want him to realise his full potential."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Project Cockatoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyril Rioli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cockatoo</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nakia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyril</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nakia Cockatoo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hocking</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
