<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412400037519665</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/special_reports/smsf/new-super-rules-will-impact-more-people-than-you-think-20170801-gxnit2</url>
  <title>New super rules will impact more people than you think</title>
  <content>
It is disconcerting the number of retirees with self-managed superannuation funds (SMSFs) who are finding the super reforms introduced on July 1 difficult to comprehend.
A case in point is a reader who runs an SMSF with his wife, with total super savings between them of $1.9 million, paying each of them a pension.
They are both aged 75 and set up their SMSF a decade ago when they retired. They have used the tax-free income the fund has earned since then to support their retirement.
What they have been unable to establish, despite telephone inquiries to the tax office, is if their super will remain tax-free under the new rules.

Colin Lewis, senior manager of strategic advice with Perpetual Private, says the reader must approach his situation in a methodical way. To start with both he and his wife are over 60 and taking pensions from their super.

Regardless of how much super they have, all pension income or lump sums they withdraw will continue to be tax-free. Some people are fearful, he says, that under the so-called , retirees drawing a pension will be taxed on withdrawals. This is not the case.
The income and capital growth generated by assets in a super pension are also tax-free. By contrast, income and capital growth generated by assets in an accumulation account will be taxed at up to 15 per cent.
Individual entitlements

One important aspect of the transfer balance cap, the amount a retiree can transfer to a tax-free pension, is that this is based on an individual entitlement.

In fact, all the rules, emphasises Lewis, are based on individual entitlements and are individually tested.
In the case of the reader and his wife, their $1.9 million of super savings refers to their joint super. While they regard themselves as equal holders of combined balance, the husband acknowledges that his contributions were much more than those of his wife.
This is where the reader must do some homework, says Lewis. The husband must determine his actual individual entitlement and that of his wife. This can be sourced from the fund's financial statements as of June 30. 
While this information may not necessarily be available, his previous year's statements can be a guide.

From the reader's comments, it would appear he has more than she does and what will be significant in this instance is whether his super balance exceeds $1.6 million.
If it does, then he must transfer any excess to an accumulation account.
Where it doesn't, which will hopefully be the case (say his super balance is $1.1 million and hers is $800,000), then the investment earnings in their SMSF will continue to be tax-free. Like the majority of SMSFs, the tax concessions will continue as they are.
Only fund members with more than $1.6 million as of July 1 will be adversely affected by the new rules, especially if the excess is greater than $100,000. That's when a penalty tax could apply to the excess transfer balance cap.

Be aware of rules

All retirees need to be aware of these rules, says Lewis. They must know that super in the pension is no longer a "set and forget" exercise.
Indeed it never had been. A superannuant drawing a pension has always needed to know their account balance in order to calculate how much they are required to withdraw each year in the form of a pension.
Lewis notes that many retirees had only a basic knowledge of the rules that existed prior to July 1. Those rules have now been expanded significantly.

In the reader's case, while he and his wife may not be affected by the new rules because neither may have more than $1.6 million in super, they may be impacted in the future if one of them dies while the fund has more than $1.6 million of assets. 
A couple may think everything is OK if neither of them have more than $1.6 million in super, says Lewis. But this could suddenly become an issue if one partner dies. When a member passes away the transfer balance cap rules can come into play, he cautions. 
Super fund members who haven't given the new super rules much thought need to be aware of what happens when they inherit a partner's super that takes them over the $1.6 million transfer balance cap.
Super death benefits

This raises the issue of super death benefits and rules that may require a significant amount of super to come out of the system altogether.
For our reader, this may mean that if either the husband or wife died, leaving their super to their spouse, as much as $300,000 or even more may have to be paid out of the fund and invested outside super.
Lewis says that as simple as the reader's question appears to be and while things may be OK on the surface, superannuants cannot guarantee this will always be the case. 
Inheriting a partner's super needs to be properly organised with death benefit nominations set in place.

Further, where the value of a partner's super pension exceeds a beneficiary's transfer balance cap, the excess will need to be cashed out of super. It is not possible to rollover a death benefit income stream to a beneficiary's accumulation account.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perpetual Private</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMSF</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
