<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412412922421693</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/garbos-putting-smiles-on-little-coast-faces/3208020/</url>
  <title>'Garbos' putting smiles on little Coast faces</title>
  <content>
UNLESS you forgot to take the bins out, you probably don't give much thought to your weekly visit from the garbage truck.
But for this Mountain Creek kid, it's the best day of the week.
In a Facebook post to a local community board, Archie's mother Shantelle Hatchman thanked the "garbos" making her son's day every Tuesday.
The post has turned the bubbly toddler, 2, into a social media sensation with more than 500 reactions and dozens of comments from others about their child's love of garbage men.
Mrs Hatchman said Archie had been obsessed with garbage trucks for six months, but expected the infatuation to hang around for years.
Archie now has hoards of trucks and bins and a driver even recently gave him a cardboard replica to build himself.
"Every Tuesday when the garbage truck comes he's out on the driveway jumping and dancing and waving to the garbage truck men," Mrs Hatchman said.
"He usually would just sit at the front window, so I thought I may as well just take him out on the driveway so he can have a look.
"If he's lucky, some days they will wave and beep.
"He was rapt."
It's not just trucks that get Archie's motor running, his mum said he loved all things with wheels.
"He's obsessed with cars, he's like a car enthusiast already," Mrs Hatchman said.
"You wouldn't think they'd be that switched on to know it already."
Tourist track takes toll with plenty of motorists caught out
Turn your dream of owning a hip cafe or bar into a reality.
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
EVEN shoes were optional, which was a complete culture shock for me.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Archie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hatchman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shantelle Hatchman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountain Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
