<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411364950386064</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:38</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4828532/have-your-say-at-wollongong-mental-health-consultation/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Panel to meet with Illawarra mental health patients, staff</title>
  <content>
A panel of mental health experts will hold a community consultation in Wollongong on August 10 as part of a statewide review.
, will also visit Shellharbour Hospital's mental health facilities as part of the investigation into seclusion, restraint and observation practices.
Mental Health Minister Tanya Davies said it was not too late for people to register their interest for the 10 community consultations.

''Feedback from patients, staff, carers and family members who have had contact with acute mental health services is vitally important for this review,'' Mrs Davies said.
''If there are members of the community who cannot attend a consultation we encourage them to lodge a written submission.''
Mrs Davies said while rates of seclusion in NSW acute mental health units had dropped from 11.1 episodes of seclusion (per 1000 occupied bed days) in 2008/9 to 8.7 episodes in 2015/16, a lot more  needed to be done.
''As a government, we are committed to reducing the practice of seclusion and restraint, which is why we are undertaking this system-level review,'' she said.
The Wollongong consultation, to take place at the Sage Hotel, is the second community consultation scheduled across the state, with the last to be held at Queanbeyan on September 20.
Details at www.health.nsw.gov.au or email MHSeclusionReview@moh.health.nsw.gov.au .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MHSeclusionReview</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queanbeyan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Tanya Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Davies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sage Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
