<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412400037519677</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4828296/a-gold-logie-hindered-john-woods-tv-career/?cs=12</url>
  <title>A Gold Logie hindered John Wood's TV career</title>
  <content>
PROMINENT: John Wood stars with Julie Nihill in Bakersfield Mist, a clever and funny examination of the value of art, class, expertise, and the nature of criticism. Running until Saturday at IPAC. Picture: Robert Peet

Veteran actor John Wood doesn't feel becoming a household face as Sergeant Tom Croydon on Blue Heelers hindered his career in any way, though what did was a gold statue most coveted by television personalities.
"More of a hindrance has been the Gold Logie. I've never been offered another gig at Channel 7 since," Wood said. 
- John Wood
The now 70-year-old said the lack of opportunities post winning in 2006 was "very strange" and had various theories as to why but didn't want to divulge further.
Wood comes to the Wollongong stage with another Blue Heelers star Julie Nihill for the play Bakersfield Mist opening on Wednesday night.
The comedy-drama follows the story of Maude who believes her painting bought from an op shop is a Jackson Pollock worth millions.

Wood plays the New York art dealer trying to authenticate the work but doesn't realise what he's in for.

Ex-'Blue Heelers' John Wood and Julie Nihill and plays at IPAC through to Saturday. Picture: Jodie Hutchinson
The play is touring to a number of regional cities but Wood still doesn't think there is enough arts in capital cities let alone smaller ones, even though he feels the arts are important to human existence.
"I went to Maribor in Slovenia a few years ago, a city of 250,000 people," he said.
"They've got an arts centre there the size of the Victorian Arts Centre, they've got a full time ballet company, theatre company and they're going seven days a week.
"Where would you find that in Australia? We're a nation of cretins, artistically, in terms of the way we're funded."

In an ideal world Wood said governments would be more supportive of arts organisations as audiences are there if they know about it.
Bakersfield Mist runs at the Illawarra Performing Arts Centre from Wednesday August 2 to Saturday August 5.

Post show Q&A Thursday August 3. For ticket information visit:  

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Wood</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slovenia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Wood's TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Nihill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Heelers' John Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBERT PEET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blue Heelers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPAC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bakersfield Mist</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Arts Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Performing Arts Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maribor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Q</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodie Hutchinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maude</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson Pollock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergeant Tom Croydon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Logie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
