<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411412195027181</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/perth-park-home-owners-on-firmer-ground-after-law-reform/8764880</url>
  <title>Perth Park home owners on firmer ground after law reform</title>
  <content>
Long-term residents of caravan parks in Western Australia are hopeful that forthcoming changes to the laws governing their tenure will give them more protection from eviction.
After , the State Government has announced it will reform the Residential Parks (Long-stay Tenants) Act and give people who own their homes but not the land on which they stand more security of tenure.
Ken Mann is the president of the Park Home Owners Association of WA (PHOA) and has lived in a park home in Woodman Point, south of Perth, for seven years.
He is delighted at the changes in the law, which appear likely to go through after years of lobbying by PHOA and Shelter WA.
Mr Mann told  that for many retirees, living in a demountable house in a long-stay caravan park was a way to achieve a comfortable lifestyle on a modest budget.
"We love it. We are not far from the beach and we have tuart forest right on our boundary line.
"All these parks have pretty active social clubs so there are always activities going on.
"There's a really strong sense of community and it frees up some funds so that we can do some caravanning or travelling."
For many retirees, park homes, which can be bought for as little as $35,000, are an attractive and low-cost option, especially if they are located in an otherwise unaffordable suburb.
But the downside is that the parks can close, change hands or be redeveloped, leaving residents .
Increased security for park tenants

Minister for Commerce Bill Johnston said changes to the law would prevent tenancies being terminated without grounds or automatically when a park owner sold or went into receivership.
Park home owners won't have an automatic right to compensation if they have to move their home off the park, but they will be able to apply to the State Administrative Tribunal for the costs of moving their house onto another lot if a park owner terminates their tenancy before the end of the lease.
For former park home owner Wendy Morris the changes come too late to help her, but she said she was pleased the Government was continuing with reform.
She lost half her superannuation and had to move into a rented granny flat after her park was sold.
In 2012 Ms Morris bought a park home at a park in Carine, in Perth's northern suburbs, for $75,000.
"I had been renting for quite some time and occasionally living with my daughter for the past 15 years after a marriage break-up which didn't leave me with enough to buy a house," Ms Morris said.
At that time Perth was still booming on the back of the mining industry, and rents had become very high and were continuing to climb, and at 65 Ms Morris could access her superannuation.
"I couldn't afford to rent any longer, so I decided to access my super and I saw this park home on the market for an amount that I could afford."
The rent on the land was $225 a week.
"It suited me fine. It had two bedrooms and a nice little kitchen," she said.
"It had good air conditioning and it was perfect for me; small and close to a lot of conveniences."

Ground sold from underneath residents

But the park's location in a leafy Perth suburb also made it attractive to developers, and in 2015 the park was sold and the other 160 residents were given nine months' notice to leave.
The closest site Ms Morris and her neighbours could find with space available was in Moora, 180km north of Perth.
And although the homes are technically mobile, it was going to cost around $20,000 to dismantle and transport the house to a new location.
She listed her home for sale but only attracted offers of around $10,000 to $15,000 as the deadline to leave the park approached.
"I couldn't put my name down for public housing because of the fact that I am on a pension and have a bit of super left; they wouldn't put me on the list, which is seven years' long anyway."
Ms Morris moved out and now lives in a rented granny flat in the Perth hills for $220 a week, close to the wildlife rescue centre where she volunteers.
"I live on the pension with a little bit of super that is rapidly declining."
She donated her park house to a resident of the .
Members of the Maritime Union of Australia volunteered their time to dismantle the house and a moving business offered to transport the home at a significant discount.
"I thought that rather than sell it to someone for $10,000 or $15,000 and have someone make money out of it, which people were attempting to do, I decided to try and donate it to someone down in Yarloop," Ms Morris said.
"I felt good about it, it was sort of an inspiration. I'd lost $75,000 on it anyway, it seemed right at the time."
Changes welcome

Mr Mann said the Government's planned changes, which also include the right to sell your own park home and the right to appeal rent increases, would make a big difference to the thousands of people who called caravan parks home.
"It's very hard to know how many people are in this situation but we estimate between 5,000 and 20,000 people in WA."
"It gives us independent living in a really nice community environment, where we are not imposing on the state housing.
"If what the government is proposing finds its way into legislation, we will be much happier little vegemites."
Mr Johnston said the amendment would "strike a fair balance between protecting the rights of tenants and ensuring the viability of the residential parks sector is maintained".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commerce Bill Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Johnston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long-stay Tenants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Residential Parks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodman Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park Home Owners Association of WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wendy Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelter WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Mann</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Morris</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Union of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarloop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PHOA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Mann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Administrative Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
