<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412365677780572</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/dandenong-magistrate-angry-at-defendants-gun-for-drugs-plan-in-noble-park/news-story/737526c0ceb0f7e3a455112810fd1ac3</url>
  <title>Gun for drugs swap, not shooting: court claim</title>
  <content>
A DEFINAT drug user told police he wasn't going to use a handgun found in his car but planned to trade it for drugs.
Jon Booth, 32, said the home made weapon had been given to him and he thought it was a "spud gun".
His defence infuriated Dandenong magistrate Jack Vandersteen when Booth appeared in court. "Well that's fantastic isn't it - so you give a gun to a drug dealer?" Mr Vandersteen said.
"This is not a spud gun - that's a ridiculous suggestion.
"Can you believe he was going to give it to a meth dealer ... what's a meth dealer going to do with it?"
Mr Vandersteen said the gun was a "serious weapon" that can "only be used to harm people."
Police prosecutor Senior Constable Aimee Ryland told Dandenong Magistrates' Court that Booth was stopped by police in an unregistered car at Railway Parade in Noble Park on May 30.
Sen-Constable Ryland said Booth told officers someone gave him the weapons that he thought was spud gun and he was "going to swap it for some drugs".
Booth pleaded guilty to being a prohibited person in possession of a firearm, and failing to comply with a community corrections order from a previous court matter.
Mr Vandersteen said Booth had missed multiple meetings with corrections workers and had failed to respond to communication.
Booth claimed work commitments and mailing address issues were the cause of his failure to comply but Mr Vandersteen labelled these "excuses"
"Why do I want to sit here and listen to excuses from a 32-year-old?" he said.
"You are required to comply with these orders."
He said it was only because of Booth's relatively limited criminal history that he was staying out of jail.
"Up until the end of last year you were what we call a clean skin - you'd never been in trouble before," he said.
Booth was once again placed on a community corrections order.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen-Constable Ryland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senior Constable Aimee Ryland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEFINAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Vandersteen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Booth, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Vandersteen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Railway Parade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Magistrates' Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
