<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411867461566777</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:35</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/deals-have-a-lifetime-of-vpn-access-for-10-devices-at-90-off/</url>
  <title>Deals: Have A Lifetime Of VPN Access For 10 Devices At 90% Off</title>
  <content>
There are tons of VPNs out on the market right now, but when it comes to offering comprehensive protection, few can compete with , especially when it's on sale for more than 90 percent off.

Praised by the likes of TechRadar and PC Mag, VPN Unlimited hides and encrypts your data on public connections, so hackers and snoopers can't peek into your personal info. Plus, it delivers unlimited high-speed connection and bandwidth. That way you can stream, download, and browse to your heart's content without compromising on security or speed. And with a growing network of more than 1,000 servers across the world, you can rest assured that you can browse safely wherever your travels take you.

VPN Unlimited has various plans for however many devices you're looking to protect, and their Infinity variants are a particularly special deal. Score  [$55.99] USD, 25 devices for $120.19 AUD [$95.99 USD], or outfit an entire office with a 100-device plan for $250 AUD [$199 USD].

For a limited time, you can take an extra 15 percent off any of their Infinity variants by using code INFINITY15.

Please note that all deals in the deal store are in US dollars. Additional shipping costs may apply for physical items.

All deals are carefully vetted to ensure relevance and value to Gizmodo readers. Commerce Content is independent of Allure Media editorial and advertising, and if you buy something through our posts, we may get a small share of the sale. Click  to learn more.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD [$199 USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Access For 10 Devices At 90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Infinity</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PC Mag</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lifetime Of VPN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TechRadar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gizmodo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VPN Unlimited</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INFINITY15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allure Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commerce Content</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD [$95.99 USD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VPNs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USD 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
