<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412013490456969</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/14/53/albert-cvetkovski-guilty-verdict-heathcote-crash-drew-cullen</url>
  <title>Truck driver found guilty of killing off-duty fireman in crash</title>
  <content>
A truck driver has been found guilty over a crash which killed an off-duty fireman in southern Sydney.
There were gasps and tears from both sides of the court room, but Albert Cvetkovski's face was blank in the moments after the guilty verdict was read out. 
The jury taking less than a day to convict the 44-year-old of dangerous driving occasioning death.
Among those in court was Susie Smith, she was feeding her 16-month-old daughter when pictures of the awful crash at Heathcote in 2015 flashed up on her television.
She knew immediately her partner, off-duty firefighter Drew Cullen was never coming home.
Cvetkovski pleaded not guilty, arguing a pot hole caused the accident.
"The steering wheel jumped out of my hands. The truck veered towards the centre of the road and within seconds I just clipped the guy," he told police.

Related Articles

"By the time I seen what happened it was all over."
He denied he had taken any drugs, that was a lie.
Crown Prosecutor Eric Balodis argued there was a low level of methamphetamine in his system and he was in the withdrawal stages, leading to a loss of concentration.
The jury agreed.
Outside court Ms Smith told 9NEWS she was relieved and happy with the verdict.
"I don't have to tell my little girl that her dad was killed by someone for no reason, there was a reason."
"We're all human, we all make mistakes, we all have accidents, but it's not accidental driving around with drugs in your system."
Cvetkovski walked out of court on strict conditional bail but he is looking at jail time.
He'll face a sentence hearing in October.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Prosecutor Eric Balodis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heathcote</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Drew Cullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Cvetkovski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cvetkovski</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susie Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
