<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411322000712365</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/nrl/nrl-wayne-bennett-wants-ash-taylor-woods-in-the-dark-eels-coach-bans-f-word/news-story/a1ff32638daf6e10a122f6bd78e3145b</url>
  <title>NRL: Wayne Bennett wants Ash Taylor; Woods in the dark; Eels coach bans 'F' word</title>
  <content>
Eels taking it week by week
2:31

NRL: Even though the Parramatta Eels are comfortably in the top 8 they are not taking any chances.

August 2nd 2017
2 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Sport news and galleries/NRL News/

Wayne Bennett wants to solve his playmaking problem.

AAP

Share

WAYNE Bennett will look to lure Ashley Taylor back to Brisbane after the Gold Coast halfback's emergence as an NRL star.
Taylor left the Broncos at the end of 2015 to join the Titans, where he's developed into a top playmaker to lead the league in try assists this season. The 22-year-old played just one of his 42 games for Brisbane and coach Bennett said his departure was linked to incumbency of halves Ben Hunt and Anthony Milford.
Hunt will depart to join St George Illawarra at season's end, while Taylor goes off-contract at the end of 2018.
"If he interested in us and he is on the open market, I am interested in talking to him," Bennett told the .
"I never wanted to lose a player of Ash's ability. Sometimes guys only get one opportunity at this level and it wouldn't have been fair to keep Ash Taylor stuck behind Ben and Anthony.
"If Ash is interested in coming back, I'll look at our salary cap position."
Taylor told the Nine Network on Tuesday he was enjoying his time at the Titans and didn't want any distractions next year around his contract. The Titans host the Broncos on Saturday.
DOGS DRAMA NEW TO WOODS

Aaron Woods is still heading to Belmore in 2018 as far as he's concerned.Source:AAP
Aaron Woods insists he's in his final weeks at Wests Tigers despite concerns NRL salary cap constraints may prevent him joining Canterbury.

The Bulldogs' efforts to be cap compliant for next year reportedly could result in recently signed players being unable to play.
The Tigers are monitoring the situation in the hope Woods will stay in 2018, Fairfax Media reports, despite the captain signing a four-year deal with Canterbury in late April.
Woods didn't buy into talk of extending his stay at the Tigers but said he was happy working under coach Ivan Cleary, who took over in April.
"I've got no idea what's happening," Woods told Sky Sports Radio on Tuesday. "All I know is I signed a contract with the Bulldogs and that's it, mate.
"I've enjoyed my time under Ivan but I signed a contract with the Bulldogs and just enjoying my last weeks with the Tigers."
Star prop Woods has played his entire 141-game career at the second-last Tigers but is set to depart after the last five regular season matches. The Bulldogs declined to comment on their salary cap situation when contacted by AAP on Wednesday.
ARTHUR BANS THE 'F' WORD

The Eels' finals drought will likely end in 2017.Source:News Corp Australia
Don't utter the 'F' word in front of Parramatta coach Brad Arthur. Finals that is.
With the blue and gold on the cusp of their first finals appearance in eight seasons, their long-suffering fans are daring to dream.
But not Arthur.
With his club in the midst of the longest finals drought of any club, he's refusing to broach the subject.
"When we've got enough wins to ensure we're in the finals, I'm happy to talk about it," Arthur said. "But at the moment we haven't."
Arthur has refused to talks finals with his charges, arguing the job to get there still has to be done.
There's an underlying hunger among the Eels playing group to make the finals after having that opportunity taken off them last year due to the salary cap scandal.
The Eels will move to 30 points, and possibly into the top four, with victory over Canterbury at ANZ Stadium on Thursday night.
Against teams in the top eight, the Eels have won seven of 10 matches, feeding their self-belief they can rattle some cages in September.
Although it should be noted two of those matches, against Melbourne and North Queensland, were affected by State of Origin.
Even without fullback Clint Gutherson, who is gone for the year with a knee injury, the Eels looked like contenders in their 28-14 win over Brisbane last week and Arthur says they must continue to prove their worth.
"Finals are the furthest thing from my mind at the moment because we're not guaranteed a finals spot," Arthur said. "What's really important is that we don't let ourselves down after what we did last weekend.
"We're coming up against a very committed Bulldogs team. They're very good defensively and they'll be tough and playing for their coach."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Cleary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Woods</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Milford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F-word</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash Taylor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clint Gutherson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta Eels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DRAMA NEW TO WOODS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARTHUR BANS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Bennett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ash</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
