<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412228238824902</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/review-needed-of-naplan-writing-tasks-for-relevancy-minister-20170802-gxnq0b.html</url>
  <title>Review needed of NAPLAN writing tasks for relevancy: Minister</title>
  <content>
Education Minister Kate Jones wants a review of the NAPLAN writing task to determine whether it is "relevant" to students.
Ms Jones was speaking after the release of preliminary NAPLAN results in Queensland that showed  or declined versus baseline results recorded in 2011.Photo: Glenn Hunt/AAP
"I think we do need to sit down with ACARA (the Australian Curriculum, Assessment and Reporting Authority) to have a look at some of the writing tasks and whether they are relevant to the students and whether they can engage more," she said.
"I think there is work that has to happen at a national level, at the education council meeting to have a look at the writing task because this is happening in New South Wales, Victoria, Western Australia.
"It's across the board and I think there has to be a national conversation about the writing task."
But Ms Jones would not bite on whether children should be taught about writing for Twitter or Instagram.

Ms Jones said parents wanted their children to have the confidence to write.
"I know there's been a lot of talk every time NAPLAN comes out about the cognisant process that happens with writing, writing by hand, and so we believe that absolutely students need the skill not only the digital skills of the future, but the ability to read and write at a level that they're going to be able to participate fully in society," she said.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I think the best place to have the conversation about what the writing task looks like in NAPLAN is at the education council meeting and certainly I know that [federal Education Minister] Simon Birmingham is keen to have that conversation and I welcome his interest this year."
Ms Jones acknowledged Queensland needed to focus on writing in the future.
"It continues to improve from when we started NAPLAN here in Queensland," she said.
"What we're not seeing is the same level of improvement year in year out that we have seen for example in numeracy and reading."
She said the government was working with the Australian Catholic University to see if there were new programs that could be introduced and how to work with schools to improve writing.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reporting Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACARA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt/AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Kate Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Catholic University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Curriculum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jones</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
