<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411459439668146</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/innovative-coast-business-hub-thrives/3207874/</url>
  <title>Innovative Coast business hub thrives</title>
  <content>
ONE of the Sunshine Coast's most innovative business hubs is thriving.
Pratt Property's Kon-Tiki building was considered one of the region's biggest commercial projects while under construction and took just over two years to complete.
Officially opening its doors in early March, the Kon-Tiki building on Plaza Pde is certainly living up to expectations.
In contrast to most business spaces, the development has been designed to feature an interesting mix of office, retail and hospitality.
Kon-Tiki centre manager Steph Peters said in just four months, 44% has been leased in tower one and tower two was already up to 15% leased.
"It's going pretty well and we've got enquiries more and more every week," she said
She said the building had been designed to encompass a unique environment.
With food, drink, retail, business and health all in one place, she said it was proving to be a one-stop-shop for owners, employees and customers.
"We've had lots of positive feedback and it has got a really good vibe around the place," she said.
"We wanted to create a really versatile space that people want to come to work and enjoy working here."
The Hive Business Space was one of the first to call the development home and hasn't looked back since opening.
The Hive manager Jen Forster said it had been important for the business to be centrally located and to be associated with a world-class development.
She said Kon-Tiki's diverse business community had been an added bonus.
"The community in Kon-Tiki itself is fantastic and it's probably one of the real pluses for the business owners to have here," she said.
"To have each other to communicate with and work with and really collaborate with (has been great).
"It offers opportunities for us all to work together which not only benefits the businesses but the building itself which then benefits the Sunshine Coast."
Centre manager Steph Peters encouraged more businesses to get on-board and invited the community to come and explore.
"There's lots of spaces still available so come and take a look," she said.
It's not just the building's community that is unique but the design itself.
There is 20,000sq m of space to be rented, 600 carpark spaces for tenants and end of trip facilities for those looking to cycle to work.
The burgeoning daytime hub also features a roof deck with barbecue facilities for staff and clients, private balconies for businesses, and modern meeting and boardroom facilities for hire.
A 6m-high Tiki sculpture rises up from a water feature in the dining atrium too.
Pratt Property also built and own the La Balsa development on Brisbane Rd in Mooloolaba.
Both buildings have been named after rafts that sailed vast voyages across the pacific ocean from French Polynesia.
Latest weather data points to big dry
SELANGOR Private Hospital has celebrated its 70th birthday.
"I'm absolutely heartbroken to hear the two humpback whales died."
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
THE Reef Hotel was the centre of Noosa's social scene.
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
The house featured on TV series Grand Designs Australia in 2014
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kon-Tiki</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pratt Property</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plaza Pde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jen Forster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steph Peters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hive Business Space</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reef Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Designs Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SELANGOR Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French Polynesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Balsa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pratt Property's Kon-Tiki</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
