<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412099389804240</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/15/19/ceos-fuel-trump-style-politics-swan</url>
  <title>CEOs 'fuel Trump-style politics': Swan</title>
  <content>
Business chiefs have been blamed for helping fuel the rise of populist politics and leaders such as Donald Trump.
Former treasurer Wayne Swan said a recent trip to the United States left him wondering whether the world was facing "a long nightmare of political polarisation and conflict" not dissimilar to the 1930s.
An analysis of the US election showed 70 per cent of white, less-educated Americans voted for Mr Trump - a margin of 39 per cent over the Democrats.
Among all voters, higher educated Americans favoured Democrats by a margin of nine per cent (53.5 - 46.5) while less educated Americans favoured Trump by eight per cent (54 - 46).
"You don't get such a large powerful demographic like that voting in such a uniform way unless there is a serious structural problem occurring in your country," Mr Swan told the Australian Investors Association conference on the Gold Coast on Wednesday.
That structural problem was seen in figures such as the top one per cent of Americans possessing almost half of the country's income. In Australia, the figure was still high at 20 per cent.
"We are now experiencing the highest levels of income inequality since the Great Depression," Mr Swan said.

Related Articles

"Across the developed world there has been an increasing concentration of wealth at the top and the hollowing out of the middle class ... and this is increasingly a handbrake on global growth which is reducing living standards."
At the same time business leaders in the US and Australia were championing corporate tax cuts, gutting unions and driving down wages as economic solutions.
"In the face of this public revolt the tactics of the Business Council of Australia have at best been ineffective and at worst thrown kerosene on the fire of public indignation," Mr Swan said.
"Sadly, Trumpification has taken a firm hold in the arguments made by leading members of the BCA."
Without the business community getting its house in order "we will also succumb to the same populist uprisings" that occurred in the US and UK, Mr Swan said.
Part of the solution lay in restoring trust in big business.
In Sweden, the top four shareholders of a company propose a board member shortlist and put it forward for consideration at the AGM.
As well, shareholders should be able to approve in advance a policy and total budget that a company can pay out in each year to the top five executives.
Approval should also be sought from shareholders for any political lobbying activity by a company.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Swan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sweden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Swan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Council of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEOs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Depression</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Investors Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trumpification</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
