<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411549633982777</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Coffs Coast Advocate</source>
  <url>http://www.coffscoastadvocate.com.au/news/rio-loss-sparks-talk-of-revenge/3207879/</url>
  <title>Rio loss sparks talk of revenge</title>
  <content>
FOOTBALL: Teenage sensation Ellie Carpenter says the Matildas will have revenge on their minds when they take on Brazil in the Tournament of Nations in America on Friday (9.15am AEST).
The Aussie women will take on the Brazilians in Carson, California just under a year on from their heartbreaking quarter-final defeat at the Rio Olympics.
Carpenter and her teammates were beaten in a penalty shootout in Brazil after regulation time ended without a goal being scored and the 17-year-old said the players were desperate to turn the tables tomorrow.
"We are definitely going out to win the game," she said.
"There will be definitely some revenge on our minds from the Olympics.
"We are excited to get out on the field and beat them this time."
The Matildas have won both of their games at the Tournament of Nations in impressive fashion, defeating the hosts 1-0 before a Sam Kerr hat-trick helped them overcome Japan 4-2.
Australia's Sam Kerr reacts after scoring in the Matildas win over Japan at the Tournament of Nations.Gregory Bull
A win or a draw would be good enough to win the trophy and Carpenter said to take out the tournament would be a great achievement and set the Matildas up for the two friendlies against Brazil on home soil in September.
"That's what we are aiming for," she said.
"To win this tournament would be massive for us, especially for our world ranking and leading into those two home games.
"Getting to play against world class opposition like America has been great and I just love being around this team."
Australia is bidding to host the Women's World Cup in 2023 and Carpenter said success at this tournament would be a big boost to the country's chances of hosting the world's best teams.
"I think if we can get the 2023 World Cup that would be just amazing for women's football in this country," she said.
"I will be 23 by then, so that would be a perfect time to get the tournament."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carpenter</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellie Carpenter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Sam Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gregory Bull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday (9.15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
