<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411755792415591</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/woman-mauled-to-death-by-dogs-at-boarding-kennel/8766934</url>
  <title>Woman mauled to death by dogs at Perth boarding kennel</title>
  <content>
A woman has been attacked and mauled to death by two dogs in the Perth suburb of Southern River.
Police said the woman, aged in her 50s, was attacked yesterday afternoon at the property on Terrier Place, which also serves as Barko's canine boarding kennels.
The woman, whose name has not been released, was declared dead by paramedics a short time later.
The City of Gosnells said rangers were called to the property about 1:45pm yesterday to collect a dog that was preventing police from accessing the woman's body.
A council spokesman told the ABC that two dogs - a bull mastiff and a Staffordshire bull terrier - had been seized and impounded by rangers.
A spokesman said the council was waiting on further instructions from the police before deciding what action, if any, would be taken with the animals.
He said the dogs were registered to the owner of the property and no previous complaints about them had been received.

'Body found by daughter'

Neighbour Greg, who did not give his surname, said he did not hear any signs of a struggle at the property.
He said the woman's body was found by her daughter, who came to check on her mother after concerns were raised when she did not turn up for work at a local childcare centre.
Greg said the dogs were very aggressive and had to be locked away when anyone came to visit the property.
He said one of the dogs believed to be involved in the attack had been living with the woman for four years, when she first moved to the neighbourhood.
Another neighbour, who did not provide their name, said the woman was passionate about dogs and dedicated her life to their care, especially rescue dogs.
Police have told the ABC the woman's death was not being treated as suspicious and a report would be prepared for the coroner.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staffordshire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrier Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Gosnells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
