<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411506684309222</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/simon-birmingham-warns-liberal-colleagues-of-crossing-the-floor-on-samesex-marriage/news-story/0029bee6012fbd104dadaf393cc4b0aa</url>
  <title>Bishop cuts trip short amid Liberals drama</title>
  <content>
JULIE Bishop will cut short a trip to the Philippines to ensure she is back for the return of Parliament next week amid Liberal infighting over same-sex marriage.
Sky News reports the Foreign Minister will cut short the planned trip to Australia's neighbour, with speculation her new schedule is a result of rising tensions in the Coalition about same-sex marriage and increased pressure on Malcolm Turnbull's leadership.
Ms Bishop's move comes as Liberal MPs were warned of the consequences of crossing the floor in a parliamentary vote on same-sex marriage.
As the debate over marriage equality , the Minister for Education and Training Simon Birmingham has warned his Liberal colleagues of what could happen if there was a conscience vote on the issue.
The South Australia Senator said just because his fellow conservatives were offered the opportunity to cross the floor on the controversial issue, it doesn't mean they should take it.
"It has always been a tradition of the Liberal Party, a right in the Liberal Party for individual members to exercise their conscience from the backbench if they choose," Mr Birmingham told Sky News.
"But equally it is of course a right people should exercise carefully, with caution and with consideration for all of the consequences.
"Therefore I would urge everybody to think about the policy we took to the last election and to work as hard as we possibly can to ensure that is implemented if it possibly can be."
Last night Tasmanian Liberal Eric Abetz said the Turnbull government should pursue a postal plebiscite.
He said he did not want to speculate on whether Prime Minster Malcolm Turnbull's leadership would be under challenge if the Liberal MPs crossed the floor.

Conservative senator Eric Abetz has insisted the government must hold a national vote on same-sex marriage.

Conservative Liberals push for plebiscite
But he was also concerned about what might happen if they did.
"What I will say as a matter of objective analysis is that if a government loses a procedural vote on the floor of the House because certain members deliberately vote with Labor and the Greens then that is an exceptionally grave matter", Mr Abetz said.
"That is why any of my colleagues who are contemplating such action should be thinking about this, not two or three times, but a dozen times, then come to the conclusion that losing government isn't worth it."

Malcolm Turnbull wouldn't be drawn on the issue during a visit to Albany in Wa.
"I speak to my colleagues all the time, more regularly than I do with members of the press," he said.
"We have discussions asbout policy issues and they are best done privately in the party room.
"I am not going to get into a public debate about party issues."
Liberal Senator for the ACT, Zed Seselja stressed the need for party unity.
"I would simply make the point that when it has come to other election promises, for instance on the ABCC, we were knocked back in the Senate and we kept pushing for our policies," he said.
"We didn't turn around in that case and adopt Labor policy and nor should we in this case and I think that overwhelmingly is the view of the Coalition party room."
The Turnbull Government was able to pass the Australian Building and Construction Commission legislation in November
Several coalition MPs have indicated this week they would be prepared to cross the floor to allow marriage equality to be debated or to support the bill if it does come before the floor of the House.
Parliament resumes next week.

Gay Liberal MPs could face a preselection threat if they cross the floor on same-sex marriage.

PM under pressure over postal plebiscite
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Training Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minster Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conservative Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Construction Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Liberal Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia's Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zed Seselja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Building</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
