<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412189584118749</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>05:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/afl/teams/port-adelaide/port-adelaide-better-positioned-to-end-twoyear-afl-showdown-nightmare-says-power-captain-travis-boak/news-story/73164018e7d0af234e6315d24c669524</url>
  <title>Power ready to end Crows hoodoo</title>
  <content>
PORT Adelaide captain Travis Boak has thrown down the gauntlet to the Crows by declaring his side is "better positioned'' to win a Showdown than it has been for more than two years.
The Power hasn't beaten Adelaide for a club-record 822 days, losing the past four derbies, but Boak suggested that jinx is about to end.
"We're a different side now,'' said Boak, whose fifth-placed team will start underdog against the top-of-the-table Crows at Adelaide Oval on Sunday.
"We've changed a fair bit over the off-season and even from earlier in the year (when they lost to the Crows in round three by 17 points), so we're better positioned with understanding all that.

AFL: Travis Boak & Taylor Walker ahead of Showdown 43.

Travis Boak & Taylor Walker ahead of Showdown 43
"We have been really consistent with the way we have defended all year, we've probably been a little bit up and down with our offence, but that has grown over the course of the year.
"Going into this week's game we are probably a lot more sound with the way we play our footy.''
Port has lost the past four Showdowns by an average of 23 points.
Showdown 43 will pit the Power's No. 1 ranked defence - a key to its resurgence, Boak says, after two years without finals - against the Crows' top-ranked attack.
Boak denied Adelaide has a psychological advantage over Port, having not lost to Ken Hinkley's side since round five, 2015, when Robbie Gray won the Showdown Medal and Jay Schulz kicked five goals.
"That doesn't have any affect,'' said Boak, whose team has never lost more than four consecutive Showdowns.
"We don't look too far into the past and what's happened previously. As I said, we are a different side now and we're just excited for this weekend.
"It's certainly a big challenge because the Crows are the best side in the comp but we can't wait for it. We go into this week with a lot of confidence that we are in a good position.''

AFL: Port Adelaide midfielder Chad Wingard has opened up about his calf rehab and posted a video of his exercises.

Wingard opens up about rehab
Boak said winning the four premiership points was more important to the Power than breaking its run of consecutive Showdown losses.
"We want to win because there is a lot on the line in terms of the season,'' he said.
"We are certainly looking for a top-four spot, so that's what we are focusing on this weekend to get the win to make sure we stay in contention with that.
"Whether we stop the four losses in a row is probably not what we're thinking about, it's more about just getting the four points.''
Crows captain Taylor Walker denied his side has the Power worked out.

"I don't think you can ever work out an opposition,'' he said.
"Like Boaky said, they've probably got different personnel and have adapted and changed a few things.
"Like most Showdowns it will start in the middle, with two of the in-form ruckmen in the competition (Port's Paddy Ryder and Adelaide's Sam Jacobs) and two great midfields.''
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port's Paddy Ryder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Schulz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Boak</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boak</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boaky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Power's No</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide's Sam Jacobs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
