<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411936181044501</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/nrl-retro-round-greg-alexander-and-michael-ennis-pick-their-best-teams-of-the-1980s-and-today/news-story/53bc7205feb68c4b777bf04f1c7bf951</url>
  <title>No room for Mal, Hayne in allstar teams</title>
  <content>
THERE'S always one guy at the pub complaining that "you can't compare eras" as debate arises over the greatest athletes and teams of all time.
It may be true, but that doesn't mean it's not fun to get involved anyway.
Penrith great Greg Alexander and former NSW hooker Michael Ennis have gone head-to-head with their top picks from their respective playing eras.
As Fox League prepares to celebrate Retro Round, Alexander named a team of the 1980s while Ennis selected a line-up of current stars.
"It's so hard to compare eras," Alexander told news.com.au. "The 80s were 30 years ago now. The players are so different, the training is so different.
"It was a part-time game. It wasn't really until the late 80s players trained more than twice a week. It used to be (train) Thursday night, Saturday morning and play Sunday."
Alexander hinted his forward pack might run into trouble with the modern-day giants occupying Ennis's front row but says talent is no issue for his troops.
"The players I've picked are some of the most talented players I've ever seen," he said.
"If you're great in one era, you can hold your own in any era. It's just hard to compare each era and figure out who is better than who.
"The game was brutal back in the mid-80s. Players these days are, generally and across the board, a bit bigger. But this side I've picked is a great side that can hold its own in any era."
"Brandy" went with Parramatta legend Peter Sterling at halfback, snubbing Bulldogs legend Steve Mortimer. And he wasn't the only huge name left out of the line-up as Queenslander Mal Meninga couldn't crack a spot in his final 13.
"Sterlo dominated that era," Alexander said. "There were a number of terrific halfbacks throughout the 80s but if you had to pick one it'd be Sterlo. His consistency stood out above the others. He played a lot of Origins.
"Mal was another tough choice. He went on four Kangaroos tours, but he couldn't crack the centre pairing of Gene Miles and Brett Kenny.
"We're also just talking 1980s. Mal's best football was probably in the 1990s. Canberra won the comp in 1990 and 1994 and he went on two more Kangaroos tours.
"For the tours I went on in the 80s, Kenny and Miles were in the centres and Wally Lewis was at five-eighth so that's why I went that way."
As good as Wally Lewis is at No. 6, Alexander struggled to make a call on who was the better five-eighth between The King and Johnathan Thurston.
"Wally is an Immortal. JT, in time, will be an Immortal too. It's hard," he said. "What I will say is that Wally dominated Origin and JT probably hasn't had the same impact.
"But look at what JT has done in his career, playing over 250 games at an unbelievable level.
"The King will always be The King but in terms of club football, I don't think he can compare to Thurston. There's not many you can compare Thurston to."
ENNIS SNUBS HAYNE, SURPRISED BY MENINGA'S ABSENCE
Sharks premiership winner Ennis picked his side on current form, meaning only those stars running around in 2017 got a look-in. He said his toughest call came in the centres, where he picked Broncos flyer James Roberts to partner Melbourne's Will Chambers, snubbing NSW centres Josh Dugan and Jarryd Hayne.
Hayne had very little impact playing out of position in Origin this year and Ennis believes several youngsters are probably ahead of him to wear the No. 3 and 4 sky blue jerseys next year. He also said halfback Daly Cherry-Evans and forwards James Graham, Josh McGuire and Sam Burgess were unlucky to miss out.
"I went with James Roberts but I'm also a huge fan of (Manly centre) Dylan Walker and (Cronulla centre) Jack Bird. With the form they've shown over the past 12-18 months ... they were tough calls," Ennis told news.com.au.
"Josh Dugan was one of the better players for NSW in this year's Origin series. Personally, I like him at fullback. Again, Jarryd Hayne has been terrific for NSW at different times throughout his career at fullback or on the wing but I didn't think Hayne probably provided in the centres.
"I'd definitely look at those three guys (Roberts, Walker and Bird) to play for NSW next year without a doubt ... they'll be knocking down the door that's for sure."
Ennis acknowledges the question of whether his or Alexander's team would win is virtually impossible to answer and was full of praise for the players in Alexander's side. He has no doubt those icons from the 80s would thrive in the modern era, but still thinks his troops would end any contest ahead - if only just.
Given greater scope to pick from players in the 21st century rather than just this year, Ennis says Andrew Johns replaces Cooper Cronk at halfback but can't decide whether former Broncos pivot Darren Lockyer is included at Thurston's expense.
He admits he was surprised by Alexander's omission of "weapon" Meninga, but was happy to trust the ex-Panther's judgment.
"Andrew Johns for me is the best halfback I've ever seen play. The Thurston-Lockyer one is enormous to try and split them. I think they're different footballers and I was so fortunate to play with Lockyer that I can't split them. I can't split Lockyer and Thurston. I can't," Ennis said
"My memories of Mal are through those early 90s I suppose but he's a household name so that was a surprise in a sense.
"Steve Roach has enormous raps on Gene Miles and talking to Peter Sterling regularly he mentions Brett Kenny in every breath of the success of NSW and Parramatta so it doesn't surprise me that those two guys are there.
"My memories of when I saw Meninga play, he was a weapon, just an enormous presence on a footy field. Brandy was one of the greatest players so he would know better than I would so I can't knock the team he's picked."
There are plenty of veterans in Ennis's side but of the young guns he has no doubt former Cronulla teammate Valentine Holmes, who made his Australian debut in 2016 and his Origin debut this year, will be one of the game's great wingers.
"Valentine Holmes for me is a superstar. His awareness and anticipation on the football field as well as his balance and speed make him such a threat," Ennis said.
"I asked (Canberra winger) Jordan Rapana the other night who his toughest opponent was and he said Holmes. He said his footwork that he puts on defenders without changing speed is a real handful.
"We saw what he was capable of doing for the Sharks last year and even throughout this season. To be able to do that at Test level and State of Origin without missing a beat just shows the quality of player he is. He's destined for an enormous future."
ALEXANDER'S  TEAM: 1. Garry Jack 2. Eric Grothe 3. Brett Kenny 4. Gene Miles 5. Dale Shearer 6. Wally Lewis 7. Peter Sterling 8. Steve Roach 9. Ben Elias 10. Les Davidson 11. Paul Sironen 12. Mark Graham 13. Ray Price
ENNIS'S TEAM: 1. Billy Slater 2. Suliasi Vunivalu 3. Will Chambers 4. James Roberts 5. Valentine Holmes 6. Johnathan Thurston 7. Cooper Cronk 8. Jesse Bromwich 9. Cameron Smith 10. Andrew Fifita 11. Matt Gillett 12. Wade Graham 13. Paul Gallen
FOX LEAGUE's Retro Round celebrates rugby league in the 1980s and will be brought to life on FOX LEAGUE throughout the week and across Round 22.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper Cronk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haynes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MAL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JT</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Shearer 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Sironen 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Roberts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's Will Chambers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Ennis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Kenny 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally Lewis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally Lewis 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Sterling 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Smith 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Sterling</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gene Miles 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Price</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarryd Hayne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Rapana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fifita 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ENNIS'S TEAM: 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurston</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Dugan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Graham 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Burgess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Roach 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Kenny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Mortimer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ENNIS SNUBS HAYNE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sterlo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holmes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Roberts 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Gallen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslander Mal Meninga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockyer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Retro Round</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meningas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ennis</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentine Holmes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Jack 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wade Graham, 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Grothe 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wally</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valentine Holmes 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SURPRISED BY MENINGA'S ABSENCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suliasi Vunivalu 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Johns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan Thurston 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daly Cherry-Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Elias 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Bromwich 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Bird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Lockyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurston-Lockyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox League's Retro Round</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ennis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TEAM: 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Davidson 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chambers 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gene Miles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dylan Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Gillett 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Roach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooper Cronk 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
