<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412447282160680</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/confidential/nerves-wont-be-a-factor-for-the-host-of-the-footy-show-as-the-show-gets-a-revamp/news-story/c9ddaf51a96ccfb2926cf1b4c1f5ec0f</url>
  <title>Footy Show fever</title>
  <content>
REBECCA Maddern admits she was so nervous the first time she co-hosted The Footy Show in 2016, but next week will be a different story.
Maddern, Eddie McGuire and Sam Newman are gearing up for the premiere of revamped The Footy Show, shooting promotional material for Channel 9 on Monday.
She told Confidential that she is much more confident and knows what to expect this time around.
"I won't be as nervous as my first night on The Footy Show, I can guarantee you that," she said.
"I will feel a lot more relaxed.
"My first night on The Footy Show, I can hardly put it into works.
"I was a nervous wreck, to say the least.
"This time around it's in familiar territory, it's going to be different, but it's also going to be the same.
"I'm really looking forward to that moment."
Maddern also paid tribute to outgoing host Craig Hutchison, especially the way he has handles the situation.
"It doesn't surprise me how he handled the situation" she said.
"I wouldn't expect anything less of Hutchy, because he is a really classy person."
Nine will today announce details of its annual My Room Telethon, which will take place this year on Thursday, August 24.
Maddern visited the Monash Children's Hospital, along with Collingwood's Taylor Adams, where they met little Harvey (pictured left, with his brothers Alfie and Charlie), who is battling leukaemia.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood's Taylor Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footy Show</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Hutchison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie McGuire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REBECCA Maddern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maddern</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hutchy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Room Telethon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
