<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411626943395141</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/more-news/is-this-the-end-for-west-coast-veteran-sam-mitchell/news-story/c162e9723688aa3242e75ff74416205d</url>
  <title>Mitchell draws end to decorated career</title>
  <content>
"IT'S time for me to hang up the little waddle and the little size 9s."
With those words, Brownlow medallist and West Coast veteran Sam Mitchell today announced 2017 would be his last playing season.
Mitchell himself admitted it was no surprise, given widespread speculation that he would move into full-time coaching next year had bubbled away for much of the season and intensified in recent weeks.
The 34-year-old four-time Hawthorn premiership player it was a "reasonably simple" decision that was made in the early part of the season.
But Mitchell said the time was now right to announce, given West Coast's final fixtured game in Melbourne is this Sunday against St Kilda at Etihad Stadium.
"We've had this planned for a while," he said. "Some friends and family who want to come along and perhaps watch me play. I thought this was a good time to get it done."
Mitchell said he believed there was plenty of life in West Coast's season, with four regular season games left and potentially finals.
"It's my belief we'll be there the last Saturday in September," Mitchell said.
"I'm really excited for what could happen in the next eight weeks. I don't look at this as four games to go. There's a lot of life left in this season and I'm really excited to pursue that.
"Is our form good enough right now, to go on and win a premiership? No. But do we have the ability within our four walls? It's certainly not out of the question"
He said his passion had drifted more to coaching than playing after taking on a part-time role since moving to Perth.
"The reason for me, over the course of the year, perhaps even longer than that, Monday mornings I wake up and I've got some coaching responsibilities and some playing responsibilities," Mitchell said.
"The idea of going my computer and doing the coaching side of things was a bit more exciting. The passion for that has outgrown the passion to jump in the pool and do my own recovery. The time for me is right."
Mitchell paid tribute to a host of football identities who helped him through his decorated career, but particularly thanked his wife Lyndall and three children Smith, Scarlett and Emmi, who attended a packed press conference at Domain Stadium today.
Mitchell admitted he had been a polarising figure in the AFL community, but said he had been fully embraced by his Eagles teammates.
"I spoke to the boys yesterday," he said.
"The way they've embraced me, after eight or 10 months, is just first class.
"My past is with Hawthorn but my future is with the Eagles.
Mitchell's specific role in the West Coast coaching group is yet to be finalised.
Mitchell retires as one of the most decorated players in the game, with his 2012 Brownlow Medal accompanied by five Hawthorn best-and-fairest awards (2006, 2009, 2011, 2012 and 2016) and three All-Australian jumpers (2011, 2013 and 2015).
Mitchell has been one of the Eagles' most consistent players this season, averaging 27 disposals.
Adam Simpson speaks to 7 News

SAM MITCHELL'S CAREER AT A GLANCE
Drafted: 2001 by Hawthorn (pick 36)
Age: 34 (fifth-oldest current AFL player)
Games: 323 (307 Hawthorn, 16 West Coast)
Goals: 69
Disposals: 8529 (fifth all-time)
Premierships in 2008, 2013, 2014, 2015
Brownlow Medallist in 2012
Brownlow votes: 220 (equal-most in AFL era)
Club champion in 2006, 2009, 2011, 2012, 2016
All-Australian in 2011, 2013, 2015
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn, 16 West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyndall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emmi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medallist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domain Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAM MITCHELL'S CAREER AT A GLANCE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
