<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411236101364896</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/lifestyle/celebrity/jessica-lange-speaks-out-on-pervasive-problem-of-ageism-in-hollywood-20170802-gxnjx0.html</url>
  <title>Jessica Lange speaks out on 'pervasive' problem of ageism in Hollywood</title>
  <content>
In recent years Jessica Lange has become an unapologetic voice in the fight against the sexism and ageism women face in the film industry. As AARP  August cover star, the actor opened up about  her career, her most famous romances and what she calls the "pervasive" problem of ageism in Hollywood.
After discussing her work in various roles including King Kong, Tootsie and a Street Car Named Desire, the 68-year-old opened up about her unexpected transition into television, particularly the horror genre.  Lange revealed she never intended to work on American Horror Story for more than one season, but was convinced to stay on for four years by Ryan Murphy, who labelled her "a great seducer."Photo: Jessica Dale/ Eleven Publicity
It was her work on the project that made Lange realise television is one of the many places Hollywood's older women turn to when they are no longer considered for "important" film roles. As Lange pointed out, the outdated issue of age differences between men and women when it comes to playing on-screen romantic interests is still minimising the roles for older women. 
"Ageism is pervasive in this industry. It's not a level playing field. You don't often see women in their 60s playing romantic leads, yet you will see men in their 60s playing romantic leads with co-stars who are decades younger," she AARP.Photo: AP
"I think about how few wonderful actresses of my generation are still doing viable, important film work. You go to television. You go to the stage. You do whatever you can because you want to keep working."
In the age where Lange continues to rule alongside her industry counterparts Meryl Streep, Helen Mirren and Susan Sarandon, the actor revealed that happiness has been a key component in maintaining her successful career. It's clearly working for the Supporting Actress Oscar winner who is still winning; she received an Emmy for 2014's American Horror Story: Coven, and a Tony for her performance in 2016's A Long Day's Journey into the Night.

"In recent years I've tried to come to grips with the idea that you can actually choose to be happy. You can choose not to let things affect you negatively. I've always had such a quick temper. I realise now, it's such a waste of energy. You can actually choose to let things roll off you." she said.
Lange also spoke candidly about her relationship with  who passed away this week. The pair met in 1982 on the set of Frances, and were together for almost three decades till their split in 2009.
"I wouldn't call Sammy easygoing and funny, but everybody has their dark side, and he always does it with a sense of humour," she told AARP.
While they never married, Lange and Sheppard had two children together,  Hannah Jane and Samuel Walker. During the interview she emphasised the profound impact that her children and grandchildren on her  life perspectives.
"Having children gives you a perspective you didn't have before. You are no longer the centre of the universe," she said.
"It opened my heart, made me a different person. Every move you make is with someone else in mind. I loved being a mother more than anything else in the world, and being a grandmother is even more fun."
This isn't the first time Lange has spoken about Hollywood's discrepancies when it comes to gender equality. Earlier this year Lange took part in a round table with Feud co-star and friend Susan Sarandon to discuss how the commodification of women is not exclusive to Hollywood, but  an issue that women need to start conversations about in every industry.
"At a certain age women are no longer considered a viable or a valuable part of the community - even if that's when they may feel like they're at the top of their game. And that's not just in Hollywood," she said to  during the interview.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tootsie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hannah Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Car Named Desire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Day's Journey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Horror Story</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supporting Actress Oscar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Sarandon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meryl Streep</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleven Publicity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sammy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Mirren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lange</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Dale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AARP.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Lange</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AARP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheppard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
