<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412314138172259</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/pair-argued-about-meth-before-death-perth-court-told/news-story/b7e2dddd1542d4718bf3281eaed69e3a</url>
  <title>Pair argued about meth before death</title>
  <content>
A PERTH couple argued about the quality of methamphetamine they had taken before the woman was found dead with ligature marks around her neck, a court has heard.
Damien Couzens is on trial in the Supreme Court of WA, charged with murdering his on-and-off partner of 10 years Jody Websdale at her Midland unit in March last year.

Before the 42-year-old was found unresponsive in the courtyard, she had taken meth and other drugs including cannabis and benzodiazepenes, while he had shot up meth and drunk alcohol, the court heard on Wednesday.
Prosecutor Les Hobson said a visitor looked outside to check on them and saw Couzens standing over Ms Websdale holding a broom or a pole, saying "get up" and trying to wake her by nudging her with his foot.
Mr Hobson said the visitor described Couzens as seeming "really aggro" as he went back inside to make some food, closing the curtains behind him and turning up music.
Mr Hobson said the visitor went briefly to his sister's unit, which was in the same complex, and when he returned, Couzens looked "really scared" and said: "Help me try and wake her up."
The court heard Couzens was aggressive towards paramedics and wouldn't let them do their job properly.
When police arrived, he told them Ms Websdale hung herself or may have jumped out of the second-storey window.
Initially he said "you won't find it" when asked where the rope was, but one was found and he then told police he had made it himself and carried it around for years, the prosecutor said.
Mr Hobson also told the jury they would see a video recording of Couzens' police interview in which he said: "I don't know what I'm capable of doing when I'm under the influence of drugs and alcohol."
Defence counsel Justine Fisher urged the jury to reserve their judgment until they had heard all the evidence, saying drug use was central to the case.
Ms Websdale's daughters attended the trial along with their brother Kirk Ugle, a former Collingwood footballer.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIDLAND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jody Websdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Couzens</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court of WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Websdale</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justine Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damien Couzens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirk Ugle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hobson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Hobson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
