<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412404332486996</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/school-bus-service-boost-after-fears-about-stalker-following-students/news-story/f9e87840e1c37ec61d61fac96c4dc67a</url>
  <title>School bus win for parents</title>
  <content>
CONCERNED parents who had been battling for more than a year for a second school bus have won their fight at last.
Teenagers, some as young as 13, had been left stranded by the roadside in Dingley Village as their overcrowded bus failed to stop for them.
Mum Catherine Berry, who had set up an online petition calling for another bus, welcomed news of the extra bus just weeks after Leader highlighted parental fears about children being left alone on the street.

"I'm really happy and surprised that this had happened and thank the Leader," Ms Berry said.
"Hopefully more kids will feel more comfortable now. This will open up the bus service to younger groups as well."
Furious parents told Leader at the end of June that students going from Dingley Village to Parkdale Secondary College only had one bus in the morning and two in the afternoon.
They said the safety of young students was at risk, especially as police had issued warnings there were reports of a man in a red sedan following children in Mentone.

Police were investigating four stalking incidents throughout June and schools had issued warnings about him to their students.
Public Transport Victoria this week introduced a second morning bus.
Labor Member for Mordialloc Tim Richardson said two 8.15am buses would run between Dingley Village and Parkdale Secondary and drop students inside the college grounds about 8.32am.
"The second bus will ensure that all students can now get on a direct service," Mr Richardson said.
"I understand PTV will continue to review services for schools in the area to ensure they are meeting the needs of families."
Ms Berry urged the school to make all parents aware of the new service.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mordialloc Tim Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dingley Village</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkdale Secondary College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Member</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkdale Secondary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mentone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
