<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411459439668108</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>03:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/breaking-news/top-of-the-lake-inspired-big-little-lies/news-story/034254c29bfa11a449b491bcd9a848dd</url>
  <title>Top Of The Lake inspired Big Little Lies</title>
  <content>
Nicole Kidman has made some surprising and successful career turns over the past year, one of the biggest has been her foray into TV.
She starred in and served as executive producer on the hit show Big Little Lies with Reese Witherspoon and will soon be seen in a curly grey wig for a role in the second season of Jane Campion's dark drama Top Of The Lake.
Her turn to TV transpired when she joined forces with Witherspoon because they were both disappointed by the film offers they were receiving.
"Reese and I were frustrated because we weren't being offered the sort of roles that we wanted in terms of complexity and so that (Big Little Lies) was born out of a desire to create an opportunity for ourselves and our friends," Kidman said at the Sydney premiere of Top Of The Lake: China Girl.
TV has now become a place where women are offered more interesting roles, and Kidman said she's lucky to have been a part of two TV shows that put women front and centre with men in the supporting roles.
"I think in television right now there's great opportunity for women because obviously it's a place in which there's money and there's directors of this calibre, Ariel (Kleiman) and Jane (Campion), who are willing to work in that medium and write and explore their storytelling and that for some reason certainly has created more roles for us," she said.
Creating a TV show from the Australian novel Big Little Lies, she revealed, was actually inspired by Campion's series which debuted in 2013, starring Elizabeth Moss.
"We saw Top of the Lake and we saw what they were able to accomplish and that was how we were able to go 'Oh maybe we can do Big Little Lies' because at the same time there was True Detective which had the male leads and we went 'We want to do something that's got female leads that's set in America but we were inspired by Top of the Lake, I think that was the stepping stone," Kidman said.
She was really happy to have been part of two dramatic TV shows with a primarily female cast, and also hinted that she's interested in trying her hand at comedy next.
"Someone asked me about playing comedy and I said well I just don't really get offered it but I would love to do it," she said.
The second season of Top Of The lake was filmed in Sydney last year, moving the series from its original rural location in New Zealand.
Campion is hoping the series may return for a third season to where it began.
"I have a little bit of a dream about a closing series which would return there (the NZ lake) which will make us feel better about our title," Campion said.
* Top of the Lake will air on BBC First from August 20 at 8.30pm
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elizabeth Moss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reese Witherspoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Kidman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Little Lies</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>True Detective</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campion</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kidman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Girl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ariel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kleiman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC First</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Campion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Witherspoon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top of the Lake</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
