<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411326295679717</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Mining</source>
  <url>https://www.australianmining.com.au/news/komatsu-unleashes-technology-make-mine-construction-smarter/</url>
  <title>Komatsu unleashes technology to make mine construction smarter - Australian Mining</title>
  <content>
Komatsu's new technology enhances the use of drones

Latest News

Komatsu has launched a project management technology it says will add significant benefits to the construction phase of mining.
The equipment manufacturer this week unveiled its SMARTCONSTRUCTION technology in Australia and New Zealand.
It describes the concept as a significant step forward in construction technology, offering integrated product, service and support solutions across all phases of a project.
Aaron Marsh, Komatsu Australia's national technology solution expert manager - construction, and head of intelligent machine control at its Smart Centre, said the concept allowed the company to integrate a host of technologies.
"With these new technologies, we are now able to provide an end-to-end solution for our customers across construction, quarrying and mining," Marsh said.
SMARTCONSTRUCTION covers critical project development steps, from initial site survey and design, through to machine control management, machine interconnectivity and review of project progress during the construction phase.
Finally, it develops detailed as-built information for future construction and infrastructure maintenance.
According to Komatsu, the new technology covers four key areas, including the use of unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) drones, covering initial site surveys, along with cut/fill and stockpile calculations, as well as ongoing progress tracking and site logistics.
It covers 3D data services, including conversion of 2D and 3D data files to formats suitable for machine control applications, and 3D design consultancy, development and management over the life of a project.
SMARTCONSTRUCTION offers the Komconnect cloud-based service, bringing together all the project-related information, from initial survey, design drawings and construction plans, through to machine control data files, project progress data generated by machines and survey equipment as the job progresses, and final as-built information once it is completed.
It also provides support services, covering remote monitoring, remote file transfer and operating training, iMC (intelligent Machine Control) advice, project integration and site set up, assistance and professional consultancy with 3D design file development, troubleshooting and servicing of machines and control systems.
To deliver SMARTCONSTRUCTION across ANZ, Marsh said Komatsu has established the Komatsu Smart Centre, with a team of company-trained technology solution experts and a national remote support team.
"SMARTCONSTRUCTION builds on our industry-leading expertise in machine management through our INSITE fleet management centre, KOMTRAX remote monitoring service, along with our highly innovative iMC - intelligent Machine Control - offerings, which are currently available in dozers and excavators," Marsh said.
"We are building on these technologies with the introduction of our drone-based survey and site management technology and now our cloud-based Komconnect information management offering."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMARTCONSTRUCTION</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UAV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Komatsu Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Komatsu</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marsh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Komconnect</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Mining</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KOMTRAX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Machine Control</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Marsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smart Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>INSITE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Komatsu Smart Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
