<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412279778433208</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>06:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/business/breaking-news/nz-dollar-falls-on-weaker-jobs-data/news-story/bb03e9a527ce1b5a05f656eb38be2bde</url>
  <title>NZ dollar falls on weaker jobs data</title>
  <content>
The New Zealand dollar fell after weaker-than-expected employment in the second quarter added to the view the central bank will keep interest rates firmly on hold for longer.
The kiwi was trading at US74.28c at 5pm versus US74.70c at 8am in Wellington from 75.04c late Tuesday..
The kiwi took a tumble after Statistics New Zealand released figures showing employment shrank 0.2 per cent in the three months ended June 30.
Economists polled by Reuters had been expecting growth of 0.7 per cent, extending the run of gains into a seventh quarter.
The participation rate dropped to 70 per cent from 70.6 per cent.
ASB Bank chief economist Nick Tuffley said the data reinforces the idea that the RBNZ will be in no rush to raise interest rates anytime soon and pushed out when he expects the next rate increase.
"We now expect the RBNZ will leave the official cash rate on hold until February 2019, previously November 2018," he said.
The central bank has indicated it plans to keep interest rates on hold at 1.75 per cent before lifting them in 2019.
"It was all on the data. And since that point the kiwi has been on the back foot. We've also seen quite a bit of selling against the Aussie," said Martin Rudings, senior dealer foreign exchange at OMF in Wellington.
The kiwi traded at A93.33c versus A93.48c and Mr Rudings said it could test below A93c later in the global trading day.
The jobs data means the central bank "is more likely to be on their hands for a very long time", he said.
The kiwi traded at 62.80 euro cents from 63.43 cents and slipped to 82.34 yen from 82.69 yen. It declined to 56.23 British pence from 56.77 pence and traded at 4.9957 yuan from 5.0409 yuan.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OMF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASB Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Statistics New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Tuffley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBNZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rudings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Rudings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US74.28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US74.70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
