<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412567541247313</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/markets/the-rba-says-more-needs-to-be-done-to-promote-economics-20170801-gxnif4</url>
  <title>The RBA says more needs to be done to promote economics</title>
  <content>
by
Philip Baker

Go and ask a typical teenager what they think of economics and it's a fair bet they won't even have to utter a word and you'll know the answer.
The blank look on their face will say it all. If they do answer maybe get ready for: It's so boring: It's useless. You can't use any of it. It's a scam.
Dismal science indeed. It's so bad even the Reserve Bank of Australia thinks it's an issue and more needs to be done to engage young people with the subject.
"In essence, economics has an image problem," said the RBA's Jacqui Dwyer, the head of the information department, in a speech to an education conference last weekend.

For sure economics can have competing paradigms and rival themes and forecasting can be a tough business, but good public policy needs the analytical skills you get by studying economics.

Yet no one is.
Dwyer's speech contained some alarming statistics that show a large decline over the past 25 years in the number of Year 12 students taking economics as a subject.
There has also been a substantial drop in the number of schools that even bother to offer economics as a subject.﻿
Gender trends

Dywer and the RBA worry  that if students continue to sidestep traditional economics in favour of "new and arguably less demanding subjects", such as business studies, then you're not going to get a good outcome when it comes to the big issues like long-term economic growth, jobs, climate change, income distribution, property prices and how to avoid another financial crisis.
Since 1992 the number of students doing economics in year 12 has fallen by 70 per cent, according to Dwyer.
"While most of this decline occurred in the early 1990s, there has been a continued downward drift. This national pattern reflects very similar trends across the Australian states" she said.
The drop off has been exacerbated by gender trends. 

In 1992 around 50 per cent of students who were studying economics in their final year at school were female whereas now  just over one third of female students are taking it.
So where did it all go wrong?
The arrival of "business studies" in 1991 has had a huge impact and is a major reason for the decline in economics.
Business studies is now the fourth most popular subject, and is arguably a little easier to do, but even Dwyer notes there's more to it than that.

Back in the 1980s and early 1990s there was a huge amount of national debate about financial deregulation that saw the Australian dollar floated and foreign banks open offices here. Then there was the labour market deregulation and tariff reform that were all hot topics of the day, she said.
But those days are gone. Now there's more pure politics at play and the state of the economy gets left to one side.
In addition, if schools don't offer the subject, it becomes less "core".
And then it gets back to the

"The bank's liaison has found that too few students understand what economics is and how it might be relevant to them," says Dwyer.
Teaching resources

"Too few educators are equipped to teach it, and a growing share of high school teachers are delivering economics courses without having studied the subject." 
Then it just feeds on itself with not enough careers advisers, or educators, who can tell how it does relate to  day-to-day living.
And then before you know it, Dwyer says, "little relevant Australian economic content and teaching resources are available".
A common complaint about economics these days is the large amount of mathematics involved, when the really interesting part is the insights into human behaviour and what makes them decide on a certain course of action.
One way to make economics more interesting is the website that uses Seinfeld episodes to explain certain concepts.
For example, one  episode was devoted to how long Jerry, Elaine and George had to wait for a table at a Chinese restaurant.  

They opted to stay and wait despite getting hungry and with plenty of other restaurants nearby.
That should help students understand opportunity cost.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwyer</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seinfeld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elaine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA's Jacqui Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jerry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dywer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philip Baker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
