<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412528886540673</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/teams/titans/matt-gillett-believes-jarrod-wallace-can-go-from-benchwarmer-to-world-cup-star/news-story/029e49f2ddbbb3280890876472190d64</url>
  <title>Could Wallace take final step in rapid rise?</title>
  <content>
LCTV: Round 22 Tipping Show

MATT Gillett believes former Broncos teammate Jarrod Wallace can go from bench player to Origin to the Kangaroos, as the pair prepare to meet in Saturday™s derby clash against the Titans.

Brisbane's forward pack has labelled Wallace as one of their biggest threats for this weekend's showdown, following a standout season for the young prop.

Wallace left the Broncos at the end of last year, after three seasons of being a regular off the bench for Brisbane.

Since he joined the Titans he has flourished as a player, starring as one of the club's best forwards and earning his Queensland Origin debut earlier this year.

But Gillett says even though the Gold Coast can no longer make this year's finals, he believes Wallace still has plenty to prove, especially with the World Cup awaiting in October.

"If he continues to play the quality football he's been doing so far, there's no reason he wouldn't be in the mix for an Australian jersey," Gillett said of Wallace.

"Jarrod just has to focus on what he can do. He can't get too far ahead of himself.

"That's probably the reason he did move, to cement a starting spot and show what he can do.

NO THANKS:

SEVEN YEARS:

"It was a big move for him. Obviously he would have loved to have stayed here but it was a big decision and one I'm sure he's pretty happy with."

The last time Wallace met the Broncos he ran for 252m in a stunning performance at Suncorp Stadium.

Gillett said if the Broncos are not careful he could do the same again.

"He seems to be playing a lot bigger minutes and getting through plenty of work," he said.

"He does get his hands on the ball a lot and gets them on the front foot. The focus for us is slowing him down and his front-row partner in Ryan James."

Sam Thaiday was also of the opinion that Wallace will be a danger man at Cbus Super Stadium on Saturday and expects him to lead the forward pack.

"Playing here at the Broncos and the year that he has had so far, he will want to come out and prove a point against some of our forwards," Thaiday said.

"I'm sure he will be putting his hand up to lead that forward pack.

"Last time he played against us he ran for almost 200m so he will want to do that again and prove a point that we shouldn't have let him go."

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 22 Tipping Show</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Thaiday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Gillett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillett</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cbus Super Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallace</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Titans</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thaiday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jarrod Wallace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
