<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412657735562184</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4828527/the-mental-health-of-lawyers-a-focus-for-rmb/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>RMB one of the first law firms in Australia to indroduce a new mental health and wellbeing initiative</title>
  <content>
The RMB Lawyers team in Wollongong

Illawarra law firm  is introducing a new initiative to improve the mental health and wellbeing of its lawyers.
The century old business with a presence in Wollongong, the Southern Highlands, Shoalhaven and Sydney knows that in the fast-paced world of law dealing with high stakes and tackling heavy workloads can have a significant impact on lawyer's mental wellbeing.

Industry statistics reveal that one-in-three lawyers will suffer some form of stress, depression, anxiety or burnout.

RMB Lawyers is tackling the issue head on by ensuring a supportive workplace environment. It is incorporating a new initiative designed to assist lawyers in managing the mental impact the profession can have.
In fact RMB is one of the first law firms to introduce the Mindfulness Training Program delivered by Chelsea Pottenger who is an accredited mindfulness teacher from EQ Consulting.

Ms Pottenger is studying a Doctorate in Clinical Psychology and Neuroscience. She has worked with national companies such as eBay, Cook Medical, GrainCorp, QBE and Dexus Property, to implement strategies and practices that improve the mental health and general wellbeing of employees in the workplace.
RMB Lawyers managing partner Craig Osborne said the firm wants to make sure that the mental health and wellbeing of its employees comes first.

The program helps improve their mind strength and performance while keeping happy and healthy. "Our lawyers perform high volumes of complex work at a high speed and work long days. To ensure that we continue to deliver outstanding service to our clients, we need to keep our minds healthy, focused and sharp".

"The program is already teaching us how to switch the pressure and stress on and off and to give ourselves allocated time to allow our minds to regenerate and be ready for the next challenge, which is very important," Mr Osborne said.

Partner and Family Law Division leader Claire Osborne said it was vitally important for RMB employees to be educated about mindfulness as the nature of their work sees them exposed to stressful situations daily.
"Being aware and informed means that our lawyers may be more inclined to practice mindfulness and improve their mental health and general wellbeing. The mindfulness training is about individuals incorporating mediation into their daily routine. Practicing mediation twice a day over an eight-week period has been found to equip employees to manage stressful situations with a more positive approach. It's important that our lawyers develop a better work-life balance and lifestyles that will provide them with a positive foundation for a healthy way to live."

Ms Pottender said the aim of the program for RMB Lawyers was to improve internal conditions for performance such as focus, clarity of thought and reducing reactivity and perceived stress, which can lead to greater efficiency and productivity for the firm. 
"Lawyers, just like any other employee in the corporate world, need strategies and practices to help them cope with burnout and improving their wellbeing. This mindfulness program will help lawyers react to stress, change, adversity and threats differently, so they can respond with a calmer and more focused approach. Law firms are now recognising the importance of mindfulness and the impact it has on their employee's resilience," she said.

RMB will continue to work with Ms Pottenger to implement the Mindfulness Training Program over the course of eight weeks for the 18 lawyers participating.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cook Medical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eBay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Pottenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMB Lawyers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Pottender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Pottenger</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clinical Psychology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QBE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claire Osborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMB</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dexus Property</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graincorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EQ Consulting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Law Division</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Osborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Osborne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mindfulness Training Program</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Highlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
