<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412657735562153</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/bidgee-boxing-gym-tackling-crime-and-homelessness/8766526</url>
  <title>Bidgee Boxing Gym in Narrandera helps cut crime and keep kids off the streets</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Trae Warren-Hickson is just 20 years old, unemployed and living in Narrandera, a small country town in New South Wales that is experiencing a rising crime rate.
A few years ago, Trae might have been caught up in that.
"I used to be real bad. My parents split up at a very young age. I was a street kid myself," he said.
"I used to hang around the streets and get in a lot of trouble, get locked up."
Today though, he has got more important things to focus on: boxing.
Trae is a member at Narrandera's new and only boxing gym, Bidgee Boxing, which opened a few weeks ago.
The gym was the brainchild of Neville Bamblett, a long-time boxing lover who was born in the town and raised by his grandmother, after his parents got mixed up in drugs.
"I've lived in Narrandera all my life and it's been a dream of mine to give something back," Mr Bamblett said.
"I can see a lot of me and what I grew up with in Trae and a lot of the kids that come through the door.
"I want to do what I can to give them the best shot at the best possible life they can achieve."

And he believes a boxing gym is the perfect way to do that.
"The stuff for youth in town is not much, so when there's no places like this to go they tend to hang around the streets," he said.
"But if they come to a gym, we can work them out, drain their energy, so all they want to do is eat and sleep.
"My aim is to help youth stay focused during life, keep them on good tracks and keep them in school."
Fun times and important lessons

The gym is not-for-profit, with primary school-aged children paying $2 a visit, annual memberships for 15-18-year-olds costing $150 and adults paying $300 per year.
"All that money goes straight back into the gym," Mr Bamblett said.
"It pays our rent. It'll cover new equipment when we need it and just generally makes sure we stay up and running."
Mr Bamblett runs the gym while also working full-time, and has a team of trainers who volunteer their time.
Most of the equipment has been donated.
All ages flock to gym to train

Primary school children are coming in droves to Bidgee Boxing, as are teens and young adults.
Mr Bamblett could not be happier to see the sport he loved enrich young people's lives in the town he grew up in.
"Boxing teaches kids to focus. It teaches them a lot of respect and discipline," he said.
"People think that with boxing you'll slug it out and get head damage, but if people learn how to fight and know how to fight, they don't fight."
What has Mr Bamblett really smiling is the mix of people who have signed up, from school children to retirees.
"We've had members come in that are 70 and 75. They come in early in the mornings and work out, which is so good to see," he said.
"That's what we want. We want people to come together. Seeing the kids and the adults helping each other is a big part of it. It's what I like to see and what I'm aiming for."

Trae sets his sights high

As for Trae, his dreams are big.
"I'm an amateur boxer at the moment but I want to go pro eventually," he said.
"For now, I just love training and showing all the young fellas a bit of what Nev's taught me.
"He's a great bloke and what he's doing for the community is really good. I'm trying to pass it on to everyone else, I guess."
It is not just in the gym that Trae leads by example.
"Before I come here, I usually go to the skate park and ask some of the young fellas to come and train with me," he said.
"They usually do so we get a few young fellas in here that are usually on the streets, but not no more."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bidgee Boxing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narrandera</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trae</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bamblett</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bidgee Boxing Gym</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neville Bamblett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trae Warren-Hickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
