<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412619080855817</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/quality-property-quality-home/3208057/</url>
  <title>Quality property, quality home</title>
  <content>
YOU will not be disappointed when inspecting this immaculate and well maintained acreage property, absolutely everything has been thought of here ensuring an extremely comfortable lifestyle.
Set on beautiful and all useable fully fenced 6.5acres, this property was once a working farm but now the owners simply enjoy the privacy and seclusion of living in the country.
The home is magnificent in every way with just over 260sq m of impeccable presentation inside and out, there is absolutely nothing left to do for the lucky purchaser except to move in and enjoy.
Stunning hickory ash floorboards flow throughout the vast open plan design which is further enhanced by contrasting white walls and high ceilings creating a bright and cheerful atmosphere within.
Enjoy the luxury of ducted reverse cycle air-conditioning along with an abundance of louvre windows to allow for cross flow ventilation and outdoor viewing from every angle.
The kitchen is positioned correctly within the home combining functionality with a lovely outlook to the front verandah and beyond and highlighting quality appliances along with ample storage and bench space. All the bedrooms are exquisitely presented as is the extra-large master bedroom which features a huge walk-in robe with all the trimmings and a large ensuite with separate toilet.
Beautiful full length north facing verandah not only adds character to the home but is the ultimate place to put your feet up and take it easy whilst savouring the winter sun and gazing out over the acreage.
A 108sq m shed with attached 81sq m machinery shed sits in a prominent position on the property with three-phase power, nice and high to cater for over-sized vehicles.
A very good working bore services all the gardens and farm land including a large quantity of fruit trees, a 50,000 buried concrete tank services the home as does the biolytix biocycle and the home also features solar hotwater, three phase power and NBN wireless.
COOTHARABA
607 Cootharaba Road
4 Bed, 2 Bath, 10 Car
Features: Impeccable home on fully fenced 2.63ha. Ducted reverse cycle air-conditioning, louvre windows and cross flow ventilation, north-facing veranda, machinery shed, bore, water tank, solar hot water, NBN wireless
Price: Offers over $725,000
Agent: Sandra Upton at HANGloosa Property Noosa
Contact: 0418 152 396
Inspection: Saturday 11-11.45am
Tourist track takes toll with plenty of motorists caught out
Turn your dream of owning a hip cafe or bar into a reality.
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
Coast researchers closing in on prawns behind white spot devastation
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>COOTHARABA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bed, 2 Bath, 10 Car</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cootharaba Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HANGloosa Property Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandra Upton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
