<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412614785888384</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-league/league-news/melbourne-storm-grapple-with-ryley-jacks-or-jahrome-hughes-as-cameron-munster-misses-with-injury-20170802-gxnx5n.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne Storm grapple with Ryley Jacks or Jahrome Hughes as Cameron Munster misses with injury</title>
  <content>
Melbourne Storm coach Craig Bellamy says he is unsure who will play at five-eighth in the absence of injured star Cameron Munster.
The Storm left Munster out of their travelling party for the clash with North Queensland Cowboys in Townsville on Friday night after he injured his ankle against Manly last round.Photo: AAP
Rookie back Ryley Jacks has been named to start in the role but impressive fullback Jahrome Hughes starred last game and remains in the squad despite Billy Slater returning to the fullback role.
Munster played out the Manly game but was seen around AAMI Park in a moon boot and resting his injury foot on a wheelie cart earlier this week.
But Bellamy scotched any idea Munster has a serious injury saying they expected Munster back as early as next game, if not soon after.
"I don't know why he was on that," Bellamy said before the team flew to Townsville on Wednesday.

"They put them in a moon boot these days if they break a toe-nail so I'm not sure how long he is going to be in that and I'm not quite sure why he was on a scooter - that might have been Munster lairing up, particularly because it is him.
"They are thinking it will only be a week but it could be longer depending on how quickly he recovers, he has been a quick healer with past injuries - hopefully he will be right for next week."

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Jacks and Hughes have both made strong claims to play on Friday night and Bellamy said he had yet to decide who to pick.
Jacks played the first part of the season in the role before Slater's return prompted Munster move to the role but Hughes has scored three tries in his three games.
"We haven't decided on it yet, we have only had one quick training and tried both of them there," Bellamy said.
"Jahrome hasn't played much there [for Storm] and Ryley has but we will have another look at them tomorrow at training."
The Cowboys have become one of the Storm's great rivals after beating them in the 2015 preliminary final at AAMI Park before the Storm beat them in last year's finals.
But Cowboys star Johnathan Thurston is out for the campaign with injury so younger backs such as Michael Morgan will look to engineer a win over the Storm.
The Storm's forward pack has been in good form   even without New Zealand star Tohu Harris who has missed the past few weeks with a shoulder problem.
"He has had a couple of injuries this season which is foreign to him - he usually gets through well," Bellamy said.
"He is probably still a couple more weeks away which is not great, we want to give him every chance to get over his injury and be right for the rest of the year.
"We would like to see him play three or four games if we can but he misses this one so hopefully we get three games out of him but we will see how he comes up."
Storm play the Cowboys in Townsville on Friday at 7.45pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jahrome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellamy</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Munster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Billy Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Slater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Storm</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Munster</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryley Jacks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Bellamy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jahrome Hughes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tohu Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Cowboys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
