<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412704980203256</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/breaking-news/terror-suspects-life-turned-upside-down/news-story/c66508c1674afea9737e1b4e7513ba10</url>
  <title>Terror suspect's 'life turned upside down'</title>
  <content>
Jamie McKinnellAustralian Associated Press

Share

It is "unfathomable" that a Sydney man arrested over a terrorist plot to bring down an aircraft had anything to do with the alleged conspiracy, his lawyer says.
Abdul Merhi, 50, was released without charge on Tuesday night, more than three days after he was arrested during a series of police raids across four Sydney suburbs.
Three other men remain behind bars after Australian Federal Police were granted the power to hold them for up to seven days. That period will expire on Sunday evening.
Mr Merhi's solicitor Moustafa Kheir says he's concerned his client's identity was revealed and has declared he'll "review what basis police had to do what they did".
"That's caused a lot of damage to him," Mr Kheir told AAP on Wednesday.
"He's had his life turned upside down.
"It's just unfathomable that he would be associated with anything like this."
Police have searched properties in Lakemba, Wiley Park, Punchbowl and Surry Hills in search of evidence.
Mr Merhi's lawyer says his client's release indicates authorities found nothing to implicate him.

"He just wants to go back to as normal life as possible now ... he was shocked that he was being questioned."
Little has been confirmed officially but authorities have said the plot involved plans to "bring down" an aircraft using an "improvised device".
Etihad Airways has confirmed it is assisting with the investigation.
One theory is the plan involved hiding a device inside a meat grinder.
"This investigation remains ongoing and further information will be provided at an appropriate time," the AFP and NSW Police said in a joint statement on Wednesday.
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull wouldn't be drawn on Mr Merhi's release.
"At this point, it's very important I respect the integrity of the investigation process," he told reporters in Albany.
The alleged plot has led to heightened security at airports across Australia, and on Wednesday the peak body for commercial pilots demanded permanent change.
AusALPA president Captain Murray Butt backed calls for all passengers to be required to produce photographic identification as they must in the US.
"We certainly don't want to alarm the public," he said in Sydney.
"But we want to make sure we're providing the best service that we can and the safest service that we can."
Pilots are worried caterers and baggage handlers aren't screened to the same degree as air crew. They say their concerns have been ignored for years.
The alleged plan has been described by Deakin University terror expert Professor Greg Barton as "clearly the most sophisticated terror plot we've had, probably ever, in Australia".
He believes it may have involved the use of acetone peroxide - or TATP - the same powerful chemical used in Manchester Arena bombing in May and the 2015 Paris attacks.
Three suspects continue to be questioned by police.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie McKinnellAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kheir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deakin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester Arena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Greg Barton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Airways</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AusALPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merhi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Murray Butt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TATP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moustafa Kheir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
