<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412614785888405</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/beauty/face-body/mum-nearly-loses-her-top-lip-after-botched-filler-jab-promoted-on-facebook-causes-her-face-to-balloon/news-story/26e040c78a506c16bf532d21f1e3c16c</url>
  <title>Mum nearly loses her top lip after botched filler jab promoted on Facebook causes her face to balloon</title>
  <content>
Siobhan Phelan nearly lost her top lip after botched jab. Picture: The Sun

Shaun Wooller

Share

A MUM was left with a huge trout pout by filler injections she saw promoted on Facebook.
Siobhan Phelan, 30, says she nearly lost her top lip and could be permanently disfigured after the botched jab made it balloon to five times its normal size.
She had a clinic's unregulated $207 treatment because she thought her lips looked too thin.
The Essex mum of two was rushed to hospital in agony and put on a drip containing steroids, antibiotics and painkillers when the swelling began within 24 hours.
Docs told her she was within minutes of losing her lip and she said yesterday: "Facebook should do more to ban rogue beauticians from promoting services like this."
It is thought the beautician at the unnamed clinic mistakenly pumped the filler into an artery, causing a blockage.

Siobhan Phelan nearly loses her top lip after botched filler jab promoted on Facebook. Picture: The SunSource:The Sun

Her lips ballooned after getting the jab. Picture: The SunSource:The Sun
The lip would eventually have burst, turned black and fallen off.
It has since shrunk after Siobhan, of Frinton-on-Sea, was injected with a chemical which dissolves the filler.
But she says a nurse at Broomfield Hospital in Chelmsford said her appearance could be ruined permanently.

Siobhan, who has had fillers every six months for five years, said: "I visited the clinic's Facebook page because a friend got her eyebrows done there.

Siobhan's top lip ballooned after the filler. Picture: The SunSource:The Sun
"I noticed they also offered lip fillers and I was impressed by the before and after pictures.
"It was cheaper than I paid before so I booked an appointment without checking if the clinician was properly qualified.
"I don't want others to make the same mistake."
PA Siobhan added: "The nurse said my lips could be permanently disfigured.
"I may go to a professional to get it fixed.
"I would never touch fillers again. I'm quite vain.
This article originally appeared on  and has been republished with permission.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broomfield Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Wooller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PA Siobhan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siobhan, of Frinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunSource</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siobhan Phelan, 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelmsford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siobhan Phelan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siobhan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
