<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412567541247284</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:18</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/macedon-state-mp-slams-disgraceful-right-to-life-pamphlets/news-story/c4a3d39d77bfdb357dc47c783daf63b9</url>
  <title>MP slams 'disgraceful' Right to Life pamphlets</title>
  <content>
PAMPHLETS authored by Right to Life Australia Inc have hit letterboxes in Woodend and Kyneton urging people to pressure the Macedon state MP to reject a potential 'right to die bill' in State Parliament.
Mary-Anne Thomas told the Leader she became aware of the letters when a string of complaints were received by her office staff yesterday.
Many of the complainants were offended by the materials in the pamphlet, with some believing they were being distributed by Ms Thomas.
The parliamentarian, who said she was still considering her position on what would be landmark provisions paving the way for the terminally ill to end their lives, said she took offence at the content of the pamphlets.
"The pamphlet is disgraceful," she said.
"I have received a lot of calls from residents angry at me and believing this is the tactics I've deployed.
"People who are offended by these pamphlets should direct their concerns to Right to Life Australia."
Ms Thomas said people receiving the letters had every right to be offended.
"This is the worst type of propaganda and for this organisation to conflate suicide with right to die is disrespectful to those in the community effected by either suicide or a terminally ill relative," she said.
"We live in a community which has taken a number of proactive steps in addressing suicide and supporting those affected by it.
"Suicide in the community is a serious issue but it is a totally different issue than assisted dying."
The title of the pamphlet asks 'Do you believe in Suicide Prevention or Suicide Assistance from a Doctor?'
It contains full contact details for Ms Thomas.
Parliament is yet to consider a bill which may pave the way for assisted dying. Among recommendations by an independent committee was for the affected person wishing to end their life to ask at least three times for the right to die.
Right to Life Australia was contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary-Anne Thomas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Life Australia Inc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suicide Assistance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suicide Prevention</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyneton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Thomas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodend</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
