<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411455144700709</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>02:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/waterfront-wonders-around-the-world-to-dream-away-adelaides-cold-weather/news-story/b62ffba5d69dfa126653e911597e560e</url>
  <title>Waterfront wonders around the world to dream away Adelaide's cold weather. - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Punta Minitas 11, Casa de Campo Resort and Villa, La Romana, Dominican Republic. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate.

IF THERE is one thing we can't get enough of while we're in the midst of a cold winter, it's dreaming about sun-drenched summers and luxury waterfront properties. These three stunners will have you packing your swimsuits and ready for drinks by the pool or beach. Have you got your sunscreen ready?
BARRINGTON HILLS, ILLINOIS, US
Price: $12.6 million

45 Lakeview Lane, Barrington Hills, Illinois, United States. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate.

If you asked me to draw a picture of where I'd most like to spend the summer, this prestigious Barrington Hills property would be what I'd try and sketch. I can't draw, so it would end up looking like a dog's breakfast, but I'd be picturing this place.

45 Lakeview Lane, Barrington Hills, Illinois, United States. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate.

Set on a gorgeous lakefront on more than eight acres of stunningly manicured rolling lawns, the home oozes luxury and has five bedrooms, a massive formal entry hall behind solid walnut double doors, floor-top ceiling windows, barrelled and coffered ceilings, custom millwork, and a glass-sided turret.

45 Lakeview Lane, Barrington Hills, Illinois, United States. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate.

Hardwood flooring features throughout and the home also has ornate fireplaces, a fitness centre, a home theatre, a poker/billiards room, a four-car garage and a stunning in-ground swimming pool that's just meant to be enjoyed by aristocratic folk sipping Pimms and eating really tiny sandwiches.
LA ROMANA, DOMINICAN REPUBLIC
Price: $16.4 million

Punta Minitas 11, Casa de Campo Resort and Villa, La Romana, Dominican Republic, La Romana, Dominican Republic. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate.

The Casa de Campo Resort has long been considered the jewel in the crown that is the Dominican Republic, and this unique property is widely regarded to be the resort's best. Set on a three-acre peninsula stretching into the Caribbean Sea, the home hits the market for the first time since it was built.

Punta Minitas 11, Casa de Campo Resort and Villa, La Romana, Dominican Republic. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate.

Designed by Mexican architect Marco Aldaco, who Architect's Digest name in their Top 100 most influential architects, the home offers panoramic 240-degree uninterrupted views to the east, south and west of the Bay of Chavon, the marina, the open sea and the Saona and Catalina islands.

Punta Minitas 11, Casa de Campo Resort and Villa, La Romana, Dominican Republic. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate.

The home has seven bedrooms, an independent three-bedroom guesthouse, circular palm thatched rooves, ornamental gardens and is set near the international yacht marina, equestrian, polo and sporting facilities, and restaurants. You won't find a place like this in Adelaide, that's for sure.
SEVEN MILE BEACH, CAYMAN ISLANDS
Price: $20.4 million

700 Seven South - The Ritz-Carlton Residences Penthouse, Seven Mile Beach, Cayman Islands. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate

A lot of apartment owners describe their homes as 'like living in a hotel'. The penthouse apartment at the top of the exclusive 700 Seven South Ritz-Carlton complex in Grand Cayman is just that. It overlooks the renowned Seven Mile Beach and has been masterfully furnished with the most luxe interiors imaginable.

700 Seven South - The Ritz-Carlton Residences Penthouse, Seven Mile Beach, Cayman Islands. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate

It features three bedrooms, four bathrooms, an elevator, ornate ceilings and cornices, sleek lines, floor-to-ceiling windows, stunning timber flooring and open-plan living. You also get the benefit of the hotel's many amenities, including five restaurants, a fitness centre, two pools and waterfront jacuzzi, a waterpark, a golf course, a gift shop and dedicated concierge.

700 Seven South - The Ritz-Carlton Residences Penthouse, Seven Mile Beach, Cayman Islands. Supplied by Christie's International Real Estate

I could certainly think of worse places to put my feet up and enjoy a nice single malt ...
All properties for sale through Christie's International Real Estate www.Christies.com/ENG
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MILE BEACH</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Cayman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BARRINGTON HILLS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Architect's Digest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illinois</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven South</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campo Resort</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Mile Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay of Chavon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven South Ritz-Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakeview Lane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Romana</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caribbean Sea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Aldaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catalinas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CASA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pimms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christie's International Real Estate</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cayman Islands</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ritz-Carlton Residences Penthouse</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punta Minitas 11</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dominican Republic</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
