<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412528886540700</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/news/world/2017/08/02/peter-oneill-re-elected-png-prime-minister/</url>
  <title>Peter O'Neill re-elected Prime Minister of Papua New Guinea</title>
  <content>
Peter O'Neill has been re-elected Prime Minister of Papua New Guinea after a vote in the country's Parliament, capping off a chaotic election period.
Mr O'Neill will serve as Prime Minister for a five-year term, with his People's National Congress leading a coalition of parties.
Wednesday's sitting has been suspended as Mr O'Neill heads to Government House to be sworn in by the Governor-General.
Not all of Papua New Guinea's MPs were in the Parliament for the vote, as counting was continuing in some electorates.
Only 106 of 111 election writs made it back in time for the sitting of Parliament.
The vote was held despite the objections of senior legal figures who said the country's electoral commissioner did not follow the law during the return of the election writs and by giving the invitation to Mr O'Neill to form government.
The proceedings also got off to a late and confusing start when two candidates, Nick Kuman and Dawa Lucas, both claimed to be the member-elect for one seat.
Both men refused to move when asked by parliamentary staff, leading to commotion in the chamber.
During the session, PNG's National Court granted an order to stop both men from participating in today's sitting, which further complicated matters.
The clerk of Parliament later announced Mr Kuman as the member-elect.
More to come
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea's MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter O'Neill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People's National Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister of Papua</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PNG's National Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawa Lucas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Guinea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Kuman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Neill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kuman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
