<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412704980203279</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/mcgowan-says-pms-visit-a-waste-of-time/news-story/d85650826c04cc415718accf02b1b2b7</url>
  <title>McGowan, PM set to dine and clash over GST</title>
  <content>
THE state's finances would have been better off with Federal Cabinet staying in Canberra and instead sending the cost of this week's flights and hotels west,  Premier Mark McGowan says. 
In an escalation of his war of words with Canberra over a looming $2 billion GST write down, the Premier set the scene for an awkward dinner with the Prime Minister tonight by declaring his week-long "listening tour" of WA a complete waste of time.
"They've now been here two-and-a-half days without a significant commitment to our State. That's not good enough," he said.
"Whenever they go to Queensland or to South Australia or to Queensland or the Norther Territory they always seem to have significant commitments but they've come here with lots of opportunities for pictures, but not important projects or GST reform and that's very disappointing.
"They would have been better off just giving us the money for the airfares and the hotel rooms and not coming if they are not going to do something about the GST."
Mr McGowan made the remarks at the WA Local Government Association convention in the city, where he signed a partnership agreement to ensure closer collaboration between the state and local authorities.
The State Government has spent the week lobbying Malcolm Turnbull and his Treasurer Scott Morrison to make sure updated census figures are not used to calculate the population component of WA's GST share, which threatens to blow a $1.9 billion hole in the September budget.
Mr Morrison has said he lacked the legal authority to intervene, drawing an angry response from Mr McGowan who pointed out the Commonwealth Grants Commission was subject to direction from the Federal Treasurer.
"The PM could resolve that issue without any adverse affect on any other state," he said.
"No other state has constructed their budget on the basis that WA is going to lose $2 billion that's going to be redistributed to other states."
Mr McGowan said the 2016 online census, which was plagued with widespread outages, was "the most comprehensively failed census in history" and should be ignored.
It was "patently ridiculous" for it to revise down WA's projected population growth by 60,000 people in three months from March, which had triggered the GST writedown.
Mr McGowan rejected Mr Turnbull's claim that Labor was the greatest impediment to GST reform and the WA Premier should be working on Opposition Leader Bill Shorten and other Labor premiers.
"None of them are the Prime Minister," Mr McGowan said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Local Government Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA's GST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norther Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Grants Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
