<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412636260725305</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:34</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/even-barry-allen-himself-thinks-barry-allen-was-a-jerk-in-the-flashs-last-season/</url>
  <title>Even Barry Allen Himself Thinks Barry Allen Was A Jerk In The Flash's Last Season</title>
  <content>
The Flash's third season had a few problems - whether it was a way-too-slow-burn on revealing its big bad, or the eventual reveal that its big bad was actually basically the same big bad it had done for two seasons already. But one of its biggest problems was that ... and the guy playing him agrees.

Image: CW

Speaking to  at San Diego Comic-Con recently, Grant Gustin discussed how the fourth season of the show will see Barry become a changed man in the light of his time in the speedforce at the end of season three. This is a good thing, because all he did in season three was forget everything he'd learned up until that point and make selfish, misguided decisions (like, say, messing up all of time) that actively harmed everyone around him:

I mean, OK, Barry was also literally the villain of season three - because Savitar was  who was evil and decided to screw with his past self's life for giggles. But it's nice to at least see Gustin and the Flash team at large acknowledging that the show is at its best when Barry can grow and learn from his mistakes, and enjoy being the hero he was developing into throughout the first three seasons.

So far we're hearing a lot of positive things about The Flash's fourth season; hopefully, the show lives up to those statements of reassurance and gives us a happier, less jerk-ish hero to watch.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gustin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Savitar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Allen Himself Thinks Barry Allen Was A Jerk In</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flash's Last Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Diego Comic Con</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Gustin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
