<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651411803037056517</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>04:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/dairy-giant-vdl-farms-mooves-towards-organic-future-in-tasmania/news-story/e5fc6a58070d8a28a91c0ce9078eec86</url>
  <title>Dairy giant mooves towards organic future</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIA'S largest dairy farm is working with a natural resource management group to help develop organic dairies in Tasmania.
VDL Farms chief executive Evan Rolley said the planting of native vegetation buffers would play an important role in gaining Australian and Chinese organic certification.
The country's largest single milk supplier, VDL operates 25 dairy farms - 13 at the Woolnorth property on Tasmania's North-West Coast.
It milks about 19,000 cows to produce between 90 million and 100 million litres of milk, or 7.7 million kilos of milk solids, a year. It employs about 150 staff
VDL Farms is collaborating with the Cradle Coast Authority's NRM team to the plant native vegetation buffers.
In a strategic project, VDL Farms owner Moon Lake Investments has identified three of its farms to convert to organic production: Robbins dairy on the Woolnorth property, Poilinna at Edith Creek, and Talawa at Trowutta.
The move aims to create value-added products with a higher return to the farms.
Mr Rolley said it would create a commercial-scale organic farm business of about 1650 cows on almost 900ha.
To gain organic farm certification, soil testing and the removal of the usual agricultural chemicals from pasture are required along with elimination of antibiotics from livestock.
"One of the requirements is to create native vegetation buffers between the organic farms and other dairy properties," Mr Rolley said.
"The Cradle Coast Authority, through the NRM team, is assisting us with the design and implementation of the buffers and the plant species required and we're working with them towards establishing a formal memorandum of understanding which we expect to sign off in late August."
Mr Rolley said the first round of assessments by both the Australian and Chinese authorities have progressed well.
"We aim to achieve organic farm in transition [status] now. Full organic farm certification typically takes two to three years," Mr Rolley said.
Read more rural stories in Tasmanian Country on Friday.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edith Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolnorth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cradle Coast Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Rolley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evan Rolley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trowutta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VDL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cradle Coast Authority's NRM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moon Lake Investments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania's North-West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VDL Farms</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poilinna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Country</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Talawa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
