<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412528886540752</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/a-new-workshop-being-run-in-berwick-aims-to-teach-first-aid-for-people-who-are-suicidal/news-story/2f2d0cf09e13d2f1e4277bf08891eca0</url>
  <title>New workshop a lifeline for people in crisis</title>
  <content>
IF someone in your life told you they wanted to die, what would you do?
Mental health charity Alive Crusade is holding the ASIST (Applied Suicide Intervention Skills) Community Workshop on August 19 to teach people how to help suicidal friends and family.
Spokeswoman Julie-Anne Williams said many people were happy to ask friends and family members if they were OK but a lot of people wouldn't know how to follow up if they got a negative response.
She said it was important to realise that asking someone if they had suicidal thoughts would not make someone become suicidal if they were not.
She said her family had intervened with her older brother, who had a long history of mental illness and suicide attempts.
Her brother is now doing much better and has started volunteering at op shops and working in vegetable gardens.
"Suicide is pretty rampant everywhere - the statistics are pretty scary around suicide because not every suicide is put down as such on the death certificate," she said.
"It's definitely a big problem in this area.
"With mental health scares a lot of people think scary to ask someone (if they are suicidal) but CPR is terrifying if you don't know what you're doing."
Ms Williams said she had already put her training into practice.
"One of the most poignant stories that has remained with me, was a time I stopped my car with my three-year-old old son inside and approached a teenage boy along the roadside near a bridge in Berwick," she said.
"Having done the training I knew what signs to look for, but most of all I was more conscious of those around me.
"I had the confidence to approach this young man and ask if he was OK.
"It was a very serious situation but I felt empowered from training and I could sit with this young man until help arrived."
For details, visit the .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie-Anne Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Applied Suicide Intervention Skills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Workshop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alive Crusade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
