<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412533181508148</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/athletics/athletics-world-championships-2017-for-usain-bolt-a-picture-perfect-ending-looms-20170802-gxnoj6.html</url>
  <title>Athletics world championships 2017: For Usain Bolt, a picture perfect ending looms</title>
  <content>
London: Four men might have run faster than Usain Bolt this year. While he's not running in the 200 metres at his last world championships, perhaps for the doubt that he could not beat Wayde Van Niekerk, it would be foolish to believe the Jamaican sprinter will  leave the sport anywhere other than on top in the 100m. 
"If I lose it won't change my mind [that I am a legend]. But it is not going to happen. The last race with 9.95 seconds shows I am going in right the direction," Bolt said at his press conference. "It is about who can keep their nerves. It is time to go, and I am ready to go.

Up Next

Acid in London attacks easily available

01:48

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Bolt: 'I'm happy to retire now'

The champion sprinter hangs up his running shoes in less than two weeks and says he's ready to enjoy life a bit more.

"I am still the fastest, without a doubt. If I show up at championships, I am confident in my abilities. I can say I am a legend, I have proven it."
As well as the 100m, he will run for Jamaica in the sprint relay. He wants to walk away from these championships with the headline as it could be written now: "'Usain Bolt retires unbeaten' - that would hopefully be the biggest headline ... Unbeatable, unstoppable Usain Bolt."Photo: AP
Bolt has always been the star, and it felt oddly appropriate that he was questioned in the first instance not by journalists but by actors and sports stars. Asafa Powell, Cara Delevingne, Thierry Henry, Virat Kohli, Idris Elba and Colin Jackson all posed gentle queries and offered garlands.
Samuel L. Jackson added a little coarsely: "Thanks for all the thrills, thanks for all the chills. Thanks for being the outstanding dope-ass motherf---er you have always been."

Bolt's parents were brought forth to give him his shoes for his last race. They are gold and purple: purple for the colour of the school that he raced for before he took on the world, and gold for the medals he has won.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But some people have strayed from their role. Canadian Andre De Grasse was a good supporting actor to Bolt at the Rio Olympics, challenging him to add sufficient drama in taking bronze in the 100m and silver in the 200. Since then, he has been less obliging and Bolt has not liked it.Photo: AP
Perhaps De Grasse is now to be the villain in this final stage of Bolt's career. Drug cheat Justin Gatlin was cast in this role at the last world championships, but that was not because of anything he said so much as what he took. De Grasse, who has run a (wind-assisted) 9.69s 100m this year, has needled Bolt by stating he was getting slower: "Everyone knows he's slowing down a little bit".
De Grasse also claimed that Bolt had made sure he was not in the field in a race in Monaco because he feared he would beat him.Photo: AP
So it was De Grasse who Bolt appeared to have in mind when he was asked about who would overtake him in the sport.
"I am not going down that road," he replied. "The last guy who I said was going to be great disrespected me. So I am not going to say who is going to be great."
Bolt, who has won eight Olympic gold medals, 11 world titles and broken six world records, was then asked directly about his relationship with De Grasse. He shrugged.
"I don't know," he said. "I see him around, I say 'hi'. That is it, I guess. I don't know how to describe that. I don't have his phone number or anything. We just say 'hi'."
Depending on your perspective, he was then courteous and respectful to the entire field, or pointed about De Grasse when he was asked about his biggest rival for the gold in the 100m.
"The seven people that are going to be in that race with me," he replied. "They are my best challengers."
But what about De Grasse? Where do you think his career is going?
"I don't know," Bolt added. "In the past he has won a bronze medal, won a silver medal, we'll see what happens in the future, it's all about consistency."
Bolt was playful as ever in his press conference and played his role to perfection. But he seemed most confronted when asked what would happen if he lost.
"I can't believe you're asking me that," he said. "We won't have that problem, don't worry about it."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Gatlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cara Delevingne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian Andre De Grasse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grasse</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>De Grasse</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samuel L. Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Idris Elba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thierry Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayde Van Niekerk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virat Kohli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monaco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asafa Powell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
