<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412528886540644</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/adelaide-captain-taylor-walker-backs-all-the-crows-have-to-keep-uncontracted-pair-mitch-mcgovern-and-jake-lever/news-story/72270cb598ee011980d067b43404763e</url>
  <title>STILL THE BEST LEVER</title>
  <content>
CAPTAIN Taylor Walker is not fearing the Adelaide Football Club will fall short as uncontracted pair Jake Lever and Mitch McGovern measure the Crows against their AFL rivals.

And the Crows skipper has fired a broadside at North Melbourne premiership hero Wayne Carey for questioning if Adelaide is prepared to pay "market value" to keep the young tyros.

"Does he do our books does he?" Walker said in response to Carey's view the Crows underpay their star players.

The prospect of either Lever or McGovern putting the increasing speculation on their AFL futures away from Adelaide's promising finals campaign next month appears less and less likely now.

Lever is reported to have recently met with Melbourne Football Club officials and players as the 21-year-old defender measures major offers - valued at around $800,000 a season - from four clubs in his home market of Victoria. This is far from unusual with AFL players now.

McGovern is increasingly linked to Fremantle in a return to his home state as the Dockers prepare a five-year, $750,000-season offer that dwarfs Adelaide's original two-year deal of $370,000-a-season.

As Lever prepares to consider the merit of continuing his football at Adelaide - or moving to his big suitors at Melbourne, the Western Bulldogs, Hawthorn or Collingwood - Walker maintains the Crows have the money, football success and culture to fulfil any player's AFL dreams.

"It is a decision for Jake to make," Walker said when asked if he would take a lead in trying to hold Lever to the Crows.

"We provide a culture and environment that, hopefully, when he comes to make that decision he choses the right one."

As the new AFL world has more and more players measure their options with in-season visits to rival clubs, Walker re-iterated: "I'd like to think, as I said, we offer an environment and culture that when it comes time for him to make his decision that it is the right one and he wants to stay at our footy club."

Carey's remarks on how Adelaide structures player contracts follows Crows premiership captain Mark Bickley's recent call on the negotiating process at West Lakes - a remark that infuriated club chief executive Andrew Fagan.

Bickley noted: "The one thing I reckon Adelaide are pretty poor at, they play the ambit claim game.

"They come well unders and expect you to come in at overs and then they keep moving towards (a deal). I don't think that endears them at all to managers."

This certainly appears the case with McGovern's manage Colin Young who - after last year learning Carlton's valuation on the 22-year-old forward - is finding Fremantle are prepared to offer his client big money and a long-term contract.

Walker appeared taken aback at the Showdown captains' press conference at Adelaide Oval on Wednesday by reports of Lever touring AFL rivals.

But the skipper did not increase the pressure on Lever and McGovern to deliver an early decision, despite Walker setting an example five weeks ago by renegotiating his contract - on the signing of a new AFL collective bargaining agreement.

"Just like every other player," Walker said of Lever and McGovern, "they're super important to our side. I'm sure they'll make their decision when they have to."

michelangelo.rucci@news.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Bickley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Carey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fagan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEST LEVER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bickley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walker</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
