<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412872483931117</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/nrl/phil-gould-defends-brutal-kenny-edwards-hit/news-story/3162739741ffdead35ef705544ab6df9</url>
  <title>Gus' stunning take on sickening NRL dog shot</title>
  <content>
THE NRL was rocked by a sickening hit on Friday night as Eels star Kenny Edwards put an ugly shoulder into Brisbane winger Jonus Pearson.
The Broncos star had already been brought to the ground before Edwards threw his entire weight down onto his opponent's chest. Pearson had been taken down by a stray hand from Eels star Nathan Brown coming into contact with his face.
"Simply, I didn't think the tackle was complete," Edwards said of the ugly shoulder. "I didn't see the high shot Browny put on until afterwards.
"I just went in hard like I always do. Unfortunately Browny hit him high, which I didn't see. I saw the replay and if I could go back I wouldn't do it again."
Fans erupted in outrage as referees failed to pull the 27-year-old up on his unsportsmanlike conduct. .

Dangerous precedent set re  Kenny Edwards 'contrary conduct' charge - so an injured player laying prone is now 'fair game'?!

NRL legend and Channel Nine commentator Phil Gould took the surprising route and defended the Parramatta forward's conduct, insisting he hadn't broken a single rule.
"Kenny Edwards did not break a rule. He hit him, he hit him to hurt him,"  . "That's the competitive nature of the man.
"The referee on the field didn't penalise him. Why? Because he didn't do anything illegal. The Bunker had a look at it several times, they didn't caution him or recommend a penalty.
"It then went to the Match Review Committee who didn't find any offence that he caused. He didn't hit him in the head, he didn't come down with elbows or knees. He didn't hit him late while he wasn't in possession of the ball."
Gould then slammed the NRL for fining Edwards, claiming it was a token fine in order to escape backlash from the media.
"Even they couldn't find a rule he had broken. So, what do they do? They fined him ($1100) for contrary conduct because they don't want to be criticised by the storm on social media and in the media."
When asked if the sudden spike in aggressive shots on players was a sign of the game changing, Gould reassured fans it was all a part of the sport.
"It's been around for 100 years," he said.
"Kenny sometimes has brain explosions. That's just him. We love his energy he brings to the game," teammate Manu Ma'u said on Monday.
Edwards admitted he regretted the incident which has been labelled a cheap shot. "We don't want to change the way Kenny plays or the attitude he brings to his game," Eels centre Michael Jennings said.
"He copped a fine, didn't he? He's a bit of a tight-ass, so he's more worried about that than what anyone else is saying to him." The Eels' win over the Broncos was their fifth straight, and puts them in a perfect position to qualify for their first finals series since their fairytale run in 2009.
It is currently the longest finals drought of any NRL team.
Jennings hailed the Eels' effort to come back from 12 points down to beat the Broncos 28-14, saying their fighting abilities were a must for any team bound for September.
"When we were 12 points down, everyone was calm. There was no disbelief," he said.
"Everyone was confident that we could just ride this wave and really weather the storm, we'll get out over the top of these guys. We hung in there, and took it away."
- with AAP
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Match Review Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonus Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gould</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pearson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Gould</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Browny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny Edwards</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Jennings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broncos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manu Ma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
