<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412747929877186</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/same-sex-marriage-should-be-taken-to-a-plebiscite-nicholls-20170802-gxny5o.html</url>
  <title>Same sex marriage should be taken to a plebiscite: Nicholls</title>
  <content>
Queensland's LNP leader has backed a plebiscite to decide the issue of same sex marriage.
Tim Nicholls' federal colleagues have been  following Liberal Senator Dean Smith's announcement he had drafted a private members' bill for same sex marriage.Photo: Darren England/AAP
Four federal Liberal MPs - Warren Entsch, Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson and Trent Zimmerman - have indicated they could cross the floor on the issue.
Queensland LNP president Gary Spence  on Tuesday stating he was "disappointed that views that do not accord with the Party's policy have been aired publicly".
Asked if he was fed up with federal LNP MPs, Mr Nicholls said there was a clear party policy position on the issue.
"This is a matter [that] should be taken to the people of Australia in a plebiscite," Mr Nicholls said.

Mr Nicholls said federal Labor leader Bill Shorten did not want that to happen and he was "disrespecting the will of the Australian people".
"They voted for a government that said put it to a plebiscite," he said.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Mr Nicholls insisted he was focusing on the issues that mattered to Queenslanders, such as affordable power and business investment.
"Those are the things that Queenslanders are talking with us about," he said.
Asked if Mr Spence was right to pull LNP supporters in to line, Mr Nicholls defended the president's actions.
"Gary was clearly restating the position of the party membership here in Queensland as he's entitled to do," he said.
At the LNP state convention last month, a resolution was carried which called on the federal government to conduct a plebiscite on the question of changing the Marriage Act to allow same sex marriage by way of a postal ballot. 
In his letter, Mr Spence said if they were contrary opinions, members had the opportunity to test them on the floor of the convention.
Mr Nicholls was speaking to reporters in Mackay on Wednesday, saying there was a need for an agriculture, energy and water council. 
He also had some scathing comments to make about Tesla.
"The Tesla battery as we've heard wouldn't supply enough power basically to turn over the starter motor in a tractor," Mr Nicholls said.
"What we do know is that a base load coal-fired power station does what it's meant to do and that is to provide reliable base load power so every morning when we all get up and flick on the kettle and turn on the toaster we've got power there.
"The Tesla battery is not going to do that for all of Queensland."
At Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk's , she said she was interested in attracting a battery factory in Queensland after visiting Tesla in the US.
It prompted a man to yell out: "Get rid of Adani and build a battery factory then".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren England/AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Nicholls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Nicholls</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Spence</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland LNP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LNP MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
