<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412790879550989</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/swoop/tyler-wright-loving-close-world-surf-title-race-as-steph-gilmore-heads-to-sand/news-story/8f40cebf4e00e46f030dfac4d1b793ee</url>
  <title>World title tussle Wright on for Tyler</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIAN surfer Stephanie Gilmore has fallen foul of the closest women's world title race in years but world champion Tyler Wright wouldn't have it any other way.
Wright says she is delighted it is shaping as a close battle for the 2017 women's world crown of surfing.
Gilmore might not be as happy after conceding her No. 3 ranking in the world title race with an unexpectedly early exit from the US Open of Surfing at the hands of a French wildcard.

But Wright, who with fellow Australian and world No. 2 Sally Fitzgibbons advanced directly into the non-elimination third round at the Huntington Pier event, is delighted with the close competition.
"It just means I need to work harder and train harder to lift my performance,'' Wright said.
"I love the fact the field is so strong. I'm both a competitor and a fan of this sport.
"So I always want to see everyone doing their best, the race being really close.''
Gilmore's exit on day one of the women's competition has added to the race tension, with American Courtney Conlogue in the box seat to move up into a podium position on the world rankings with a good result at the US Open.

Gilmore posted her worst result of the season with her second round elimination at the hands of French surfer Maud Le Car, ranked 29th on the world qualifying series,
The loss is a major blow to Gilmore's bid to equal the record of lane Beachley in winning seven world crowns.
"I was a little confused out there. Disappointing result, for sure," Gilmore said.
The loss also opens the way for both Wright and Fitzgibbons to put distance between them and rival surfers in the world rankings with top performances at Huntington.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilmore</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Open of Surfing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Courtney Conlogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington Pier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzgibbon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maud Le Car</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beachley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Fitzgibbons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Gilmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
