<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412919728572249</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/superracing/outgoing-mrc-boss-brodie-arnhold-says-gloves-might-be-off-between-victoria-and-nsw-if-protocols-ignored/news-story/6a35e2544033db27f2d55ebc1f5af194</url>
  <title>Heavyweights must play by the rules</title>
  <content>
OUTGOING Melbourne Racing Club boss Brodie Arnhold says an unfettered racing "arms race'' might occur if NSW continues to ignore protocol.
Arnhold, , said it was vital each jurisdiction - particularly dominant NSW and Victoria - recognise the roles of the Pattern Committee and Racing Australia.
RACEDAY FOCUS:
He said a "most extreme scenario'' of unchecked encroachment between state carnivals could have Sydney's The Championships pitted against the Melbourne spring carnival and the Melbourne summer/autumn gatecrash Sydney's traditional autumn slot.
"These are the sorts of things that could be possible unless things are kept in check,'' Arnhold said. "Weather is better in Melbourne in autumn, before the football has started, and the weather in Sydney in spring is far better than it is up there in the autumn.
"I accept the idea of competition between the states, it's healthy.
"But there needs to be someone, an independent body with powers that are respected, sitting at the top ensuring normal protocols are adhered to and that race programming is done for the betterment of the entire industry.
"Racing should not see it as in competition with itself but with other sports.''
Arnhold said the collision of the  and the traditional Caulfield Guineas meeting at Caulfield, on October 14, plus changes to other Sydney races on and around that date, could be the beginning of a headache for NSW.
He said any date and status changes made without the authority of the Asian Pattern Committee, which acts in concert with Racing Australia and the Australian Pattern Committee, could mean they go unrecognised.

He said people such as Frances Nelson, RA chairman and South Australian racing powerbroker, should be concerned about the ripple effect of a .
"The smaller states will lose out,'' he said.
The clash of the bumped-up Craven Plate (Randwick) and Caulfield Stakes, both over 2000m on October 14, is poised to rob the MRC of a reappearance of Winx in the Caulfield Stakes.
"We haven't completely given up on getting her," Arnhold said. "If we get a bit of rain down here, he (Chris Waller) might get the track he's looking for.''
Arnhold said the likelihood of a "bumper edition'' of the Caulfield Cup, featuring possibly six northern hemisphere runners, has put talk of a weight-for-age Caulfield Cup "to the side for a while".
matthew.stewart@news.com.au
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Pattern Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craven Plate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brodie Arnhold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield Guineas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Waller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pattern Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frances Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Pattern Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield Stakes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Racing Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arnhold</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
