<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412704980203274</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/nrl/cowboys/cowboys-prop-matt-scott-on-road-to-recovery-from-knee-injury/news-story/9b4c65c00827e2aa4abb62a8bf1c9aaf</url>
  <title>Scott running on road to recovery</title>
  <content>
INJURED Cowboys co-captain Matt Scott is back running at training, but he doesn't expect to walk straight into his starting role when he returns to the field next season.
North Queensland's forward stocks have been stretched thin since Scott ruptured his ACL only two games into the season, with his replacement Patrick Kaufusi (foot) also ruled out just a few weeks later.
But it could be a case of short-term pain for long-term gain for the Cowboys, with Scott Bolton in career-best form in Scott's absence and Storm enforcer Jordan McLean set to join the club in 2018.
Add the likes of Dally M winner Jason Taumalolo and young guns Corey Jensen and Coen Hess into the mix and Scott said it was an exciting time for the club's middle forwards.
"I might struggle to get my starting spot back," the veteran prop joked.
"I think 'Bolts' has been one of the best players all year for us, if not one of the form front-rowers in the competition, and Jordan McLean is a great addition.
"I think with how well the side's going this year, then you look at 'JT' (Johnathan Thurston) and myself to come back in the side and a couple of other guys on deck, it's exciting times for next year."
Scott ran for the first time last month and hopes to be back into full training after the Christmas break as he targets next year's season opener for his NRL return.
The 31-year-old admitted his recovery was a slow and frustrating process at times, but Scott said he was happy to take his time to ensure he comes back as strong as ever.
"This recovery is pretty long so everyone milestone you hit is a pretty good feeling. Obviously running is a big part of the recovery process so it's good to be back," Scott said.
"I'm definitely on track, but it's not the sort of thing you can be ahead of. The medical staff are pretty careful at keeping the reins on and making sure we don't get too ahead of ourselves.
"I've had a few trips away which has been good to break the recovery process up. It mixes it up a little bit, but it is just a bit of a process you've got to go through.
"It is a bit frustrating, but I'm training well at the moment and the boys are playing well so it does make it easier."
Scott isn't alone in North Queensland's rehab group with hooker Josh Chudleigh and outside back Shaun Hudson also recovering from serious knee injuries.
Hudson ruptured his ACL while scoring a try for the Cowboys at this year's Auckland Nines which shattered the 22-year-old's hopes of making his NRL debut this season.
The Gold Coast product admitted it was a bitter pill to swallow so early in his Cowboys career, but he said training alongside his co-captain Scott was helping to keep him motivated.
"It helps mentally and physically being with 'Thumper'. I think he's only a week behind me so we've been training a fair bit together," Hudson said.
"You can see what sort of weight he lifts in the gym which motivates me. It's been really good.
"There's a great bunch of boys here that give you a real confidence boost knowing that you'll be able to get back and they're really supportive. I knew that I'd be able to get through it."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>JT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shaun Hudson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Chudleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland Nines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnathan Thurston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hudson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dally M</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Scott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan McLean</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Kaufusi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coen Hess</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Taumalolo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corey Jensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
