<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412747929877097</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/business/electricity-billing-complaints-are-up-even-before-the-price-hikes-kick-in/news-story/06c205398298da7c3e53486303918964</url>
  <title>Complaints up even before price hike</title>
  <content>
ELECTRICITY and gas billing complaints are up, and the NSW energy ombudsman's office is bracing for that to .
Price increases of up to 20 per cent which came into effect on July 1 will see average customers' in some states.
In NSW, residential EnergyAustralia customers' next bills will see hikes of up to 19.6 per cent. Origin Energy customers will get a 16.1 per cent rise.
But quarterly figures from the NSW Energy Ombudsman reveal that billing complaints were on the rise long before the price hikes kicked in.
"Complaints about electricity have increased by 10.8 per cent (between the first and third quarters 2016/2017)," an EWON spokesman said.
It comes as new research shows 68 per cent of NSW households have seen their bills rise over the past 12 months and one in four are cutting back on groceries just to pay their bills, as profits for big three giants of the NSW electricity market - AGL, Origin Energy and Energy Australia - soar in excess of $100 million, according to .
Meanwhile, in Victoria., the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission has demanded the "big three" operators and some smaller retailers divulge sensitive cost and price calculations as part of a nationwide federal government-ordered power affordability inquiry.
And in Queensland, more than 460 residents a week who are struggling to pay their bills have had their electricity disconnected - a 55 per cent surge in disconnections.
Back at the ombudsman's office, the 10.8 per cent increase in electricity complaints outstrips an increase of 6.6 per cent for all complaints (including those about gas and water) received by EWON.
"Our electricity complaints increased steadily for the first three quarters last financial year," said Helen Ford, EWON's General Manager of Governance, Awareness and Policy.
"The main electricity-related issues customers complained to us about over the 12 months from April 2016 to March 2017 were high bills, poor customer service, failure of providers to respond to customers, payment difficulties, debt collection, opening and closing accounts, estimated bills and billing errors."
It's the third successive quarter in which complaints have risen, and that looks set to continue once the dreaded winter bills roll into homes around October.
From January to March this year, the Ombudsman's office received 5904 complaints.
Of the 5904 complaints, 4366 were electricity cases, and 1343 were gas cases.
The complaints raised issues about billing in 3295 cases and customer service in 2588 cases - often one went with the other.
The Ombudsman's quarterly newsletter warns consumers to prepare for bill shock when the next bills roll in.
"Quarterly billing means many households won't see how their charges add up for several months," it said.
"With the pressure on households to keep on top of their bills, topped off by the return of the cooler weather, it's timely to remind customers how heaters, electric blankets, extra hot showers and more time spent inside staying warm, contributes to an increase in power consumption over winter. Informed decisions can help avoid bill shock when the winter bill arrives."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Competition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EWON's General Manager of Governance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ombudsman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helen Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Energy Ombudsman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EnergyAustralia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EWON</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Origin Energy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
