<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412872483931052</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/halle-berry-accidentally-flashes-her-bra-as-her-shirt-falls-open-on-the-red-carpet/news-story/a4861459cdf950bbfe732c46ec7a3ee1</url>
  <title>Halle Berry accidentally flashes boob on red carpet</title>
  <content>
YOU know that dream where all your clothes fall off in front of a massive audience? Well spare a thought for Halle Berry, who literally lived that nightmare at the premiere of her new movie last night in LA.
On the red carpet for action film Kidnap, Halle's white shirt fell open, exposing her bra to the waiting bank of photographers. She didn't notice and just kept smiling for photos, reports.
Halle, who was posing with production company bigshots David Dinerstein and William Sadleir, seemed totally unaware that her shirt had flopped open.
Didn't she feel a breeze? Didn't anyone think to tell her? It's making us nervous just thinking about it.
Then, when Halle cuddled up to co-star Sage Correa, it happened again. It feels like Halle's stylist might need to invest in a few safety pins.
Halle finally seemed to notice her fashion disaster and pulled her shirt shut again - and managed to smile through the rest of the photocall.
The movie is about a mum who risks everything to rescue her abducted son, who gets kidnapped from a carnival when his mum's back is turned.
At the premiere, Halle told a scary story where she thought her daughter Nahla had been taken from a shop.
"I was busy looking at a tag, Nahla was very little," she told Entertainment Tonight. "She was there, I looked around, and she was not there."
"And you have that moment where I was like, 'Shut the store! Shut the doors!' I went right into 'nobody's leaving this place until I find out where my daughter is'."
Fortunately, Halle's daughter, who is now nine, hadn't actually gone very far.
"Luckily, she was like a foot away from me under the turnstile," she said. "But in that moment, she was gone."
Halle also has son Maceo, with Olivier Martinez.
This article first appeared on .
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William Sadleir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maceo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Tonight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halle Berry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sage Correa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nahla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halle</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Dinerstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olivier Martinez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
