<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412747929877112</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/injury-news/melbourne-demons-hopeful-jesse-hogan-will-have-an-impact-this-season-after-successful-collarbone-surgery-20170802-gxny51.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne hopeful Jesse Hogan will have an impact this season after successful collarbone surgery</title>
  <content>
Melbourne are not putting a timeframe on Jesse Hogan's return to the field but they are hopeful the gun young forward will still have an impact this season after having collarbone surgery.
Hogan, 22, had a plate inserted during surgery on Sunday. The injury occurred after a third-quarter collision with North Melbourne's Luke McDonald .

Up Next

Sam Mitchell retires

02:57

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

FootyFix: Can the Cats win without Danger?

Sam McClure previews all the footy action ahead of round 20 in the AFL.

The injury was the latest blow to the Melbourne forward who has been limited to just eight AFL games this season due to suspension, the death of his father, and a battle with testicular cancer.
Sports physician Dr Peter Larkins said the standard time away from the game after collarbone surgery was six weeks, and the minimum time off was four weeks. That timeframe could potentially lead to Hogan returning in round 23 against Collingwood - should the Demons not have already locked away a finals berth.Photo: AAP
Hogan's injury has prompted questions about whether he could follow Lin Jong's path after the Bulldog returned to footy with a best-on-ground performance in the VFL premiership just 17 days after breaking his collarbone in the Dogs' elimination final victory over West Coast.
While Jong didn't go on to play in the club's drought-breaking AFL premiership one week later, the Bulldog successfully gambled with an early return to footy. Dr Larkins said the Bulldogs had "rolled the dice" with Jong last September.

"It's pretty standard to have six weeks to heal (after collarbone surgery)," Dr Larkins said.   

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The Demons will assess Hogan's condition later this week. Melbourne's elite performance manager Dave Misson said the surgery, undertaken by orthopaedic surgeon Andrew Oppy, was a success.
"Jesse had surgery on Sunday afternoon and the surgery went well. He had a plate inserted onto that collarbone," Misson told the club's website.
"He's recovering OK. We'll have a look and see how it is by the end of the week. We're hoping, as [coach] Simon Goodwin said, we're hoping that he's going to come back and play again this year. 
"But we're not putting any timeframes on it. We just want to assess Jesse and see how he's going and take it from there."
The Demons might also have the option of playing Hogan with Casey Scorpions in the VFL during the AFL bye week after round 23, allowing the important forward to have a game under his belt before the AFL finals.
Melbourne's more immediate concern will be Saturday's tough clash against Greater Western Sydney in Canberra. Cameron Pedersen may be considered to replace Hogan but they are set to be bolstered by the return of co-captain Nathan Jones (quad) and midfielder Bernie Vince (suspension). 
Jones hasn't played since round 13 while Vince was suspended for an elbow to the face of Eddie Betts in Darwin three weeks ago.
Young high-flying forward Joel Smith, who was injured in his AFL debut in round one and returned to play two senior games, is set to play again in the VFL after having a week off.
"He had an incident with this hip at training last week," Misson said.
"He was pretty close to playing but he did some pretty decent training today and we're hoping we can tick him off on Thursday and he'll play again for Casey on the weekend."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Misson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joel Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Oppy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FootyFix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lin Jong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam McClure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Larkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne's Luke McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Pedersen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bernie Vince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Demons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Misson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Hogan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey Scorpions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hogan, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Casey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Goodwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hogan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Peter Larkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
