<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413220376288688</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/cricket/drafting-issues-delay-resolution-to-australian-cricket-pay-dispute-20170802-gxnzro.html</url>
  <title>'Drafting' issues delay resolution to Australian cricket pay dispute</title>
  <content>
David Warner started preparations for the Bangladesh Test series as parties worked deep into Wednesday night in a bid to thrash out a peace deal and end Australian cricket's ugly pay dispute.
, there were issues around the drafting of the heads of agreement with concerns focused on revenue share definitions.Photo: AP
There had been hopes a resolution may have been reached  but the latest differences, believed to be minor, have pushed this back.
Industry insiders say the distrust between Cricket Australia and the Australian Cricketers Association, which has been present since the start, are a major reason for this week's delays.

if it was not resolved by early this week but that move appeared less likely after the progress made in the last seven days.
The Australian Cricketers Association is believed to have won back pay for the 200-plus players who came out of contract on July 1.

The ACA executive convened on Tuesday morning via teleconference happy with the agreement, but sources say there has been to-ing and fro-ing between the two sides over granular legal points.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

A deal remains vital to the two-Test tour of Bangladesh going ahead. CA's sponsors and broadcast partners will also be looking for a swift resolution so they can regain access to players, whose IP has been handed over to the ACA's The Cricketers Brand.
Despite the uncertainty, players are focusing on the upcoming series and are due to head into camp next week in Darwin.
It will be the first time the Test squad has been together since the memorable series in India where Australia came tantalisingly close to a historic series win.
"Had my first hit back today - actually looking forward to getting back into it," Test vice-captain David Warner said on Channel Nine.
"Look, we're hoping a deal gets done in the next 24 to 48 hours.
"Obviously I don't know anything that's been happening this morning. Steve spoke last night - he's been speaking to Pat [Howard] and Alistair [Nicholson] behind closed doors which is fantastic for us to hopefully get a deal done.
"The plan is Darwin, Bangladesh. We want to get out there and play cricket. That's our job, that's what we love doing and all the fans out there really want to see us back on the park and playing well."
Australia have won all four of its Tests against Bangladesh but this is shaping as a much tougher assignment.
The Tigers remain a lowly ninth in Test rankings but are no longer easybeats, as seen by drawn series at home against South Africa and England and a last-start win in Sri Lanka in March.
Unlike Australia, Bangladesh are much deeper into their training having started several weeks ago.
Australia exceeded expectations in India after being put through one of their most thorough lead-ups for a subcontinental assignment in recent memory, in stark contrast to the bitter fight that has strained player-board relations.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricketers Brand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers' Association</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>India</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Warner</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alistair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lanka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
