<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413048577593713</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/18/50/late-husbands-backyard-gravesite-under-threat-as-developer-claims-land-encroachment</url>
  <title>Late husband</title>
  <content>
Western Sydney woman Roslyn McCartney is begging for a break from development giant Lendlease - or else she'll be forced to move her husband from his final resting place.
Mrs McCartney is one of a number of Sydney residents in the suburb of Werrington Downs with a back fence that borders on a new housing estate being constructed by Lendlease.
She and her neighbours said they were recently told their back fences impeded on the development land by 40cm to 50cm, which Lendlease wants to claim.
For Mrs McCartney, the issue is a deeply personal one.
She interred the ashes of her late husband Graeme in their backyard, in a spot that would be lost to the new development if the back fence was moved.
"I will fight for his ashes to stay in the place where he wanted to be," she said.
The financial stakes are also high for her, she said, as she would also have to move her late husband's shed.

Related Articles

"I'm on a pension, I just can't afford to do that now," she said.
Another resident, Jeff Raymond, said the claim by Lendlease was salt in the wound after the neighbours had put up with "nearly two years of dust" from the development.
"I think it's just a land grab," he said.
"The division's done, the roads are in, the sewerage is in, the water's in, half the blocks of land are sold, what are they going to gain by 18 inches?"
Up to 57 homes along the border of the new housing development could be affected by the potentially costly reclamation.
Resident Ken Rollinson said he was faced with shouldering the costs of moving his shed - built on a concrete slab that would also need to be dug up - and removing a tree that would be right on the new fence line.
Lendlease issued a statement saying the engagement with residents was in its "very early stages."
"Lendlease is meeting with residents to better understand the circumstances at each property," the statement read.
"We intend to work with property owners to find solutions that are mutually beneficial and minimise impacts."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Raymond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs McCartney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roslyn McCartney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Rollinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werrington Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graeme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lendlease</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
