<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412915433604924</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/banking-and-finance/qbe-refunds-159-million-in-addon-insurance-20170802-gxnsyw.html</url>
  <title>Car buyers urged to check for junk insurance refunds</title>
  <content>
QBE Group will refund $15.9 million in insurance premiums to more than 35,000 customers, after the regulator found it sold cover through car dealerships that was of "little or no benefit" to consumers.
The Australian Securities and Investments Commission (ASIC) on Wednesday announced the refunds as a result of a detailed review into questionable insurance sold through car yards. Consumer advocates urged anyone who has bought a car in recent years to check if they may have bought "junk insurance."

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Do you need to buy health insurance?

Is it worth taking out private health insurance when the Medicare system is available to everyone?

The refunds relate to two types of add-on insurance sold to car buyers that ASIC believes can be near useless in some circumstances: guaranteed asset protection (GAP) insurance and consumer credit insurance (CCI).
GAP insurance covers car owners for any shortfall between their car loan and the amount the car is insured for if it is written off. CCI covers car loan repayments if the borrower loses their job, gets sick, or dies.

QBE had sold GAP insurance where it was unlikely to be needed because it duplicated other insurance customers already had, or over-insured customers, while it sold CCI to young people without dependents who were unlikely to need it.
ASIC said both types of cover provided "little or no benefit."

"Insurance must meet the needs of the consumer first and foremost. All add-on insurers should review the sale of policies and refund consumers who were sold policies they didn't need," ASIC deputy chair Peter Kell said.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

QBE said it had identified customers who "may not have received value" when buying the insurance, and it had started contacting them to offer refunds. It will continue contacting customers over the coming months, and it has changed its guidelines for motor dealers.Photo: Nic Walker
"We take our responsibility to provide quality, value for money products seriously and we're committed to doing the right thing by our customers and the broader community," the company said.
It comes after banks a product that has long been linked with "poor consumer outcomes."
The Consumer Action Law Centre, which is running a campaign to stop insurers and car dealers selling what it views as "junk insurance", said people who had bought such policies when buying a car in recent years may be eligible for a refund, even if they had chosen to buy the cover.
"Anyone who has bought a car in recent years should check their paperwork-you could get your money back," said Susan Quinn, senior policy officer at the centre.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consumer Action Law Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan Quinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QBE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Kell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QBE Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCI</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
