<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413052872561116</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/dont-be-surprised-if-the-mcgovern-brothers-end-up-fremantle-brad-hardie-20170802-gxo34i.html</url>
  <title>Don't be surprised if the McGovern brothers end up Fremantle: Brad Hardie</title>
  <content>
Don't be surprised if West Coast's Jeremy McGovern moves to Fremantle if his brother Mitch joins the Dockers, with the Eagles defender unhappy with how the club handled Matt Priddis' retirement.
Adelaide is under siege at the moment to keep Jake Lever and McGovern who are out-of-contract at the end of the year and Fremantle are in pole position to land Mitch.Photo: Adam Trafford/AFL Media
But don't be shocked if, some time down the track, Jeremy ends up at Fremantle as well.
We all thought Mitch was going to be reunited with Jeremy at West Coast with all the romance about the two playing together at the Eagles.Photo: AAP/Julian Smith
Jeremy is apparently upset about what happened , and with West Coast unlikely to get Mitch and Priddis going, don't be surprised if he ends up with Mitch at the Dockers.
Like I , Fremantle should up their ante for Mitch and even if he is keen to go to West Coast, the Dockers should go after him just as hard.

His stocks will only have risen this week after his four goal game against the Pies, including the major which levelled the scores, and he's a much better player than the blokes currently running around in the Dockers' forward line at the moment.
And both Jeremy and Mitch have a connection with the Dockers because their old man Andrew wasn't a bad player for Fremantle.
There has also been a lot of talk about Lever leaving to go to the Bulldogs and reports this week that he .
Let me tell you it's all a smokescreen because Collingwood will be a big player in getting Lever from the Crows to the Pies.
Meanwhile, August 1 might be the horses' birthday but it's also the deadline for a lot assistant coaches who will get an indication from their clubs whether they have got a future or not.
So it isn't going to be a birthday for a lot of them.
Two clubs that are in the firing line are Nathan Buckley's Pies and Rodney Eade's Suns.
If you look at the Pies only Brenton Sanderson looks safe but the rest of them have been told if Buckley stays there is no guarantee you will have a job and if Buckley goes there is no guarantee you will have a job.
We are taking about the likes of Robert Harvey, Scott Burns and Jared Rivers who all could go.

Collingwood's coaching staff could be set for a shake-up. Photo: Joe Armao, Fairfax Media.

It's the same at the Suns with Dean Solomon and Matthew Primus. The Suns are saying it's all part of a review which they are using as an out not to tell them now.
You can take it from me they will be gone, but it doesn't stop there.
There is also movement at Essendon to try and bolster John Worsfold in the box. Pressure is going on the likes of Mark Neeld, Guy McKenna and co at Bomberland.
In a case of musical chairs Scott Burns could end up at the Bombers, who has worked with Worsfold and Solomon could find his way to Windy Hill.
You would have to think there is going to be a shake-up of the footy department at West Coast as well. There will probably be shuffling of the decks there but you wouldn't be safe if you were the list manager or recruitment officer.
Hero of the week: The North Melbourne side of 1977.
Goat of the week: All the football commentators that thought Patrick Dangerfield should have gotten off want to changes the rules because they lost the battle, but they don't want to lose the war.
Things that make you hmmm: I reckon Dustin Martin is already ahead of Dangerfield in the Brownlow count but if Dangerfield polls more votes it could be awkward if he has to hand over Charlie to Dusty.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solomon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bomberland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley's Pies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Neeld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Hardie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Trafford/AFL Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Solomon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Worsfold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Armao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Burns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Primus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP/Julian Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast's Jeremy McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Rivers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McKenna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dockers</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brenton Sanderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Eade's Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Worsfold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windy Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
