<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413052872561137</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/02/melbourne-tram-crash-four-hospitalised</url>
  <title>Melbourne tram crash, four hospitalised</title>
  <content>
An investigation is under way to determine how one tram managed to rear-end another in Melbourne's CBD, injuring passengers.

1 MIN AGO 

Two trams collided in Melbourne's CBD, sending passengers flying onto the floor, with a number left bruised and bleeding.

Four people were taken to hospital and 15 people were assessed by paramedics after one tram rear ended another on busy Bourke Street on Wednesday afternoon.

The front tram had pulled into the stop and was about to let passengers off when it was hit and passengers about to alight were thrown across the carriage.

A number of passengers were left bleeding, including a pregnant woman, and elderly passenger Ann Ensten was thrown to ground.

"There was an enormous thump and I was flat on my face," Ms Ensten told the Nine Network.

"I'm shaken. I've bruised my face and I've already got a sore knee and that's hurting."

A pre-school aged child was taken to the Royal Children's Hospital in a stable condition and three adults suffered minor injuries and were taken to The Alfred and Royal Melbourne hospitals, also in a stable condition.

Yarra Trams is investigating how the crash occurred, including whether the driver of the rear tram braked before the collision.

The scene was cleared by about 4.30pm.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bourke Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Trams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ann Ensten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne's CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Children's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIN AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ensten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
