<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413048577593709</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/lance-franklin-wont-be-changing-his-game-style-despite-being-close-to-suspension/news-story/5ce2682efeac924860a634a4a3a0d5e4</url>
  <title>Swans to maintain aggressive edge</title>
  <content>
LANCE Franklin is walking the suspension tightrope but coach John Longmire hasn't told him to soften his game ahead of Friday night's blockbuster against Geelong at Simonds Stadium.
Franklin's $2500 fine for making unreasonable contact with Luke Hodge's face last Friday night is his second this year and has him one indiscretion away from a ban.
Hodge's tap to the stomach on Tom Papley has earned him a one-week suspension, illustrating how easily Franklin could find himself on the sidelines.
ALL-AUSTRALIAN:
DUSTY SPECIAL:
"Players are aware of where they stand with the MRP and they know to be mindful of it, that's all you can do," Longmire said.
"Most teams want to play a hard physical brand of footy and not give away free kicks or get suspended. But we don't work in a perfect world.
"All teams want to play hard strong physical football but you don't want to give away free kicks and don't want to get suspended. We try our best and the players try their best to get it right and hopefully most of the time you do."
Zak Jones copped a one-match ban when he chalked up his third offence this year when he struck Richmond's Dan Butler in the round 13 clash at the MCG.
But Franklin's young teammate says they will both be maintaining their aggressive edge against the Cats.
"I think every club wants their players to play on the line," Jones said.
"You're definitely aware of how close you are to the line. A lot of players push the line a bit but that's football and you have to play hard, you can't shy away from a contest."
Jones said returning to the Swans' aggressive brand of football has them back in the top eight after losing the first six games of the year.
"We've gone back to playing on the line and getting after the ball," Jones said.
"It's a big focus as is playing with confidence is a really big thing for us. I wouldn't say it's just me, our whole team plays on the line and we play a hard brand of contested football."
Earlier this week Jones extended his stay at the Swans until the end of 2019.
"They've been loyal to me," Jones said.
"They drafted me and that was something big for me. I want to be loyal to the team, it's a great culture here and I want to learn from those leaders. I love this team. I wanted to put it (decision) in the back of my mind and stay away from it for a while and it was good."
Jones sought the advice of his older brother and Melbourne co-captain Nathan Jones before he re-signed.
"He bounced a few things off me and told me what I should look at," Jones said.
"Once we had those discussions I felt confident in what I wanted to do. It would have been great to play with my brother but I want to be my own player and I'm focusing on staying up here."
The Swans are likely to have last week's late withdrawals Jake Lloyd (hip) and Gary Rohan (back) for Friday night's clash with the Cats.
Josh Kennedy (hamstring) trained very lightly but is expected to be named as is Sam Reid (groin) who moved well at training. Ruckman Sam Naismith didn't train at all and looks likely to miss.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Rohan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simonds Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Naismith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Papley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lance Franklin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Franklin's $2500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zak Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond's Dan Butler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Longmire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
