<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412743634909681</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/nt-remotest-students-miss-school-with-poor-internet-phone-lines/8767856</url>
  <title>NT's remote students missing school due to poor telecommunications, parents demand action</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Some children in remote areas of Australia are missing out on a whole term of school due to internet and phone outages, and frustrated parents are demanding action.
Every two to three months, system faults at Leza Cook's property near the border of the Northern Territory and Western Australia cause the phone line to drop out, putting distance schooling and business on hold for weeks.
"We use what we call radio telephone, which is now obsolete technology, and we've gone for months where we haven't had access to a phoneline which has proved to have its trying times," she said.
"I think there's one technician that services this whole area.
"I know we do live very remote but I would like to see equity."
'I'm missing out'

At Supplejack Downs Station, 730 kilometres north-west of Alice Springs, seven children there rely on the single line for school, and to call for help in emergency situations.
When it drops out, it can take weeks or months to be repaired, and although the National Broadband Network is now connected at the remote property, it is not reliable enough.
Seven-year-old Mackenzie Cook said she really liked school and talking with her teachers but the internet connection issues made that difficult.
"I don't feel very happy, I just feel like I'm missing out on stuff," she said.
"Because when [the teacher's] getting to the [important] part, sometimes we get kicked out of the computer, it gets all fuzzy and we can't really hear.
"I have to log back in and she has to restart what she's saying."

Improving bush communications 'not the silver bullet'

Members of the Isolated Children's Parents' Association (ICPA) are meeting in Alice Springs this week for a national conference, and will call on telecommunication providers and the Federal Government to introduce a system that prioritises repair work on properties where children rely on a connection for school.
Frustrated parents, whose children sometimes miss up to a term of schooling due to poor connections, also want telecommunication providers to develop better short-term solutions, and to undertake regular maintenance of their equipment in remote areas.
"Phones and internet are the lifelines these days, particularly in distance education classrooms and also small schools," federal president of the ICPA Wendy Hick said.
"When the internet's down, school stops. When the phone is down, school stops. It's like the teacher's walked right out of the classroom."
Ms Hick said there had been improvements in recent years but more needed to be done to improve standards and reliability.
The association was also calling for the Federal Government to recognise the high travel costs for rural students who move away to study and to develop a national allowance scheme, long-standing issues which have triggered a review into regional, rural, and remote education.
Emeritus Professor John Halsey, an independent reviewer, said he had been meeting with teachers and parents in remote schools.
He hoped to come up with recommendations on how to retain good teachers in regional areas, improve curriculum and assessment, foster entrepreneurship, and help rural students transition beyond school.
"The results profile tends to decline the further you move out from population centres ... [but] there are some outstanding exceptions," he said.
"[Internet] services are patchy at best and it does need to be addressed, there's no two ways about it.
"However, improving [communications] in the bush is not the silver bullet, it's part of the mix."
Public submissions for the independent review close at the end of this month with the final report to be handed to the Federal Government by the end of the year.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supplejack Downs Station, 730</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leza Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Broadband Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Isolated Children's Parents' Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICPA Wendy Hick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms. Hicks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackenzie Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emeritus Professor John Halsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iCPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Internet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
