<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413087232300212</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/afl-news/one-lucky-punter-gets-bailed-out-as-bets-on-patrick-dangerfield-are-refunded-20170802-gxo197.html</url>
  <title>One lucky punter gets bailed out as bets on Patrick Dangerfield are refunded</title>
  <content>
Just three-and-a-half weeks ago one brave football punter wagered one of the biggest bets of the season with the TAB, outlaying $25,000 on Patrick Dangerfield to win this year's Brownlow Medal at the cramped odds of $2.
The punter was convinced Dangerfield could make it back-to-back medals and thought the odds on offer were most attractive.Photo: AAP
Just days later, the Geelong champion rolled his ankle during a best-afield performance against Hawthorn, putting his short-term future in doubt.
Last Saturday, the same investor waited to see if the silky midfielder would escape a charge from his tackle on Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer. But the AFL handed down a one-match suspension, ending Dangerfield's hopes of another medal.
Enter the TAB. Australia's largest wagering organisation declared that they would refund all Brownlow bets on Dangerfield, the first time since it has taken such action since it started betting on the medal.
"The Brownlow is one of the biggest events in football the TAB wager on," a Tabcorp spokesman said."Most punters were on Patrick Dangerfield, who had been the favourite since betting opened late in 2016 and looked set to win the medal."As an act of goodwill we decided to refund all money in full on Dangerfield.
"There's a lot of involvement from punters across the board and we felt it was an opportunity for them to reinvest, or take their cash."
The TAB held more than $200,000 on wagers for Dangerfield to win the medal.The big winners appear to be the punters who took $13 about Richmond midfielder Dustin Martin bringing the medal home to Punt Road. The best you can get now on the red-hot Tiger with the TAB is $1.20.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton's Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tabcorp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punt Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
