<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412576131182057</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/found-the-ideal-hobby-farm/3208050/</url>
  <title>Found! The ideal hobby farm</title>
  <content>
ON the Pomona side of fabulous Kin Kin and just 1.5km from the Village is a 15-acre farmlet, perfect for a few horses or cattle, with high paddocks featuring sensational views and an elevated second potential house site.
The original farmhouse has four bedrooms, beautiful timber floors and a relaxing rear veranda with ramp access, a great space to sit and enjoy privacy and peace.
Inside is comfortable and functional and there are exposed rafters in the front third of the house due to a renovation in the '90s. A second bathroom via the rear veranda has a second shower and doubles as a spacious laundry.
There are two useful 6m x 7m sheds with space to fit four cars undercover and one has a high roof, perfect for a caravan or horse float.
The superb thing about this property is the usable land. Next to the house and sheds is a chook yard, heaps of room for vegie gardens and a mature home orchard including mango, orange, guava and mulberry, all growing in fertile soil.
An adjacent fenced horse paddock sits below another huge paddock, which is gently sloping and approximately three acres itself.
Excellent pastures all irrigated via a small dam connected to a large 5000 gallon concrete water tank positioned high up in the paddock.
On the southern boundary is another small dam next to a grassy access track, which is drivable in dry weather and leads to a high ridgeline with even better views than below. A top spot for a cabin with 360-degree vistas and well over 100 metres above sea level.
Kin Kin has a fantastic primary school, a vibrant local cafe/general store and the historic Country Life Hotel, a central meeting spot for day-trippers and those fortunate enough to discover the Noosa Tracks and Trails network.
KIN KIN
1055 Pomona-Kin Kin Rd
4 Bed, 2 Bath, 4 Car
Features: Four-bedroom farmhouse plus sheds on 6.46ha, ideal as a hobby farm. Irrigated pastures, small dam
Price: Offers over $419,000
Agent: George Andrews at Hargrave Real Estate
Contact: 0477 703 429 5485 2200
Inspection: Saturday 10-11am
Tourist track takes toll with plenty of motorists caught out
Turn your dream of owning a hip cafe or bar into a reality.
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
Coast researchers closing in on prawns behind white spot devastation
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Tracks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pomona-Kin Kin Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kin Kin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Life Hotel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hargrave Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four-bedroom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pomona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bed, 2 Bath, 4 Car</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
