<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413173131647725</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/pwc-mulls-purchase-of-creative-agency-thinkerbell-20170726-gxjlwo</url>
  <title>PwC mulls purchase of creative agency Thinkerbell</title>
  <content>
The shiny new thing in accounting and consulting firms these days is the purchase of an advertising agency.
Accenture did it recently with their multimillion-dollar purchase of Sydney-based creative outfit The Monkeys, PwC signalled their intention to come over all creative when they brought Russel "One L" Howcroft on board and even KPMG's Paul Howes took another step in vaguely the same direction last week with the Lisa Bora.
The number-crunching firms have been busily spinning the story that it's all about creating an "end-to-end solution" for their clients - which is to say, they tell their clients what is wrong with their business, charge them a bucketload to fix it, then hit 'em again on the way out the door by selling them a rebranding and advertising package. Hey presto! It's genius.
In reality though, we all know it's just an attempt by the accountants to get someone vaguely interesting into the tea room. After all, if you can't be cool yourself, you might as well be near it. But we digress.

The latest move in this space is rumoured to be PwC mulling the purchase of Thinkerbell, a new creative agency set up only this year by ad types Adam Ferrier, Jim Ingram and Ben Couzens.

It's only a few months old, but the agency - according to well-placed ad industry sources - has attracted the attention of Howcroft, whose tenure at PwC follows a stint running Network Ten and a couple of years at the head of ad agency Y&R.
Ferrier and Howcroft are old buddies from their time spent sharing desk space and airtime on ABC TV's panel show The Gruen Transfer.
We asked PwC if they cared to comment on the rumours, to receive the following cryptic response: "We are always in the market looking for opportunities that make commercial sense and add value to our clients, but we have no news to announce."
Hopefully, it's second time lucky for PwC. They were in the running for the The Monkeys but never made a formal offer. . We can't imagine PwC shelling out too much for the much smaller, and much more recently-established Thinkerbell.

We'll keep an eye on the for the scoop.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Ingram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thinkerbell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Network Ten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Ferrier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KPMG's Paul Howes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Couzens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PwC</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Accenture</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>R</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gruen Transfer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One L</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Bora</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
