<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413130181973944</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/nsw/five-teams-of-firefighters-called-to-lane-cove-house-fire-20170802-gxo3yl.html</url>
  <title>Five teams of firefighters called to Lane Cove house fire</title>
  <content>
Five teams of firefighters are battling to contain a "fully involved" house fire blazing in Lane Cove, which is posing a "major traffic hazard" due to thick smoke in the area.
Fire services were called to a property on the corner of Lihon Street and Burns Bay Road shortly before 6pm on Wednesday, after receiving "numerous" reports that a fire was blazing through the roof of the house.Photo: Twitter/@IntheCoveITC
An estimated 26 firefighters are currently undertaking "defensive firefighting", spraying water from three sides of the property, in an attempt to prevent the fire from spreading to neighbouring properties. 
The house is fully alight, and Fire and Rescue NSW believe a roof collapse is "imminent". Photo: Twitter/@IntheCoveITC
The blaze is expected to be contained under control within the next half hour, although Fire & Rescue NSW expect it will be later in the evening before the fire is fully extinguished. 
The house is believed to have been unoccupied, but emergency services have been unable to enter the house to confirm. Eight people have been evacuated from neighbouring properties. 

Fire and Rescue NSW reported that smoke from the blaze was "blanketing" the suburb, posing a major traffic hazard to motorists in the area. 
Traffic conditions remain "heavy" in the area, with buses delayed up to 55 minutes, according to Transport for NSW.
While traffic on the southbound direction on Burns Bay Road is being diverted into Penrose Street, cars travelling in the northbound direction are being allowed through using the southbound lane. 
It is unclear at this stage whether the cause of the fire is suspicious. 
More to come.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lane Cove</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burns Bay Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrose Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rescue NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lihon Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IntheCoveITC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
