<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413048577593693</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/webjet-readies-jactravel-pitch-145m-rights-issue-20170801-gxnh24</url>
  <title>Webjet readies JacTravel pitch, $145m rights issue </title>
  <content>
Fund managers can expect a call from Credit Suisse and UBS's equities desks on Thursday morning. 
Topic of the day will be travel bookings and ASX-listed Webjet's plan to create the No.2 business-to-business player globally, and a chunky earnings accretive acquisition offshore.
Webjet has agreed to buy UK-based JacTravel.
When combined with Webjet's WebBeds, it would have relationships with about 17,000 hotels worldwide and the second biggest business-to-business network. 

Webjet's brokers will seek to raise $165 million via an entitlement offer, to part fund the £200 million ($330 million) deal. The raising is priced at $10 a share and structured as a one-for-six non-renounceable rights issue. 

It was underwritten by the two brokers. 
Webjet paid 10.5-times historical earnings for the business, and told investors it would be at least 25 per cent accretive to earnings per share on proforma 2017 financial year numbers, pre synergies. 
The company has also locked in JacTravel management with shares, and they will continue to run the business. 
The acquisition comes at an interesting time for the company after it last week told investors of a disagreement with its auditor BDO over its fiscal year financial statements.

Webjet management is also expected to front investors and analysts on Thursday morning, seeking to secure their support for the raising. 
It comes after a big year for the company with the stock up about 50 per cent compared to a 2 per cent climb in the S&P/ASX200 over the same timeframe. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BDO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK-based JacTravel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed Webjet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JacTravel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credit Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webjet</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webjet's WebBeds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
