<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412958383278622</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/radio/triple-j-launches-survey-to-examine-changing-hottest-100-date-from-january-26-20170802-gxo0de.html</url>
  <title>Triple J launches survey about changing Hottest 100 date</title>
  <content>
Triple J expects to make an announcement in the coming months over its decision about potentially changing the date of its Hottest 100 music countdown in 2018.
Held on January 26, as part of Australia Day celebrations, , which also include council held fireworks and backyard barbecues.

Up Next

Rachel Griffiths speaks against orphanage tourism

01:49

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Entertainment news highlights

Bitchiness on The Bachelor, Dr G Yunupingu's marvelous career, talk shows take on Trump's transgender ban, fans' anger at Australian Ninja Warrior and Ringo and Paul back together again.

The ABC's national youth broadcaster  after it came under increasing pressure from an  in recognition of the offence it caused indigenous Australians.
At the time, indigenous rappers Briggs and Trials, who form A.B. Original, put out a track, titled January 26, addressing the outrage they felt at Australia Day.

"The premise of Australia Day doesn't resonate as a holiday for us so much as it is a reminder of how far we haven't come as a nation," Briggs told Fairfax Media in September last year. "The celebration is just a reminder of the history and things that haven't been addressed whole-heartedly. It's basically a farce of a holiday."
Triple J says it has been consulting with "a variety of groups on the differing perspectives of 26 January" over the past 10 months.

"We're consulting with the ABC Bonner Committee, who are ABC's primary advisory body on issues relating to Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander staff, content and communities," its website said.

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"There's also discussions with Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander media, language groups, and many of the Indigenous artists featured on triple j.Photo: Daniel Boud
"We're also working through an extensive list of contacts from around the country, including Reconciliation Australia, National Congress of Australia's First Peoples, Recognise, and the National Australia Day Council."
Launching , the broadcaster says it now wants to hear from listeners.
"You are the people who vote, listen to and celebrate the Hottest 100.  We want your thoughts on how you feel about triple j, the Hottest 100, and holding the Hottest 100 on Australia Day, January 26," the website said.
The survey, which is anonymous, is made up mostly of multiple-choice responses that span from how often participants listen to Triple J and partake in Hottest 100-related events to their demographic; such as age, gender, state and postcode they reside in, level of education and work situation.
A response to changing the date had to be written and was not limited to a "yes" or "no" answer.
Triple J declined to comment about the  until the process had been completed.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B. Original</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Day Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hottest 100</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Bonner Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 26</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr G. Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Strait Islander</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple J</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Peoples</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitchiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reconciliation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Congress of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Boud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Briggs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
