<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413001332952488</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/breaking-news/wa-premier-tells-pm-fix-gst-or-stay-home/news-story/bdcee123a31347a2a949399628f77919</url>
  <title>PM says WA premier 'belligerent' on GST</title>
  <content>
Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull expects WA Premier Mark McGowan will be all charm when they meet after making "belligerent" remarks about the federal government's refusal to cough up more cash.
The WA government has asked for urgent intervention after calculating new ABS population estimates resulting from last year's bungled census will lead to a $1.9 billion drop in GST share, but Treasurer Scott Morrison says he legally cannot step in.
Mr McGowan rejected the response as "misleading" at a fiery press conference on Wednesday, just a few hours before a meeting with the prime minister that the Labor leader demanded.
"Honestly, they just make up excuses," Mr McGowan told reporters in Perth.
"That is wrong. If Mr Morrison or Mr Turnbull want to direct them (the Commonwealth Grants Commission), they can.
"The prime minister needs to show some national leadership on this issue and he can do it today, without impacting any other state, by reaffirming the earlier census figures so we don't lose that $2 billion."
Mr McGowan said it was "not good enough" the entire cabinet had been in the cash-strapped state for two-and-a-half days without making a significant financial commitment.
"They would have been better off just giving us the money for the airfares and hotel rooms, and not come, if they're not going to do something about the GST, capital works - all the things that are bothering WA," he said.
Mr Turnbull was unimpressed, saying West Australians would expect the premier to be courteous and persuasive if he was seeking co-operation from the federal government, "not issue bellicose, belligerent remarks".
"You know what will happen. I'll see him this afternoon ... he'll be very charming ... he'll say 'oh look I had to say all those things for the media'," Mr Turnbull told reporters in Busselton.
"But I'll tell you something ... in the real world which we should all operate in, you don't have to say things you don't want to."
With Treasury poised to sign off on the state budget figures in one week, Mr McGowan would not rule out slugging taxpayers to make up the $2 billion shortfall.
"We will deal with the budget when that comes along," he said.
Mr Morrison made it clear on Tuesday he wouldn't move on the broader issue of changing the way the GST is carved-up before a Productivity Commission report next year.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McGowan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA Premier Mark McGowan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Productivity Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Morrison</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GST</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Grants Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Busselton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
