<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413048577593772</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/horseracing/nick-olive-has-single-gaze-set-for-caulfield-cup-20170711-gx8r1o.html</url>
  <title>Nick Olive has Single Gaze set for Caulfield Cup</title>
  <content>
With Aussie supermare Winx owning the Cox Plate, Canberra trainer Nick Olive will set stable-star Single Gaze for this year's Caulfield Cup.
The four-year-old mare has returned to work at Olive's Canberra stable after a four-week spell in Queensland.Photo: Jamila Toderas
She'll begin a path towards one of Australia's holy trinity, with Olive deciding on the $3 million Caulfield Cup (2400 metres) as the daughter of Not A Single Doubt's grand final.
Last year, Fairfax Media revealed  before a ligament injury ruled her out of running for the entire spring.

A year on and a successful Brisbane winter campaign behind her, Olive felt the Caulfield Cup should be the next target for his young mare.
She'll begin her campaign in the group 1 Memsie Stakes (1400m) on September 2, the first of four runs leading into the Cup.

If she makes it into the field then it will be Olive's first runner in one of Australia's big three races - the Caulfield Cup, Cox Plate or the Melbourne Cup.
"Single Gaze came back into work [Tuesday], so that's good, that's exciting. She'll probably head for a Caulfield Cup campaign," Olive told Fairfax Media.
"She's come back in good order from Queensland. She had four weeks off. She's back in familiar territory, even though it's quite cool.
"We'll probably start in the Memsie Stakes first up and I think that's on September 2.
"She'll have four runs leading into it and the Caulfield Cup will be her fifth run.
"It's very exciting to have a horse good enough to be heading in that direction. Hopefully everything goes right and she comes up and things go to plan."
After missing the spring, Single Gaze returned to form in Queensland.
She won the listed Tail Stakes (1600m) before placing in the group 2 Hollindale Stakes (1800m).
The mare then bounced back from a sixth on a heavy track in the group 1 Doomben Cup (2000m) by saluting in the group 2 PJ O'Shea Stakes (2200m) and a second in the group 2 Brisbane Cup (2200m).
After saluting in her first group 1, the Vinery Stud Stakes (2000m) at Rosehill in March 2016, she had a spectacular fall in last year's group 1 ATC Oaks (2400m), which amazingly only left her shaken and bruised. 
Despite her strong Brisbane stint, Olive felt it was wise to avoid Winx, who has won the last two Cox Plates as part of a string of 17 consecutive wins. 
"It's was the Cox Plate last year, but obviously we're trying to avoid Winx as much as possible," he said.
"I thought she went really well during the winter in Brisbane. I think she'll improve again this campaign.
"That was her first campaign back from the fall and she'll be even better this campaign."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Cup (2200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosehill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PJ O'Shea Stakes (2200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memsie Stakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollindale Stakes (1800</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olive's Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield Cup</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATC Oaks (2400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Single Gaze</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Single Doubt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memsie Stakes (1400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winx</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamila Toderas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vinery Stud Stakes (2000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tail Stakes (1600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield Cup (2400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doomben Cup (2000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cox Plate</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Olive</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
