<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413173131647781</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/chanticleer/dividends-and-capital-management-underpin-genworth-investment-story-20170802-gxo02l</url>
  <title>Dividends stream from Genworth capital machine </title>
  <content>
Counter-intuitive investors would have smiled on Wednesday when Genworth Mortgage Insurance Australia shares jumped 6.5 per cent on the back of a long list of negative financial indicators.
The negatives outnumbered the positives by about 10 to one. Gross earned premiums fell 7.7 per cent, interim net profit fell 34.7 per cent, its insurance margin tumbled 15.4 per cent and return on equity fell 3.4 per cent.
Some of these negative numbers were driven by structural changes in the market, including Macquarie Group's decision to dump Genworth as its mortgage insurer. Westpac Banking Corp dumped Genworth in 2015 and there is talk National Australia Bank will do the same.
On top of that the company's loss ratio rose 1.8 per cent and the delinquency rate on its mortgages rose from 0.43 per cent to 0.51 per cent.

Adding to the apparent negativity is the company's decision to stick with its financial guidance for the year to December. It is forecasting net earned premium growth will fall by 10 to 15 per cent.

The market got excited for two reasons: the 14¢ a share dividend payment and the capital return through a $100 million buyback.
These capital management moves go to the heart of the market's misunderstanding of exactly what Genworth is about.
Rather than being viewed as a mortgage insurance company in decline with a grim earnings outlook it can be seen as a capital-generating machine.
Also, there are good reasons why it should stay that way for several years to come.

Genworth is not risk free. Its mortgage insurance product is one of the first lines of defence for major banks that have forced customers with loan to value ratios in excess of 80 per cent to take out cover.
That means it is not immune from a crash in the housing market. Those with first-hand experience of the global financial crisis will know that mortgage insurers were hit hard when the toxic sub-prime mortgage market blew up in the United States.
In the US the handful of big listed mortgage insurers had insufficient capital to meet the losses  that flowed from poor underwriting practices, mainly in Florida and California.
But even in those dim dark days Australian mortgage insurers were relatively immune from the residential market downturn in the US.

Our version of US mortgage insurance crisis involved the PMI Group in the US selling its Australian arm to QBE Insurance for $1 billion. In hindsight, QBE got a bargain, which can't be said for many of the businesses it bought over the past decade.
Genworth came to be listed on the Australian market because of financial pressures on its parent, which is headquartered in Richmond Virginia, a satellite town for Washington's public servants.
Genworth's financial pressures also forced it to sell a stake in its Canadian operations, which are now owned 55 per cent by the US parent.
Genworth in the US kept a 52 per cent controlling stake in the Australian business.

The Australian and Canadian operations of Genworth are, in effect, the cash cows for meeting the pressing financial obligations of its parent. Both subsidiaries pay reliable dividends.
In Australia the normal interim and final dividends have been topped up with special cash dividends in 2014, 2015, 2016 and again in 2017. Genworth also had a capital return in 2016.
On Wednesday, Genworth said it would pay an interim dividend of 12c a share and a special dividend of 2c a share. The $100 million buyback is equivalent to about 6.5 per cent of issued capital.
At the last Genworth annual meeting shareholders approved the buyback of up to 25 per cent of the issued capital. In other words there are more buybacks to come because only about a quarter of what was approved is in progress.

A feature of the latest result was the amount of cash and liquid investments that are held by Genworth. Prior to the payment of the interim dividend and special dividend the company's net tangible asset backing was $3.87 a share.
One investor in the stock said  there were at least three reasons why he bought the stock.
"I am being paid a fully franked dividend yield of 10 per cent to hold a stock that is trading at a discount to NTA.
"Secondly, the company has excess capital and the capacity to increase that capital through more buybacks.
"Third, as the mortgage loan book matures the risks in the portfolio decrease."
That last point is an important one because it suggests that as the Australian housing boom continues, Genworth will have  fewer of the new, more risky loans on its books.
It is apparent that the parent in the US has an incentive to continue streaming capital to itself through dividends and buybacks, given that it will participate in the buyback.
Genworth in Australia has a dividend payout ratio range of between 50 per cent and 80 per cent. In the latest interim period it was 53.9 per cent.

The US parent wants to maintain control of the company while enjoying the benefits of the local Genworth loan book being run off.
One astute investor, who was involved in the run-off of mortgage loans at RHG Ltd, said he saw great similarities between the situation facing Genworth shareholders and shareholders in RHG.
When RHG was in run-off it took the market some time to work out what that would mean in terms of dividends paid and capital management. In the last two years of its life up to June 2013, RHG paid out $1.21 in dividends. That is not bad for a stock that was trading at around 14¢ a share in 2009.
There are some wild cards associated with Genworth. First, NAB could decide to dump them as a provider of mortgage insurance, which would affect earnings.
Second, a Chinese company, China Oceanwide, has made a $US2.7 billion takeover bid for the US parent company.
This week the two parties agreed to extend the deadline for the merger until November because of delays caused by the demands of regulators in the US charged with approving the transaction.
If the Chinese are successful in buying Genworth in the US it could have negative implications for the local stock. Genworth is sitting on about $280 million in excess capital. Would China Oceanwide attempt to get its hands on that cash in a way that was not fair to all shareholders?
Fortunately, the Australian Prudential Regulation Authority rules mortgage insurers with an iron fist. It will ensure that Genworth maintains sufficient capital to protect mortgage insurance customers.

Also, it is hard to see the Chinese turning against the baked-in strategy of streaming income from Australia to the parent in the most efficient manner possible, which is dividends and buybacks.
Disclosure: The author's self managed super fund owns shares in Genworth.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>QBE Insurance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RHG Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NTA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond Virginia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genworth Mortgage Insurance Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMI Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QBE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Oceanwide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Prudential Regulation Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac Banking Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RHG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genworth</name>
    <count>22</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
