<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413052872561093</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/riverside-refresh-wins-tenancy-for-gpt-20170802-gxnp5y</url>
  <title>Riverside refresh wins tenancy for GPT </title>
  <content>
GPT's unlisted office fund has signed up Deloitte for another decade at the Riverside Centre after a $30 million overhaul of the office tower in Brisbane's Golden Square.
Deloitte, a major tenant at the 123 Eagle Street tower, is extending its lease over 6,000 square metres until November 2028 with an option for another four years.
Under the new deal Deloitte gets signage rights at the well-known Brisbane landmark and has plans for a rooftop logo.
"Deloitte's decision to remain at the Riverside Centre is a strong endorsement for the building," said Martin Ritchie, fund manager for the GPT Wholesale Office Fund.

"New furniture, lighting, contemporary artwork, collaboration areas and quiet spaces have been included in the upgrade of the lobby allowing it to adapt to a more modern style of work and doing business," he said.

The 41-storey tower, designed by Harry Seidler, comprises 51,600 square metres and has a 4.5 Star NABERS energy rating. Its book value is close to $630 million.
The recently completed refurbishment included an upgrade to the lobby, forecourt area, and food court. The lifts were refurbished and converted to a destination control system.
"We're using this opportunity to invest in a complete refurbishment of our floors in recognition that the nature of work as we know it is profoundly changing," said John Greig, Deloitte's managing partner in Queensland.
"Queensland needs to be on the front foot of changes in the labour market, to ensure that all Queenslanders have great jobs that suit their needs.

"We're investing in the best technology, environment and methods to help our people play to their strengths."
GPT's unlisted office fund delivered a total return of 14.5 per cent in its 2016 financial year. It holds 18 office properties in portfolio worth $6.6 billion.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Greig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deloitte</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star NABERS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2028</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagle Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT Wholesale Office Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverside Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Seidler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPT</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Ritchie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane's Golden Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
