<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412915433604820</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/the-age-editorial/curbing-the-use-of-family-trusts-to-avoid-tax-is-about-fairness-not-class-war-20170802-gxnuo0.html</url>
  <title>Curbing the use of family trusts to avoid tax is about fairness, not class war</title>
  <content>
The flaw in Opposition Leader Bill Shorten's proposed crackdown on the use of family trusts to avoid tax is that it would only partially close a loophole politicians of all hues have for decades known is exploited primarily by the very wealthy. Claims by the Coalition and business lobby groups that it is "class warfare" and "the politics of envy" do not stand scrutiny.
Mr Shorten merits credit for a policy to at least prune a practice that should be offensive to anyone who professes to believe in fairness.
Currently, discretionary trusts allow high and middle-income breadwinners to split their income and distribute it to family members on lower tax rates - adult children at university or retired parents, for example.
So a rich miner or manufacturer with the right tax agent is able to minimise or even extinguish their tax bill by promising money to his kids and his parents.
The ethics of these practices are open to question, but it is absolutely rational and legal behaviour. That is why the law should be changed. Discretionary trusts originated as far back as Norman England, after William the Conqueror invaded in 1066.
We don't really know the origins, although some speculate that Crusaders established trusts so their lands could be managed in their absence.

Far more recently, trusts have come to be used to split incomes between adult family members. This is estimated to reduce public revenue by billions. As then treasurer Peter Costello said almost 20 years ago, "the community subsidises the wealthy taxpayer". Mr Costello tried and failed to reform trusts. He was right to try, as was John Howard when he changed the tax arrangements to prevent people splitting income with children under the age of 18. All these years later, Mr Shorten is advocating a tax of 30 per cent on payments by discretionary trusts.
As this is well below the top marginal rate of 45 per cent, an incentive remains to split incomes. But it is estimated the move would generate more than $1 billion a year, which Mr Shorten says would be mostly used to reduce the budget deficit and national debt, both of which have increased significantly under the Coalition government.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Labor's plan to clamp down on trusts still allows a significant loophole: wealthy trust users can already cut their tax bill to 30 per cent by making distributions to other companies rather than family members - this is what is known as the "bucket company" option.
While the trust reforms do not go as far as they might, Mr Shorten's proposal is a step in the right direction. May it have more success than previous federal government attempts.

A note from the editor - Subscribers can get Age editor Alex Lavelle's exclusive weekly newsletter delivered to their inbox by signing up here:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Lavelle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opposition Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norman England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conquerors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Shorten</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Costello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
