<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413259030995032</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/afl/teams/hawthorn/sam-mitchell-never-forgot-the-people-who-helped-him-realise-his-afl-dream/news-story/cbaa4dbec7efed280c83e8599d185a8c</url>
  <title>Mitchell never forgot where it started</title>
  <content>
AS MANY of his Hawthorn teammates were reaching for the endless supply of cold beverages in the moments immediately after the club's 2008 premiership win, Sam Mitchell was searching the contact list on his phone.
He wanted to thank those who had afforded him the only thing he had asked for - a chance.
Mitchell had been overlooked in the 2000 national draft and dismissed as "too slow" for the 21st century athletic prototype.
MARK ROBINSON:
NEXT PHASE:
If it hadn't been for the hard work and hard sell from a number of people around Box Hill and Hawthorn during the 2001 season, he might not have been selected as pick 36 in what turned out to be the AFL's Super Draft.
David Parkin was one of the first few calls Mitchell made that 2008 Grand Final day.
"Sam rang me within half an hour of playing in that first premiership, to thank me for having the confidence in him," Parkin recalled.
"That is the sort of person he is.
"I said to him, 'Sam, I appreciate you would even think to ring me, but it was Donald McDonald who really supported you the most, so make sure you give him a call to thank him'.
"His answer was 'I rang him before I rang you'."
McDonald, who gave him a chance at the Box Hill Hawks and who constantly talked up his draft potential to then-Hawks recruiting manager John Turnbull during the 2001 season, says Mitchell has never forgotten where he has come from.
Before his 300th game with Hawthorn last year, Mitchell invited a dozen or so past coaches and mentors to a dinner in Balwyn, speaking about each of their impact on his football career.
"He's so respectful of where he has come from," McDonald said.
"It's a credit to him that he never gave up. He just wanted an opportunity."
Parkin rates the 34-year-old as the equal of dual Brownlow medallist Greg Williams as the best inside midfielders he has seen.
"I can't think of two more players who have influenced games like Williams and Mitch, as people who didn't have the attributes that maybe Australian football demands.
Those two blokes turned themselves into players who became as good as anyone else in the game."
When he was coach of Carlton in the 1980s, Parkin twice passed on Williams before he went on to start his career elsewhere and return full circle to the Blues.
When he was football director at Hawthorn in 2001, Parkin knew had to give the kid who reminded him so much of Williams the benefit of the doubt.
- adding three more flags to his 2008 success, awarded the 2012 Brownlow, a five-time Hawthorn best-and-fairest winner and leaving Hawthorn after 15 happy years for a season at West Coast.
During his press conference in Perth - watched on by his wife, Lyndall, and his three children, Smith, Scarlett and Emmy - Mitchell thanked those who had supported him across 16 seasons,
"It's no great surprise but it's time for me to hang up the little waddle and the little size nines at the end of the season," Mitchell said.
He's proud of his many achievements, but just as grateful for the help along the way.
"Whatever the game threw at me, whether that was my body shape or I couldn't kick too far, I just always found a way," he said.
"I'm really proud of that now."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balwyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill Hawks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyndall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emmy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MARK ROBINSON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>13</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand Final</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald McDonald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Parkin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL's Super Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
