<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412524591573335</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/sex/straight-men-who-have-sex-with-other-men/news-story/7c32167307be0ad47f3568c9e5e789ab</url>
  <title>Straight men who have sex with other men</title>
  <content>
Can a straight man hook up with a guy and still be straight? Girls can.

Nikki Goldstein

Share

WARNING: Sexual content
IF A man is sexual with another man, is he gay? You can kiss a girl and like it and be straight, but man on man sex is quickly put in the category of homosexuality.
It's a subject that has always fascinated me because I have many gay friends who bed these so-called straight (and often married) men with excitement, enthusiasm and frequency.
I'd heard of the term "men who have sex with men" (msm), but was confused as to why these straight men/gay men hook-ups were occurring so commonly, and what it was all about.
Are these men secretly gay and in hiding?
As it turns out, not all of them are. After investigating the issue and speaking to some of the men involved, I was surprised to find out that as well as some of these men being in the closet, there is also a population of guys out there who are hooking up with other guys just for the pure ease at which a hook up can occur.
It is not necessarily about sexual attraction to a gender, but sexual pleasure.
Finding a gay man who has experience in this was not difficult at all. Max* informed me that finding straight men to hook up with is not that hard. "It's pretty easy to find if you know where you are looking. Probably any toilet you go to is a beat," he said.
He also informed me of a recent encounter he had with a straight man at a sex on premises club who he thought was gay.

Towards the end of the encounter, his phone rang displaying a photo of the man he was hooking up with and his wife on their wedding day. This was later reconfirmed by a text message which said, "You give head as good as my wife does."
I also spoke to another man who has a glory hole (a sheet in his apartment that has a hole in it which sexual acts can be anonymously carried out through) and puts out ads to have encounters with straight men only.
These men will walk in and walk away without knowing who the person is on the other side but understand that it is another man.
While some men might be experimenting with their sexuality and desires, Max explains that the glory hole encounters between men where one might not identify as gay could be more to do with the ease at which men can get off.
"The majority of straight men who are going to a glory hole are going because they don't want to see who is on the other side. It is about just getting off.
"Is it that easy to find another girl who is just willing to give a blow job and say nothing more? Guys know what other guys are like. Guys just want to (get off). It sounds harsh, but it's true."
As much as gay men are willing to boast about their encounters with straight men, finding a straight man who engages in these same sex experiences to talk openly was like the hunt for Bin Laden.
After a call out I received a message from a man name Paul who identified as straight but admitted, "he had an occasional urge to have a different sexual experience, one you can have with a guy".
His overall advice: "Try to understand it and embrace it. I think there are so many more men out than the world realises, than woman realise, that enjoy a different type of stimulation."
Paul continues, "I would think that society would be amused by the number of men that are out there that seek a slightly different adventure and it doesn't necessarily mean in any way shape or form that they are gay or bi. They are just wanting to experiment and have a bit of fun just like we see girls out there on the dance floor."
And by girls on the dance floor, Paul is referring to the hypersexual behaviour of women towards each other, sometimes even sexual encounters, that don't require any labels. The idea that two women together is hot but two men together is gay.
Paul wants to experience different sexual encounters and not be restricted by a label. He describes it as "going to a theme park and saying I haven't tired that ride before, this looks like fun."
Which begs the question: If you are a straight man who has sex with men, why identify as straight? If you enjoy it, why not call yourself bi or fluid?
It seems there are many issues when it comes to homosexuality that many men are not comfortable with, and these might stem from lifestyle, masculinity to cultural or religion.
"If you are attracted to sex with men and you are straight, do we have to put a label on it?" agrees Max. "There isn't a straight forward answer, it's a complex issue about sexual identity, labels, mixed with cultural expectations."
The issue with many labels is they come attached with set assumptions and even some negative associations about how someone who identities with that label must be and live their life.
It can also be very confusing when someone doesn't stick to stereotypically what that label says. We all have a right to change our minds and go with the flow. Isn't that what being true to ourselves is all about? Why should we correct someone's label if they are comfortable with it?
As the number of sexual labels increases and the complexity of how we identify grows, maybe the answer is to understand how someone lives their life, not try change or correct them if we don't agree.
Dr Nikki Goldstein is a sexologist. She goes deeper into the topic of straight men who have sex with men in her new podcast on PodcastOne.
*Names have been changed
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PodcastOne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Nikki Goldstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikki Goldstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bin Laden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
