<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412915433604840</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/18/31/nurofen-settles-3-5m-class-action</url>
  <title>Nurofen settles $3.5m class action</title>
  <content>
Australians who bought a packet of Nurofen between 2011 and 2015 could be compensated after the company that makes the popular painkillers agreed to settle a consumer class action, a law firm says.
Bannister Law on Wednesday said it had reached a $3.5 million settlement with drug company Reckitt Benckiser, subject to final approval in the Federal Court.
An independent third party will use the money to reimburse eligible consumers who bought products in the Nurofen Specific Pain Range, the law firm said in a statement.
The firm expects settlement notices will be published in Australian newspapers, calling for people who purchased the products between January 2011 and December 2015 to register a claim.
Reckitt Benckiser was previously hit with a $6 million fine over the Nurofen Specific Pain Range in 2016.
The consumer watchdog successfully argued in the Federal Court that four of the range's products - for back pain, period pain, migraines and tension headaches - were chemically identical despite claims they targeted specific pain.
The ACCC also said the products were similar to other standard Nurofen ibuprofen products but almost double the price.

Related Articles

Justice James Edelman ruled Reckitt Benckiser had breached Australian consumer law but noted in his 2016 penalty judgment that the company had since changed its packaging.
Comment has been sought from Reckitt Benckiser.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice James Edelman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reckitt Benckiser</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen Specific Pain Range</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bannister Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
