<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413310570603592</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/water-from-the-fenton-plant-is-officially-the-best-tasting-water-in-the-state/news-story/4d77aceab47d84554f65afea68d1384d</url>
  <title>State's best water boiled down</title>
  <content>
THEY nosed the drop and they swirled the fluid around in their mouths but this was no highbrow affair at a winery.
This was a battle of Tasmania's tap waters.
While 17 of the state's towns are still on boil water alerts, the 16 samples taken from TasWater sources and tasted at the Ixon TasWater Taste Test came from water plants across the state that supply towns where residents can drink straight from the tap.
The competition is run by the Water Industry Operators Association of Australia and was held at Launceston's Mowbray Racecourse.
During a blind taste test, samples were arbitrated on colour, clarity, odour and taste.
Water Industry Operators Association of Australia young operator of the year Patrick Cotton was taken aback by the odour from one of the four samples.
"This one's a bit on the nose. That's not the best start before you taste," Mr Cotton said.
By 3pm the results were in and last year's winner and reigning 2016 National Champion, Barrington Water Treatment Plant, had been knocked off its perch.
The state's best water now officially comes from Fenton, a plant that supplies water from Lake Fenton to parts of the Hobart area. Fenton will represent Tasmania at the national water competition on October 18.
Because the best water in the nation came from the state last year, Tasmania will host the national competition this year.
TasWater is embroiled in a fight with the State Government as it prepares to take legislation to the Upper House to transfer control of Tasmania's water assets from the council-owned entity to government hands.

TasWater has cancelled boil water alerts to several Tasmanian communities in the past few weeks, including Avoca, Ringarooma, Legerwood and Lady Barron.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legerwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston's Mowbray Racecourse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ixon TasWater Taste Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringarooma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Fenton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasWater</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Champion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barrington Water Treatment Plant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fenton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Cotton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avoca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Barron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Industry Operators Association of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Cotton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Industry Operators Association of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
