<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413177426615112</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/basketball/gun-hobart-chargers-guard-alex-ciabattoni-making-a-move-back-to-the-wnbl/news-story/c66a712b4840848be6c561edcd8decb9</url>
  <title>Ciabattoni scores spot with WNBL team</title>
  <content>
HOBART Chargers star Alex Ciabattoni will make a well-earned return to the WNBL after signing a contract with Perth Lynx for the upcoming season, but the 23-year-old plans to return next season.
The guard has signed a five-month deal with the Lynx for the 2017-18 campaign, which starts on October 6 and finishes in January.
It will be her second stint in the big league after playing for Adelaide Lightning in 2015-16 - where she was also named the WNBL rookie of the year - and 2016-17.
After a second season at Adelaide, Ciabattoni originally signed with SEABL side Melbourne Tigers this year. However she left the club because it wasn't the right fit and .
Ciabattoni has netted 349 points in 19 games for the Chargers this year at an average of 18.4 and will play on with the side until the end of their campaign.
"I value this a lot as there's not a lot of positions going so I felt so fortunate to have a chance to prove myself," she said. "I am hoping to come back here [to Hobart] - I really liked it here."
Chargers coach Dwain Davie said Ciabattoni had made an impact for his side both on and off the court and wished her the best at Perth.
"Getting Alex has been an absolute godsend for us," Davie said.
"It's pleasing to see her get the rewards ... because she's really capable and a quality player that can make a difference at that level.
"She's got the size, she's got the versatility, she can play all three guard positions and defend bigger people."
Davie said the club would look to re-sign Ciabattoni for the 2017-18 SEABL season, which commences in March.
Meanwhile, the fourth-placed Chargers face their final two games this weekend ahead of the SEABL finals. They meet the Centre of Excellence in Canberra on Friday night before travelling to Frankston on Saturday night.
Hobart has won four of its past five games and Davie said a third-place finish - and a home semi final - was still on the cards. Currently, Launceston sits in third and faces Dandenong on Saturday.
"We need to at least win one out of two games to catch [Launceston] and if they win their game then we need to win both of ours," he said.
"We get Izzy Morgan back for the game in Canberra and hopefully she'll be available if we make it to the finals."
Tip off is 7.30pm against the CoE and 6pm against Frankston.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HOBART Chargers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dwain Davie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Lightning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEABL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Izzy Morgan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Ciabattoni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Lynx</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centre of Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ciabattoni</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
