<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413301980668909</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/help-for-parents-of-kids-addicted-to-social-media-and-phones/news-story/f7aa95a8f816aa044b93c29386ff1d91</url>
  <title>Help for parents of phone-addicted kids</title>
  <content>
SOUTH Australian mums and dads are increasingly turning to parental-control tools in a desperate bid to manage their children's online and social media activity.
Parental controls can block sexually explicit sites, set screen time limits, block in-app purchases, block numbers and SMS, restrict chat features and allow for parental monitoring.
Parents can even opt to block the smartphone's camera, to stop kids from taking selfies in the bathroom.
According to the , 70 per cent of parents are monitoring their child's internet usage, including through the use of either free or paid-for parental-control apps such as "OurPact".

Tips for parents from the SA Department for Education and Child Development on ways to keep children safe online

How to keep your child safe online
Cyber safety educator Jordan Foster says while not new, the surge in uptake of this type of technology reflects a growing fear among parents that teens are exposing themselves to risky sites as well as a growth in "deception apps" - disturbing apps disguised as something innocent-looking such as a calculator but hiding a private vault of photos, videos and texts.
"I speak to thousands of parents each year and the number one thing I am asked, is about parent-control tools," the clinical psychologist and founder of  says.

"There is a sense of panic - parents know there is a problem but don't know what to do about it." - Jordan Foster
"There is a sense of panic - parents know there is a problem but don't know what to do about it and they are desperate to know what is available in the way of tools."
One Adelaide mum of a 14-year-old girl told The Advertiser: "It's really, really sad to see how addicted kids are to their phones, especially girls - for them it's all about seeking validation, seeing how many likes they can get, how many Snapchat streaks they can get, how many people tell them they're gorgeous."
Ms Foster says a major issue for parents is they can't keep up with their tech-savvy kids.
"It can be really difficult for parents to keep on top of online trends and risks among all the other parenting duties and family happenings," she says.
"Cloud-based parental-control tools, especially those that provide 'expert opinion advice' can give some peace of mind as downloads deemed risky or not age appropriate for a child are automatically blocked and parents alerted to it via an email, including a short description as to why it has been blocked.
"This can be so valuable in not only minimising risk but also buying parents time to find out more about the app so they can then have a discussion with their child about it, creating an important communication loop.
"An example of this is the Yellow app which appears as a yellow logo and seems really innocent but is basically a teenager version of Tinder and is actually really dangerous."
Ms Foster says while some parents may worry they are being intrusive by monitoring their child's screen habits, keeping them safe must be paramount, and suggests eight or nine is a good time to start.
"If parents start young, kids naturally adapt to it and you can change settings, rules as the child gets older," she says.
"Initially there can be resistance from kids but I've had many young people admit to me it's actually been a positive thing for them and meant they haven't been tempted to wake up at 2am to check their Instagram and Snapchat pages."
Tim Levy, , agrees and says a recent survey of 1000 young people by his company showed 45 per cent of pre-teens were using unsafe social media, teenagers were spending four hours a day on social media and more than 30 per cent were sending or receiving 10 or more texts every night.
"It is becoming an increasingly important part of parenting to control the time and content of electronic devices in the home," he says.
While Woolcock Institute Of Medical Research adolescent sleep physician Chris Seton worries about the impact these habits are having on young people's sleep patterns, saying a good night's sleep is imperative to a young person's development.
"The (Family Zone) survey shows 85 per cent of teenagers have electronic devices in their bedrooms, while 58 per cent use electronic screens while lying in bed, both dangerous habits which research has shown has a detrimental effect on teenagers' mental and physical health," Dr Seton said.
eSafety Commissioner Julie Inman Grant warns while parental control tools can be useful they are not "100 per cent foolproof".
"There is no silver bullet to protecting your child online," she said.
"Parental controls should be used in conjunction with a range of other strategies - most importantly, regular conversations with your children about potential online risks and ways to develop good cyber judgment and resilience for when they do come across inappropriate or concerning content."
Warning signs to look out for when your child is using social media include (from the Office of the eSafety Commissoner):
BEING secretive with their devices or the computer
OVERLY tired /a change in sleep patterns
BEING upset after using the internet or their device
APPEARING lonely or distressed
A DECLINE in school work
UNEXPECTED changes to friendship groups
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Levy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commissoner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Child Development</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolcock Institute Of Medical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Office of the eSafety</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Foster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OurPact</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapchat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Foster</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eSafety Commissioner Julie Inman Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tinder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Zone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
