<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413344930342821</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828880/charges-after-phones-stolen/?cs=12&utm_source=latestnews&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=Latest%20news%20traffic</url>
  <title>Charges after phones stolen</title>
  <content>
A man has been charged after he allegedly broke into an elderly woman's home in Morpeth and stole two mobile phones right in front of her.
Police claim the man went into the rear yard of the Morpeth Road home about 7am Friday, June 30 and looked through a glass sliding door where he saw the woman in the kitchen.
It is alleged he walked in to the house and stole two mobile phones from a kitchen bench before he fled the home.
The woman told police she witnessed the whole incident take place.
After the man left the woman cried out for help. Her husband, who was in a front bedroom, heard his wife's plea and yelled out to the man.
The man then approached the bedroom window where it is alleged he punched through fly screen in an attempt to strike the man.
The elderly man was not harmed, but the fly screen was damaged.
The couple told police the man ran from the area.
Maitland Police were called out to the scene and canvassed the area. They sourced CCTV footage which helped identify the man.

Investigations led police to a home in Korbell Street, Tenambit on Wednesday morning where they arrested the man.

Police said he was apprehended while trying to escape out the back door of the home.
The man was taken to Maitland Police Station and charged with aggravated break, enter and steal, malicious damage, assault and trespassing.
The two stolen mobile phones were recovered. Central Hunter crime manager Detective Inspector George Radmore said the phones will be returned to the woman.

Police claim ammunition, handcuffs and other items including tools and jewelry, which were suspected to be stolen, were all found at the home.

Inspector Radmore said information from the public helped lead to the man's arrest. He thanked those who contacted police with information.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tenambit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morpeth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector Radmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Inspector George Radmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morpeth Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korbell Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
