<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413306275636249</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4829554/watson-eager-for-pivotal-role/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Watson eager for pivotal role</title>
  <content>
After spending two years as a Sydney Roosters utility, Connor Watson is eyeing the stability of being Newcastle's five-eighth next NRL season.
Watson will join the Knights on three-year deal from 2018 after playing most of his 31 games with the Roosters off the bench.
The 21-year-old wants to play 80 minutes weekly at Newcastle after Roosters coach Trent Robinson could not guarantee him an expanded role next year.
"Obviously I didn't get to play too many minutes at the start of the year and there was a few clubs interested and asking around," Watson told reporters on Wednesday.
"It sort of turned out that there was an opportunity and I was really happy the Roosters would let me go.
"Obviously, it's in my best interests as a player because I can go up there and look to play 80 minutes every week, where if I stayed here I would be stuck in that utility role for another year."
Watson has played the past two matches at fullback due to an injury to No.1 Michael Gordon but is adamant he's best suited to playing in the halves.
Unfortunately for him, he sits behind playmakers Luke Keary and Mitchell Pearce in the Roosters' pecking order.
He is expected to get the No.6 jersey at the Knights next year given current playmakers Brock Lamb and Trent Hodkinson both prefer to play at halfback.
There is a chance Watson could also partner fellow new arrival Kalyn Ponga in the halves but the young Cowboy is expected to play fullback for Newcastle.
"There's no guarantees in rugby league but there's a spot at six up there at the Knights," Watson said.

SIGNED: Connor Watson

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalyn Ponga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Hodkinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Lamb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor Watson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Keary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
