<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413559678711716</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/naplan-results-2017-townsville-data-for-all-schools/news-story/c442f6bb8f992d238a1b75b5deafc31e</url>
  <title>Who topped Townsville's NAPLAN results?</title>
  <content>
TOWNSVILLE private schools have come out on top in high school NAPLAN results, mirroring a statewide trend.
The Queensland Curriculum and Assessment Authority yesterday released preliminary NAPLAN data for school achievement in Years 3, 5, 7 and 9 across five test areas.
Scroll down for Queensland schools data
Townsville Grammar School had the city's top average scores for Years 7 and 9, with The Cathedral School and St Margaret Mary's College close behind.
When Queensland schools with more than 20 students were ranked by their cumulative mean score across all five tests, nine of the top 10 performing schools in Years 7 and 9 were private schools.
In comparison, five state primary schools were in the top 10 performers.
Townsville Grammar School director of studies Stephen Monk said the school was proud of its results.
"NAPLAN results are important, but we do not teach to the test and more importantly these results are an indicator of a healthy school culture of love of learning," he said. "As a school we can only give credit where it is due - to the parents who make sacrifices, to the children who really put in so much effort and to our professional staff who give so much to their students. All three stakeholders working together have achieved this."
The Cathedral School principal Ian Gamack said the school had seen significant improvements across all grades.
"It's great affirmation that the programs we have put in place in the last 24 months are actually working," he said.
"As a school that has a holistic approach to learning, NAPLAN is not a strong focus here. We believe in educating the whole child.
"We have goals that we set for our students and our staff and people are all on the same page in terms of what we value in whole child development and in academic development."
Education Minister Kate Jones said comparing the private and public sectors was unfair given state schools did the heavy lifting to educate disadvantaged students.
"When you are comparing select-entry schools that choose who come in with schools that welcome all students that live in their local area, there is a always going to be a difference," she said.
The final results will be published in the NAPLAN National Report in December.Queensland NAPLAN data 2017
The data shows the average scale score of students at each school, as provided by the Queensland Curriculum & Assessment Authority.
Raw scores are transformed into scale scores that allow comparison of students between year levels and in the future, across years. Higher scores indicate higher performance.
Viewing these tables on your mobile? Flip to landscape for optimal reading.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville's NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assessment Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Grammar School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December.Queensland NAPLAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 7</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Monk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathedral School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Kate Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN National Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Gamack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Margaret Mary's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Curriculum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
