<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412524591573297</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/crown-towers-perth-wins-was-top-construction-award/news-story/7e4ac094a0901eef3523ed39699f5453</url>
  <title>Crown Towers wins top gong</title>
  <content>
WA™s first major six-star hotel, Crown Towers Perth, is shining even brighter after winning the State™s top construction award.

The $460 million Multiplex development outscored a slew of competitors to take out the coveted 2017 Bankwest Best Project title at this year's Master Builders-Bankwest Excellence in Construction Awards.

In addition to being the best project, Crown Towers is also the biggest hotel in WA. Its split tower of 15 and 22 storeys contains 500 luxury rooms, suites and villas within a world-class resort complex that spans more than 33,000sqm and includes a multi-tiered, lagoon-style pool, poolside bar and dining, a day spa, fitness centre and lush landscaping.

Master Builders Awards judge Rod Sproule said it was an "exceptionally well-executed project".

"The commitment to quality design and workmanship is evident from the moment you step into the lobby," he said.

"Congratulations to architect TWS International and all the tradespersons who worked on this project, it's set a new benchmark for luxury accommodation in WA."

It's the ninth time in the awards' 28-year history that Multiplex has received this prestigious honour.

Multiplex also won the Best Building Fit-Out and Best Multi-Unit development over $50 million for its work on Crown Towers Perth.

First-time entrant Commercial Aquatics won the Subcontractor of the Year award for creating the resort's elaborate, beautifully tiled swimming pools, water features and indoor spas.

"The man hours required to meticulously install all of the 2.2 million mosaics (tiles) to a consistently high standard is a credit to the team at Commercial Aquatics," Mr Sproule said.

Fifty eight projects that covered work valued at more than $2.3 billion were entered in the 2017 awards. Master Builders executive director Michael McLean said "this reflects a strong commercial construction market across metropolitan and regional areas of the State."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Building Fit-Out</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TWS International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Multi-Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Construction Awards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sproule</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Sproule</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael McLean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Subcontractor of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commercial Aquatics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bankwest Best Project</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Towers Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown Towers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Builders-Bankwest Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
