<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413387880016553</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/homelessness-nsw-calls-blame-shifting-over-tent-city-to-end/8768346</url>
  <title>Homelessness peak body calls for end to government 'blame shifting' over Sydney tent city</title>
  <content>
New South Wales' peak homelessness body has called for an end to "blame shifting" in the growing feud over the Martin Place tent city between Premier Gladys Berejiklian and Sydney lord mayor Clover Moore.

Key points:

Gladys Berejiklian has called on the City of Sydney to move the tent city on
Homelessness NSW says the tent city is a symptom of deep social problems
Tent city residents say they have been forced to live there because of a lack of sustainable housing

A group of tents housing rough sleepers have for weeks been set up outside the Reserve Bank building just steps away from the State Parliament on Macquarie Street.
Ms Berejiklian said on Tuesday the homeless people set up in Martin Place  and has called on the City of Sydney to remove them.
But according to Homelessness NSW chief executive Katherine McKernan, the tent city is a symptom of deep social problems in the state.
"We're seeing an increasing number of people sleeping rough in the city because there's a real lack of affordable housing in Sydney and across NSW," Ms McKernan said.
"There's around 60,000 people waiting on the social housing waiting list at the moment and less than 1 per cent of private rentals in Sydney are affordable."
Ms McKernan said both local and state governments need to work together to find a long-term solution to homelessness.
"What we need is for both the local government and the state government to sit down together, develop a planned approach to address hotspots as they arise," she said.

"[They need to] look at providing affordable housing with long-term support but also looking at preventing homelessness as well."
For the moment, however, Ms McKernan said people living in the tent city had a right to remain there.
"If you're homeless, you have the right to use public space.
"So why the City of Sydney is not moving them on because firstly there isn't really anywhere to move them on to," she said.
'You get a feed here but it's obviously not the solution'

Ms Berejiklian says rough sleepers in the tent city have declined offers from government officials of alternative accommodation.

External Link:

Tent city tweet
But according to Blake, who provides hot meals to the approximately 50 tent city residents in Martin Place, rough sleepers need a more sustainable housing solution.
"Some people have refused temporary accommodation because it's only like a week or two and then they're back on the streets," he said.
One resident is Beau, who has been homeless for a year since moving from WA, said he is comfortable but the tent city is not sustainable.
"[I was] put up in a hotel for one or two weeks a couple of months ago, been here since so look I don't mind it," Beau said.
"It's safe, you get a feed here but it's obviously not the solution to the whole dilemma.
"I made up a sign yesterday to hang up alongside of my tent just for any share accommodation that I may be able to get for anywhere.
"But I don't really want to be here full stop, but it could be some time yet because housing, it's not an even playing field."
Andrea has temporary accommodation at a crisis centre nearby, but spent last night in her son's Martin Place tent after he was taken to hospital with injuries from a fight.
"It's lovely because you know that there's someone the next tent over that's listening to your problems. Everyone is supporting me."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katherine McKernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Berejiklian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clover Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homelessness NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beau</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Place</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McKernan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladys Berejiklian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
