<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413087232300264</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/afl/greater-western-sydney-giants/brett-deledio-to-make-gws-giants-debut-against-melbourne-demons-20170802-gxnu9d.html</url>
  <title>Brett Deledio to make GWS Giants debut against Melbourne Demons</title>
  <content>
If Saturday's GWS debut against Melbourne in Canberra is Brett Deledio's new dawn, then his darkest hour came seven weeks ago when he was convinced his wretched 2017 had finally ended.
The former Richmond star had just completed his first main training session after joining the Giants in last year's trade period, having finally overcome the right calf troubles that curtailed his past 12 months. But in the most cruel of twists, his left calf, not his right, failed to navigate its way safely through training.

Up Next

FootyFix: Can the Cats win without Danger?

03:57

More AFL Real Footy Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

AFL plays of round 19

Fancy Hawthorn footwork, Gray's goal that devastated St Kilda, Geelong's Hawkins kicks a stunning six goals, Travis Cloke returns in style and the jaw-dropping draw in the dying seconds of Adelaide v Collingwood.

"I've had some dark days," Deledio said on Wednesday.

"When I came back I joined the group for a short little warm-up, then did my running and hurt my calf again. Thoughts certainly did go through my head that I'm better off just to cool my heels for the rest of the year and get it right.
"I have lost count. Overall I think I've had a little nick in both calves eight or nine times ... they've never really been huge, significant tears, they're just tiny little things that just set you back a couple of weeks at a time. That's probably the most frustrating thing.

"You can probably deal with a big tear and know that you're out for a certain amount of time. When they're little ones you probably get the ball rolling a little bit too quickly and hence you have another setback."

You will now receive updates from

Realfooty Newsletter

Realfooty Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Not since round 17 against Essendon last year has Deledio pulled on an AFL jumper. He's played two matches with limited game time for the Giants reserves in the NEAFL leading into Saturday's long-overdue debut, which comes 385 days after that Bombers clash.Photo: AAP
Calf and Achilles problems ended his final year at Richmond early, but he trained strongly early in pre-season at his new club before the injury curse struck again.
Since then it has been a rocky road back to fitness, quite often taking one step forward and two steps back in a desperate bid to start the first of his three years with the Giants.
"You want nothing more than to be able to go out and earn the respect of your teammates, show them what you can do and the reasons you came here," Deledio said.
"When you're battling away on the cross trainer, on the bike and in the pool it makes it hard and it can be a lonely place at times.
"We've tried a lot of different techniques, a lot of needling and sand work and just firing up my glutes to get specific, and it's been working really well for me.
"I'm just rapt that I'm out there training with them, and trying to give them a little bit of energy because I'm fresh, I haven't played the whole season."
Prior to last season, Deledio was one of the AFL's most durable combatants and didn't miss a game between round 18, 2007, and round two of 2014.
, which only narrowly missed last year's grand final, and all year he has loomed as a luxurious addition to the half-forward line leading into the finals.
Yet his debut comes at a crucial time for the club, which ended a run of four games without a win last weekend by narrowly overhauling Fremantle. He will need to play a role to help the Giants to a second-straight win and realign their charge to the finals.
Shane Mumford is set to return with coach Leon Cameron flagging the possibility of playing two ruckmen against Melbourne star Max Gawn after Dawson Simpson's strong showing last weekend.
Midfielder Jacob Hopper also looks set to play his first AFL match since round seven, although Steve Johnson will likely miss another week with a knee problem. Will Setterfield is still overcoming the concussion he suffered last weekend.

Cameron warned his side against complacency now that Deledio was finally fit to play.
"He's only one player and one inclusion," Cameron said. "Just because he comes in to the team doesn't mean that the other 21 think it's just going to happen."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FootyFix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Achilles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realfooty Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leon Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEAFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Real Footy Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday's GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Hopper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Mumford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deledio</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Cloke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Max Gawn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dawson Simpson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Deledio</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong's Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Demons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Setterfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fancy Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS Giants</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
