<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413516729037769</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/world/prince-philip-retires-from-public-life-after-royal-marines-parade-at-buckingham-palace/news-story/e2c7a9556a54ff0993a20a7a2c45e05e</url>
  <title>Prince Philip's final royal wave</title>
  <content>
THE Queen's husband, 96-year-old Prince Philip, is formally retiring from public life, marking the event at a parade on the forecourt at Buckingham Palace overnight.
Prince Philip, the Duke of Edinburgh, announced in May that he would no longer undertake a
program of public events.
While he may appear with Queen Elizabeth, 91, from time to time, a parade by the Royal Marines will mark his final royal appearance in his own right.
The Duke is due to appear at the parade, which started just after midnight Australian time, in his position of Captain General of the Royal Marines, a position he has held for the past 64 years.

He succeeded the late King George VI, Queen's Elizabeth's father, when the king died in 1952.
The Captain General's Parade last night was planned to mark the finale of the 1664 Global Challenge, a charitable event which saw members of the Royal Marines run 16.64 miles (26.77kms) each day for 100 days, totalling a distance of 1664 miles (2674kms).
Prince Philip is due to appear to take the royal salute and the national anthem before meeting some of the Royal Marines runners, including two who completed the entire distance.
A march past was scheduled, and the Royal Marines were due to offer three cheers for their retiring Captain General.
In his 64-year royal career, Prince Philip has undertaken 22,219 solo engagements, made 637 solo overseas visits, given 5496 speeches, been patron of 785 organisations and authored 14 books.
His grandson Prince Harry, like his grandfather a war veteran, will replace him as Captain General of the Royal Marines.
Since Prince Philip announced his plans to retire, other members of the royal family have taken on a greater load, including the heir to the throne Prince Charles, and the young royals Prince William and his wife Catherine, and Prince Harry.
Prince William and Catherine accompanied Prince Charles to Belgium this week for the centenary commemorations of the battle of Passchendaele.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke of Edinburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Philip</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Harry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince Charles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain General of the Royal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain General's Parade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princes William</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckingham Palace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Passchendaele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George VI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belgium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Marines</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen Elizabeth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
