<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413542498842081</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:05</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/this-10-hour-video-of-planet-earth-cityscapes-is-strangely-hypnotic/</url>
  <title>This 10-Hour Video Of Planet Earth Cityscapes Is Strangely Hypnotic</title>
  <content>
Video: In what is now the sixth instalment of a stunning and weirdly addictive series, the BBC has released 10 full hours of video shot during the filming of the Planet Earth II "Cities" episode.

The beauty of this video, aside from the sheer volume of it all, is that it's delivered without any commentary and the action (if you can call it that) is kept to a bare minimum. We have nothing against , , or even Sir David Attenborough for that matter, but there's something to be said for watching this breathtaking footage in its uncut, unadulterated form.

Like all of the videos in this series, the film was shot by Planet Earth II camera teams while they were out on location. Rather than tossing hours upon hours of extra footage in the garbage, the BBC is putting it together into glorious, long-form videos. Cities shown in this video include Jodphur, Mumbai, Rome, Toronto and others. If you haven't seen the original "Cities", or any of the Planet Earth II episodes for that matter, you should make it a priority.

Here are the other episodes in BBC's "10 Hour" series so far.

Desert:

Jungle:

Grasslands:

Islands:

Mountains:

[]

WATCH MORE: Science & Health News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planet Earth II</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BBC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toronto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir David Attenborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hour Video Of Planet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jodphur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mumbai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Earth Cityscapes Is Strangely Hypnotic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
