<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412528886540692</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/the-fitz-files/laurie-daley-the-nsw-blues-and-the-good-bloke-syndrome-20170802-gxny2q.html</url>
  <title>Laurie Daley and the good bloke syndrome</title>
  <content>
Suppose.
Just suppose you and I were in the highest echelons of the NSWRL, trying to work out what to do, to fix the myriad problems of the NSW Origin team, so it could maybe win more than once a decade. And suppose we came to the glaringly obvious solution, to try a different coach, given that the one we've had for the last five years has only delivered one series win and there is absolutely no sign that they are on the rise under his stewardship.Photo: AAP
Here is my question. If we were in that meeting and came to that conclusion, could either of us break the news to the incumbent coach that we were giving him the bullet?
I just couldn't do it. Could you?
I mean, Laurie Daley! You want me to tell Laurie Daley, who has done more in rugby league, for rugby league than just about anybody you and I know personally, that he is not wanted? The one who has clearly been bleeding for the past three weeks over the loss, while everyone else is recovering - just as he has bled for all bar one of the last five years?  Laurie Daley, the strong family man, who you always hear good things about and never nasty things?
No, you bastard, you tell him.

And herein, you see, I think is the central problem with trying to sack Daley as coach of NSW. See, despite his notable lack of overall success, despite the fact that in this last series he had blokes getting pissed as newts on his watch and he didn't even know about it, despite the fact that after a great opening win away from home their whole campaign hit the wall straight afterwards, there just isn't the gumption to do down such a nice bloke.
So, he will survive.
And it is not a rare phenomenon, particularly for former great players who become mediocre coaches.
Other examples that spring to mind are Artie Beetson and John Kirwan.
Both of them, as good as blokes as you'd find in six days march in any direction. Neither achieved anything as coaches remotely close to what they achieved as players. Both were able to stay in their positions long after those of lesser resumes, lesser generosity, lesser sheer charisma were shown the door.
When they at last started circling Arthur Beetson at the Roosters, I remember Alan Jones robustly defending him on the airwaves, along the lines of "I cannot imagine that for any young man, time spent around Arthur would not be beneficial to him".
Now, for Alan, as you will appreciate, it must have been a nice change to be robustly defending someone that hadn't committed a murder, a late-night atrocity or corruption in high places, and in this case he was quite right. For of course time spent around Artie would be beneficial to young men.
But that, of course, is not the test. Could he coach? It took rugby league a long time to decide, but ultimately it came to the conclusion that the broad answer was, "no, we love you Artie, always have, and always will, but we'd rather you as the eminence gris, the selector, mentor and runner of Indigenous programs, than actual coach".
Ditto Sir John Kirwan, an absolutely beloved figure in New Zealand rugby, an iconic All Black who joined the coaching ranks shortly after leaving, and then through all of Japan, Italy and Kiwi provincial ranks worked really hard as a coach ... but achieved nothing, at least in comparison to his honours as a player.
You can probably throw Nathan Buckley into the mix. Great bloke. Great player. Gives everything he has, as coach, and couldn't possibly work harder. But results? They're just not there. And yet nobody wants to do him down, so he survives for so much longer than he otherwise would have.
So they will reappoint Laurie, and we will all feel good about it.
Will he do better than the last five times? We will all hope so, because he is such a good bloke. But the evidence is against it.
When they do get around to appointing his successor, perhaps the answer is to look for someone with an established track record as a great coach, even if he is not a beloved figure in the game. Back in the day, in rugby, we got Alan Jones. He was a complete bastard, but gee, he could coach!
Twitter: @Peter_Fitz
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Origin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Daley</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Artie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSWRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ditto Sir John Kirwan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Kirwan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter_Fitz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Beetson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Artie Beetson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiwi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alan Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
