<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412833829224696</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/federal-politics/political-opinion/could-marriage-showdown-bring-down-malcolm-turnbulls-government-20170802-gxnkix.html</url>
  <title>Could the same-sex marriage showdown bring down Malcolm Turnbull's government?</title>
  <content>
The stakes in the looming same-sex marriage showdown within the governing parties may be higher than you think. Serious enough to raise confidence issues and cataclysmic enough therefore, to see the rebels back off.
And it gets worse. As recriminations fly, hardline conservatives are threatening to quit the Liberal Party and render Malcolm Turnbull a minority Prime Minister if marriage equality somehow comes to a vote.

Up Next

Driverless bus to trial in Sydney

00:58

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Government sticking to its plan

Despite calls for a conscience vote on same sex marriage and some Liberal MPs threatening to cross the floor over the issue, the government isn't budging on its plan for a plebiscite,.

Such consequences will give reform MPs pause for thought.
Even without defections, the risk is of a government losing a contentious policy vote in the House of Representatives courtesy of its own members crossing the floor. 

That in effect, amounts to the Parliament making laws contrary to stated government policy.
Depending on their weight, such events could force the Coalition to an immediate confidence test.

House of Representatives Practice (6th edition) is the go-to text for gauging the implications of abnormal parliamentary events.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The situation, should it transpire, is less than black and white.Photo: Andrew Meares
In essence, the question becomes, would the loss of a vote on marriage reform in chamber where the government is formed amount to a loss of confidence?
According to Practice, the answer is "Yes". And "No".
"The withdrawal by the House of its confidence in the government may be shown by a direct vote ... [or] by defeat on an issue central to government policy or rejecting a legislative measure proposed by the government, the acceptance of which the government has declared to be of vital importance. Conversely, a vote by the House agreeing to a particular legislative measure or provision contrary to the advice and consent of the government could similarly be regarded as a matter of confidence."
You can see the problem. Well-intentioned they may be, but Liberals proposing to cross the floor would be making a "legislative measure or provision contrary to the advice and consent of the government".
The kicker is that it would be up to the PM to decide whether it was centrally important policy.
Admittedly there is some wriggle-room around whether marriage reform constitutes "an issue central to government policy", but given how much money's involved in the plebiscite and the lengths to which MPs are prepared to go to stick to it - including resignation etc - Turnbull might find it hard to frame the marriage laws as peripheral.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Meares</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Practice (6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
