<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412571836214656</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/south/sport/passionate-club-legend-mervs-four-decades-in-the-coaches-box/news-story/9cb95530566f71abec87807d83ab8abb</url>
  <title>Merv's four decades in the coaches box</title>
  <content>
RECEIVING "constructive criticism" from Merv "Granma" Mules is almost a tradition at Morphett Vale Football Club.
Mules, 80, has been handing it out over more than four decades at the Emus while serving in various roles including timekeeper, runner, goal umpire, team manager, secretary and treasurer.
Usually, he voices his opinion wearing his trademark red, woollen op-shop jumper with a patched on Morphett Vale logo and tends to direct it at coaches.
So it was somewhat ironic that this month the Emus named their coaches box after the passionate club legend.
"Of course I'm a pain in the bum to a lot of people," says Mules, the club's present timekeeper, with a chuckle.
"I accept that - I would drive some people up a wall, but that's me.
"I give what I call constructive criticism ... and when new coaches came along they were told 'Somewhere along the line Granma will tell you what to do'.
"(The naming of the coaches box) is embarrassing but I'm very honoured."
Mules joined the Emus in 1973 - a decade after moving into the area and being told about the club by a workmate.
He has volunteered at Morphett Vale since his first season to stay involved while his sons Andrew, Stephen, Stuart and Darren rose through the ranks to the A grade, and his daughter Suzanne helped with timekeeping.
Along the way, Mules earnt the nickname "Granma" while helping in the canteen and talking to children.
Dedicating himself to the club has led to plenty of stories.
Such as getting reported for letting a quarter run too long when he was timekeeping or the day he was goal umpiring and a player tried to take a screamer on his back.
"He climbed up ... and buried me into the ground.
"A couple of blokes raced out to me and I told them I was dying for a port because I like a port.
"So they brought me out a butcher."
Port is the drink Emus members most associate with Mules.
In terms of food, it is his wife Edna's curried egg sausages, which he is known for handing out at games.
He used to pack them in his red Datsun 1000 ute, which had the personalised numberplate "Merv05".
"If I didn't bring the sausages, I'd be in the sh**."
Emus people give Mules plenty of stick but it is the camaraderie and friendships that he enjoys most about the club.
"I watched my kids grow up at Morphett Vale and other kids grow up.
"I've loved it."
Mules is "practising barracking" because he is not far away from stepping aside as a volunteer.
"I'll still be at the footy, just with the so-called older supporters giving the umpires constructive criticism."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Granma</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Datsun 1000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merv</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzanne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphett Vale</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphett Vale Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merv05</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EMU</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mules, 80</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
