<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413044282626361</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/mirvac-development-caters-for-those-working-from-home/news-story/816be9743ff765fa81584098ad1da4ac</url>
  <title>Mirvac development caters for those working from home - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Mirvac's Cargo Homes in the Wharf's Entrance precinct in Docklands.

DEVELOPER Mirvac has started construction on the second stage of a Docklands townhouse project that responds to the growing work-from-home trend.
The Cargo Homes development in the Wharf's Entrance precinct at Yarra's Edge is designed to meet demand from the increasing number of Australians who combine their work and home lives.
RELATED:
Australian Bureau of Statistics data shows 3.5 million people regularly work from home, making up 30 per cent of the workforce in 2015.
This was a jump from 20 per cent of the workforce a decade earlier.

Mirvac's Cargo Homes in the Wharf's Entrance precinct in Docklands.

Mirvac's Victorian residential general manager, Elysa Anderson, said the Cargo Homes allowed the home to become an extension of work or a place of work.
"Telecommuting is fast on the rise and we're seeing more and more people abandoning the workplace in favour of working from home," Ms Anderson said.
"We recognised a gap in the market, with few new homes containing deliberately designed office spaces and we're proud to deliver this hybrid home office in one of Melbourne's key hubs for professionals."
Stage one of the project has been sold out, with its seven townhouses completed last October. Another seven homes, with three or four bedrooms, were released in stage two and all but one has been snapped up.

Mirvac's Cargo Homes in the Wharf's Entrance precinct in Docklands.

The stage two homes are 234-300sq m, with the ground floor accommodating a home office space, kitchenette, bathroom and storage space.
Living areas flow across the two top levels, with balconies providing city views.
Kitchens feature stone benchtops and Smeg appliances, while bathrooms and ensuites also have stone benchtops and full-height wall tiles.
The area's wharf side history is referenced in the project's name and architecture, with brick, zinc, copper, concrete and timber panels used in building facades.
The stage two homes are due to be finished mid next year, with the remaining three-bedroom property priced at $2.05 million.
For more information, call Janet Walker on 0466 440 863 or see
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janet Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirvac's Cargo Homes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirvac</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirvac's Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra's Edge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smeg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elysa Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wharf's Entrance</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cargo Homes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
