<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413563973679060</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/western-bulldogs-veteran-dale-morris-says-hes-keen-to-play-on-despite-his-run-of-injuries/news-story/4bc977e65eb1ad84e29162745e901eab</url>
  <title>'If the club want me then I'll keep going forever'</title>
  <content>
WESTERN Bulldogs veteran Dale Morris says he's keen to play on in 2018 - if the Bulldogs will have him.
The 34-year-old has suffered a horror run of injuries this year, with a broken leg sidelining him for seven weeks early in the season, while a broken arm sustained in Round 18 will likely see him unavailable until finals - if the Bulldogs make the eight.
But Morris said he would happily "front up" next year if the door was open for another year at the top level.
"Except for my chalky bones, yes, I feel great," Morris said on Fox Footy's AFL 360.
"I've said all along that if the club want me and there's a role for me there, then I'll keep going forever.
"But we'll have those discussions in due course and work all that out."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
Morris has played 239 games for the Bulldogs since making his debut in 2005 - despite both a series of major injuries and a late entry to AFL football.
The defender was originally signed as a mature-aged rookie, off the back of impressing for Werribee in the VFL.
Named an All-Australian in 2008, Morris has been a fixture of the Bulldogs' backline since his debut. After featuring in the club's 2016 premiership team, it was later revealed the defender had played through the entire finals series with a fractured vertebrae.
Morris said while he would accept whatever call the club made on his future, it was unfortunate that his current injury made it difficult for him to prove his ability to play on.
"I'm one of the fortunate ones in that Ive been lucky to play AFL footy and forge a career and to make something out of an opportunity that I never thought I'd get," he said.
"So if the club turned to me and said 'that's it', I would be upset, and probably devastated.
"But I understand where things are at, I understand how lucky I am and I've been there - I've been up the top, we've won the premiership and I've been a part of a successful club, I've been a part of a club that's not so successful.
"So it is what it is (and) a lot of this stuff's out of my control unfortunately - I can't be out there playing footy but I'll keep fronting up."
Meanwhile, Morris said the positive to come from his injury was it forced the club's youngsters to step up.
Lewis Young has been a revelation since making his debut, while Zaine Cordy's efforts late in the game against Joe Daniher proved crucial in the win over Essendon.
"The silver lining in injuries like mine - and like anyone who goes through injuries - is you get to see young guys step up," Morris said.
"We saw on the weekend, some of Zaine Cordy; s effort's were fantastic. We've got Lewis Young (too) ... these kids are standing up and being vital cogs in our success - so there is a silver lining in it all."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ive</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Werribee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Daniher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zaine Cordy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Young</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morris</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
