<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412700685235917</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/accounting/remaining-cpa-board-to-appear-before-senate-committee-20160831-gr5lax</url>
  <title>Remaining CPA board to appear before Senate committee</title>
  <content>
An angry Senate committee has resolved to call the remaining board members of CPA Australia to appear before them and explain their actions .
The decision was made after CPA representatives were unable to explain during a hearing the thinking behind the CPA board's decision to not send out an email calling for a spill of the current board on behalf of 16 and to hold their annual general meeting in Singapore. 
If the board members appear, it would be the first time they have been  asked to publicly explain their behaviour during the past three months, when seven of their number have resigned and CEO Alex Malley was fired with a $4.9 million payment.
The public hearing, in Sydney on Wednesday morning, was part of the committee's examination of potential updates to the Corporations Act to compel companies to store and then provide the email addresses of their membership base to members who ask for it.

DEAN LEWINS

The amendment, if passed, would become the biggest legal change to come out of the CPA saga and represents a major update in the type of information that firms are legally compelled to keep about their shareholders or members. .

The potential amendment, , was inspired by rebel CPA member Brett Stevenson's battle with the accounting body to get a list of member contacts to share his concerns about the way the CPA is run.
CPA, which communicates regularly with its members via email, supplied mailing addresses but omitted email addresses in their response to to Mr Stevenson's request, which was made under the Corporations Act. This meant it would have cost Mr Stevenson at least $150,000 to do a mail-out to the 155,000-strong membership.
At the hearing, CPA representatives were asked why the body had sent out an email expressing regret over having to produce the register and warning members they may receive unsolicited email after complying with Mr Stevenson's request for the register.
CPA general manager of policy and spokesman Stuart Dignam said "the board felt we had a duty of care to our global membership to advise them of this circumstance."

Mr Xenophon shot back: "Mr Dignam, you're going to give us a lecture on duty of care when you paid out Mr Malley $4.9 million?"
Mr Dignam replied: "Mr Malley's termination was made in accordance with our obligations. The full amount was disclosed, I'm not at liberty to discuss that any further."
The committee then asked about why it wouldn't send out an email on the past leaders' behalf, calling for a full board spill, to deal with privacy concerns over releasing the list of member emails. The request was made in June but wasn't acted upon by the board or management of the CPA.
Mr Dignam said: "I'm aware of the correspondences to which you refer Senator, the board and the management of CPA Australia don't believe that an entire spill is in the best interest of the organisation."

Mr Xenophon then accused the CPA of censorship, saying: "Isn't that up to members to decide that? They just wanted you to circulate that [message]. "
Chair Liberal Senator Jane Hume ending the CPA appearence by expressed the bewilderment of the committee about the actions of the CPA board, including the decision to hold the AGM in Singapore in April
"My greatest frustration...is that the reason why we are needing to have this discussion is the extraordinary behaviour of your organisation," she said. "[The] opacity and obfuscation is just mind-blowing. There are plenty of global organisation listed on the ASX and none of them have their AGM overseas. I cannot understand why on earth you would deny your members a say at the very forum that is created for that purpose."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Dignam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Malley $4.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Xenophon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stevenson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporations Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dignam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator Jane Hume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett Stevenson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Alex Malley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AGM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CPA</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Lewins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
