<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413344930342785</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/travel/travel-advice/travellers-stories/this-is-what-happens-and-how-much-it-sucks-when-lost-luggage-ruins-your-trip/news-story/91a2e1e7dfdb1f3121397bb13d6a78e5</url>
  <title>This is what happens, and how much it sucks, when lost luggage ruins your trip</title>
  <content>
Matt is abroad without his luggage and with no end to his torture in sight.

Share

I have been wearing the same clothes for three days now.
Same underwear. Same dirty socks. Same smelly shirt. The works.
In fact I actually think I smell. Even after I shower there's no escaping this stench.
This is the unfortunate reality I find myself in after the airline I flew to Stockholm, which is where I'm currently holidaying, lost my luggage. Thanks a bunch, AirBerlin. And a little known company called Menzies Aviation. These are one of the businesses that handle luggage. Yours, too.
In fact, the process has been so awful I'm still none the wiser about what to do and where to go from here. This could happen to anyone. I understand bags get lost, but the process getting it back is, frankly, a nightmare.
After three flights and a 34-hour journey to get here, once I finally stepped off that plane I was in holiday heaven. Finally here. Ready to relax.
But after standing at the baggage claim for an hour, I started to worry.
. I'm told there is a long wait for luggage because you have lost so many in last week. What am I to do now? Great start to trip.
Starting my three week holiday with just the clothes on my back and no toiletries in sight. Thanks

There's sunny Stockholm outside. There I am inside, stuck on hold, waiting to talk to  and Menzies Aviation over my lost luggage.

The worry then turned to panic when all of a sudden, the conveyor belt carrying luggage stopped. A message in Swedish popped up on the screen - I had no idea what it said but it was written in red capital letters. Surely, I thought, this is not a good sign.
There was no information about what to do - I guessed my way through it.

I'm forced to take a number and wait.
After another hour, I finally am able to talk to someone from the airport.
Finally when I speak to someone, he tells me AirBerlin likely lost my luggage at Tegel airport in Berlin - one of the stopovers on the long flight here. There's no indication of whether I will get my luggage back, or when.
Thank God I didn't wear sweats on the flight.
After talking to fellow travellers apparently Berlin is notorious for this - the man at Stockholm airport told me a number of bags had been lost in the last week. At my hotel they told me a man had gone through the same thing last week - and his luggage still hasn't been found.
I'm given a flimsy piece of paper with a number to call and a reference number at the airport. It's called a 'property irregularity report' which tells me to contact a company called Menzies Aviation within five days.
'They will not contact you if they find your luggage at the airport,' a stern woman from Menzies Aviation told me. I thought that odd, but perhaps it's the language barrier?
'So I just have to wait?' I ask?
'Exactly,' I'm told.
I've been wearing the same clothes for three days. So gross.

Hi  I have contacted Menzies. They have given me no details. Except to tell me they won't contact me and all I can do is wait

The man at the airport desk asks for my phone number but considering I've just landed in a foreign country - I don't have one. And frankly I'm not prepared to pay the exorbitant fees I'd be charged for an international call. I believe it's $1.50/minute.
So I give the airline worker a description of my luggage - a grey suitcase with ridges and a yellow tag with my name on it. Like finding a needle in a haystack.
The issue of compensation has been discussed by friends but the company has so far not offered any instructions. Apparently I have to wait another 24 hours. That'll make it four days in the same clothes.
I'm told I will be able to go out and buy some new things and claim it on compensation - but let's be real. I did not budget for this. In fact I'm already stretching it with this holiday and now that I'm facing out of pocket expenses on top of my holiday spending, I'm concerned I'll be left O/S with no cash, but fabulous new clothes and clean teeth.
The problem with compensation is there is a delay between buying the items and actually being compensated. I must keep receipts and go through a formal process before any money is given back.

A post shared by Matt Young (@__my___) on

So while I should be out on the streets soaking up the cultural delights of a new city, I'm sitting in my hotel room on hold attempting to figure out what to do next.
This wasn't my idea of a holiday.
AirBerlin tells me there are no updates on my luggage and I'm being forced to lodge complaints and make calls.
My call to Menzies Aviation made me wait on hold for half an hour with no answer at the end.
This could happen to you and has likely happened to many people reading this.
What do you do in these situations? I have no idea. At the end of the day, I just want my luggage back.
The issue for all fellow travellers is the fact that nothing is guaranteed when you fly. But what matters in the end is the way these businesses handle the matter - and so far - my luggage is still lost. I'm still none the wiser. I'm just told to be patient.
I've asked AirBerlin for a statement so I can share information with fellow travellers.
I'm still waiting. Fair enough it has been technically a day since my luggage went missing - but I've been without for much longer. And I wonder what to do next? If I had an endless money supply it wouldn't be an issue. But that damn Aussie dollar just doesn't stack up to the Euro.
This has happened to me - and it could happen to you too. Beware. Because it really does suck. And smell.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O/S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AirBerlin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stockholm</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swedish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Menzies Aviation</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tegel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
