<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413478074331349</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/health/inquest-hears-of-roster-error-in-deaths-of-two-stroke-patients-at-royal-adelaide-hospital/news-story/9454f2993c6a424b0905290e58a8c6b4</url>
  <title>Roster error claimed two lives</title>
  <content>
The head of radiology at the Royal Adelaide Hospital has told an inquest it was a mistake for him to sign leave forms that meant the hospital's two clot-busting stroke specialists were away at the same time.
Jim Buckley said when he signed the second specialist's form he did so "inadvertently" and didn't realise her colleague would be away for some of the same period in April this year, when two people died after suffering strokes. Dr Buckley said the situation was of great concern.
"It was an error," he told South Australian coroner Mark Johns on Wednesday. Mr Johns is investigating the deaths of 60-year-old Michael John Russell and 87-year-old Leslie Robert Graham.
Mr Graham was admitted to the RAH after suffering a stroke at home. He was assessed as a suitable candidate for the delicate clot retrieval procedure but one specialist was overseas and the other on a fishing trip, south of Adelaide.
A similarly qualified specialist was called in from the Flinders Medical Centre to perform the procedure but it was unsuccessful.
Mr Russell was admitted to the hospital the same day suffering from a heart attack but had a stroke while undergoing a procedure to clear a blocked artery. He was also worked on by the visiting specialist, who had been called back, but again the procedure proved unsuccessful.
Dr Buckley said despite the mix-up over leave, arrangements had been made for another radiologist to cover and handle emergency cases over the four-day period.
But he said having only two clot retrieval specialists employed at the RAH was not acceptable and meant if one was on leave the other would be on call 24/7. "That's a very fragile roster indeed," he said.
Dr Buckley said a third full-time specialist had recently been appointed, something that had been recommended some years ago by an internal review. The inquest is continuing.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Buckley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Buckley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Medical Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Johns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie Robert Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael John Russell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
