<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412919728572257</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/18/27/nz-opposition-leader-asked-about-motherhood-on-first-day-of-job</url>
  <title>'Unacceptable': NZ opposition leader asked about motherhood on first day of job</title>
  <content>
The newly-appointed New Zealand opposition leader has been asked about her motherhood plans on day one of the job, sparking wide-spread criticism on social media.
Jacinda Ardern, 37, became the leader of the Labour party yesterday after Andrew Little resigned seven weeks before New Zealand holds their parliamentary elections.

I feel privileged and honoured to have been elected leader of the Labour Party, and ready for the challenge! Bring on 23 September.

This morning, local radio host Mark Richardson said voters had the "right to know" whether their prime minister planned bear children.
Richardson asked Ms Ardern, who does not have children, whether she thought it was "okay for a PM to take maternity leave while in office".
The opposition leader replied that it was "totally unacceptable" for women to be discriminated against for their maternity plans.
"It is totally unacceptable in 2017 to say that women should have to answer that question in the workplace. It is unacceptable, it is unacceptable," she said.

Related Articles

"It is a woman's decision about when they choose to have children and it should not predetermine whether or not they are given a job or have job opportunities."
It comes after Ms Ardern appeared on New Zealand's The Project and was asked a question regarding motherhood by host Jesse Mulligan.
"I've got a question, and we've been discussing today whether I'm allowed to ask it or not," Mulligan said.
"Let me put it this way. A lot of women in New Zealand feel like they have to make a choice between having babies and having a career, or continuing their career at a certain point in their lives - late 30s."
"Is that a decision that you feel you have to make, or that you feel that you've already made?"
Ms Ardern said she was "open about the dilemma" and said she "had no problem" being asked the question.
"For me, my position is no different to the woman who works three jobs, or who might be in a position where they are juggling lots of responsibilities."
Many people have since taken to social media to voice their disapproval of the politician being quizzed about motherhood.

I've heard Jacinda Ardern's baby plans are that she's going to lock them all up in an underground dungeon like in Chitty Chitty Bang Bang Y˜Y˜

Not to mention that whether Jacinda Ardern decides to have a kid or not should not be a decision beholden to anyone but her and her partner.

If you're wondering why the reaction to Jacinda Ardern baby q, it's b/c NZ women have been reminded they're baby makers first and foremost

"Let's be very clear here...neither employer nor public has any 'right' to know if a person plans to have children," Twitter user Di Frances wrote.
Fellow tweeter Liam Hehir said it was "nobody's business and totally irrelevant to (Ms Ardern's) credentials".
"No, a man would not be asked the same question," Mr Hehir added.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mulligan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Hehir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Little</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chitty Chitty Bang Bang Y</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinda Ardern</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Richardson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Di Frances</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hehir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacinda Ardern, 37</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ardern</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesse Mulligan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
