<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413611218320349</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/football/a-league/melbourne-city-happy-to-start-ffa-cup-title-defence-with-a-win/news-story/81af42e8929d9cb767f185eb6bffc99a</url>
  <title>City happy not to slip up early</title>
  <content>
MELBOURNE City relied on goals in stoppage time of both halves to beat local Brisbane side Peninsula Power 2-0 on Tuesday night.
But given the massive FFA Cup upset Heidelberg United caused against Perth Glory elsewhere that night, City fullback Scott Jamieson said the successful start to the club's title defence should be seen as nothing but a positive.
"Full respect to Peninsula, they were a tough team to break down," Jamieson said.
"There was a period in the second half where they did put some pressure on us and caused a few problems.
"If you look at the first couple of years of the FFA Cup, the only real banana skin for A-League teams was Western Sydney getting knocked out by Adelaide City. It was always quite straight forward.
"But over the years the NPL teams - and even those outside the NPL - have closed that gap a little bit and made it really tough.
"With these cup ties being played at suburban grounds, that makes it tougher for the A-League teams to go to as well.
"But having said that, I thought we were very professional in our approach. I thought we were in control for large parts of the game."
Striker Bruno Fornaroli scored the second half sealer, but Stefan Mauk put City ahead with a header in his first game back for the club after 18 months away.
He also copped a heavy knock from Peninsula's goalkeeper for his troubles, forcing him from the field.
The midfielder was sore and sorry on Wednesday, but was reporting no serious issues, with Jamieson lauding the 21-year-old's courage in latching on to Neil Kilkenny's cross.
"The first thing I ran over to him and said was how brave he was," Jamieson said.
"He's a very good footballer, but he showed that other side of him.
"He'd be feeling a lot sorer if he didn't get the goal."
It was Jamieson's competitive debut for City as it was for new coach Warren Joyce.
All things considered, the left back described the hitout as a "pleasing" night
"It's pre-season and you're looking at trying to work on things, but it's also a cup competition and you want to win," he said.
"We did that, which is important, but we also executed a few things that were asked of us by the manager."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NPL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Jamieson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Kilkenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruno Fornaroli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STEFAN Mauk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Glory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamieson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
