<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413615513287713</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/football/neymar-transfer-rumours-barcelona-to-psg-tells-teammates-leaves-training/news-story/fb52605b25ef2275df0f5a6c814d8260</url>
  <title>Barca bombshell! Club CONFIRMS Neymar to PSG is ON</title>
  <content>
NEYMAR has told Barcelona that he plans to leave the club, with a blockbuster move to Paris Saint-Germain seemingly imminent.
The club said Wednesday that the Brazil striker told his teammates "that he had the intention of leaving the club and seeking his future elsewhere, and the coach has given him permission to leave training."
PSG is rumored to be ready to pay his release clause of 222 million euros ($262 million).
That would dwarf the 105 million euros (then $116 million) that Manchester United paid for France midfielder Paul Pogba last year.

Neymar Jr hasn't trained on Wednesday with the permission of the coach

1/2 PSG going to La Liga offices this afternoon. La Liga say they will NOT accept €220m payment to trigger Neymar release clause

2/2 La Liga: "We will not accept the money for the clause. We have doubts this money is in accordance with UEFA Financial Fair Play rules."
Barcelona said Neymar did not specify where he wants to play next, but the only club speculated to be after him - and one of few which could handle the cost of the transfer - is the Qatari-owned PSG.
Barcelona said Neymar left the training ground 30 minutes after arriving on Wednesday. He had arrived to Spain on Tuesday night after holding publicity events for both his personal brand and Barcelona in China.
In an interview with Spanish paper AS, La Liga chief Javier Tebas declared the league will challenge PSG's right to pay the release clause, while then declaring that La Liga is bigger than Neymar.
"No. We will not accept that money from a club like PSG that, without belonging to La Liga, want to embrace the rights of our organisation," he said.
He added: "The complaint is ready and will be presented to UEFA, the European Union, and the Swiss Courts, those are the tribunals that have power. Basically, La Liga will denounce the unfairness of competing against state-backed clubs; the teams that receive economic investment from countries that gift players to their fans at the cost of taking them from other clubs.
"In terms of PSG, it is a clear case of 'financial doping', with the club and the state. PSG's accounts show that they have a larger commercial income than Real Madrid and Manchester United, which is to say that the value of their brand is greater than those clubs. Well, that is impossible."
As for Neymar, he sledged: "He is a fantastic player, but honestly, I believe that La Liga is greater than Neymar. With the greatest of respect to him, I would be more worried if we were talking about [Lionel] Messi or Cristiano [Ronaldo]."
Strangely, however, PSG president Nasser Al-Khelaifi has told Moroccan television station Medi 1 TV: "All of this is talk. Neymar is a Barcelona player and we will see what happens with him.
"PSG respect all contracts that exist between other teams and their players. I hope to speak about this issue another time."
However, he added: "PSG's ambition is to have great players who are recognised around the world.
"That helps to increase our reputation and the club look to have coaches and players who can help us realise our expectations."
With his lightning-quick feet, creative instincts and scoring touch, Neymar helped maintain Barcelona as one of the top clubs in Europe for the past four seasons as he blossomed into a worldwide star.
He teamed up with Lionel Messi and Luis Suarez to make an almost unstoppable attack. Neymar scored 105 goals - some of them true gems - and was a key playmaker for Barcelona as it won a Champions League, two Spanish leagues, three Copa del Reys, one Club World Cup, a UEFA Super Cup and two Spanish Super Cups.
Yet, even before this drawn-out saga, Neymar also provided more than one headache for his club.
His transfer from Brazilian club Santos in 2013 became the source of a legal dispute that has dogged Barcelona even since. Barcelona said at the time that his transfer cost 57 million euros, while an investigative judge says that the real cost was at least 83.3 million euros.
Now Bartomeu and predecessor Sandro Rosell, who resigned as president of the club amid the transfer scandal, are facing trial on charges of fraudulent administration.
Neymar has also mixed his flair for fancy goals with bouts of immaturity on the field, often needlessly taunting defenders and trying to upstage them with his dribbling skills.
But nobody doubts Neymar is one of the greatest talents of his generation. PSG saw it first-hand in last season's Champions League. In his most memorable performance at Camp Nou, Neymar scored two goals and set up two more to lead Barcelona to a 6-1 rout to overturn PSG's 4-0 first-leg win in the last 16. Unless PSG gets last-second jitters, Neymar will take over a team that is searching for a leader who can achieve elusive Champions League success.

BREAKING:  give Neymar permission to miss training this morning. More on Sky Sports News.

Neymar hasn't trained with Barcelona today. Deal close with PSG but still not yet signed.

Neymar didn't train today + told team mates he's off to PSG. Key players were fed up with situation and wanted him to say it to the group.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Madrid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Copa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javier Tebas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatari-owned PSG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bartomeu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nasser Al-Khelaifi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medi1 TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moroccan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Liga</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cristiano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pogba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ronaldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandro Rosell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Suarez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swiss Courts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Santos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uefa's Financial Fair Play</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Nou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>21</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
