<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412662030529549</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-02/trio-of-hawk-teens-sign-new-deals</url>
  <title>Trio of Hawk teens sign new deals</title>
  <content>
Conor Glass is one of three players to ink new deals with Hawthorn

HAWTHORN has shored up its playing stocks for the next few seasons, with Conor Glass, James Cousins and Oliver Hanrahan signing new contracts.

Cousins (pick 46) and Hanrahan (pick 14) joined the Hawks through the rookie draft last year, while Glass came to the club midway through 2015 after being recruited as an international rookie.

Cousins impressed as a ball-winning midfielder at Box Hill and played three senior games for Hawthorn in the middle of the season, while Glass has played the last two games at AFL level and has excited the Hawks with his ball use and footy smarts.

He will remain on the rookie list next season, and has been promised a place on the senior list in 2019.

Hanrahan came to the Hawks from outside the established talent pathways and having played school football only, but has developed quickly at Box Hill as a midfielder and forward.

"We're thrilled that each of these guys have extended their contracts," Hawks list manager Graham Wright told hawthornfc.com.au.

"Being on the rookie list, these boys are obviously still developing as footy players, but we're really pleased with the steps they have taken since joining the club."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cousins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Hanrahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hanrahan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor Glass</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
