<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413344930342814</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/controversial-antivaxxer-movie-screens-at-crown-casino-20170802-gxo29k.html</url>
  <title>Controversial anti-vaccination documentary screens at Crown casino </title>
  <content>
A leading Australian immunisation expert has slammed a decision to screen an American anti-vaccination film at Village's Crown casino cinemas, arguing it endangered public health. 
The Southbank cinema played host to a secret screening of the film Vaxxed: From Cover-up to Catastrophe at 6.30pm on Wednesday. 

Up Next

Dramatic siege ends in Melbourne's east

01:29

More National News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Are vaccines safe?

How safe are vaccines, and what kind of testing is done before they're included in Australia's national schedule?

Directed by Andrew Wakefield - a former doctor whose debunked study played a key role in the anti-vaccination movement - the film reignites false claims about a link between the mumps, measles and rubella vaccine and autism.
The documentary, being toured by the Australian Vaccination-skeptics Network , has been met with staunch opposition from public health advocates across the country.Photo: Supplied
Earlier this week, the Australian National University's science department was condemned for unwittingly screening the film.
The AVN later uploaded videos of the event to social media showing some of those involved claiming the event was implicitly endorsed by the university, when it was not. 

Melbourne Orthopaedic surgeon Dr John Cunningham, who was awarded an Order of Australia medal for his research and promotion of immunisation, said it was one of the most dangerous films he had ever come across.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"My biggest issue is that a big corporation like Village Cinemas shouldn't be enabling these sort of people to have a platform to screen their film," he said.Photo: Supplied
"They are not obliged to screen these sorts of movies, they don't have to accept the bookings, they can use their common sense and realise it is not a safe or a good thing to do. In fact, it's endangering public health and putting lives at risk."
The AVN revealed the venue to Melbourne ticket-holders by text and email two hours before it was due to screen. Photo: Supplied
The group's Facebook page had said it would be held at a "secret" Melbourne venue. 
The post also implored viewers to come along to the screening to meet "like-minded" individuals. 
"Aside from watching the movie "They" don't want you to see, you will meet like-minded individuals in your area, help form a community for mutual information and support and just get an all-around warm feeling from knowing that you are NOT ALONE," it read.
Earlier this year, the State of Minnesota faced its biggest outbreak of measles in almost 30 years, which authorities blame on anti-vaccine propaganda targeting parents of Somali-American children.
Dr Cunningham said the film had the potential to harm generations of children in Australia.  
"We are living in an era where people are dying needlessly," Dr Cunningham said.
"Babies will die if they are not vaccinated. Just last week an Australian woman contracted meningococcal, believed to be contracted from an unvaccinated toddler and died."
"These sort of lies and misinformation are a threat to public health and people who promote these ideas should be treated with disdain and shouldn't be given a stage in which to spread their lives."
Fairfax Media has contacted Village Cinemas centre management for comment.
The AVN has also been contacted for comment.  
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Orthopaedic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somali-American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cover-up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Wakefield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian National University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Village's Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State of Minnesota</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Cunningham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Order of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Village Cinemas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1.4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr John Cunningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AVN</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vaxxed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Vaccination-skeptics Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
