<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412533181508185</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4829399/digital-focus-in-schools-highlighted-in-wollongong-seminar/?cs=12</url>
  <title>NSW Department of Education secretary highlights Wollongong Education Week event</title>
  <content>
Secretary of the NSW Department of Education, Mark Scott will talk at the 2nd Annual CNI Education Week Conference and Dinner in Wollongong on Thursday, August 3. Picture: Janie Barrett

About 100 Illawarra educators will drop by Wollongong Golf Club for the 2nd Annual CNI Education Week Conference and Dinner on Thursday.

NSW Department of Education secretary Mark Scott will be the guest speaker at the seminar, where he will discuss the use of digital technology in schools.
The August 3 seminar starts at 4.15pm and will celebrate Curriculum Networks Illawarra's (CNI) achievements over the last 12 months.

2017 CNI steering committee chair and Dapto High School principal, Andrew FitzSimons, said the group's participants were particularly keen to learn about Mr Scott's thinking on the use of digital technologies in schools to amplify good learning and teaching.
''Mr Scott's record of digital innovation whilst leading the ABC has sharpened local teacher appetite to learn more of where he might be leading us,'' Mr FitzSimons said.
''In a recent survey of teachers in CNI schools, 81 per cent of 468 respondents advised they were keen to become more adept at using technology to collaborate with colleagues.
''The CNI has significant expertise in this area and we hope Mr Scott's presentation at our annual conference will amplify the collaboration already underway amongst our local educators.''
The CNI initiative was established in 2013 to facilitate learning and sharing of resources between all high schools so as to improve learning outcomes for students in the region. 
It consists of teachers and executive staff from 17 high schools from Bulli to Kiama who together represent around 12,000 students and 1500 employees.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curriculum Networks Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Scott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Education Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dapto High School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Annual CNI Education Week Conference</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Scott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secretary of the NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Education</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Department of Education</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janie Barrett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Fitzsimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr FitzSimons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNI</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
