<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412782289616183</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:08</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/girl-2-in-critical-condition-with-meningococcal-disease/news-story/b463939d01fef522bdf4ece8e1908034</url>
  <title>Girl, 2, fighting for life with meningococcal</title>
  <content>
A TWO-year-old girl from metropolitan Adelaide is fighting for her life in hospital, in a critical condition with meningococcal disease.
Health authorities issued an alert on Wednesday about the new case, reassuring the public "that anyone who requires antibiotics has been contacted by SA Health".
SA Health has identified multiple people who had contact with the patient and nine people have been directed to receive antibiotics.
"SA Health is aware that a childcare centre where the child attended, as well as a local school sent out alarmist and inappropriate information," the statement reads.
"As the disease is only spread by close or lengthy contact, there is no increased public health risk."
The strain of the disease is not yet known and no links have been established between this case and other recent cases.
So far this year there have been 21 cases of meningococcal in South Australia, compared with 13 cases recorded at the same time last year.
Of the cases this year, 13 have been the B-strain, five have been the W-strain and two have been the Y-strain.
For infants and young children, meningococcal symptoms include refusal to feed, a high-pitched or moaning cry, leg pain, cold hands and feet and tiny red or purple spots that soon spread and enlarge to look like fresh bruises.
In older children and adults, symptoms include headache, fever, vomiting, neck stiffness, drowsiness or confusion and the distinctive rash.

Vaccination of our kids is essential for creating herd immunity against diseases like measles, whooping cough and meningococcal. Which Vaccines are provided to Australian kids for free on the vaccination schedule, and which are available for parents to purchase at an additional cost? Advice on what to kid if your kids are afraid of needles.

Vaccination Update
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B-strain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W-strain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y-strain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Health</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
