<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413701412635701</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/ryan-claims-state-golf-honours/3208123/</url>
  <title>Ryan claims state golf honours</title>
  <content>
GOLF: Headland Golf Club's Josie Ryan is on the hunt for her third national golfing title after claiming top state honours.
Ryan overcame a bout of illness to take her fifth Queensland Senior Women's golf championship at Maroochy River Golf Club last week.
Ryan, who battled a heavy dose of the flu in the month leading up to the event, defeated Alex Belongoft (Pacific) 2 & 1 in the match play final.
She has been a consistent performer over many years, winning the Australian Seniors title twice and finishing runner-up at the two previous Queensland championships.
Ryan will be on the hunt for her third national title in October and will tee-off her campaign with local knowledge on her side as the Maroochy River Golf Club gears up to host the Australian Women's Senior Amateur Golf Championships. After claiming the state crown at the course, Ryan has already proven a formidable golfer on home turf but said she had plans to hit the greens regularly in the lead-up to nationals in a bid to enhance her game further.
"Maroochy River is a different style of golf course to most of the ones here in this area and it requires a number of different golf shots to play.
"Depending if wind gets up, the wind can be very difficult out there and can change the shot of a hole by two clubs either with the wind or against it."
Ryan, 65, has also fixed her sights on competing at the South Australian and Victorian titles this month to claim some vital national ranking points.
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
Child taken to hospital after being hit by car while leaving school
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
EVEN shoes were optional, which was a complete culture shock for me.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Headland Golf Club's Josie Ryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River Golf Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pacific) 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Women's Senior Amateur Golf Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Senior Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan, 65</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Belongoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Seniors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
