<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413645578059608</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/religious-instruction-furore-sparks-education-queensland-review-20170802-gxo17u.html</url>
  <title>Religious instruction furore sparks Education Queensland review</title>
  <content>
Education Queensland's contentious religious instruction report will be reviewed following a furore that saw Christian groups pitted against the Palaszczuk government over claims students had been barred from talking about religion at school.
Last week, Education Minister Kate Jones was forced to release a statement , after reports students were banned from referencing Jesus in the school yard.Photo: Steve Lunam
Ms Jones said nobody was telling a child what they could and could not say in the playground, which was welcomed by the Queensland Christian Religious Instruction Network.
A review of the GodSpace religious instruction materials, completed in March 2017, said RI instructors should be reminded that students "should not be encouraged to evangelise to other students at the school".
In Queensland, about 23 per cent of state school students participated in RI programs.
The decision to make changes to the documents comes after an urgent meeting was held with Ms Jones and the Religious Instruction Quality Assurance Committee on Tuesday.

The committee includes representatives from various faiths and advises the Education Department on RI.
Late on Tuesday, the department's RI policy statement webpage was quietly updated, with the addition of the words: "Please note: These reports are currently under review and will be updated."

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

It is understood the updates will focus on clarifying the phrasing in the report that caused concern among religious groups that young people would be barred from talking about their faith.
Queensland Parents for Secular State Schools has also requested a meeting with Education Queensland.
Meanwhile, a read of the original GodSpace review report shows the syllabus contained a reference to child sacrifice in the teachers' background information, which was not intended for discussion with students.
"During this period (Old Testament) other cultures held very poor views about children. Some saw children as possessions, a commodity to be sold, while some thought that children should be used as innocent sacrifices, killed when the 'gods' were angry," it reads.
The reviewers said if it was necessary to keep the reference in the teachers' background information, an explicit statement should be included to indicate that child sacrifice should not be discussed with students in any lesson.
The lessons also included taking a group to a grassed area to play a game of "slave tag", where the teacher would say: "Joseph was sold as a slave. Slaves were dragged around until sold to a master."
The game of tag included a 'slave trader', who tipped a person who became a 'slave' and had to link arms with the 'slave trader', who then both chased after other 'slaves'.
The reviewers said playing a game of 'slaves' was not appropriate in RI classes in Queensland state schools.
The GodSpace review did not find major inconsistencies with legislation, departmental policies, procedures or frameworks, but recommended some elements be addressed with the publisher.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ri</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Christian Religious Instruction Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Secular State Schools</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GodSpace</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Parents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Kate Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.25</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Religious Instruction Quality Assurance Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Lunam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Testament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
