<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413396469951305</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/boxing-mma/this-mma-fighter-was-signed-to-the-ufc-after-this-ridiculous-ko/news-story/84f72530fcc30239c1bc08ac0f45b6a7</url>
  <title>Disgusting sound after horrifying MMA KO</title>
  <content>
FANS begin watching MMA knowing there will be violence, blood and gore. But sometimes even the hardiest of fans have their stomach churn at the sight (or sound) of carnage in the Octagon.
MMA star Julian Maruqez stunned the crowd with a ridiculous kick to bring down Phil Hawes during the fourth instalment of Dana White's Contender Series.
The middleweight powerhouse belted Hawes with a series of punches as his opponent retreated to the edge of the Octagon.
What followed was nothing short of gladiatorial.
Marquez shot up his leg with a lighting-fast kick, smashing Hawes in the face and immediately knocking him out cold.
The fight referee stood to protect the motionless Hawes as the crowd erupted.
The UFC boss was so impressed with the plucky 27-year-old that he offered him a contract with the promotion as soon as he completed the fight.
White was forced out of his seat, screaming in excitement, as Maruqez sealed the win.
"I didn't fight for Dana White. I fought for myself," Maruqez said after the fight.

THINK THAT WAS BAD? WATCH THIS
A heavyweight MMA clash in South Korea lasted just seven seconds after one fighter took a excruciating kick to the groin.
Aorigele, 22, was taking on opponent Myung Hyun-Man in Road FC 39 as the pair sized each other up following the bell.
But blink and the fight was ruled a non-contest after Myung took a brutal blow to his nether regions.
After taking the kick, Myung collapsed to the ground and withered in pain as the panicked referee rushed to his aid.
Aorigele could only stand and watch as his stricken opponent could barely contain the pain before his coaches ran to help out the fighter.
Doctors then piled into the octagon and covered the fighter with a sheet so they could check in privacy whether any damage had been done.

- with Richard Forrester, The Sun
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dana White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Forrester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myung</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Road FC 39</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Myung Hyun-Man</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian Maruqez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dana White's Contender Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA KO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phil Hawes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aorigele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maruqez</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marquez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH THIS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aorigele, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
