<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413697117668381</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/brisbane-bus-strike-lord-mayor-graham-quirk-says-pay-offer-nonnegotiable/news-story/e7db964a2fa96336f408d830189fcd8e</url>
  <title>New Battle of Brisbane: 'We will never surrender'</title>
  <content>
BRISBANE Lord Mayor Graham Quirk has declared the city won't be held to ransom over  during the next five weeks.
A cabal of 11 unions are refusing to rule out broadening strike action from bus drivers and cleaners to librarians, call centre workers and other frontline services in a new Battle of Brisbane.
However as about 500 union members rallied outside City Hall yesterday, Cr Quirk said council would refuse to budge from its 2.5 per cent pay rise offer for employees.
"We've already indicated that we've got a solid offer on the table," Cr Quirk said.
"We believe that it's a fair and reasonable offer and we're not about to budge on that offer."
Bus drivers went out on strike yesterday for four hours, with hundreds protesting in King George Square while nearby streets were empty of buses.
The powerful union bloc have about five more weeks to undertake a range of protected industrial action, including striking for up to 24 hours, as part of negotiating tactics against council.
But Cr Quirk said he had a responsibility as the "custodian of ratepayers' money" to maintain the 2.5 per cent pay rise offer as part of the new enterprise bargaining agreement.
The union caucus on Tuesday presented council with a formal request for a 3.5 per cent pay rise over three years, plus an $800 sign-on bonus, which is above council's $400 offer.
The Courier-Mail revealed this week a 3.5 per cent pay rise would cost ratepayers an extra $52 million above the $128 million budgeted for the 2.5 per cent pay rise for 7500 employees.
However unions argue the pay rise would be on par with wages growth for minimum workers.
Australian Services Union secretary Neil Henderson refused to rule out strike action for frontline council staff, including call centre operators, but said it would be used as a last resort.
"For the council, it needs to start bargaining because the workers are showing they're putting their money where their mouth is," Mr Henderson said.
It comes as bus drivers will refuse to collect fares tomorrow, costing ratepayers an estimated $515,000, after they yesterday walked off the job for the fourth time in two weeks.
Council said about 50 per cent of drivers participated in the strike, with 65 per cent of bus trips unaffected.
Rail, Tram and Bus spokesman Tom Brown said it was "unprecedented" for all council unions to rally against the administration. It is the first time bus drivers have gone on strike since 1998.
Meanwhile, Transport Workers Union spokesman Troy Fernandez said members were just asking for a "lousy dollar an hour for our members".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Lord Mayor Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Henderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Quirk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Battle of Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Services Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Workers Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Battle of Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Troy Fernandez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courier-Mail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
