<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413645578059601</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/world/under-pressure-from-the-us-over-north-korea-will-china-cave-in-not-likely-20170802-gxo13t</url>
  <title>Under pressure from the US over North Korea, will China cave in? Not likely</title>
  <content>
As Washington plans an investigation into China's trade practices in apparent retaliation to Beijing's inaction on North Korea, the Chinese state-owned media went on the offensive on Wednesday.
The Communist Party mouthpiece, the People's Daily, blamed the US for North Korea's nuclear program. "The case can be made that North Korean nuclear weapons are the only reliable deterrent to American aggression," wrote one of the paper's columnists.
The China Daily argued in an editorial that China, too, feels threatened by Pyongyang's nuclear ambitions and Beijing has been "unfairly burdened with a task that is obviously beyond it".
"Trump is wrong in his assumption that Beijing can single-handedly handle the matter," it said in the newspaper's editorial.

"As Beijing has said, repeatedly, it does not have the kind of 'control' over Pyongyang that the US president believes it does."

The newspaper said stakeholders must act collectively but that "Trump's threat to link the issue to trade and mount pressure on China show these two stakeholders are moving further apart".
Pressure on China to "do more on North Korea" has become the response-of-choice for diplomats not just in the US, but also in Australia and the UK. But there is a danger this focus comes in lieu of a more coherent strategy to deal with the escalating tensions on the Korean peninsula.
China has made it abundantly clear it is not about to cave in to pressure from the US and Trump's scolding tweets will only harden Beijing's resolve.
Diplomatically, China's influence over North Korea has weakened under the rule of Kim Jong-un. As Andrew O'Neil, a professor of political science at Griffith University, points out, he hasn't visited China since taking power in late-2011.

He has also purged most of the pro-Beijing officials from his entourage.
"Kim Jong-un is a different leader from his father and grandfather, who both had deep fraternal links with Beijing," says O'Neil.
Relations between China and North Korea reached a new low in February this year, following the assassination of Kim's estranged older brother Kim Jong-nam at Kuala Lumpur's international airport. The elder Kim had been living between Beijing and Macau and was widely regarded to be under the protection of Chinese authorities.
While diplomatic relations are strained, it is true that economically, China still has significant leverage. It is North Korea's most important trading partner, accounting for more than 90 per cent of its total trade volume. However, while Beijing says it complies with UN sanctions, it is reluctant to go further as it fears a regime collapse, resulting in a flood of refugees across the border into north-eastern China.

A reunified Korea could also leave China faced with the unpalatable situation of US troops and military bases close to its border.
And so there is a standoff. The US wants China to do more while Beijing has put forward its own proposal to get Washington and Pyongyang back to the negotiating table. This involves a freeze in North Korea's nuclear program in exchange for a suspension of joint US and South Korean military exercises.
The problem with this proposal is that it makes no mention of North Korea halting its military exercises, which are also regarded as a threat to South Korea.
"China's proposal is heavily biased," says Bruce Bennett, a senior defence researcher at the Rand Corporation.

"And North Korea has been very clear they're not going to give up their nuclear weapons."
While some analysts argue a variation of China's proposal might be the only way for negotiations to restart and a crisis to be avoided, Bennett says political pressure could be applied to Kim Jong-un.
"He needs to be convinced the costs he will suffer are greater than the benefits [of continuing the nuclear program]. The only cost he cares about is regime survival," he says.
But for now the debate is centred on Beijing's role and the Trump administration has taken the gloves off, with US media reporting that plans for an investigation into China's trade practices will be announced any day.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyongyang</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffith University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew O'Neil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KUALA LUMPUR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rand Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People's Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communist Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong Nam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
