<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413044282626377</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/18/33/dad-says-exwife-getting-paid-for-kids-hes-looking-after</url>
  <title>Dad says ex-wife getting paid for kids he</title>
  <content>
A single father has accused his ex-wife of pocketing parenting benefits from Centrelink despite having no children in her care.
Geordie Meek told A Current Affair he looked after all four children he had with ex Natalia.
For this he said he received a weekly Centrelink single parent payment of $725, $400 of which was spent on rent.
He said despite his ex-partner claiming benefits for looking after two of the children, he received little support from her.
Ms Meek refused to comment when approached by A Current Affair but stated on Facebook she was supporting Mr Meeks financially, to the tune of $100 a week.
Mr Meeks said it was meant to be $150 a week, but that getting any support was difficult.
"I gave up my work, I gave up everything, all my friends, to be with my kids to look after them and raise them as a father should," he said.

Related Articles

Barry Williams from the Lone Fathers Association said cases like Mr Meek's were not isolated.
"There's so much help for women in this country - and rightly so because they need it - but compared to men's services, we can't even get men and children in any accommodation sometimes," he said.
Ms Meek has told Mr Meek she was willing to take care of some of the children once she is set up in her own rental property, which she hoped to find in the Brisbane suburb of Inala.
There is no custody dispute involving any of the children.
A Department of Human Services spokesperson said they were working closely with the family to ensure they received the appropriate support.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lone Fathers Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centrelink</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Human</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geordie Meek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Meek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Meeks</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Current Affair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
