<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413658462961709</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-jockey-gets-awarded-top-title/3208122/</url>
  <title>Coast jockey gets awarded top title</title>
  <content>
HORSE RACING: As Beerwah jockey Tiffani Brooker approaches the end of her apprenticeship, she does so with a coveted title and record to her name.
The 24-year-old has had a stellar 2016-17 season in the saddle, placing in the top three at more than 140 meets.
The solid effort resulted in Brooker winning the Queensland apprentice title.
In her journey to becoming the best Queensland metropolitan apprentice jockey, Brooker also claimed a slice of history by becoming the first female apprentice jockey to ride 50 metropolitan winners in a season.
The premiership-winning jockey, who is based at Corbould Park working for trainer Stuart Kendrick, still has six months left on her apprenticeship. Despite her recent success, she said a second tilt at the title was unlikely.
Brooker hoped life after the apprenticeship would lead to riding in the professional ranks of the sport.
"My goal is to just out-ride my claim and see how the next six months goes," she said.
"So, it's just to keep improving and if I come out of my time and become a senior and still mix it in town obviously I'll really enjoy that. Then, perhaps in the future if it takes me somewhere else around Australia or overseas that's a bonus."
At Corbould Park, Stuart Kendrick finished the season strong to be crowned the Sunshine Coast Turf Club's leading trainer, while Jeff Lloyd stormed home to be named the top jockey.
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
Child taken to hospital after being hit by car while leaving school
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
EVEN shoes were optional, which was a complete culture shock for me.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeff Lloyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beerwah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brooker</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiffani Brooker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Kendrick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Turf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corbould Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
