<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412713570138160</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/latest-news/pathology-workers-likely-to-strike-in-vic/news-story/07e0a31710b1886520b80d4f5e496153</url>
  <title>Pathology workers likely to strike in Vic</title>
  <content>
A pay dispute has reached boiling point in Victoria with more than 500 pathology workers expected to walk off the job "for a fair bloody go".
Dorevitch Pathology staff have voted to take protected industrial action on Monday over what the Health Workers Unions says is a "zero per cent pay offer on the table".
"Dorevitch received our worst health employer of the year award for a reason - these workers have waited for over a decade for a pay deal," union secretary Diana Asmar said in a statement on Wednesday.
"Right now, they are the lowest paid and unhappiest pathology workers in Australia by a country mile. Enough is enough."
The union says Dorevitch's owner, Primary Health, has posted more than $1.2 billion in profits since the last pay deal, with wages remaining stagnant over a decade.
Striking employees will include pathology collectors, couriers, clerical staff, laboratory assistants, cleaners and maintenance staff.
Dorevitch only foresees minimal disruption to its services.
"There will be no impact to the services we provide public and private hospitals, and our laboratories will continue to process tests and work with GPs to deliver results as per normal," a company spokeswoman told AAP.
"A number of contingencies have been implemented to limit the impact to patients and GPs."
The pathology giant has more than 300 sites across the state and contracts with many public and private hospitals - with only a small number of collection centres to close on Monday.
They also manage urine drug testing for the state's prisoners.
The union says it holds concerns about the company's ability to meet national standards on urine drug testing during the industrial action.
The Department of Justice has been contacted for comment.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Justice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorevitch Pathology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Workers Unions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana Asmar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorevitch</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
