<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412533181508121</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/supporting-kids-in-care/3205853/</url>
  <title>Supporting kids in care</title>
  <content>
CHILDREN in foster care often face significant disruptions in both schooling and their home lives, and a little stability can go a long way.
After becoming a foster parent through Anglicare Enhanced, Sarah Johnson realised something more needed to be done.
Together with Mell Newell and Sammy Dwyer, who came from a background of department and youth work respectively, Ms Johnson decided to create the new Breaking Thru centre in Nambour.
"A lot of kids who have been in care don't have basic reading or writing skills," Ms Johnson said.
"Some are 9 or 10 and they don't know the alphabet...often they miss a whole year so we are trying to bridge that, so this is a place youth workers can bring them to spend the day.
"It's a breathing space too...for foster carers, teachers and the department...with social workers for example, they all have their hearts in the right place and they want to make a difference, but a lot of the time they can't."
The Breaking Thru centre is comprised of a playroom, media room, kitchenette, learning spaces and even a bedroom for cases where children have been removed from emergency situations and are yet to be placed into care.
Ms Johnson said the idea had been a long time coming.
"We have been renovating for months; the tradespeople and community have been unbelievable and BFX in Yandina donated a lot of furniture.
"There's nothing else like this."
For more information, email admin@ breaking thru.org.au.
Tourist track takes toll with plenty of motorists caught out
Turn your dream of owning a hip cafe or bar into a reality.
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
EVEN shoes were optional, which was a complete culture shock for me.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
FANTASY series thrown into chaos as hackers leak top secret scripts.
Three contestants reveal lesbian encounters.
Botched stunt does $40,000 worth of damage.
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
"We've been told that it has the best beaches and snorkelling."
Three potential sites have been identified by city leaders
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BFX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mell Newell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sammy Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglicare Enhanced</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Johnson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yandina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breaking Thru</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
