<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413516729037748</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/524199/thirroul-teen-saves-brother-from-drowning/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Thirroul teen saves brother from drowning</title>
  <content>
Thirroul teen saves brother from drowning

Kyle Squires in front of the family pool. Picture: ROBERT PEET

exit
A Thirroul teen has been hailed a hero after he rescued his two-year-old brother from the family pool.

Kyle Squires, 14, and his brother Jack, 5, were playing in their backyard pool yesterday afternoon while their younger brother, Charlie, sat on a wading ledge. Their father Jayson Squires was keeping watch from a nearby chair. 
Around 4pm, Mr Squires asked Kyle to keep an eye on Charlie while he ducked inside. As soon as he left, Charlie slipped into the pool.
Kyle, who was at the other end of the pool, acted quickly.
"I was at the other end of the pool and I swam over and got him out, then I called out to my
dad for help," Kyle said.
Mr Squires heard Kyle's cries and ran to the scene. The pair, both members of Thirroul Surf Life Saving Club, resuscitated the two-year-old.
An ambulance was called and three paramedics rushed to the house.
Charlie was taken to Wollongong Hospital yesterday afternoon.
Paramedic Peter Cribbs, who attended the home, said Kyle was instrumental in saving his younger brother's life.
"I've got no doubt whatsoever if Kyle hadn't pulled his brother out yesterday, he wouldn't be
with us today,'' Mr Cribbs said.
The toddler has now fully recovered from the accident and is home from hospital.
Full story in tomorrow's Mercury

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Cribbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ROBERT PEET</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack, 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thirroul Surf Life Saving Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Squires, 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Squires</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kyle Squires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Cribbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jayson Squires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
