<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412704980203320</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/theatre/ruby-rae-spiegels-dry-land-play-causes-audience-member-to-faint-opening-night-20170802-gxnvsr.html</url>
  <title>Dry Land play causes audience member to faint on opening night</title>
  <content>
A graphic production by an up-and-coming American playwright has already seen one Australian faint during its most "intense" scene during the local premiere in Sydney. 
The play, Dry Land, from US playwright Ruby Rae Spiegel, follows two high school swim-team mates who bond after one of the girls reveals she wants to end her unwanted pregnancy.

Up Next

Rachel Griffiths speaks against orphanage tourism

01:49

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Entertainment news highlights

Bitchiness on The Bachelor, Dr G Yunupingu's marvelous career, talk shows take on Trump's transgender ban, fans' anger at Australian Ninja Warrior and Ringo and Paul back together again.

Dry Land actors Sarah Meacham​ and Patricia Pemberton had just finished acting out the crucial scene involving fake blood when a man in the audience briefly lost consciousness. 
The sequence, which shows one of the characters bleeding during the graphic DIY abortion, also drew some criticism during the show's US run.

A spokeswoman for King's Cross Theatre confirmed Tuesday night's show was stopped for four minutes while a gentleman in the audience received first aid. 
"He made a quick recovery and enjoyed a drink with the cast and crew on the rooftop after the performance," the spokeswoman said. "It's important to focus on what the play is really about - the challenges of young women in a world where they may not feel comfortable to speak freely about difficult and/or life-changing experiences and decisions."

One audience member, meanwhile, said the cast and crew handled the situation like "pros". 

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

One of the actresses involved in the scene, Pemberton, admitted it would have been a very "intense" and "emotional" time for the audience. Photo: James Brickwood
"Both Sarah [Meacham] and I weren't 100 per cent sure what happened because we were so involved in the circumstances of the play," she said. "So we just stayed with each other and were lucky we were in an embrace. We stayed in the moment - lucky it was quite quick." 
However, the 23-year-old actress said the play wasn't designed to "shock" audiences. Instead, she said the scene was about staying true to real-life situations.  Photo: Supplied
"That, in a way, speaks volumes," she said. 
The play's official program - which recommends the production for audiences aged 16 years and older - cites "graphic and confronting content" and features a trigger warning for "sexual content".  Photo: Supplied
Spiegel had previously shrugged off reports of widespread fainting among US audiences as "exaggerations".
"One person fainted during my play and there was all this press about it, but it was just that she was feeling sick that day," she told Fairfax Media last month.
"The fact that people are shocked says a lot about how squeamish we are with women's bodies."
The production is the latest to spark an extreme reaction from local theatre audiences.
Earlier this year, a touring production of George Orwell's 1984 left some theatregoers fainting and vomiting over an extended torture scene and its jarring soundtrack and strobe light effects. 
Dry Land continues its Australian run at Sydney's Kings Cross Theatre until August 19. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meacham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr G. Yunupingu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruby Rae Spiegel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Brickwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pemberton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitchiness</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Kings Cross Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Pemberton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King's Cross Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spiegel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ringo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dry Land</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Meacham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Orwell's 1984</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DIY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
