<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412739339942380</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828840/knights-keeping-the-faith/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Knights keeping the faith</title>
  <content>
Knights keeping the faith

exit

On the weekend, unlike many other times this season, we found a way to win rather than finding a way to lose.
And not only was it much sweeter singing that team song in the sheds and celebrating with Newcastle Knights fans at home, but it showed why we must keep the faith.   
In such an integral week for the NRL club, as voting for the historic Wests ownership proposal continues, Saturday's morale-boosting victory over the Dragons highlighted the direction this place is heading.

Beyond the valuable two competition points, it was the nature of this performance which stood out.

By our own admission it probably wasn't our best 80 minutes but we managed to get the job done.

It bucked the recent trend, where half-time leads disappeared into losses, but we'd been knocking on the door and it was only a matter of time until the ball bounced our way for a breakthrough.

That moment has arrived and it feels like those darker days are now behind us.  

Much of that credit lies with the Knights coaching staff of 2017 - headed by Nathan Brown and supported by the likes of Michael Potter, Kurt Wrigley and Simon Woolford. 
They have asked us, the players, and supporters alike to believe in the process going forward and after much patience and heartache we're starting to reap the rewards.

There's also a genuine sense from camp that our best football lies ahead of us - in the remaining five rounds, next year and beyond.
With the foundations that have been built this season and last, combined with the quality recruits en route to McDonald Jones Stadium in 2018, do we dare to dream about finals football? 

Obviously the best we can hope for over the next month or so is avoiding that dreaded piece of sporting culinary, but the future is filled with both hope and belief.

In the meantime, and most importantly this weekend, we must back it up and triumph twice in a row.
I'm not sure the last time the Knights have done that, but we're up for the challenge.
Filled with confidence but aware of our errors, especially last month when expected to win against the Wests Tigers.
Our attitude must be spot on to overcome the always-unpredictable but ever-dangerous Warriors, who managed to run us down in New Zealand in round one. 

Bring on Saturday afternoon already!
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Knights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Potter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Wrigley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nathan Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald Jones Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Woolford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
