<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413525318972484</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/bitcoin-cash-price-and-marketcap-2017-8</url>
  <title>Bitcoin cash is already the 3rd largest cryptocurrency</title>
  <content>
Bitcoin cash has already secured its place as a top cryptocurrency, just a day after it entered the marketplace.

According to , the cryptocurrency is trading at about $US490 per coin and its marketcap now stands above $US8 billion. As such, it is the third largest cryptocurrency by marketcap, surpassing big name coins such as Ripple ($US6.7 billion) and Litecoin ($US2.2 billion).

Bitcoin cash came to fruition Tuesday after  bitcoin. To recap, the split was preceded by a .

Supporters of the newly formed bitcoin cash believe the currency will "" the nearly 10-year-old bitcoin by addressing some of the issues facing bitcoin of late, such as slow transaction speeds.

And it looks like investors are singing the same tune. Bitcoin cash is up about 80% since its inception. That's a higher appreciation than any of the other top 10 cryptocurrencies.

Because bitcoin cash will initially draw its value from bitcoin's market cap, according to Charles Morris, the chief investment officer of NextBlock Global, an investment firm with digital assets, it will most likely cause bitcoin's value to drop by an amount proportional to its adoption.

is currently down 3.7% at $US2,690.

Get the latest Bitcoin price

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Litecoin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2,690</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US490</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Morris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NextBlock Global</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
