<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413353520277564</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/how-michael-hooper-can-use-the-adversity-of-2014-to-become-a-better-wallabies-captain-20170802-gxo01a.html</url>
  <title>How Hooper's 2014 experience will make him a better Wallabies captain</title>
  <content>
Three years ago Michael Hooper was 22, a fill-in captain of the Wallabies and barking orders at senior players, some of whom were a decade older than him. 
"I found that very difficult," Hooper said on Wednesday. "You'd think a group of 18 to 34-year-olds would be reasonably similar blokes but it's not the case. Photo: Daniel Munoz
"Everyone has different needs, different wants, different motivations. Catering for those and being able to handle different emotions and feelings in the squad is something I am better at than I was then." 
Hooper's introduction to the captaincy was a baptism of fire and came at a controversial time for Australian rugby in late 2014. 
Kurtley Beale was embroiled in a texting scandal involving team manager Di Patston while on tour in Argentina. This was followed shortly after by the resignation of coach Ewen McKenzie after a Test loss against New Zealand that followed a string of poor performances and a mountain of pressure. 
Despite these distractions, Wallabies prop Benn Robinson saw something in Hooper at the time; traits that proved he was destined to be an influential leader of men in the years to come.

"The way he talks to players around the field, everyone has got their eyes up," Robinson told Fairfax Media. "That's a sign of a good leader when the chips are down. 
"He commanded respect immediately from players and players respected him back.

You will now receive updates from

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"Back then he was always a player that led by his actions. That's the quality you want in a leader.
"It was a very natural role for him. There was never any doubting his leadership or why he was there. He was always a player that led by example and it was easy to follow him. He can get a team focused onto the job straight away," he said.
"I don't see him really reflecting too much on that year but as a leader you always learn from your experiences." 
When Stephen Moore returned from injury, Hooper resumed back-seat duties but continued as a battle-hardened back-rower, proving proved to be an influential figure in Australia's World Cup campaign. 
Hooper has had time to refine his leadership skills at the Waratahs and from all reports is getting more out of his players than when he was learning on the run. 
But it is the adversity of 2014 and being a young man dealing with problems beyond his pay-grade that Wallabies legend Simon Poidevin believes will benefit Hooper long-term. 
"That's the way of life," Poidevin said. "You learn to gain that resilience through hard times. That's great he's had that experience at such a young age. 
"He now has 15 Tests under his belt, so he's far from being a novice as a leader." 
Hooper admits there were tough times when he first took over but he now views himself as a completely different person. 
"You're a young guy and you just want to play rugby," Hooper said. "It's understanding that there's so much more than what's on the field. 
"You've got guys you look up to and guys you've been around a long time. I'd only really had two years in the Wallabies, so it's tough. You have to push yourself out of your comfort zone. 
"Taking it into this role, it's good to have that preparation under the belt. While we're all friends, you have to have uncomfortable situations to be able to get the best result." 
There was, however, some negative reaction to the news Hooper will take over the Wallabies captaincy full-time, mainly from outside the borders of NSW. 
The Wallabies need a player to lead from the front and with Hooper at the helm, coach Michael Cheika believes will lead Australia into a new era. 
"He's a pretty brazen young guy in the way he plays the game," Cheika said. "He hasn't got the hugest frame of all-time but he plays like he has got that. 
"He understands when his team really needs him to come up and make a big play and that's what he's getting better at." 
There is also the small matter of what happens when David Pocock returns to the Wallabies fold next year after a sabbatical from the game. 
Both men have played together in the back-row in recent years but according to Poidevin, one of Australia's greatest No.7s, Pocock might have to get in the queue. 
"Pocock is going to have to win his spot back," he said. "He can't walk straight back into the side, there's some strong talent emerging in the Wallabies back-row. 
"Himself and Michael Hooper have vastly different skill sets but they are very complementary." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hooper</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper's 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argentina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugbyheaven Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurtley Beale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Poidevin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Munoz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cheika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pocock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Pocock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Poidevin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Di Patston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ewen McKenzie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benn Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
