<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413216081321360</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/a-league/teams/western-sydney/wanderers-boss-tony-popovic-hails-impact-of-new-signings-in-teams-progress-to-last-16-of-ffa-cup/news-story/b68e7577757ee5620c2134145f85a5b3</url>
  <title>Popa spies progress in Cup victory</title>
  <content>
IT was an inauspicious start to the new campaign, but Wanderers boss Tony Popovic believes the seeds of success were evident in his side's on Tuesday night.
A header in the last minute of extra-time from marquee striker Oriol Riera secured Western Sydney a place in the last 16 of the tournament, though it was a forgettable tie between two sides still two months away from the start of the A-League.
Popovic, however, was buoyed by the contributions of Riera and playmaker Roley Bonevacia, who was taking on the team he quit in May to join Western Sydney. Both will be leading figures in a restructured side, as the Wanderers seek to return to a place challenging for the A-League title as well as the FFA Cup.
"Riera showed an amazing work rate," Popovic said. "You can see that the team and he are trying to get to know each other but to have that leap (in the air), in the 120th minute, when your condition isn't good and you're not match fit, shows he'll be a fantastic player for us.
"Roley's work rate was phenomenal too and he kept wanting to get on the ball. Will he get better? Yes he will, much better. At times I felt he was a bit anxious on the ball, maybe because it was against his old club or trying a bit too hard for us.
"But amongst all that he showed some fantastic signs, and did some great things on the ball."
The goal was a rare flash of skill in a scrappy encounter, with young forward Abraham Majok creating the opportunity with a powerful run that was halted by a terrible tackle from Wellington defender Tom Doyle. Riera headed home from the resultant corner, just as the game seemed destined for penalties.
Popovic said that he was "not surprised so much as pleased" at his team's energy levels in a game that went to extra time. "They're in good condition for this stage of the season," he said. "There was never a sense of us not being able to run out the game, but you still have to win it.

Football: FFA CUp action.

FFA Cup: Overnight goals
"Abra making a run late in the game shows physical strength; Oriol winning the header over a number of bodies shows physical strength. We envisage that improving week by week, to be at another level by October."
The club's second Spanish marquee, winger Alvaro Cejudo, did not feature, and Popovic was unclear as to when he would be physically ready for competitive action.
"Playing, I'm not sure," he said. "If it was up to him he'd have played against Wellington. That's a good sign, that he wants to be involved, but we'll go day by day. We have a process and a plan for him, and the key was to have him ready for October."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alvaro Cejudo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riera</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Doyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Popovic</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oriol Riera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanderers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Popa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roley Bonevacia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abraham Majok</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oriol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wellington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Popovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
