<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413606923352964</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/sport/football/heidelberg-striker-ken-athiu-keeping-a-level-head-after-his-winning-ffa-cup-goal-against-perth-glory/news-story/29a2ca151272d53c45541d886167d361</url>
  <title>Back to work for Heidelberg heroes</title>
  <content>
AS Perth Glory players flew home on Wednesday, Heidelberg United's part-timers returned to their day jobs.
But for the tilers, removalists, baristas, painters, hairdressers, car salesmen and full-time students, the buzz from their mammoth FFA Cup upset the night before certainly had not subsided.
Heidelberg's 1-0 win over Perth at Olympic Village - and the manner in which it was achieved - sent shockwaves through the competition.
And for one player in particular the night could be especially life changing.
MATCH:
Ken Athiu harbours ambitions of playing in the A-League.
The 24-year-old striker arrived in Australia as an 11-year-old with his parents having fled war-torn South Sudan.
Having settled in Keysborough, before moving to Noble Park and now Narre Warren, Athiu played at the likes of South Springvale and Springvale White Eagles before finding his senior level feet at Heidelberg under the expert tutelage of George Katsakis.
Athiu has been a goal scoring sensation in the National Premier League for the past two seasons, netting 17 times last year and 15 so far this year for the Victorian ladder leaders.
But it is the booming strike on Tuesday night that sent Perth crashing out of the cup that has seen his face beamed around the country.
A commanding presence on the pitch, but softly spoken off it, Athiu said he is ready for the extra attention that is set to come his way.
"But my lifestyle is pretty chilled," Athiu said.

Football: A moving moment ahead of the FFA Cup match between Perth and Heidelberg.

FFA's Les Murray tribute
"I don't let my head get too big with anything that happens.
"My main focus now is just on our next game against Oakleigh (in the league) on Friday night and nothing more than that."
With talk abound for the need for a second division in Australia, Katsakis said his side's exploits against Perth is further proof that the gap between the A-League and the current second tier competitions is not as big as some make it out to be.
"I think it's narrowing," Katsakis said.
"You talk about a second tier, I really do think some of these boys are fairly appropriate to fill spots in those teams.
"Who was the A-League team out there? I really think we stood tall and took the game to them and were very much on par."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springvale White Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Katsakis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sudan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Springvale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Athiu</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA's Les Murray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heidelberg United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katsakis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keysborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Athiu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narre Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympic Village</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Glory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
