<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412571836214672</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/technology/a-driverless-shuttle-bus-is-set-to-take-to-roads-at-sydney-olympic-park/news-story/3fc2fb87ab2869e644f5354bca3c83a2</url>
  <title>Sydney gets first self-driving bus</title>
  <content>
A DRIVERLESS bus carrying passengers is set to take to NSW roads for the first time.
As part of a two-year trial to begin later this month the small shuttle bus will whiz around closed within the Newington Armoury at Sydney Olympic Park.
At first, the vehicle that can carry about six or eight people, will not pick up any passengers until safety checks and other tests are successfully complete.
But by the beginning of next year it is expected that the shuttle bus will have passengers on board and be using roads around Sydney Olympic Park.
The trial, part of the NSW Government's push towards "technology-enabled transport", was launched at the Armoury this morning by Transport Minister Andrew Constance and Roads Minister Melinda Pavey.
The Government has joined forces with intelligent transport company HMI Technologies, the NRMA, Telstra, IAG and Sydney Olympic Park Authority, to conduct the trial.
"The trial, starting later this month, showcases a small part of our much bigger vision for a technology-enabled transport future," Mr Constance said.
"Today we drive our cars but the reality is, cars will soon drive us and while we are not there yet, we need to be prepared for this change and we need to stay ahead of the game.
"The ultimate goal of the trial is to find the best way to harness the next generation of driverless technology and how to make it work for NSW while also answering questions about how it can improve safety and reliability."
Mrs Pavey said she expected office workers around Sydney Olympic Park would be using the automated shuttle next year.
"We want to use the trial to help develop the systems that will enable automated vehicles to be connected to our infrastructure, like traffic lights and to our customers through their devices and applications.," Mrs Pavey said.
"It's the combination of connectivity and automation that will provide the safety and mobility benefits we are looking for.
"There is still some way to go before automated shuttles become common place on Australian roads, but as a Government we are ready to take the next step and from here all sorts of possibilities open up for transport in NSW."
The NSW Government has established the Smart Innovation Centre, to work with industry to develop similar trials like this and explore future transport plans.
Legislation to allow to driverless bus trial to go ahead has been introduced into Parliament.
For more information go to
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roads Minister Melinda Pavey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smart Innovation Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Minister Andrew Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Constance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HMI Technologies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARMOURY</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Pavey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Olympic Park Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newington Armoury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
