<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413572563613773</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-02/bombers-nt-links-to-play-part-in-aflw-licence-call</url>
  <title>Bombers' NT links to play part in AFLW licence call</title>
  <content>
Inaugural AFLW premier Adelaide had nine NT-based players on its list in 2017

AFL WOMEN'S powerbrokers are yet to reveal whether they are considering Next Generation Academy draft rules similar to the men's league.

The competition continues to adapt on the run, with potential licensee Essendon's commitment to developing talent in its NGA areas on the Tiwi Islands and at Maningrida presenting an interesting case.

AFL clubs have first access to their applicable NGA players and the ability to match rivals' draft bids, the same as father-son and northern academy selections. But the AFLW draft equivalent is not as advanced or complex.

The brief nature of the AFLW season and inability yet to provide a sustainable income for players mean state-based drafts are the most appropriate system.

The AFL's head of women's football, Josh Vanderloo, declined to discuss any potential NGA rule for AFLW, but acknowledged the academies were already part of clubs' thinking.

"We were pleased with the level of planning clubs put into their 2019 team bids and, naturally, many included synergies with their existing NGA," Vanderloo told AFL.com.au.

"In Essendon's case, the club is already working closely with the Tiwi Islands community and these types of connections will be considered when contemplating new AFLW teams."

Adelaide, the inaugural AFLW premier, has a partnership with AFL Northern Territory that saw nine Darwin-based footballers feature on the Crows' list this year. They lived and trained in the Top End throughout the season.

The Bombers were one of eight clubs - along with Geelong, Gold Coast, Hawthorn, North Melbourne (with AFL Tasmania), Richmond, St Kilda and West Coast - to submit a bid to enter the women's league in 2019. They presented their case at AFL House last week.

Essendon made Darwin footballer Michaela Long, the daughter of club legend Michael and sister of Jake, the face of their pitch, as well as going to great lengths to highlight its interest in the Tiwi Islands, in particular. 

The Bombers even want to play their first AFLW match in a remote NT community.

But without special NGA dispensation, Essendon would have to request any NT prospects nominate for the Victorian draft and risk other Melbourne clubs pinching them. 

Among the Tiwi Islanders that the Bombers could consider in the 2018 draft are Arthurina Moreen, the Cunningham sisters - Kimberley and Jessica - and Jamie-Lee Puautjimi. Essendon's website refers to there being "a number of talented women training and playing football in the Northern Territory as part of (its) NGA".

The Bombers have not made formal contact with AFLNT chief executive Michael Solomon, a key player in orchestrating the arrangement with Adelaide, about any plans to draft NT footballers.

"We haven't gone, 'How do we set up an Essendon version of the Adelaide deal?'," Solomon said.

"If we got to numbers where Adelaide's talent profile lifted that much that we had only three girls up here being picked, then the first thing you would do is go, 'Let's try to get them into other clubs'.

"Our job as (AFLNT), like for the boys, is to get as many people on to lists as we can. (But) we are very, very happy with the relationship we have with the Adelaide Football Club ... if it ain't broke, don't fix it."

An Adelaide spokesman did not directly address Essendon's potential threat to its AFLW player pool, but said the Crows were committed to "developing and fostering appropriate talent pathways".

AFL.com.au has contacted Essendon for comment.

Geelong, Hawthorn, Collingwood and Melbourne - all of which could be in AFLW in 2019 - also have NGAs in the NT.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Solomon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maningrida</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nga</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanderloo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michaela Long</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cunningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiwi Islanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Women</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Vanderloo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthurina Moreen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiwi Islands</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Solomon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFLW</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NGAs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie-Lee Puautjimi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Next Generation Academy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
