<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413263325962388</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/act-news/act-parliament-knocks-back-bid-for-exgratia-payment-for-dog-attack-victim-20170802-gxnlen.html</url>
  <title>ACT parliament knocks back bid for ex-gratia payment for dog attack victim</title>
  <content>
The Canberra Liberals have urged the government to reconsider helping with a young dog attack victim 's medical bills.
Jack Hartigan, 13, and his parents Patrick and Joanna watched from the front row of the Legislative Assembly public gallery on Wednesday as the Liberals' Steve Doszpot made the application on their behalf.Photo: Melissa Adams
Chief Minister Andrew Barr defended his decision to refuse their application for an ex-gratia sum of $200,000
Their two previous attempts had failed and Mrs Hartigan said she hoped she would get closure when the a private members' motion was moved on Wednesday.
Instead, Mr Barr doubled down on his reasons for rejecting their claim.
Mr Doszpot said the government appeared to be more willing to give $23 million to a Sydney-based football team, buy a $4 million block from the Tradies Club or give a $750,000 grant for six beach volleyball courts than help a family in need.

He said ex-gratia payments were used in other jurisdictions to help people impacted by gaps in the law.
"I am sure that the ACT Chief Minister has a social conscience, but the trouble is, it is becoming increasingly difficult to find it," Mr Doszpot said.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Mr Barr thanked Mr Doszpot for the assessment of his character but said the Hartigans' claim did not meet the strict set of criteria needed to approve such a payment.
City services minister Meegan Fitzharris said "considerable" changes had already been made because of Jack's attack.
More changes to domestic animal laws are due by the end of September, she noted.
"I'd like to again extend my sympathies to the family.  I'm confident [in] the work we've done to date over many years sadly prompted by considerable distress to the Hartigan family and we will continue to progress this area," Ms Fitzharris said.
Greens crossbencher Caroline Le Couteur helped Labor to shut down Mr Doszpot's bid, saying while the attack was "horrific", the ACT's parliament was not the right place to be "raking over" a tragic case involving a child.
Mr Doszpot said the "obstinacy" shown by Mr Barr in refusing to reexamine the Hartigans' case made him feel a "deep shame".
"Even now he's got his back turned to the family," Mr Doszpot said.
"Mr Barr should turn and at least acknowledge the family, perhaps meet with them to understand, the opportunity is here for him."
Jack said he felt let down by the politicians in the chamber.
"Mr Barr did not look at us once. He was very rude, he just tried to block us out," Jack said.
Mrs Hartigan was distraught. She said her son still suffered because of the attack and his medical bills were crippling. 
"Over the last seven years I've wasted so much time dwelling on this. To not get any acknowledgement ... everyone is acting like it didn't happen. It was an insult. I feel like we're nothing," she said.
In 2010, six-year-old Jack was mauled by two dogs while visiting a friend on a government housing property in Griffith. 
He suffered horrific injuries and psychological trauma as a result of the attack, with skin ripped from his head, his face torn open, teeth knocked out and eaten, and an eye damaged.
, even though the animals were being kept without permission and had been the subject of repeated complaints. 
However, Justice Hilary Penfold suggested the cost of licensing dangerous dogs could include a contribution to an insurance scheme that could offer compensation for people injured in attacks.
She noted the relatively insignificant penalties for breaching requirements of dangerous dog licence conditions. There were also limited instances in which the government could destroy a dog.
You can help with Jack Hartigan's medical bills here:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Hartigan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACT Chief Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Hilary Penfold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberals' Steve Doszpot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tradies Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Hartigan, 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legislative Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Doszpot</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meegan Fitzharris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chief Minister Andrew Barr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fitzharris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hartigan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hartigan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Barr</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Le Couteur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
