<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413430829690315</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:39</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/samesex-marriage-vote-labor-mp-kate-ellis-may-suspend-maternity-leave-to-vote-tony-abbott-condemns-breakdown-in-liberal-party/news-story/9d3c5afec0460d86011592e8604a0423</url>
  <title>Kate awaits, Tony pours scorn on gay marriage</title>
  <content>
FEDERAL Labor MP Kate Ellis has promised to break into her maternity leave and dash back to Canberra if her vote is needed to ensure same-sex marriage is introduced in Australia.
Marriage equality advocates are counting votes in Federal Parliament after a group of Liberal MPs threatened to cross the floor and vote with Labor to ensure the Marriage Act is changed.
Ms Ellis, who gave birth to her second son Charlie two weeks ago, is keeping in contact with Opposition parliamentary business manager Tony Burke in case a vote on same-sex marriage is brought on.
"If my vote is critical to the outcome, I'll make sure I'm in Canberra,'' she said in a statement to The Advertiser.
"I'm in contact with Tony Burke to keep me up to date on developments in the Parliament."
Same sex marriage advocates are hopeful a private members' bill could pass the House of Representatives without Ms Ellis having to vote. The Government has agreed to grant Ms Ellis a "pair" for most major votes.
Foreign Minister and Deputy Liberal Leader Julie Bishop has cut short an overseas trip to ensure she will be present at a Coalition party room meeting on Tuesday where same-sex marriage policy is expected to be debated.
Former prime minister Tony Abbott on Wednesday  in Liberal Party discipline over same-sex marriage.
Mr Abbott criticised backbenchers for threatening to vote for same-sex marriage in Parliament before the issue had been put to the Australian people at a plebiscite.
"That is a real breach of faith with the public,'' Mr Abbott told Sydney radio after he visited the Coopers Brewery in Adelaide.

Coopers have released a statement from senior members in full support of diversity and equality after the uproar over the "keep It Light" campaign. Courtesy: Twitter/@Coopersbrewery

Coopers release statement in support of diversity and equality
"It's obviously a dramatic loss of discipline inside the Government. It's a serious attack on the authority of the leadership.''
The Federal Government has been unable to persuade the Senate to sign-off on a same-sex marriage plebiscite and is considering whether to hold a national postal vote on the issue instead.
A postal vote held without parliamentary approval could be the subject of a court challenge.
Asked repeatedly whether he would hold a postal ballot, Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull simply said he supported a plebiscite.
"I've dealt with the issue. We have a policy, I am for the policy we took to the election. That's our policy - it has not changed,'' Mr Turnbull said.
Liberal MPs Tim Wilson, Trevor Evans, Warren Entsch, Jason Wood and Trent Zimmerman are all pushing for a conscience vote to be held on same-sex marriage.
During his visit to Adelaide on Wednesday, Mr Abbott attacked "green theology" which he said threatened reliable and affordable electricity supplies.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coopersbrewery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FEDERAL Labor MP Kate Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Burke</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Liberal Leader Julie Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coopers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coopers Brewery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foreign Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ellis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
