<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413173131647740</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/health/2017/08/02/18/18/satins-australians-medication-uk-treatment</url>
  <title>Startling amount of people may need cholesterol-lowering drugs, study finds</title>
  <content>
A new Harvard-led investigation into statin guidelines in the UK has revealed that almost all men over 60 and all women over 75 would require medication.
The findings reinforce age as a big driver of risk.
The study also stated "there is limited evidence from clinical trials on statin efficacy among older people and uncertainties remain regarding adverse effects".
The National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) updated guidelines for cardiovascular risk and cholesterol-lowering medication in 2014.
The study's authors note that a recommendation for treatment does not necessarily lead to people taking the tablets.
Compliance is considered a big issue and the Royal Australian College of GP's says more effort needs to be made to ensure those who need statins take it.
"The first question we have to ask ourselves is should we be doing more to address non-compliance," said Dr Guan Yeo, NSW Chair of RACGP.

Related Articles

A recent retrospective study revealed that 28,000 patients who reported side effects led to about one third dropping their treatment within a year.
Muscle symptoms were the most common form of statin intolerance.
Associate Professor David Sullivan from Royal Prince Alfred Hospital says they're investigating the true extent of side-effects that are attributed to the medication.
The study is recruiting dozens of people who can't tolerate the drug to take part.
"It's very difficult with a very commonly taken treatment like statin therapy to know who is having very real side-effects and who is having a flare up of their arthritis or some other problem," Associate Prof David Sullivan said.
"So we're trying to help people with rotations through both real and dummy treatments over periods of time," he said.
He said it's very important for people to be confident in the treatment, especially when they're managing a risk factor that bears no symptoms.
"There's certainly evidence that people who interrupt their prescribed statin treatment do have higher heart attack and death rates," he said.
People who want to take part in the Sydney-based statin study can email .
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor David Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prof David Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Care Excellence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Australian College of GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Guan Yeo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Prince Alfred Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Chair of RACGP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvard-led</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
