<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412739339942374</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:58</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/crime-and-justice/ashleigh-watterson-found-guilt-of-assault-not-guilty-on-two-counts-of-trying-to-smother-baby/news-story/3b47a888c08f3aae8d59fd083e6e713d</url>
  <title>No further jail time for attack on baby</title>
  <content>
A BRISBANE mother who "attacked" her baby by smothering her at her home has escaped further prison time.
Justice Martin Burns said a period of imprisonment may be appropriate for Ashleigh Watterson, 30, of Scarborough, given the seriousness of her crime.
"The question is whether she serves more time," Justice Burns told Watterson's barrister Peter Richards, referring to the fact that she had served 19 days behind bars.
Sarah Jade Watterson died from undetermined causes in March 2012, aged 21 months.
Justice Burns late this afternoon sentenced her to a wholly suspended two-year term for deliberately cutting off her baby's air supply seven years ago.
"This caused your baby considerable distress and interfered with her health and comfort," Justice Burns said.
"You called and ambulance and your baby was conveyed with you to Redcliffe Hospital where she was treated.
"No permanent injury was sustained by your child as a consequence of that act."
She was acquitted of two further charges of attempted murder and one of assault occasioning grievous bodily harm.
Her two-year sentence has been suspended for five years, meaning she must be of good behaviour for that time.
Justice Burns rejected Watterson's defence barristers claim that she attacked baby Sarah because of the "stress or grief" of the death of her baby Lara from SIDS in May 2009.
"Why you attacked your baby is not explained and no attempt is made to explain it by your counsel other than referring to suffering stress or grief in the aftermath of the loss of your second child to SIDS," Justice Burns said
Watterson, who had showed no emotion when the verdict was handed down, stood calmly with her hands clasped in front of her body as Justice Burns sentenced her.
After Watterson's conviction Mr Richards had suggested Watterson be given probation or community service.
Prosecutor Danny Boyle told the court that Watterson's assault of the four-month-old on October 28, 2010, was an "attack on a defenceless victim".
"It is a serious example of as assault causing bodily harm," Mr Boyle told the court.
The sentencing hearing continues.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarborough</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2012</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIDS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Boyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watterson</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Jade Watterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Richards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redcliffe Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Martin Burns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justice Burns</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashleigh Watterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
