<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413048577593769</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/transurban-defends-price-of-tolls-against-growing-gripes-from-motorists-20170802-gxnlzk</url>
  <title>54pc of motorists pay less than $10 a month in tolls: Transurban</title>
  <content>
Australia's , has hit back against growing complaints over hefty tolls, claiming more than half of drivers using its motorways pay less than $10 a month.
The listed tollroad operator has also told a Senate inquiry the proportion of tolled roads in Australia is "significantly lower" than other countries, making up just 0.5 per cent of the motorway network.
The Senate inquiry is looking at the operations of tollways and comes ahead of a looming study by the Turnbull government into the benefits and impact of .
The politically fraught study will lay the groundwork to eventually charge motorists based on when and how far they drive, shifting away from relying on car registration fees and fuel excise to build and maintain roads.

The case for road user charging is becoming more compelling as revenue from fuel excise declines - despite the 2014 reintroduction of biannual tax increases - because cars are becoming more efficient. The trend is expected to accelerate as more electric vehicles take to the streets.

A number of reports have called for the introduction of road user charging, including the Henry tax review, Infrastructure Australia and the Productivity Commission.
With Transurban officials to front the Senate inquiry in Melbourne on Thursday, the company said in its submission it supported the introduction of road user charging as a way of securing a sustainable funding source for roads.
It would also address inequities among motorists, where infrequent drivers' licence and registration fees effectively cross-subsidise heavier road users.
Good value

With the company already operating 13 tollroads in Sydney, Melbourne and Brisbane, Transurban denies they represent poor value, saying the cost of tolls is outweighed by fuel and travel time savings.
According to figures provided to the inquiry, Transurban said 93 per cent of its customer account holders paid less than $100 month in tolls, 68 per cent paid less than $20 a month and 54 per cent less than $10. Just 0.3 per cent spend more than $500 a month on tolls, the majority of them commercial operators.
Transurban said the toll roads collectively added up to 240km out of a national motorway network of 50,000km, or 0.5 per cent. Across Sydney, Melbourne and Brisbane, where toll roads are located, they comprised less than 1 per cent of the motorway network.
By comparison, 3 per cent of the road network in both China and the US was tolled while in Spain 18 per cent of roads attracted a fee.

The company argues that allowing private operators to build tollways frees up government balance sheets to spend money on other infrastructure, including public transport.
"That is attractive to all those taxpayers who would otherwise have to pay their share of the added tax burden needed to build such road networks which they might never use themselves," the submission said.
"Motorists are able to choose whether they use a toll road or bypass it by using alternative non-tolled roads. That decision will be made by motorists depending on what they believe will deliver them the most value in the circumstances surrounding their travel needs from time to time."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain 18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transurban</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Productivity Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
