<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412915433604921</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/national/woman-mauled-to-death-by-dog-in-southern-river-perth/news-story/7831d22bcf415813fa2bb8defc6b2edc</url>
  <title>Woman mauled to death by two dogs</title>
  <content>
A WOMAN has been mauled to death by two dogs in Perth.
Reports suggest the attack happened in Southern River, a residential suburb in the city's southeast.
Police were called to Barko's Boarding Kennels on Terrier Place about 1.30pm local time (3.30pm EST) on Tuesday. The woman is believed to be Sue Lopicich, the owner of the boarding kennels.
St John Ambulance officers arrived not long after the attack but the woman died a short time later as a result of life threatening injuries caused by the dogs.
It is believed the dogs are both male adults, one a Bull Mastiff and the other a Staffordshire Bull Terrier.
Gosnells Council has seized the dog and police are not treating the death as suspicious. A report is being prepared for the coroner.
The City of Gosnells said in a statement its rangers were contacted by police.
"City of Gosnells rangers received a request from the police to attend a licensed kennel in Southern River, to collect a dog which was preventing police from accessing the body of a deceased person on the property," the statement said.
"As a result, the city is currently holding two dogs that were taken from the property. The adult, male dogs, one a Bull Mastiff and the other a Staffordshire Bull Terrier, are being held at the request of police.
"An investigation is being conducted by the police and the city is waiting to hear further from them. The dogs are microchipped and registered to the owner of the property. No previous complaints have been made to the city about these dogs."
A neighbour told the  the dogs had to be tied up when people visited the woman's house because they were aggressive. He said one involved in the attack had been living on the property about four years. Another neighbour told the ABC the woman had a passion for canines, and cared for rescue dogs.
The tragic incident comes just weeks after a Melbourne man was attacked at a beach in Brighton East.
Cam McIntyre said he was lucky to be alive after a dog, believed to be a labrador-rottweiler cross, attacked him and left him with a gash in his neck just millimetres from a major artery. The dog bit his hand and neck and he was treated with 40 stitches.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barko's Boarding Kennel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrier Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gosnells Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Ambulance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Lopicich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bull Mastiff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam McIntyre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern River</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staffordshire Bull Terrier</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Gosnells</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
