<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413602628385589</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-02/apple-ceo-tim-cook-defends-decision-to-remove-vpn-software-from-app-store-in-china/1690736</url>
  <title>Apple CEO Tim Cook defends decision to remove VPN software from App Store in China</title>
  <content>
CEO Tim Cook has defended Apple's decision to remove VPN software from its China App Store, in compliance with the Chinese Government's demands.

Key points:

Apple's revenue in China has fallen for a fifth straight quarter
The company is building a data centre in the Guizhou province
The build is part of a $US1 billion investment by Apple in the area

Mr Cook said Apple believed in "engaging with governments even when we disagree".
"We would obviously rather not remove the apps," he said.
"But like we do in other countries, we follow the law wherever we do business."
VPN apps allow users to access region-restricted websites and bypass internet censorship.

External Link:

Tweet from Star VPN
Users within China are able to get around government-imposed restrictions known as the "Great Firewall" and access the whole internet.
China is tightening regulation of what it sees as its cyberspace, including online media, live streaming and gaming.
Beijing has targeted VPNs in its bid to , a drive that is ramping up ahead of the Communist Party Congress later this year.
To operate a VPN service in the country, companies must now be authorised by the Chinese authorities.
In 2016 the United Nations passed a non-binding declaration that unrestricted access to the internet is a human right that must be protected.
The article states that the UN condemns measures that "intentionally prevent or disrupt access to or dissemination of information online" and that doing so is "in violation of international human rights law".
Countries including China, Russia, South Africa and Saudi Arabia opposed the resolution.
'Abide by the law'

Critics said Apple's decision to comply with the Chinese Government contradicts action taken by the company in the United States last year opposing a court order by the FBI.
US investigators wanted to break into an iPhone of a gunman who fatally shot 14 people in the Californian city of San Bernardino.
Mr Cook said that the situations were very different, and the laws in each country were clear.

External Link:

Tweet from Joshua Wong
"In the US case, the law in the US supported us," he said.
"We have to abide by [the law] in both cases. That doesn't mean we don't state our point of view in the appropriate way, we always do that."
Willy Wo-Lap Lam from the Chinese University of Hong Kong said the move was a "commercial and political quid pro quo between Apple and the Chinese Government".
China is a key growth area for Apple, where revenues have stalled - falling for a fifth straight quarter - as sales grew in every other region.
The once coveted iPhone has slipped into fifth position behind offerings from local rivals Huawei, Oppo, Vivo and Xiaomi, analysts said.
"They don't want to be kept out of this lucrative market," Dr Lam said.
"After considering the potential damage to their business if they were to defy Chinese Government relations, I think they've decided to follow regulations, even though there are some critics who think that this is kowtowing to the ego of the Government."
Tightening cyber security

Apple - along with other US tech brands such as Facebook - have looked to cultivate a good relationship with China's leaders to achieve greater access and success within the market.
Apple is building a new data centre in the province of Guizhou to comply with a new cyber security law passed on June 1, which pushed firms to store user data inside China's borders.

External Link:

Tweet Edward Snowden
The build is part of a $US1 billion ($1.25 billion) investment in the area, which has a potential political upside.
Beijing wants to turn Guizhou into a tech hub, while President Xi Jinping himself has close ties to the region, as a delegate for the province at the Communist Party congress.
Dr Lam said the centre was a welcome development for the Chinese Government which is "very keen to acquire top technology from American companies".
But Apple would not be allowed to build the research and development facilities unless they it was "willing to abide by Chinese rules", he said.
Dr Lam said Apple's Chinese customers would rather the company complied with authorities, "otherwise Apple products might be shut out from the Chinese market".
Russian President Vladimir Putin took note of China's tightened restrictions and passed similar legislation late last week.
The law, which will come into effect on November 1, bans the use of VPNs and other technologies that allow people to access the internet anonymously.
ABC/Wires
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Firewall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lam</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saudi Arabia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.25</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China App Store</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese Government</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Xi Jinping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star VPN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xiaomi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese University of Hong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Willy Wo-Lap Lam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VPN</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communist Party Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joshua Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>App Store</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Tim Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEIJING</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward Snowden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guizhou</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC/Wires</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huawei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Bernardino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Cook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communist Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple CEO Tim Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VPNs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple's Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oppo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
