<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413259030995016</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4829146/debut-fuels-mitchells-fire-to-stay-at-bulldogs/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Debut fuels Mitchell's fire to stay at Bulldogs</title>
  <content>
VISION: Kurri Kurri Bulldogs prop Jordy Mitchell at Wests Mayfield on Wednesday helping to promote this year's second "futures round", which gives Newcastle under-19 players a chance to trial with the Knights. Picture: Josh Callinan

Jordy Mitchell has only been in the top grade for a month but he's already looking forward to next season at the Kurri Kurri Bulldogs.

The 19-year-old Greta-based prop reckons the tri-colours can continue to improve in 2018 if they can manage to keep their young squad together.

Mitchell and fellow bench forward Reid Alchin, both still eligible for under 19s, have been promoted to the main Newcastle Rugby League competition in recent times along with the likes of lock Jake Moore, centre Brock Hollis and substitute Jack Riddett, who debuted on the weekend against Souths.  

"We've got a really young side up against teams with a lot of experienced players and we've been able to stick it to them," Mitchell said. 

"We've only just missed out a few times, but that's footy at the end of the day.

"Next year hopefully we can all stick together and prove everyone wrong with the side we've got, in terms of everyone being so young. 
"That's the plan with everyone, each of us have talked about it and we don't really want to go anywhere. Hopefully even a premiership or something there soon."
Mitchell, who played juniors at the Greta Branxton Colts and now in his third season at Kurri, was called up to firsts on June 25.

The Bulldogs played away against Central, who they face again at St John Oval on Sunday, and he has now lined up five times in total, including a Coalfields derby with Cessnock and a solitary win over Maitland. 
"I started off the year in under 19s but had a few setbacks with injuries," Mitchell said.

"Then I got asked to make my debut when we played Central last. I've played ever since and I'm loving it. 

"It's an awesome change, heaps faster and much more physical. It's a new challenge every week."
Seventh-placed Kurri must win their last three games to have any chance of making the semi-finals but regardless the former All Saints College student at St Joseph's, Lochinvar, said teaming up with experienced campaigners like Mick Campton, Mitch Cullen and Ben Wyborn was beneficial.

The teenager also remains hopeful coach Ron Griffiths will stay on at the Bulldogs with negotiations underway between the current mentor and the club. 
"I think Ron has a job next year, but it would be good if he does so we can keep the same system going and not keep changing," Mitchell said. "It would be good if everyone out there now stays, to keep the ball rolling."

Mitchell endorsed the upcoming "futures round", which gives selected under-19 players a chance to trial with the Knights.

"Great idea to give local kids a foot in and closer view at the next level," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Riddett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lochinvar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Callinan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Joseph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brock Hollis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ron Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Wyborn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greta Branxton Colts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greta-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reid Alchin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Campton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Cullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Saints College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurri Kurri Bulldogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knight</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Mayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordy Mitchell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessnock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
