<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413735772374843</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/law-order/son-of-late-bra-boys-surf-gangster-cade-dallas-to-inherit-at-least-100000-as-dispute-over-his-claimed-30-million-estate-is-settled/news-story/f15390726e49fd63050c4c01544fe001</url>
  <title>Bitter fight over Bra Boy</title>
  <content>
THE son of Bra Boy Cade Dallas will inherit more than $100,000 after settling a soap opera-like lawsuit over the surf gangster™s purported $30 million empire.

Keanu Dallas, his mother Veny Amelia and grandmother Kerrie Dallas have opted to end the Supreme Court trial that has publicly exposed the family's deep and bitter divisions.

The high-profile case also involved allegedly fake signatures, "scandalous allegations" and whether the gangster's Balinese clothing empire was actually of any value.

As part of the settlement, Ms Amelia has also promised to never again sue her former mother-in-law.

Cade Dallas was a member of the Bra Boys, a surf-gang based in Maroubra, NSW, that was the subject of a 2007 documentary narrated by Russell Crowe.

The gang and its code - "My Brother's Keeper" - also inspired a 2011 Home and Away storyline, while members were involved in the infamous 2005 Cronulla race riots.

Cade died in Indonesia in 2012, leaving behind a clothing empire - called "Somewhere" - valued at $30 million and a handwritten will signed with a smiley face.

Ms Amelia moved to Adelaide and sued a year later, claiming Mrs Dallas had told her "the business is mine" and ran it to fund a "lavish" lifestyle while denying Keanu's inheritance.

"I'm not a greedy person like Kerrie ... it's not about the money, I'm not here for money," she said at trial.

"I would like to claim my son's right."

Mrs Dallas, however, asserted "Somewhere" was insolvent and dubbed Ms Amelia's claims "scandalous allegations" without "a skerrick of material" to support them.

Court records, released to The Advertiser, show the parties reached a settlement on Monday, bringing the trial to an end with each side bearing its own legal costs.

Under its terms, Ms Amelia agrees to release Mrs Dallas "from all claims, suits, demands or proceedings" and never again seek to sue her.

In turn, Mrs Dallas will transfer all funds held in trust for Keanu, in Indonesian banks, to the boy, along with an additional $100,000.

She and Ms Amelia have further agreed to release each other from any remaining legal action in the Indonesian courts.

Because of the settlement, the court was not required to make rulings about the value, ownership or future viability of "Somewhere".

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cade Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Amelia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keanu</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bra Boy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brother's Keeper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroubra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bra Boy Cade Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerrie Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Veny Amelia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Crowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CADE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keanu Dallas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Dallas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cronulla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
