<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413795901918009</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:04</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>https://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/glittery-iphone-cases-recalled-after-dozens-burned-by-mystery-liquid/</url>
  <title>Glittery iPhone Cases Recalled After Dozens Burned By Mystery Liquid</title>
  <content>
All that glitters is recalled.

Image: US Consumer Product Safety Commission / Gizmodo

MixBin Electronics just  that contained liquid and glitter because they were burning users. A  noted that there have been 24 reports around the world, including 19 in the US, of skin irritation or chemical burns.

"One consumer reported permanent scarring from a chemical burn and another consumer reported chemical burns and swelling to her leg, face, neck, chest, upper body and hands," the report states.

There have been about 263,000 of these cases sold in the US as well as 11,400 in Canada and 400 in Mexico. They were sold by major retailers including Amazon, Henri Bendel, MixBin, Nordstrom Rack, Tory Burch and Victoria's Secret.

"In the United Kingdom, the distributor has received four reports of chemical burns, itching, redness and blisters due to the leakage of the liquid material contained in the liquid glitter phone case," . The ACCC has not announced a recall in Australia, however it might be a good idea to check if that a glittery phone case you got from overseas falls under the recall.

As for what in the hell this "liquid material" is made of, we have reached out to MixBin for comment. According to the Amazon page of  (which is no longer for sale), the fluid is "safe food grade snow globe liquid".

So if you caught yourself daydreaming over a shimmering iPhone case with the Victoria's Secret logo emblazoned on it, think again. It may ooze out and burn your beautiful face. Also, come on. These cases are so fugly.

[]

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nordstrom Rack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone Cases Recalled After Dozens Burned By Mystery Liquid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MixBin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MixBin Electronics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henri Bendel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Secret</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United Kingdom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gizmodo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Consumer Product Safety Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tory Burch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
