<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412571836214668</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/afl/afl-news/geelong-cats-jed-bews-ready-for-another-crack-at-the-sydney-swans-20170802-gxnsjx.html</url>
  <title>Bews ready for another crack at the Swans</title>
  <content>
Geelong defender Jed Bews was considered only a small part of the Cats side that was beaten by Sydney in last year's preliminary final, but that didn't shield the youngster from the burning disappointment of seeing the side's grand final aspirations swept away in under 30 minutes of football.
For the first time since that night in September last year, Geelong have the chance to settle the score of that defeat, when they meet the Swans at home on Friday.Photo: Joe Armao
Bews was philosophical about the absence of suspended star Patrick Dangerfield for Friday's clash.
"It's a chance for someone else to stand up and get a place in the side and make a significant difference to us winning. 'Danger' himself will put the coach's hat on and it will be another set of eyes to oversee our performance. At half-time he'll be the first one in the rooms to talk to the mids (midfielders)," he said.
Last year's September loss to the Swans was Bews' first AFL final, and while he'd only had limited exposure in the strong Geelong outfit, he could feel older and more experienced players rallying in belief that another flag was heading down the highway.
"It's still burning inside. It was my first final and I won't forget it because the game was lost in just one terrible quarter. It affected us all, naturally. We reviewed the game a few days afterwards and then we put it away and it was part of history," Bews said.

Bews, now 23, also remembers how overwhelmed he was when he sat in a Geelong coffee shop six years ago, watching the heavy hitters of the Geelong Football Club file in with the news that he was to be taken on as a father-son.
Bews, the son of former Geelong great Andrew, privately struggled to contain his excitement as Neil Balme and recruiting guru Stephen Wells outlined the coming years for the youngster.
"I was 17, just going on 18, and I knew I'd put my first foot on the ladder by being taken as a father-son. Actually back then I could have gone for father-son in Brisbane as well, but those rules have changed now and I don't think I would have looked anywhere else.
"When I looked at playing in the backline for the Cats it was a challenging thought.
"I had to get over the likes of [Matthew] Scarlett, [Andrew] Mackie, [Harry] Taylor and the list just goes on. But I was on the list and it was up to me to just keep working on it," he said.
After working hard in his first 18 months, with the lingering thought that he could well be cut at any time, he was rewarded with a new contract..
The speedy backman appears to have cemented a position in a side that is in contention for grand final success. And with that surety has come confidence, an ingredient that has bolstered Bews' game.
"I've come a long way. It's not the end of the world when you make a mistake. That was something I had to get over. We will make mistakes at certain times but we are only trying to do our best.
"And I get confidence in other areas. When you're in the back line you see everything set up in front of you. So I've learned to speak up, call out to this one or the other, and the beauty of this team is that we're there for each other," he said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Armao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Wells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bews</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mackie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Balme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scarlett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jed Bews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
