<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412829534257354</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/uq-alert-as-student-tests-positive-for-meningococcal-20170802-gxo1l5.html</url>
  <title>UQ alert as student tests positive for meningococcal</title>
  <content>
A student at a residential college of the University of Queensland has tested positive for meningococcal disease.
Other students who had been in close contact with the 18-year-old girl were given antibiotics, a Metro North Public Health Unit spokeswoman said.Photo: Jane Dyson
"At this stage no meningococcal vaccinations will be required amongst the close contacts," the spokeswoman said.
So far this year, there have been 37 cases of meningococcal disease, compared with 21 in the same period in 2016.
Meningococcal disease is "severe but uncommon", and is spread by meningococcal bacteria entering the nose or throat.
The bacteria is carried by about 10 per cent of the population in their nose or throat and they remain well, but they are able to spread the bacteria to other people who may become sick.

The Metro North spokesman said it was "not easy" to catch the disease.
"Those in close contact with a person with meningococcal disease have an increased, although still low chance of developing the infection," she said.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The spokesperson said it was likely this case was isolated and there was a low chace of the disease spreading through the community.
However people should still watch out for symptoms, and seek medical assistance if they believe they have the disease.
Typical symptoms include vomiting, fever, headache, a stiff neck, drowsiness, a dislike of bright lights, joint pain, and a red-purple coloured spotty rash.
Vaccination against the meningococcal A, C, W and Y strains is free for all year 10 students in Queensland through the school immunisation program, and for all young people aged 15 to 19 through their GP until May 2018.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro North Public Health Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jane Dyson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
