<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413263325962402</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/victoria/carnegie-crash-dashcam-footage-captures-moment-two-cars-collide/news-story/bd1c797bd17b39adada75394432dda41</url>
  <title>Carnegie crash: Dashcam footage captures moment two cars collide</title>
  <content>
Carnegie car crash splits opinion
0:20

Dashcam footage divides motorists.

August 2nd 2017
2 hours ago
/display/heraldsun.com.au/Web/Leader/All local news and photos/

Bianca CarmonaCaulfield Glen Eira Leader

Share

A DRAMATIC car crash in Carnegie caught on dashcam has divided motorists over who was to blame.
The footage, posted on the Dash Cam Owners Australia Facebook page, shows a black car being hit as that car's driver attempted to change lanes after overtaking on the left through an intersection on Koornang Rd.

The driver of the car with the dashcam posted the footage with a message: "I am not sure whether I did the right thing, just let people judge."
HAVE YOUR SAY: Who do you think was at fault? Tell us below.
And judge they did, with more than 3300 comments and almost 260,000 views.
Viewer Adam Krustofski blamed the dashcam driver: "There was legit no reason this person couldn't have slowed down or braked to allow the car to merge.
"I would hate to think if the driver had a child or baby in the car and this person caused serious injury just to prove a point and protect their ego."
Scott Thomson agreed: "The two lanes become one without dotted line, so whoever is in front has right of way."
But Jason King disagreed, saying the merging car was in the wrong.

"They crossed a solid white line to try to merge, but a portion of the blame will be attributed to the cam car as they failed to act to avoid an accident."
Dan Goode also blamed the merging car.
"People darting down the left and expecting to be let in," he wrote.
"I don't care if you are the Prime Minister or the Pope, dotted lines mean you have to give way to the lane you are trying to merge into."
Tong Ly had an interesting take on the matter: "Only go left lane if you plan on smoking the car behind you."
There was some sensible advice from Matt Tucker, who wrote: "It's everyone's responsibility to avoid a crash where possible no matter what the other driver has done."
"Anyone that doesn't understand this should not be on the road."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Krustofski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koornang Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dash Cam Owners Australia Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tong Ly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Goode</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pope</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/Leader/All</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bianca CarmonaCaulfield Glen Eira Leader</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carnegie</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Tucker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
