<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412524591573301</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/entertainment/music/triple-js-new-move-that-could-potentially-move-the-hottest-100-countdown-from-australia-day/news-story/4f60ec199fec4bb89e0b13d788d937d2</url>
  <title>This could change Triple J</title>
  <content>
From 1990 to 2016: Triple J's Hottest 100 winners

TRIPLE J is polling listeners about potentially moving the Hottest 100 countdown from January 26.

The radio station has faced a growing backlash from listeners who see Australia Day as 'invasion day' and would like the iconic countdown to move to a more inclusive and less controversial date.

follows the station spending the past 10 months "consulting with a range of people, musicians, community leaders and representative groups on their opinions of Australia Day and the implications of holding the Hottest 100 on that day."

The poll - which is open for another week - asks listeners specific questions about a potential date change for the Hottest 100.

Options in the poll ask for reactions (from strongly agree to strongly disagree) on questions including "I'm just there for the tunes and the party and I don't care what day it's on" to "I wouldn't feel comfortable if the Hottest 100 remained on Australia Day" to "I don't really understand the issue about what day it's on and I don't want the date of the Hottest 100 to change."

The poll includes links to articles to educate those who may not realise why the date is divisive.

The Hottest 100 is the biggest music poll in the world and has spawned lucrative compilation albums.

However the station has felt increasing pressure to move the date - despite it becoming a national tradition to be held in summer on a holiday and the soundtrack to parties and barbecues.

This year indigenous act AB Original's January 26 (featuring Dan Sultan) charted at No. 16 on the Hottest 100.

The station said they will "make an announcement in the coming months" about when next year's Hottest 100 will air.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hottest 100</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple J's Hottest 100</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Sultan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple J</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AB Original's January 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
