<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412868188963717</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:28</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/amazon-effect-extends-to-qubes-moorebank-freight-hub-citigroup-20170802-gxnmav</url>
  <title>Amazon effect extends to Qube's Moorebank freight hub: Citigroup </title>
  <content>
Amazon's entry into the Australian market will make Qube's Moorebank freight hub attractive to retailers and manufacturers because they will be under more pressure to slash costs, Citigroup has forecast.
"Amazon will make retailers think about taking costs out," Citigroup transport and infrastructure analyst Anthony Moulder told a briefing in Sydney. "The attractiveness of Moorebank is a function of Amazon coming."
The US retail giant is expected have  by encouraging more consumers to shop online, where margins are thinner.
Qube is one of Citigroup's top three investment picks in the transport and infrastructure sector, along with Qantas and Transurban, amid expectations that the logistics group's long term earnings will be boosted by retailers establishing warehouses at the Moorebank hub in southwestern Sydney.

Moorebank will be the largest intermodal terminal in Australia when it starts operating in 2018, and will have up to 850,000 square metres of warehouse space, some of which will be automated, and a rail link to Port Botany.

​Qube has been having talks with major retailers interested in moving to Moorebank and provided tours of the site, and is expected to announce some new tenants in the next few months.
The logistics group is likely to offer competitive prices to entice retailers to move from western Sydney - where many lease warehouses - to Moorebank, which is much closer to Port Botany, Mr Moulder said.  
While some retailers, like Woolworths, may have "contractual constraints" in exiting existing warehouse leases before they expire, they may be able to negotiate with landlords to move to Moorebank, he said.
Qube will discuss its progress on Moorebank at its annual results on August 23.

Separately, Citigroup has been analysing the impact of the NSW government's upcoming sale of Sydney motorway WestConnex on Transurban, which is expected to be one of several bidders for the $16.8 billion tollroad.
The NSW government has not yet revealed how it plans to structure the sale, but awarding most or all of WestConnex could raise concerns among politicians about creating a monopoly for Transurban on the east coast, Mr Moulder said. 
While a Transurban monopoly could benefit the NSW government by enabling it to deal with only one operator on tollroad concessions - making it easier to change existing agreements to allow for more flexible time-of-day toll fares or weekly toll fare caps - the government may also be eager to bring competition into the market, he said.
Foreign tollroad operators like Ferrovial's Cintra and Spain's Abertis - which has received a €16.3 billion ($24.2 billion)  - are also expected to be keen bidders for WestConnex so they can enter the Australian market.

But even if Transurban loses WestConnex initially, it could end up becoming the eventual owner if foreign operators overpay for the tollroad and it does not generate as much traffic as expected.
"If someone bids a crazy price for WestConnex, [Transurban] will sit there and wait for three years and buy it from debt holders at 50¢ in the dollar," Mr Moulder said.
Transurban has already bought several other failed Australian tollroads, including Sydney's Lane Cove Tunnel and Cross City Tunnel.
The WestConnex motorway is controversial and opposed by several Sydney councils, which have complained about the road's disruption to communities, its lack of integration with public transport and the high cost of forecast toll fares.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Citigroup</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Botany</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney's Lane Cove Tunnel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qube</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qube's Moorebank</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Moulder</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transurban</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woolworths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cross City Tunnel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Moulder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain's Abertis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ferrovial's Cintra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moorebank</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WestConnex</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
