<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413044282626329</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/18/45/sons-of-murdered-mum-maria-james-want-priests-body-exhumed-as-cold-case-evidence-bungle-revealed</url>
  <title>Sons of murdered mum Maria James want priest</title>
  <content>
The sons of a woman brutally stabbed to death in Melbourne's north in 1980 have called for the exhumation of a Catholic priest's body for DNA testing as an evidence bungle comes to light.
Victoria Police have admitted an exhibit from the murder scene of Maria James - one that had been used to eliminate suspects - was in fact from another case.
A Current Affair can also reveal the quilt cover police took from Mrs James' home as an exhibit in the investigation, is now missing.
Nearly 40 years ago, the mother of two was stabbed 68 times while on the phone to her ex-husband, in the Thornbury bookstore that was her home and workplace.
Her ex-husband, John James, grew concerned after claiming to hear screaming over the phone, and went to the store to investigate.
Finding the front door locked, he entered by the back and discovered Ms James's body.
He then saw the front door was open - the killer having made their escape as Mr James moved towards the back door.

Related Articles

Police believe the killer may have run out into traffic.
A facial composite was constructed of a man almost run over outside Maria's shop, who was then seen in another street nearby.
He has never been identified, but police are sure Ms James knew her killer.
Her two sons suspect the former local priest, the late Father Anthony Bongiorno.
The eldest brother, Mark, said that before the murder his brother had claimed he had been sexually assaulted by Fr Bongiorno, prompting his mother to plan a confrontation.
A new witness has also claimed to have seen Fr Bongiorno "covered in blood" nearby in the moments after the murder, Mark James said.
However, the priest was initially cleared by police, who said DNA tested from a pillow slip taken from the murder scene ruled him out.
Now, with the police admitting to an evidence mix-up, Ms James's sons are pushing for a renewed focus, including a new coronial investigation.
"I would like (Fr Bongiorno's) body exhumed and tested against DNA samples of the crime scene," Mr James said.
"We have Fr Bongiorno, a witness clearly putting him outside the bookshop just before the murder, we have another witness talking about him being covered in blood, we have my mother finding out that my brother had been sexually assaulted by Bongiorno, telling my brother that she was going to confront the church.
"All of a sudden, mum's dead. What more do you need?"
Victoria Police has said it will likely not need to exhume Fr Bongiorno's body, but it is currently re-visiting the examination of all exhibits involved in the case.
A Current Affair understands the original pillow case that should have been tested for DNA remains in police possession.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thornbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fr Bongiorno</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. James</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bongiorno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Father Anthony Bongiorno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms James</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maria James</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Current Affair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
