<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413482369298668</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/damaso-lopez-serrano-shares-wealthy-lifestyle-on-instagram-before-arrest/news-story/29d3e4c31a4170da9e5bf664c7e132b7</url>
  <title>Rich thug of Instagram's luxurious lifestyle</title>
  <content>
A RICH thug of Instagram turned himself into police after posting a number of photos on social media showing off his luxurious lifestyle.
Damaso Lopez Serrano, the godson of Mexican drug boss El Chapo, posted pictures of flashy guns, wads of cash and even a pet tiger on Instagram.
Serrano, the son of drug kingpin Damaso Lopez Nunez, bragged about his wealthy lifestyle, paid presumably with money earned from drugs, before being arrested last week.
The US authorities have not released further information about his crime.
According to , Serrano handed himself in to the US Drug Enforcement Administration at the border of Calexico, a city in Imperial County in California, and Mexicali, a city in Mexico.
"What we know is that he handed himself over yesterday (Wednesday July 25)," an unidentified official told Reuters.
EFE news agency reported Mexicali authorities had been hunting Serrano in the days before he was supposed to cross the border.
Serrano's father, known as El Chapo's right-hand man, was arrested in May and the  reported he had been in the middle of a turf battle for the control of the Sinaloa cartel, an international drug trafficking, money laundering and organised crime syndicate.
It has been described as the most powerful drug trafficking organisation in the world.
Reuters reported the US Attorney General said the group distributed nearly 200 tonnes of cocaine and mass amounts of heroin between 1990 and 2008.
Serrano, known as "Mini Lic", is believed to be the leader of the group "Los Antrax".
reports Los Antrax was allegedly battling the Chapitos, which means the children of El Chapo.
Pictures of Serrano's glamorous life show a man sniffing white powder and gold-plated guns. Splashed on social media are also pictures of sports cars and people carrying weapons.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Imperial County</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sinaloa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Drug Enforcement Administration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Antrax</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday July 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Attorney General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>El Chapo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damaso Lopez Serrano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serrano</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Efe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mini Lic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reuters</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chapitos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexicali</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damaso Lopez Nunez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
