<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413177426615096</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/belnorth-explores-legal-action-after-canberra-soccer-jersey-clash-with-gungahlin-united-20170802-gxnqk3.html</url>
  <title>Legal threat as Canberra soccer clubs Belnorth and Gungahlin United battle over colour of jerseys</title>
  <content>
Canberra soccer club Belnorth is considering legal action over a clash of colours with Gungahlin United, issuing a cease and desist letter which could see the matter land in court.
Belnorth has asked Gungahlin to agree to engage an independent mediator about changing colours after talks broke down between the clubs and Capital Football, the game's governing body in Canberra.Photo: Rohan Thomson
Belnorth, which represents Belconnen suburbs from Kaleen to Charnwood and has a player base in some parts of Gungahlin, wants to protect a 43-year history of wearing yellow and royal blue in junior and senior competitions.
Gungahlin changed its colours from black and white to gold at the end of last year in a bid to unite teams from all divisions when the club was on its knees financially.

Capital Football confirmed the clubs were involved in mediation, but were not able to reach a resolution and the matter has been passed on to the FFA, Australia's peak body.

But Belnorth has asked Gungahlin to respond to an independent mediator request by Sunday. Belnorth has threatened legal action if Gungahlin does not respond.

Belnorth says sponsors have threatened to withdraw $6000 of financial support because of the colour clash and one prospective sponsor will not commit if the clash continues.
Capital Football has asked to see documentation, but Belnorth is reluctant to hand over details given previous interactions with officials and instead want to engage an independent party.
Belnorth has kept records of dealings with Capital Football to document a timeline of almost 12 months, while Gungahlin is not keen to use an independent party because of the cost.

Gungahlin United's new strip. Photo: Sitthixay Ditthavong

Belnorth president Nick Blair wanted the matter resolved as soon as possible after first notifying Capital Football of the clash last year.
"It's been a source of frustration for us ... Gungahlin has made a decision to wear a similar colour shirt and that has caused issues when we play them," Blair said.
"From a branding exercise, the gold colour has a strong association with Belnorth. Having Gungahlin, the club next to us, in the same shirt causes a lot of issues in terms of sponsorship as well because of dilution in the brand.
"We got our shirt approved by Capital Football last year and went through the process. We alerted Capital Football to it last year and it's been dragging on and on through no fault of our own.
"We've had some potential sponsors say they weren't going to take up a deal because the colour is associated with Belnorth and they didn't want their brand to get mixed up with Gungahlin."
It was proposed the teams would wear alternating strips for away games, but Belnorth said it would cost the club $7000 to purchase new strips for away games against Gungahlin.
Belnorth has more than 1200 players and says it will take a combined financial hit of more than $25,000 through lost sponsorship opportunities and the cost of new playing shirts.
Gungahlin president Aaron Alexander said the club did not want to waste money on legal proceedings or independent mediators, instead preferring for Capital Football to handle the matter.
Gungahlin, which has more than 200 teams and 2000 players, received a cease and desist notice to stop wearing a gold jersey and did so during mediation.
However, they reverted back gold when Capital Football did not reach a final decision last month.

Gungahlin in white and black last year. Photo: Jay Cronan

Alexander said on-field colour clashes were decided by the referee and there had been minimal disruption this season.

"It frustrates me very much. It's disappointing and sad to see community players affected by something of this nature," Alexander said.
"We wanted to change the culture of the club at the end of last year when we had some trouble, so we decided to unify the club by changing the strip.
"Under regulation 3.7 of the rules, we followed our strip change. We have to be on the defence at this point in time.
"Kids don't care what they're wearing. They could be wearing their pyjamas, they just want to play football."
Capital Football declined to comment, but said in a statement: "Capital Football has engaged in mediation with both clubs in regards to the playing strip topic.
"We requested Belnorth to submit documents substantiating their claim however no documentation has been received, and as a result the matter has been referred to FFA and a response is awaited."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capital Football</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin United</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jay Cronan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Alexander</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belnorth</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kaleen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charnwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gungahlin</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexander</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sitthixay Ditthavong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rohan Thomson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belconnen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
