<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412958383278637</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/tassal-gets-federal-approval-for-okehampton-bay-fish-farm/8768330</url>
  <title>Salmon producer Tassal gets federal approval for Okehampton Bay fish farm</title>
  <content>
A controversial fish farm on Tasmania's east coast has been given federal approval to start operating, drawing the ire of conservationists and some politicians.
Salmon will start going into the water at Okehampton Bay this month after aquaculture giant Tassal was given the final green light by the Commonwealth under its Environment Protection and Biodiversity Conservation (EPBC) Act.
Environmentalists have argued the company's plans .
But the Federal Environment Department has cleared the farm to operate, as long as it follows certain measures.
Barbara McGregor from Tassal said the requirements were similar to those expected at its other sites.
"It's around ensuring when it comes to animals, such as whales, that we are well equipped to know if they're in the area, well in advance," she said.
"So sonar detection, making sure that we're conscious with noise levels, which we are across all of our operations."
'Environment laws are broken'

Laura Kelly from Environment Tasmania said the salmon farm would threaten ideal calving habitat for the endangered southern right whale.
"This decision shows that our environment laws are broken," she said.
"Any Tasmanian that wants their children to grow up in a world where there are whales should be dismayed by this decision."
Ms McGregor rejected the claim the bay was a breeding ground for whales.
"The Australian Government came out last week and it aligned with our research that showed Okehampton Bay is not a breeding ground for whale calves," she said.
Environment Tasmania said it would be going through the EPBC approval with its lawyers.
'Community needs confidence in salmon industry'

The  and divided the community.
Greens senator Peter Whish-Wilson said he was "bitterly disappointed" by the federal approval.
"Given the mess that the Hodgman Government has created in regulating Macquarie Harbour, why would anyone trust them to get it right in pristine coastal areas like east coast Tasmania?" he said.
"Tasmanians don't want our beautiful marine environment to be surrounded by rings of industrial fish farms, and they don't want big companies calling the shots in our parliaments."
Independent MP Andrew Wilkie also raised concerns.
"The Tasmanian salmon industry has enormous potential but the community needs to have confidence that it is genuinely sustainable," he said.
"Clearly allowing expansion into Okehampton Bay does not give the community this confidence."
But the Tasmanian Government welcomed the decision, saying it was great news for jobs in regional Tasmania.
"This is the highest environmental tick in the land and further supports the earlier recommendation by the independent Marine Farm Planning Review Panel that current environmental science supports fin fish farming at Okehampton Bay," Minister for Primary Industries and Water Jeremy Rockliff said.
Tassal said 17 locals were ready to begin work at the farm, the majority of which had been unemployed or having to live away for work.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodgman Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine Farm Planning Review Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biodiversity Conservation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barbara McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Andrew Wilkie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okehampton Bay</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPBC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Jeremy Rockliff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Environment Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassal</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Whish-Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Primary Industries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
