<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412657735562164</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/design-contest-to-be-held-for-new-brisbane-fountains-20170802-gxnt9x.html</url>
  <title>Design contest to be held for new Brisbane fountains</title>
  <content>
About eight years after a water fountain was removed from King George square, millions of dollars will be spent bringing it back. 
Lord Mayor Graham Quirk said ratepayers would invest $6.6 million to bring two new water features to Brisbane after fountains were turned off or removed during drought.Photo: Supplied - Brisbane City Council
The money has been allocated for two fountains - one in King George Square and the other in the Brisbane River.
In 2015, the council brought three fountains that were decommissioned during the drought back to life including one at E.E McCormack Place, Emma Miller Place and the Mooney Memorial Fountain. 

Cr Quirk said if another wave of drought hit Brisbane the new water features would not be affected. 
"The difference with the fountains we are constructing now versus the fountains when they were originally in place is that the water is being recycled, so this is a key factor," he said.

"Design is obviously a key component of this competition. The sustainability of those fountains is an important feature."

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The council is calling for world-class designers to put forward their best idea for a new water feature.
"[Council is] calling on people to express interest between now and the end of August towards the design, the constructability, the affordability, maintenance and style of those particular fountains and each entry can put up to two proposals forward for each of those fountains," Cr Quirk said.Photo: Supplied - Brisbane City Council
"We want entrants to think outside the box to work within the parameters of each location, while creating something impressive that will be a feature of our city for years to come.
"Designers are being asked to develop concepts for three possible locations in King George Square and two location in the Brisbane River, that reflect the unique city landmarks."Photo: Photographer Unknown
Cr Quirk said there was nothing stopping an "everyday resident" making an entry, but they should team up with engineers to work on their design.
Opposition leader Peter Cumming said the water features were an example of council wasting money.
"They're spending money on things that perhaps aren't necessary," Cr Cumming said.
"I think there's more important things. With all this industrial disputes going on the Lord Mayor should be solving industrial disputes and sorting out the contact with TechnologyOne rather than expensive options of things that aren't really necessary."
Of the $6.6 million in the budget for the two projects, $1.1 million is allocated for King George Square, $3.3 million for the fountain in the Brisbane River and $2.2 million for the overheads and design engineering across both projects.
The Brisbane River fountain will be named after Brisbane artists Daphne Mayo. 
Expressions of interest for the design competition are now open and can be submitted via the
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane City Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TechnologyOne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Miller Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daphne Mayo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane River</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooney Memorial Fountain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Quirk</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lord Mayor Graham Quirk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King George Square</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photographer Unknown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Cumming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>E.E McCormack Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Cumming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
