<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412958383278625</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>08:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4829203/njc-keen-not-to-waste-opportunity/?cs=305</url>
  <title>NJC keen not to waste opportunity</title>
  <content>
NEWCASTLE Jockey Club is exploring the possibility of building an onsite treated wastewater storage facility to provide irrigation to their Broadmeadow tracks and surrounding areas.

DRAINING RESOURCES: Newcastle Jockey Club chairman Geoff Barnett and CEO Matt Benson check out the renovated course proper during construction in May. The club will budget for $200,000 in water costs this financial year, which is four times more than for the former surface. Picture: Jonathan Carroll
The NJC is expected to post a substantial loss from the last financial year as the cost of maintaining its $11.2 million state-of-the-art course proper bites hard.
NJC chief Matt Benson said the StrathAyr main course, which opened in March, and the Beaumont track would cost at least $250,000 a year more to maintain than the former surfaces. 
Benson said that in summer the tracks "can use two megalitres of water a day".
"Dealing with this track is a steep learning curve," Benson said. "It's employing technology which is largely new to NSW racing and we are trying to manage three to four feet of sand.

"While it drains very well when you get rain, it's also exceptionally thirsty and hungry, so when we go through dry spells like we did over summer and at the moment, it takes a lot of water to maintain moisture through the different levels.
"We have water in our dam at the moment but over summer when every local bore user wants their piece, that dam, which is connected to the aquifer, goes down and we have to use a significant amount of mains water."
In response, Benson has started talks with Hunter Water about a potential connection from the track to nearby Burwood Beach Wastewater Treatment Works. The facility daily treats about 48 megalitres of effluent, which is then pumped into the ocean. 

Benson's vision is to put that wastewater to better use on the tracks and at nearby parks and gardens from a dam at the racecourse. He said early discussions with Hunter Water were positive.
"We want to work through whether it is feasible to bring back treated water from Burwood and use that on the tracks," he said. "The intention is for it to be treated to the degree that it would be palatable to put on the tracks and what the NJC would look very favourably at is potentially allocating unused land in the centre of the track to develop a storage site."

He was unable to state the NJC's losses for 2016-17 because the club is awaiting distribution figures from Racing NSW. However, he said it would be inflated by more than $400,000 in one-off costs associated with the track renovations. They included new fencing, rails, security gates, track equipment and two stewards' towers.
"Whatever the quantum is as far as a deficit last year, it will be made up in this year's budget and we're absolutely confident a lot of the one-off costs will be effectively paid off this year," he said.
He said cutbacks, including job losses, were part of a necessary restructure.

"We have had to change our focus because all of a sudden we have a track that will consistently cost us at least $250,000 a year more to maintain, and probably more depending on what nature throws up," he said. "There had to be hard calls about the balance of the business and that echos through hospitality, marketing, finance and track management."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Water</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NJC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Matt Benson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Racing NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Barnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Benson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burwood Beach Wastewater Treatment Works</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>StrathAyr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaumont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NEWCASTLE Jockey Club</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
