<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413516729037741</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>10:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-02/indigenous-suicide-inquest-turns-into-remote-community-argument/8768628</url>
  <title>Indigenous youth suicide inquest turns into remote community argument</title>
  <content>
An inquest into the suicides of 13 Indigenous young people in WA's far north Kimberley region has turned into an argument over whether people in remote communities should expect to receive government services.
On the first day of hearings in the central Kimberley town of Fitzroy Crossing, State Government solicitor Caroline Thatcher questioned senior community leader Emily Carter about why people should expect the same level of services if they chose to live in bush communities.
"As citizens of this country they should be able to get the same services as people who live in the city or in Broome, " Ms Carter responded.

If you need help:

When Ms Thatcher asked if that was reasonable for those who chose to live remotely, where there were very few economic opportunities, Ms Carter said "you're trying to take me down a path here that is not mine".
"It's not just about jobs, it's about spiritual wellbeing, and about living on country. So it's that social and emotional wellbeing, our inner spirit, so that's why people go there," Ms Carter said.
The exchange came during a lengthy questioning of Ms Carter, who is the chief executive officer of the Marninwarntikura Women's Resource Centre.
The discussion focused on broader social issues facing Kimberley communities, rather than the details of why each of the young people took their lives.
'People are living in trauma'

WA coroner Ros Fogliani is examining the suicides of 13 young people, five of them children aged under 13 in one .
The hearings, which are taking place in five separate WA cities and towns, are expected to take three months.
Some clear common threads have emerged - all the young people chose the same method to end their lives, most suffered medical issues and "failed to thrive" as babies, and most were exposed to alcoholism and domestic violence at home.

Ms Carter outlined the challenges facing the Fitzroy Crossing community - sly groggers illegally selling alcohol, stop-start funding for successful local programs, a shortage of housing and culturally inappropriate health services.
At one point she became tearful, explaining she had only realised upon arriving at the courthouse that the death of a close relative was among those being examined in the wide-scale inquest.
"People are living in trauma. What we're seeing is intergenerational trauma that's been passed on ... and the alcohol, the drugs, the domestic violence, they're all symptoms," she told the court.
"We are at the moment working in crisis ... we have to get a point where we are not working reactively, but looking to the long-term."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily Carter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marninwarntikura Women's Resource Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Thatcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ros Fogliani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzroy Crossing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Carter</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Thatcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
