<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413649873026941</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>11:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/more-sports/iaaf-world-championships-patrick-tiernan-out-make-impression-on-mo-farah-to-set-tempo-for-aussies/news-story/0b2739edc7a2cef39c605ccf6bce2193</url>
  <title>Tiernan out to set tempo for Aussie medal chase</title>
  <content>
QUEENSLANDER Patrick Tiernan says he is not entirely sure that Mo Farah knows of his emergence in distance running but hopes to make a medal impression on the British great in Saturday's 10,000m final at the world championships.
Tiernan has gone from training on grass on frosty Toowoomba winter's mornings to racing four-time Olympic champion Farah twice this season via a successful four-year athletics scholarship at Philadelphia's Villanova College.
The 22-year-old says he will stand on the start line in London for the 10,000m final (there are no heats) on Saturday morning (Qld time) happy for nothing less than a medal.
In his second race with Farah, Tiernan was just 0.42 sec behind the British winner in their 3000m race at Kingston, Jamaica.
"I'll make sure I'm known at the end of the race,'' Tiernan said from London.
"Our goal ultimately is to feel I've given it everything at the end of the race, I think I definitely have the potential to do well and medal in the 10,000. It doesn't mean I'll do it.
"It's worked out well with it being the first final on the track. I hope I can set a tempo for the Australian team.''
London will be Farah's last world championships and the British star hopes to again win the 5000m-10,000m double, something he achieved at the past two world titles and the past two Olympics.
Tiernan won the prestigious NCAA cross-country title in the US last year while attending Villanova College and is still coached in Philadelphia by Marcus O'Sullivan.
He was in Spain earlier this week training with the distance team of his agent Nic Bideau's Melbourne Track Club.
Australia is not best known for distance runners, although Craig Mottram's quality running which culminated in a bronze medal in the 5000m at the 2005 world championships caught the attention of the young Tiernan.
"My coach from Toowoomba Tom Bradbury had a huge influence on my running and he's one of the main reasons I've kept such a strong drive,'' Tiernan said.
"He was able to pace me very well while I was at St Joseph's College in Toowoomba.
"We had a 400m grass track we'd use and a couple of parks we'd run at for reps (repetitions). We made the most of what we had, but I think not having access to an all-weather track actually worked out in my favour as a young athlete. You can get caught up with going too quick or spiking up.
"Seeing the success Mottram had and guys like Collis Birmingham who is in our group, it helps me to get on with the job.''
Tiernan, who will also compete in his second-string event, the 5000m, later in the meet, clocked a 10,000m personal best 27min 29.81 in California in May. It makes him the ninth-best performed man of the year at the distance.
"We have a lot of potential in Australian distance running in the next few championships,'' he said.
●The world championships will be telecast on Eurosport.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba Tom Bradbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Bideau's Melbourne Track Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcus O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Josephs College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collis Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia's Villanova College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Mottram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Farah</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mottram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mo Farah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eurosport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toowoomba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villanova College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday's 10,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NCAA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QUEENSLANDER Patrick Tiernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tiernan</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philadelphia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
