<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413130181973981</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/02/18/54/divine-heritage-listed-church-up-for-sale-in-sydney</url>
  <title>'Divine' heritage-listed church up for sale in Sydney</title>
  <content>
If the thought of buying property in Sydney drives you to prayer, then this might just be for you.
A gothic church in the heart of Redfern went on sale today, offering a unique opportunity to secure a rare - and perhaps divine - deal.
The Uniting Church Tonga Parish has occupied the corner of Regent and Margaret Streets in Redfern for 145 years - although, in 1872, it  was probably surrounded by very little.
Victorian Gothic in style, it held regular services until only recently.
When the last congregation outgrew it and moved elsewhere, the Uniting Church seized the opportunity to put it up for sale.
The real estate agent selling it, Peter Vines from CBRE Commercial Property, has sold many churches in the past couple of years.
But he describes this one as "a unique piece of architecture and a part of Sydney's history."

Related Articles

While the gems are clear to see - high ceilings, a vast internal space and a remarkable stained glass window - it can best be described as a fixer upper.
With peeling paint, threadbare carpets and odd side rooms, its best days are long past.
That is unlikely to be a hindrance for buyers who can see the potential.
"We're expecting to get bowled over in the rush with the inquiries that will come from something like this, just being so unique," Mr Vines said.
While churches do come up for sale from time to time - and more so in recent years - few come up in such prime locations.
This one is just a level 300 metre walk to busy Redfern station, in an area where residential and commercial development has taken off.
It is heritage listed by the City of Sydney, and any change to its exterior and interior will need to be negotiated.
But specialist heritage architect Hector Abrahams believes it still presents an exciting opportunity.
"Most churches remain churches. Occasionally, like in the inner city here, they turn over into other uses and that's very exciting, especially for one that's so architectural," Mr Abrahams said.
Asked how much imagination it will take to transform the church, he added: "With one that has heritage restrictions such as this, that challenge actually brings out the best in architects and potential buyers."
The last Census showed an increase in the number of Australians who declare themselves as non-religious, with that particularly true in inner city areas of our major capitals.
Including this one, the Uniting Church is expected to sell property worth $80 million in the next 12 months so it can direct its resources to where its congregations and ministries are strongest.
The Redfern Church will most likely become a restaurant, bar or funky offices, although, a home or apartments are also possible.
It's expected to have a sale price above two million dollars.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abraham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redfern Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uniting Church</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBRE Commercial Property</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Vines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uniting Church Tonga Parish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Vines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Streets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redfern</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Gothic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hector Abrahams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
