<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413091527267593</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>09:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/neymar-to-psg-transfer-barcelona-confirms-he-wants-to-leave/news-story/1c2a3c58120f95ad37072068b2d4f6aa</url>
  <title>Barca bombshell: Club confirms Neymar transfer</title>
  <content>
NEYMAR has told Barcelona that he plans to leave the club, with a blockbuster move to Paris Saint-Germain seemingly imminent.
The club said Wednesday that the Brazil striker told his teammates "that he had the intention of leaving the club and seeking his future elsewhere, and the coach has given him permission to leave training."
PSG is rumored to be ready to pay his release clause of 222 million euros ($262 million).
That would dwarf the 105 million euros (then $116 million) that Manchester United paid for France midfielder Paul Pogba last year.

Neymar Jr hasn't trained on Wednesday with the permission of the coach

1/2 PSG going to La Liga offices this afternoon. La Liga say they will NOT accept €220m payment to trigger Neymar release clause

2/2 La Liga: "We will not accept the money for the clause. We have doubts this money is in accordance with UEFA Financial Fair Play rules."

Barcelona said Neymar did not specify where he wants to play next, but the only club speculated to be after him - and one of few which could handle the cost of the transfer - is the Qatari-owned PSG.
Barcelona said Neymar left the training ground 30 minutes after arriving on Wednesday. He had arrived to Spain on Tuesday night after holding publicity events for both his personal brand and Barcelona in China.
With his lightning-quick feet, creative instincts and scoring touch, Neymar helped maintain Barcelona as one of the top clubs in Europe for the past four seasons as he blossomed into a worldwide star.
He teamed up with Lionel Messi and Luis Saurez to make an almost unstoppable attack. Neymar scored 105 goals - some of them true gems - and was a key playmaker for Barcelona as it won a Champions League, two Spanish leagues, three Copa del Reys, one Club World Cup, a UEFA Super Cup and two Spanish Super Cups.

BREAKING:  give Neymar permission to miss training this morning. More on Sky Sports News.

Neymar hasn't trained with Barcelona today. Deal close with PSG but still not yet signed.

Neymar didn't train today + told team mates he's off to PSG. Key players were fed up with situation and wanted him to say it to the group.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Copa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatari-owned PSG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Sports News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Liga</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Saurez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pogba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uefa's Financial Fair Play</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
