<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651412610490921055</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>07:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/competitors-take-on-challenging-avon-descent/news-story/2989ce2186d4953e22b5901566c6f390</url>
  <title>Tough weekend ahead for competitors</title>
  <content>
AS more than 35,000 people have discovered over the past four decades, the Avon Descent is the toughest weekend you can have sitting down.
Starting at 8am on Saturday, 370 competitors will leave Northam for a two-day white water adrenalin-pumping ride down the Avon Valley.
Defending single kayak champion Josh Kippin and second-placed Brendan Rice will contest the race as a duo this year in preparation for the World Championships in South Africa in September.

The pair are favourites for the duo title and their absence in the solo race has left the door open for Matthew Dean to potentially step up to take line honours after finishing third last year.
Matt Even and Nick Gardner will look to go one better than their second place in 2016 in the power craft section.
However, defending champions Michael Prosser and Perrin Franks are not going to give up their hard-earned crown without a fight.
Perennial placegetters Scott Goodbody and Justin Green will need to draw on all their experience and knowledge as Goodbody will only arrive back in Perth the night before the race because of six months of work commitments in Kununurra.
"I have had a very old Avon-style flat-bottomed boat up here (in Kununurra) so I have at least been getting in some practice on the Ord to strengthen my driving arm," he said.
"Normally there is only still water up here in this time of year but the Ord spillway is running over, giving me at least some white water to train in.
"While I have been away, Justin has been sending me videos of the water conditions in the river to study."
The two-day course starts with a 52km stretch from Northam, 100km east of Perth, through Toodyay, with the finish line and overnight campsite at Cobbler Pool, 20km west of the town.
The first big test for competitors, and best spectator point, on Saturday will be at Extracts Weir, 5km east of Toodyay.
It has always challenged the competitors whether to take on the rocky weir wall head-on or port (carry) their craft around.
Those who have been brave enough to try to go over have provided spectacular spills and thrills for spectators, with many of the power boat drivers separated from their craft and landing on the jagged rocks.
In 2016, the weir was modified, with some of the rocks cleared to form a 6m-wide central chute. The aim was to create an easier route down the rapids in low water while encouraging more competitors to take the jump when the river is flooded.
The next major obstacle, especially for the tiring paddlers, will be the treacherous ti trees in the last 6km before Cobbler Pool, snagging paddles and craft in the overhanging branches just when the fatigue of the first day's efforts are setting in.
Sunday's course is 72km long, with competitors tackling the river's major white-water obstacles and challenges including Supershoot, Emu Falls, Championship, Syd's, Walyunga and Bells Rapids - all providing great spectator vantage points.
In the run home, the paddlers face a marathon 30km, flat water arm-burning stretch to Bayswater.
Meanwhile, the power craft will use this section to reach maximum speeds, with the river wide enough for some head-to-head dashes to the fin ish line at Riverside Gardens.
The first competitors are expected at the finish line around mid-morning on Sunday.
The Avon Challenge will also take place on Sunday over the last 15km of the course starting at Middle Swan Reserve and is open to junior paddlers from schools, clubs, and individuals paddling kayaks, Canadian canoes, and surf skis.
The budding future Avon Descent champions will either compete in team relays using all three craft or individually in the ironman event. Juniors and adults will team up in the dragon boat class, adding colour and spectacle to the event.
Follow the Avon Descent at
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perrin Franks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Gardner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Prosser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Dean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kippin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Even</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toodyay</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riverside Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Goodbody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodbody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Swan Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Rice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kununurra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Extracts Weir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon Descent</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avon Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walyunga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emu Falls</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cobbler Pool</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bells Rapids</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bayswater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supershoot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
