<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413817376754993</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/entertainment/confidential/olympia-valance-doesnt-mind-being-compared-to-margot-robbie-it-excites-me-theres-no-pressure/news-story/c4b2d557c598e932dc1e66b8f225bbed</url>
  <title>Olympia inspired by Margot's success</title>
  <content>
OLYMPIA Valance is not worried about being compared to, or being called, the next Margot Robbie.
The Melbourne actor is tipped for big things, recently signing a global deal with talent agency IMG.
Like Robbie, Valance is starring in Neighbours and sees her story as in inspiration, not a burden.
"It really excites me," she said. "As an Aussie, I've loved watching the country get behind Margo and cheering her on as she found incredible success overseas," she said.
"There has never been and kind of tall poppy vibes directed towards her from the media at all, it has instead felt like a nationwide camaraderie, because one of our own is doing so well.
"I don't think there is any kind of pressure. "Margot is awesome, and I've loved watching her progress.
"As a young Australian actor myself, what she is achieving is everything I could hope for, and more."

Valance has got a new gig to front the latest Nancy Ganz "lingerie with benefits' campaign.
She felt very comfortable in her Nancy Ganz, taking part in a glamorous photo shoot.
"That inner self assurance is something that radiates from the inside out, and I wanted to get this message out there, so more women reap the rewards," she said.
Valance is tipped to head overseas once her time on Neighbours finishes.
Even if she hopes to follow in the footsteps of many former Neighbours stars - including Kylie Minogue, Natalie Imbruglia and Guy Pearce - to bigger and better things, Valance will always have a soft spot for Ramsay Street.
"I feel so incredibly lucky that my first job in this industry was not only on such an iconic Australian show, but also with the best group of people I've ever met."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valance</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylie Minogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IMG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margot</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramsay Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nancy Ganz</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margot Robbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympia Valance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Imbruglia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guy Pearce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
