<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414032125124761</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828075/jets-swoop-late-to-beat-maitland/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Jets swoop late to beat Maitland</title>
  <content>
ON TARGET: Devante Clut celebrates his goal in the 4-0 win over Maitland. Picture: Sproule Sports Focus

COACH Ernie Merrick warned that the Jets will have to lift a notch to trouble Adelaide United in the FFA Cup after they struggled to break down an under-manned Maitland at Cooks Square Park on Wednesday night.

The Jets finished 4-0 winners but it took them until midway through the second half to break the game open.

Jets swoop late to beat Maitland

exit
A well-worked Dimi Petratos goal in the 22nd minute was all that separated the teams at half time. Merrick changed the entire team at the break. Kosta Petratos doubled the lead from the penalty spot in the 53rd minute before late goals to Zhu Zhengyu (78th) and Devante Clut (81st).

The Jets meet Adelaide in Adelaide next Wednesday.

"Maitland made it very difficult for us," Merrick said. "The first half they defended really well, and we had trouble breaking them down.We have to have a bit more killer instinct. Instead of taking the easy pass wide to the flanks, I think we have to go down the middle more often. This wasn't even Maitland's first team. They had several players out. We have to put it in perspective. We will have to do a lot more to break down teams and create more goal-scoring opportunities.'
The Jets dominated possession in the first half. They led the corner count 12-0 but struggled to manufacture clear cut chances against a Magpies outfit that got men behind the ball, blocked the passing channels and scrambled well.

After hitting the woodwork with a stinging freekick in the 15th minute, Petratos put the visitors ahead on 22 minutes.

Nikolai Topor-Stanley won possession deep in the Jets half. He found Daniel Georgievski, who released Andrew Nabbout down the left touch line. The winger muscled past two defenders before arching a pass to Petratos on the right. He took a touch on the inside and hit a bullet across goal and into the left corner.

"The goal was a good piece of play," Merrick said.
Nigel Boogaard, playing his first games of the pre-season, was strong in a back four that was rarely tested.
"The overall shape and structure of the team was good," Merrick said. "Nigel and Nikolai jelled together well. In front of them Ben Kantarovksi and Steve Ugarkovic were good and both fullbacks covered well."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sproule Sports Focus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dimi Petratos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Ugarkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Nabbout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikolai Topor-Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Kantarovksi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petratos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel Boogaard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devante Clut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magpies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nigel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merrick</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Devante Clut (81</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernie Merrick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikolai</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooks Square Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kosta Petratos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Georgievski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zhu Zhengyu (78</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
