<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413830261657333</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/movies/review-the-big-sick-heals-whats-been-wrong-with-so-many-romcoms-these-days/news-story/e14bb6206e09bfbe80bd11b499c7468e</url>
  <title>The Big Sick is a big dose of rom and com</title>
  <content>
THE BIG SICK (M)
Rating: four stars (4 out of 5)
Director: Michael Showalter (Hello, My Name Is Doris)
Starring: Kumail Nanjiani, Zoe Kazan, Holly Hunter, Ray Romano, Kurt Braunohler.
The right cure in rude health
The heavily regimented formula of the rom-com drained all life and vitality out of the genre a long time ago.
So when an amusing love story as alive and vital as The Big Sick comes along, it would be a grave mistake to miss it.
Kumail Nanjiani (best known for TV's Silicon Valley) is effectively playing himself here, but his is a breakout performance of considerable warmth and wit nonetheless.
He plays a young Pakistani stand-up comic from Chicago who has found his perfect match in Emily (Zoe Kazan).
However, Kumail's ultra-traditional parents are unaware of the relationship, and keep pressing for an arranged marriage from within their own community.
This cultural disconnect forces the couple to part, after which Emily contracts an illness that puts her in a deep coma.
Mention of this shock development is by no means a spoiler. In fact, emphasis on the medical crisis at the heart of The Big Sick has been the lynchpin of the movie's publicity campaign.
(And for good reason: Nunjiani co-wrote the screenplay with his real-life wife Emily V. Gordon, based on similar events that transpired during their own fraught courtship.)
While it is lights out for Emily relatively early into The Big Sick, rest assured it won't dissolve into a wonk-ish weepie, or desperately grasp for the nearest sentimental cliche.
In dact, it is at this dramatic turning point really comes into its own as a superior storytelling package, as Kumail is instinctively drawn to join Emily's parents for an extended bedside vigil at a local hospital.
Neither Beth (Holly Hunter) nor Terry (Ray Romano) are initially all that thrilled with Kumail taking a ringside side during a period of deep personal crisis for their family. Kumail himself isn't all that sure he should be there.
However, the trio come to bond in a uniquely unified way - a scene where Beth and Terry support Kumail during a problematic set at a comedy club is a true highlight of the film - that genuinely earns every laugh (and the odd sniffle).
Nanjiani and Gordon's sharp, intuitive scripting has a lot to say about modern love, age-old prejudices and the simple act of being there for someone who doesn't even know you're there.
Though you'll be listening hard, the odds are you'll be often laughing even harder.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holly Hunter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Sick</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zoe Kazan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nunjiani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV's Silicon Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Romano</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emily V. Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beth</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Showalter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Name Is Doris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nanjiani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kumail</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kumail Nanjiani</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Braunohler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pakistani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
