<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413856031461703</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:18</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/courts-law/jean-claude-perrottet-sex-attack-trial-alleged-offender-rang-brother-for-advice/news-story/ae5461821cbda03d25581ee135f81ac5</url>
  <title>Jean Claude Perrottet sex attack trial: Alleged offender rang brother for advice</title>
  <content>
Jean-Claude Perrottet allegedly sexually assaulted a young woman on the grounds of a residential college associated with The University of Sydney in 2015 leaves Downing Centre Court, Monday, 24 July, 201. Photo Jeremy Piper

IAN PATERSON

Share

THE younger brother of the NSW Treasurer has admitted to a court he was drunk and thrown out of an after-party the night he is alleged to have sexually assaulted a woman.
Jean Claude Perrottet gave evidence today that he had consumed several beers, a couple of glasses of champagne and a French martini before he hit the dance floor at the St John's College formal at the University of Sydney in October 2015.
"I was drunk at that point," he said.

NSW Treasurer Dominic Perrottet is the accused's brother.Source:News Corp Australia

Mr Perrottet leaves court. Picture: John GraingerSource:News Corp Australia
It also emerged police claim they overheard him telling a family member "it was just second base".
Perrottet, 20, who wasn't a resident of the college, is on trial in the NSW District Court after pleading not guilty to three counts of sexual intercourse without consent.
The sexual encounter allegedly took place in a carpark near the college in the early hours of October 19 after the formal.
On the night of the alleged assault, the woman had -attended the annual event along with more than 500 others.
During questioning from his defence barrister Alissa Moen, Perrottet, whose brother Dominic has been Treasurer since earlier this year, said he was thrown out of an after-party.
"There were security guards there letting people in and out and kicking people out as well and I got kicked out," he said.

Jean-Claude Perrottet leaving the Downing Centre
0:10

Jean-Claude Perrottet, 20, the younger brother of NSW Finance Minister leaving the Downing centre today. Perrottet allegedly sexually assaulted a young woman on the grounds of a residential college associated with The University of Sydney, after being invited as a guest to the St John's College Annual Formal, in 2015.

July 24th 2017
9 days ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Moen: "How long after you first came into the Lemon Grove area were asked to leave by security guards?"
Perrottet: "Not long, but I am not sure how long it was."
The court earlier heard that during a police interview Perrottet made a phone call to his brother Oliver to ask for advice after he was arrested.
According to police notes, he told his brother over the phone: "It was just second base, it was a bit of handwork, she may have given me a headjob but it was all consensual."
Reading to the court from his investigation notes Detective Senior Constable Adam Royds said that when brought in for questioning Perrottet asked him: "What was I supposed to have done?"
"You are alleged to have had digital, penile and oral sex with a woman," Sen Con Royds said. "He then said, 'There is no way I had sex with her - it is against my religion'."
The trial continues today.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John's College Annual Formal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lemon Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Perrottet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Paterson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Treasurer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perrottet</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downing Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo Jeremy Piper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perrottet, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John's College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John GraingerSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Treasurer Dominic Perrottet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean-Claude Perrottet, 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday, 24 July, 201</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sen Con Royds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dominic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alissa Moen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean Claude Perrottet</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downing Centre Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Senior Constable Adam Royds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Finance Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
