<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414221103690269</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:43</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/commercial/leasing/before-amazon-arrives-online-retailer-kogan-and-catch-in-push-for-space-20170731-gxm18q</url>
  <title>Online retailers in big push for warehouse space</title>
  <content>
Local online retail heavyweights Kogan and Catch Group are lifting their distribution game ahead of the arrival of Amazon in Australia with tenders in the market for more than 60,000 square metres of new state-of-the-art logistics facilities.
Amazon, which plans to roll out its full suite of online retailing services in Australia over time, recently secured the  as its first Melbourne fulfilment hub with another on the cards at a Goodman Group business park in Sydney's west.
The $300 million-a-year turnover Catch Group, whose online retail businesses include include catch.com.au and scoopon.com.au, is in the market for a 35,000sq m distribution facility in Melbourne's west while eStore Logistics, whose clients include Kogan, Temple & Webster, and Patagonia, is tendering for a new 15-17,000sq m warehouse in Sydney and a new 10-12,000sq m warehouse in Melbourne to complement its existing facilities.
"We are running out of space. At the moment we are at 95 per cent capacity in our warehouse as a result of expanding our product range and our growth in sales," said Catch Group CEO Nati Harpaz.

"We have had a very strong 12 months and are projecting the next 12 months to continue to be very strong," he said.

Mr Harpaz said he believed Amazon would "raise the bar on fulfilment and logistics".
"We are already gearing and building our capabilities and expanding our warehouse as part of that strategy," he said. Catch Group also plans to open  as it looks to win more retail customers.
eStore founder and managing director Leigh Williams said the expansion of its warehousing was being driven by its existing clients selling more stock and more retailers approaching the group to perform its warehouse and fulfilment functions.
Kogan founder Ruslan Kogan has a minority share in eStore which fulfils 30,000 online orders a day, distributing everything from television screens to wine, clothing and washing machines on behalf of more than 50 retailers.

'Speed to customer'

"The trend in retail is towards online and away from bricks and mortar, Mr Williams told The Australian Financial Review. "Amazon will be a game changer in Australia if they are able to master super fast delivery," he said.
Both eStore and Catch Group are being assisted in their procurement strategy by specialist supply chain consultancy TM Insight led by Travis Erridge and Milan Jelkovic.
Mr Erridge said online retailers were looking to optimise their supply chains and distribution as Amazon prepares to launch. "The objective is simple: it's all about speed to customer," Mr Erridge said.

He said distribution centres designed for pure B2B activity - rather than direct goods deliver to customers - could not cater for the shifting retail landscape and needed substantial change and investment to remain relevant.
"Every time an item is touched it adds to the cost of delivery. Things like smart technology, automation, high bay storage and 24/7 fulfilment are now keys to success" he said.
According to the NAB Online Retail Sales Index, Australian consumers spent about $23 billion a year online, about 7.4 per cent of the spending at traditional bricks & mortar retailers. Online sales are growing at about 8 per cent per annum.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eStore Logistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruslan Kogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patagonia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travis Erridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TM Insight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eStore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Temples</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catch Group</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Harpaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catch Group CEO Nati Harpaz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB Online Retail Sales Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milan Jelkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kogan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>B2B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Erridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goodman Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
