<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413864621396440</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/victoria/it-shouldnt-have-happened-to-me-i-didnt-deserve-it-shot-mum-bares-scars-20170801-gxn8j2.html</url>
  <title>She gave evidence against her criminal son. Then she took a bullet to her belly</title>
  <content>
The scar reminds Leonie Stuart of a centipede, crawling up her belly.
It also reminds her of the bang, like a balloon popping, echoing through her Glenroy house just before midnight on March 2.

Up Next

Accused dangerous driver calls Australia 'racist'

01:09

More Victoria News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

'I didn't deserve it': Shot mum bares scars

After testifying against her son, grandmother Leonie Stuart was shot in her own home. Now, she relives her torment to try and find her assailant.

The sound came from a handgun being held by someone outside her screen door.
They squeezed the trigger and sent a bullet through the door and into her flesh, leaving a hole just smaller than a five-cent piece below her left breast.

Ms Stuart, 52, had given everything to her five boys.
Only one of them lived with her, but the troubles they had with police and the drink and drugs were never far away. And, now, she had almost given her life.

Police are investigating whether Ms Stuart's shooting is linked to the feared Prisoners of War jailhouse gang, of which her son Rodney Phillips is a member.
Ms Stuart gave evidence against Phillips during a committal hearing last year - something severely frowned upon by the gang, which is headed by Matthew Johnson.Photo: Justin McManus
Johnson murdered Carl Williams in Barwon Prison because of similar concerns about co-operating with the authorities.
Phillips later pleaded guilty to charges relating to shootings and firebombings targeting the father and ex-wife of Williams, attacks motivated by his allegiance to the POW.Photo: Justin McManus
During this rampage, Phillips and a co-accused also shot two police in Moonee Ponds.
It is an irony not lost on Ms Stuart that the armed crime squad, who investigated Phillips for shooting at police, are now investigating who shot her.
"I actually testified against Rodney, because I've never been a person who can lie. I've always been an honest person," Ms Stuart said.
"I still think to this day: it's revenge. This is about revenge.Photo: Supreme Court
"Because people know how to find people's family members if they really want to ...[and] I did say harsh words at the committal against Rodney."
Ms Stuart, who is also a grandmother, spent 2 1/2 weeks in hospital after the shooting, which left her in a critical condition.Photo: Victoria Police
The vertical scar is from surgery to remove her spleen, and she had another less intrusive surgery only last week to remove some shrapnel from her back.
Ms Stuart should make a full recovery and was incredibly lucky, doctors say, but she will have to take medication for years.
The decision to reveal her scars, physical and mental, was not easy.
But she needs to know why someone wanted to hurt her - even if the answer may be as painful as the shooting itself.
"I love my boys, I love them all dearly," she said.
"But my life, I've got nothing.
"And for this to happen, it shouldn't have happened to me. I didn't deserve it. That's why I'm here today."
Detective Sergeant Warren Chapman hopes someone, somewhere, hears Ms Stuart's story and sees her scars and comes forward.
"We can not say with any certainty that Leonie was the target of the shooting or that the motive relates to the activities of one of her children," he said.
"The investigation is in danger of going unsolved unless someone does the decent thing and comes forward.
"There's people in the underworld who still have a sense of morality and these people will look at this and think she shouldn't have been shot."
A son who had been living at the Glenroy house with Ms Stuart had returned from overseas only a few days before the shooting, but it remains unclear whether this is linked.
Her partner claimed hours after the shooting during media interviews that he knew who was responsible, but, today, Leonie says he "does not, 100 per cent, have a clue who did this to me" and regretted the comments, she said.
It is believed a dark grey 4WD fled the scene and was last seen travelling south along Hubert Avenue towards Hilton Street.
A motorcycle was also seen in the area at the time of the shooting, and police would like more information regarding this.
Anyone with information is urged to contact Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or submit a confidential report at www.crimestoppersvic.com.a
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phillips</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilton Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonee Ponds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin McManus</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonie Stuart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prisoners of War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenroy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detective Sergeant Warren Chapman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Stuart, 52</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>POW.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Johnson.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Stuart</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>9.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leonie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carl Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>William</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hubert Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barwon Prison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
