<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413817376755080</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/relationships/sam-hensman-in-rehabilitation-after-battling-rare-brain-disorder-and-haemorrhages-wants-to-walk-down-the-aisle-for-his-fiancee-tess-delony/news-story/f0b1b2316b8d76aea506df657b2c91ef</url>
  <title>True fighters: Sam and Tess' beautiful love story</title>
  <content>
SAM Hensman won the girl of his dreams in a wedding proposal with a smile from his hospital bed.
Now he's determined to say his vows and walk back down the aisle with that girl, Tess Delony, when they wed.
Miss Delony told The Advertiser wedding plans had to be distant in their minds as they first focused on Mr Hensman's continued recovery and getting him home within the next couple of months.
"Obviously with the engagement there will also be a wedding on the cards eventually," she said.
"I know that Sam would really love to be able to say his vows and to walk back down the aisle, so I'd like to wait a little while to give him the opportunity.
"I think focusing all of our time and energy on rehabilitating Sam is the most important thing right now, so we'll just take things as they come."
The young couple proved that true love conquers all when news of their engagement emerged last month.
Unable to talk,  after she had stayed by his side while he battled a series of haemorrhages and operations for a rare brain disorder.
Speaking publicly for the first time since the proposal, Miss Delony recalled the moment the couple's life was turned upside down.
Mr Hensman was diagnosed with an arteriovenous malformation in the centre of his brain in April 2015.
He began consulting with a specialist neurosurgeon in Sydney who recommended a treatment program over 10 years.
But on July 24 last year, a week before he was scheduled to have a meeting with the surgeon to discuss the growing mass of blood vessels, Mr Hensman suffered a life-changing haemorrhage.
"We went from having this beautiful moment at my house where he'd put his arms tight around me, saying 'I love you, I really, really love you' to suddenly having him unconscious on my bedroom floor," Miss Delony said.

"Even though I knew his condition was serious, I think because he had walked out of hospital okay after two (previous) haemorrhages, it gave me a false sense of security.
"That's the day I really thought he wasn't going to make it and I'd have to say goodbye."
Surgeons had to remove half of Mr Hensman's skull to relieve pressure on the brain and placed him in a medical coma.
In the following months, he was brought out of the coma and flown to Sydney for surgery to remove the mass.
The first surgery did not entirely remove the mass and two more risky operations were required.
In December, the section of skull was replaced and Mr Hensman was flown back to Adelaide where he is continuing his long rehabilitation, training his body to move again and working for his voice to come back.
It is hoped Mr Hensman will return home within two months, but the costly process of adapting the family home to accommodate the medical equipment necessary to support him is a hurdle.
But Miss Delony said she was amazed at the generosity of strangers, which was also raising the spirits of Mr Hensman.
has so raised almost $22,000.
"The response to Sam's story has just been mind-blowing," Miss Delony said.
"It is so heartwarming to see that there are still people in the world with huge hearts that care.
"I think what is truly beautiful to watch though is Sam's response to everyone's support.
"I have never seen so much joy and gratitude."
Miss Delony said she dreams of a future when they will live together and start their own photography business.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAM Hensman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miss Delony</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delony</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tess Delony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hensman</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TESS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
