<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414203923820845</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/policy/industrial-relations/maritime-unions-seek-to-block-mua-merger-with-cfmeu-20170802-gxns11</url>
  <title>Maritime unions seek to block MUA-CFMEU merger over fears of membership grab</title>
  <content>
Maritime unions are lining up to oppose the Maritime Union of Australia's merger with the Construction, Forestry, Mining and Energy Union, fearing the new super union will encroach on their territory and dominate the offshore resources industry.
The Australian Maritime Officers Union and the Australian Institute of Marine and Power Engineers, which represent officers and engineers at the large coal and , filed expressions of interest this week to appear at a Fair Work Commission hearing on  this Friday.
AMOU executive officer Mark Davis said the union's number one concern was the MUA would seek to expand its coverage as part of a newly merged "CFMMEU", prompting a poaching war on the docks.
He noted the MUA had passed a resolution at its national conference last year to changes its eligibility rules to effectively cover marine pilots, maintenance technicians, masters and harbour traffic control officers.

The MUA quietly applied to change its rules shortly before Christmas, but later withdrew the claim over concerns it would become an obstacle to its amalgamation with the CFMEU.

The AMOU and the AIMPE are both historic rivals of the more militant MUA, although the unions have not had a demarcation war since the early 1990s.
Mr Davis said there had been "effectively peace on the waterfront since then" and the MUA's membership bid "was seen as a pretty aggressive move to destabilise the port services sector".
Despite the MUA's amalgamation featuring no proposed eligibility changes, Mr Davis said he feared its membership bid will be "resurrected".
"I'm thinking the worst that they will probably want another go at it."

The MUA declined to comment ahead of the hearing on Friday.
The Australian Mines and Metals Association has warned the resources industry is  that the merger will give the MUA greater capacity to inflict economic damage on the sector.
AIMPE senior national organiser Michael Bakhaazi said a CFMEU-MUA merger would gift the militant union with "unlimited resources" to campaign, recruit and litigate for what it wants.
"It's not easy to fight a bigger union," he said. "It costs money, it's not cheap."

He contrasted the MUA's militant approach to AIMPE. "We think wages have stabilised and you shouldn't ask for more and more all the time because that destroys the industry."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forestry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MUA</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Institute of Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MUA-CFMEU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMEU-MUA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metals Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Energy Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Davis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Power Engineers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMOU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maritime Union of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Davis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Mines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Bakhaazi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIMPE</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFMMEU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Maritime Officers Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
