<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414075074798797</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/rendezview/stop-hijacking-my-religion-to-stop-marriage-equality/news-story/4b77aff6e7f4545171be25f07ce4ba8b</url>
  <title>Jesus would want marriage equality</title>
  <content>
IT is clear that opponents to marriage equality are not protecting the interests of Christians. A recent poll showed that even among the post-census smaller number of Australia's Christians, 54 per cent continue to support civil marriage equality. Christian supporters of civil marriage equality still have their bums stuck firmly to the pews. So when people oppose marriage equality on so-called Christian grounds they are not protecting religious freedom. They are only trying to impose a minority viewpoint on the Australian population.
I want religious freedom in this country and for my convictions to be heard in the Like many others I don't want people opposed to marriage equality to hijack my spirituality and misrepresent it as some basis for denying other people their rights. People like me don't want to impose our faith on others, including co-religionists who disagree with us. We get that Christianity seems ridiculous to many. We've known since the beginning that we Christians can look stupid. As one of our founders put it, we are fools. But we still want our voice to be heard as citizens of this country.
Here's why we support marriage equality. Some support it because of their deep, loving sense of fairness for others. Others look at the content of our faith and find that it encourages us to support it.

A new poll shows the majority of baby boomers living in liberal electorates support marriage equality.

Poll finds liberal voters want gay marriage
When opponents to marriage equality quote chapters from the book of Leviticus, we ask, what did Jesus quote from those chapters? And it wasn't the bits about sex but the bit about loving your neighbour as yourself. So, following Jesus' lead, we don't worry about how an ancient society organised its sex life, rather we see that Jesus wants us to love the LGBTQI community as we would love ourselves, as equals with respect and fairness.
When people quote an obscure word used by Paul in his letter to the Corinthians (arsenokoitai, if you're interested) and interpret it to condemn homosexuality, we try to understand Paul through everything he said. We remember that Paul discussed sex later in his career in his letter to the Romans. Here it is clear that his views were that sex should be according to nature, which he believed reflects God's qualities. So we ask the scientists, what is nature like? And they tell us that it's full of same sex activity and that genes don't always determine gender. Wow, if only Paul knew that! So, recognising that gender diversity is natural we follow Paul's guidance to look to nature, not his historical interpretation that was based on the limited natural science of his day.
And at the end of the day, we act on how we understand the fundamentals that Jesus gave us. When we look at his explanation about what unites people with God or alienates them, he is very consistent. It's about how we treat others. Being kind to people is not an optional extra, it's how we relate to God. As he taught, if we can't love those we do see, how can we love God we can't see? A famous parable of his summed it up - it has phrases that have a core place in the hearts of Christians: "When I was hungry, you fed me." "When I was sick, you visited me." So we hear Jesus today saying, "When I was LGBTQI, you got out of the way and let me get married."
That is why so many Christians support civil marriage equality. From Catholic Ireland to Catholic Malta marriage equality is enabled. The Christian Democratic Union party in Germany made it a conscience vote so 70 Christian Democrats could cross the floor and enable marriage equality. Christians are supporting marriage equality around the world as a way to love their neighbours through equal rights. So it's hardly surprising that so many Australian Christians want the same thing.
To all those people in Canberra who are playing games trying to stop civil marriage equality going ahead, stop hijacking my religion to justify your opposition. As a citizen and part of that 54 per cent, I ask you to get out of the way and let it through. It's way overdue.
Paul Hegerty is a former Catholic priest.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Christians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Democrats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LGBTQI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leviticus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christianity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corinthians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Democratic Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jesus</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Christians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Hegerty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catholic Malta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
