<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413898981135626</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/white-knights-donate-300000-to-castlemaine-gallery-20170802-gxo4ln.html</url>
  <title>White knights save Castlemaine Art Museum from closure</title>
  <content>
Shock and anger at the closure of the 104-year-old Castlemaine Art Museum turned to joy on Wednesday night.
White knight private donors have pledged $300,000 to save the key Castlemaine tourist attraction, which was slated for closure after the board said it had .Photo: Joe Armao
Board chair Jan Savage told a meeting of gallery members at Castlemaine Town Hall that a Melbourne couple would give a total of $250,000 over two years so the gallery can stay open. 
Board member Chris McAuliffe told Fairfax Media that the couple, who wished to remain anonymous, were acting through two Sotheby's auctions representatives.Photo: Joe Armao
Mr McAuliffe said the donors, who had "long associations with central Victoria, and Castlemaine is their favourite regional gallery", had pledged $125,000 for each of the next two financial years, 2017-18 and 2018-19.
This was "to keep the doors of the museum open to the public, on limited hours", with no special exhibitions, to keep costs down. "They did not want the museum to close its doors."

In addition, it was announced at the meeting that Ms Melissa Macfarlane made a $50,000 donation from the legacy fund of her father Donald Macfarlane, former managing director of Amcor.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Mr McAuliffe said that this amount was for the 2017-18 financial year, "to support the community consultation and development work that will allow us to re-imagine and reinvent the brand of the Castlemaine Art Museum".Photo: Joe Armao
"Both of those donors want to specifically invest in the renewal of the museum. They don't see it as a bailout. They see it as investing in the renewal."
Locals formed a , and prominent artists condemned the looming closure, scheduled for August 11, of one of Castlemaine's biggest tourist drawcards.
The board said the closure could have lasted until 2019 while a complete financial restructure was conducted.
The gallery in recent years has hosted touring exhibitions by Ben Quilty, Bill Henson and Patricia Piccinini.
It owns works by masters including Arthur Streeton and Frederick McCubbin, often displays local artists' pieces, and holds gold rush heritage items.
Quilty had labelled the closure "another kick in the guts" to the Australian arts community. "Tell me this is a bad dream," he wrote on Facebook.
The board cited revenue reductions, rising compliance and maintenance costs and "deep-rooted vulnerabilities in financial structures" as reasons for the closure.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlemaine</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jan Savage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Melissa Macfarlane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlemaine Art Museum</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Henson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Armao</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris McAuliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amcor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Piccinini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McAuliffe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Macfarlane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Streeton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sotheby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frederick McCubbin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlemaine Town Hall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
