<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413907571070329</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/thesourcesa/south-australian-winemaker-paul-hotker-named-winemaker-of-the-year-in-james-halliday-annual-awards/news-story/4cea250c4bc58fb01a9f0e8f0159b9c9</url>
  <title>SA winemaker named best in Australia</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIA'S modern eating habits have prompted a major shift in red wine styles, the newly crowned James Halliday winemaker of the year, Paul Hotker says.
The evolution from old-school meat and three boiled-to-death veg to foods inspired by Mediterranean and Asian cuisines, as well as tapas and salads, has inspired a change in Australian reds from big blockbuster, oaky and heavy styles to more vibrant, fresher and medium-bodied styles, he says.
Mr Hotker, of Bleasdale, was named the James Halliday Winemaker of the Year for 2017-18 on Wednesday, leading the other major awards for Wine of the Year (SA's Henschke 2012 Hill of Grace) and Winery of the Year (Mount Mary).
Australian wine doyen Halliday cited as the reason for Hotker's accolade being the huge haul of show medals Bleasdale has scored in the past two years for wines in a modern, medium-bodied style.
"We're eating more fresh foods, cooked quickly - even meat is served a bit rarer - and younger, fresher wines suit that style of cuisine," Mr Hotker said.
"We're getting back to our roots and making good, fresh-fruit-style wines, and the trend all over is to capture freshness in wines.

Other Stories

"The major show-circuit judges are looking for it, and our sales figures indicate that people want to drink fresher styles."
Mr Hotker said the Langhorne Creek region excels in lighter styles because of its growing conditions, which are kept cool by prevailing breezes from the Southern Ocean and Lake Alexandrina.
Paul Hotker's crowning as Halliday Winemaker of the Year tops off an extraordinary previous two years, during which he scored eight trophies from five separate shows in 2015, then winning another five in 2016 for one wine alone, the Bleasdale 2015 Wellington Road Grenache Shiraz, and topping that off with two more for its Second Innings Malbec.
He describes the recognition as exciting, admitting that neither he nor Bleasdale nor Langhorne Creek are among the "cool kids" of the wine industry.
"We're a conservative wine business simply doing the best we can," he said.
Minor awards coming out of the annual release of the Halliday Wine Companion, published on Wednesday, also includes Grosset Wines from the Clare Valley named as Best Value Winery, Dappled Wine awarded Best New Winery, and Boat O'Craigo named the Dark Horse Winery of the Year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clare Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hotker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Hotker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best Value Winery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dark Horse Winery of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Second Innings Malbec</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halliday Wine Companion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halliday Winemaker of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Ocean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Best New Winery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Halliday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hotker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winery of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boat O'Craigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Langhorne Creek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Mary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wine of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halliday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bleasdale</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hotker, of Bleasdale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Halliday Winemaker of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bleasdale 2015 Wellington Road Grenache Shiraz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mediterranean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA's Henschke 2012 Hill of Grace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grosset Wines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Alexandrina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dappled Wine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
