<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414165269114127</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:30</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/lifestyle/parenting/naplan-results-2017-qld-st-margarets-bucks-trend-in-writing/news-story/6dff50088edb209c9e191977b50d1cd6</url>
  <title>Girls who bucked the NAPLAN trend</title>
  <content>
IT'S the trickiest of tasks but the girls at St Margaret's have topped the state in  this year.
The junior students recorded the highest average score and 100 per cent of students were above the national minimum writing standard, at a time when the skill is slipping.
The latest NAPLAN data shows average children's writing results have gone backwards in the past six years across all states and territories.
One of the biggest changes on NAPLAN this year was the way students were asked to write a persuasive essay instead of a narrative.
St Margaret's Anglican Girls' School Principal Ros Curtis said it was using a number of new researched-backed programs to build up literacy and numeracy.
She said the school had a huge reading program with the primary school students reading about 52 million words from novels selected for their ability that they then have tests on.
"The students have an opportunity to write more but they are also reading more which means they can write more interesting things and better spelling means they have a wider vocabulary of words to write," she said.
On a mobile device? Use landscape mode to read these tables

St Margaret's also has a "second chance test" program to challenge students' expectations in a subject by giving feedback from a first test and showing how effort can change outcomes in a second test.
Helping students' writing via feedback is the focus of a three-year study of 13 primary schools across Brisbane that has just started coaching teachers in the art of feedback.
Educator in residence at the University of Queensland, one of the universities involved, Rochelle Burton said teachers already give lots of feedback but students often don't find it useful so the trick was finding the most effective method.
At the same time educational researchers from the Learning Sciences Institute Australia have been working with the Queensland government to tackle writing.
Headed by Professor Claire Wyatt-Smith, the project's preliminary results reveal the teaching of writing needs to be a priority in teacher education.
"Australia needs a national position on the teaching of writing. We already have one for literacy and we have seen improvements in reading because that is where governments are focused," Professor Wyatt-Smith said.
"We need to be focused on developing teachers' identities as writers themselves if they are to teach writing at a level that will reverse this decline."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAPLAN</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Learning Sciences Institute Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Margaret's Anglican Girls' School Principal Ros Curtis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ST MARGARET</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Claire Wyatt-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Wyatt-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rochelle Burton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
