<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413903276102957</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828606/magic-fade-out-in-ffa-cup-loss/?cs=306</url>
  <title>Magic fade out in FFA Cup loss</title>
  <content>
Broadmeadow finished with 10 men in a dramatic 4-2 extra-time loss to Moreton Bay to bow out of the FFA Cup on Wednesday night.

Kale Bradbery
Magic missed a penalty but still led 1-0 at half-time after dominating chances in the first 45 minutes at Wolter Park, Albany Creek, in the round of 32 contest.

The Jets, though, had the better of the second half and scored in the 72nd and 74th minutes to lead.

Kale Bradbery put Magic into extra-time when he earned then converted a penalty five seconds into stoppage time after he was fouled by Paul Mikula.
However, Broadmeadow's hopes dropped when first-half goalscorer Dino Fajkovic was shown a second yellow card in the eighth minute of extra-time for what appeared a minor foul on Mikula.
It was Mikula, a late substitute, who put the Jets in front with a crisp header off a free kick in the 106th minute. Declan Smith's header two minutes later sealed Magic's fate.
The loss revived memories of Broadmeadow's first foray into the round of 32 in 2014 when they finished with nine men in a 3-2 extra-time loss to Brisbane Strikers. They lost to Heidelberg 3-1 at the same stage in 2015.
On Wednesday night, two two-minute periods of defensive lapses proved costly for Magic, who started the better. They put the disappointment of a missed penalty behind them quickly thanks to a cool finish from Fajkovic in the 18th minute.

Fajkovic was put into space on the left by a through ball from Bradbery and showed composure to knocked it past goalkeeper Jordan Thurtell, who rushed off his line.

The goal came after James Virgili earned but then missed a penalty for Magic in the 15th minute. Virgili was barged over on the edge of the box by Matthew Byrnes but hit his penalty down the centre, where a diving Thurtell cleared it will his leg.
Alex Janovsky equalised from the spot for the hosts after Jon Griffiths was judged to have fouled during a penalty-box scramble. Substitute Lachlan Strogusz then put the Jets in front with a volleyed strike off a free kick rebound.

Luke Virgili went agonisingly close to an equaliser in the 79th minute when his free kick hit both posts without crossing the line. Fajkovic also hit the woodwork with a flick-on header in the 81st.

The result follows Edgeworth's 1-0 round of 32 loss to South Melbourne last week. The Newcastle Jets take on Adelaide United away next Wednesday night.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wolter Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Jets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Strikers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradbery</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Virgili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Mikula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadmeadows</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikula</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Declan Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Strogusz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fajkovic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dino Fajkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Janovsky</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Thurtell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albany Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Byrnes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurtell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Virgili</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
