<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414160974146801</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/barnaby-joyces-board-nominee-quits-after-being-offered-secret-water-data-20170801-gxnhr8</url>
  <title>Joyce's board nominee quits after being offered secret water data</title>
  <content>
A former lobbyist nominated by Barnaby Joyce to sit on the board of the Murray-Darling Basin Authority attended a meeting at which a NSW government official was recorded offering her and other irrigators sensitive data.
Late on Wednesday, Perin Davey, once a lobbyist for Murray Irrigation, asked Mr Joyce to withdraw her nomination following inquiries by The Australian Financial Review, but
It can be confirmed that Ms Davey was part of a teleconference in which NSW government water official Gavin Hanlon proposed handing over de-badged documents, those which are stripped of the departmental logo, to help irrigators exploit the Murray-Darling Basin Plan
"Obviously we would have to de-badge it," Mr Hanlon says of the data in the recording.

One lobbyist, now identified as Ms Davey, responds: "Yeah, that would be fabulous".

Following revelations last week by the ABC's Four Corners program of that teleconference, Mr Hanlon referred himself to the NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption.
Contacted by the Financial Review on Tuesday, Ms Davey did not dispute she was at the meeting but said she was unable to comment because of the ICAC process and a separate NSW government investigation.
It is understood Mr Hanlon will contend the conversation was reported out of context by Four Corners.
Mr Joyce wrote to basin state water ministers in late June proposing Ms Davey be accepted to fill one of two board vacancies on the MDBA.

David Rowe

When Four Corners aired , and the behaviour of Mr Hanlon in allegedly helping undermine the basin plan, Mr Joyce recommended the MDBA - presumably with Ms Davey on the board - conduct .
Federal Labor and a cross-party delegation of South Australian state and federal politicians rejected this as inadequate and nor do they accept an independent investigation ordered by the NSW government, saying the state cannot be trusted.
They are demanding a judicial inquiry and for Mr Joyce to be relieved of the Water Resources portfolio.
This clamour has intensified following confirmation of Ms Davey's attendance at the teleconference.

"When the Murray-Darling Basin Authority was first set up, Malcolm Turnbull said it would be expert and independent," said federal shadow environment minister Tony Burke.
"If there was a phone hook-up where people conspired to undo the plan, I can't see how the government can seriously say the participants should be put in charge.
"When people heard that phone hook-up on Four Corners last week they were shocked. You'd only put the participants in charge if you wanted to destroy the plan."
Ms Davey's nomination to the board was never ratified and there is no suggestion Mr Joyce knew about Ms Davey's attendance at the teleconference when he nominated her. She requested her nomination be withdrawn so as not to create any further harm or controversy.

In recommending Ms Davey, Mr Joyce cited her "extensive experience in water management, water markets, the irrigation industry and public relations and communications".
"Ms Davey has a well-grounded understanding of the Murray-Darling Basin Plan and is very experienced in stakeholder engagement regarding water policy issues in Australia."
South Australian Water Minister Ian Hunter opposed her nomination, telling Mr Joyce in writing that Ms Davey had previously lobbied for lower environmental flows down the river.
"This is a person with an agenda being put onto an authority that's in place to deliver the Murray-Darling Basin agreement - and that says to me there are ulterior motives here," he said.

"It says to me there are National Party shenanigans going on to try to undermine the plan."
The latest revelations follow a report in Sydney's The Daily Telegraph that NSW Primary Industries Minister Niall Blair, a former National Party state chairman, is trying to change the law retrospectively to justify a decision by his department to allocate more water to cotton farmer Peter Harris who is also a political donor.
Mr Joyce is under fire from South Australians who believe his response to the alleged water theft downplayed the threat to the basin plan. Anger intensified when he told irrigators in a Victoria country pub last week that he . He also disparaged the Four Corner's report.
SA Senator Nick Xenophon said clearly Ms Davey should never have been appointed to the MDBA board and, more than ever, there needed to be an independent judicial inquiry.
"I don't think she's a suitable person to be on the board," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Joyce</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MDBA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gavin Hanlon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Davey</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>4.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Irrigation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Burke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Plan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Senator Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perin Davey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Primary Industries Minister Niall Blair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hanlon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Darling Basin Authority</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Water Resources</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian Water Minister Ian Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Labor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Corners</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daily Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
