<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413860326429052</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/sport/afl/sam-mitchell-says-while-hes-a-polarising-player-he-doesnt-think-he-has-a-bad-reputation/news-story/2f0875e0cb86c429a2925b60d59072ab</url>
  <title>'There's not too much that I've done wrong'</title>
  <content>
RETIRING Eagle Sam Mitchell says while he admits he's been a "polarising" figure in the game, fans shouldn't be "too harsh" on his reputation.
The Hawthorn great made his mark as a relentless, ruthless midfielder - an approach that earned him the love of Hawks fans, and at time, the ire of opposition supporters.
"I understand that I've been quite polarising in my career," Mitchell said on Fox Footy's AFL 360.
"Someone once told me 'don't complain and don't explain' and I think it's a pretty good moral to live by as a player."
"I've done a lot of good in the game, I've also probably been on the other end."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.
On Wednesday, Mitchell announced he would retire at the end of the season, bringing an end to a career that started at Box Hill, saw him win four premierships at Hawthorn then move to the Eagles.
Remarkably, Mitchell has been suspended just once in his career, despite a series of match review panel citings - for offences including striking, kneeing and tripping - and guilty pleas.
"I've been suspended for one game in my career so I don't think you can be too harsh towards me," he said.
"(When) I actually got suspended it was in a pre-season game as well. There's not too much that I've done wrong in my career."
When asked about his remarkable record of avoiding suspensions - despite frequently being involved in on-field scuffles and conflicts, the midfielder said it was a matter of knowing what he could get away with.
"You've got to know where the line is," he said.
The 34-year-old will end his career a Brownlow Medallist, a Rising Star winner, a three-time All-Australian, a five-time club best and fairest winner and a four-time premiership player - including captaining the Hawks to their breakthrough 2008 flag.
A star clearance player, Mitchell became renowned for his ability to open up games through handballing, his excellent kicking on both feet and his poise and balance under pressure.
Despite his tremendous work over 323 games, Mitchell said he felt like it had taken until the closing years of his career to earn recognition for his talent, rather than his hard work alone.
"I think it took until I was about 30 until anyone said 'the talented player,' Mitchell said.
"Before that it was always 'the hard worker who tried his best but he wasn't that talented' and by the time I hit 30 I'd become a talented player.
"So I think maybe it's advice for young kids - just stick at it, keep trying, keep trying to learn, keep making mistakes and eventually they'll call you talented."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rising Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagle Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Box Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medallist</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Footy's AFL 360</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
