<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414246873494656</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/breaking-news/indonesian-prisons-to-target-traffickers/news-story/53e981b6a0db5baffe4169c21bfbebd9</url>
  <title>Indonesian prisons to target traffickers</title>
  <content>
Lauren Farrow and Heru RahadiAustralian Associated Press

Share

Indonesian authorities are hoping to concentrate drug traffickers in four jails across the country, saying they are "overwhelmed" by inmates masterminding large-scale trafficking operations from behind bars.
After months of investigations Indonesian police seized more than 1.2 million ecstasy tablets in two raids last month, leading to two arrests and the shooting death of a suspect.
A prisoner named Aseng is now being held in isolation after he allegedly plotted the deal from within Indonesia's notorious island prison Nusakambangan, in Central Java.
He is alleged to have organised the shipment of the tablets from the Netherlands.
Acting Director General for Corrections, Makmun, said claims half of Indonesia's drug trade is operated from within prison was "debatable" but conceded on Wednesday there was no doubt many are controlling distribution from behind bars.
"We're concentrating on those traffickers. Those with wider networks ...This is not an easy problem," he told reporters.
He announced they now plan to house prisoners "drug traffickers" in four facilities across the archipelago, in order to better monitor their activities.
The prisons - in West Java, North Sumatra, Central Java and Central Kalimantan - will be specially equipped with X-ray scanners.
Corrections officials couldn't say whether Australian prisoners, including members of the Bali Nine, would be affected by the changes.

Meanwhile an investigation is ongoing into security guards who may be helping the trade from within prison.
This, he hoped, would conclude "as soon as possible".
"Our officers are overwhelmed and so, this needs extraordinary measures by supporting officials, by collaborating with BNN (the National Narcotics Agency) and the police. Hopefully with this extra layered security, it will work," Security Director from Corrections, Sutrisman told reporters.
Indonesia's prisons are chronically overcrowded.
There are about 225,000 inmates in a system designed for 122,000.
Of this population, about 86,000 are drug dealers, traffickers or users, corrections said.
Corruption is rife, with raids on prisons uncovering everything from drugs and handphones, to "luxury cells", complete with aquariums.
The Institute for Criminal Justice Reform (ICJR) has previously called on the government to ease crowding by creating alternative sentencing options and boosting rehabilitation programs.
Corrections said on Wednesday rehabilitation programs "need a lot of funding" and it was "not in their budget yet".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aseng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Criminal Justice Reform</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Farrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X-rays</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bali Nine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Makmun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Narcotics Agency</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sutrisman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Java</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Sumatra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Security Director</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICJR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nusakambangan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Heru RahadiAustralian Associated Press</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Java</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netherlands</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Kalimantan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
