<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413903276102941</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/entertainment/confidential/save-our-spit-alliance-president-rules-out-running-for-parliament/news-story/d43d35d4ac0e36f5b6f6f1a4a6c407ec</url>
  <title>Meet the crusader who 'saved our Spit'</title>
  <content>
THE greenie actor who led the successful campaign against a $3 billion casino resort on the Southport Spit has ruled out running for Labor at the looming state election.
Save Our Spit Alliance president Dr Steve Gration, who was photographed hugging Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk after she controversially dumped the project, rejected speculation he could make a tilt for State Parliament following his triumphant campaign.
Dr Gration, an actor, playwright and drama consultant who also works as a cultural ambassador for the AFL, said he had not been approached by Labor and wanted to remain an independent community campaigner.
He revealed he had only met Ms Palaszczuk once previously, at a 2015 Community Cabinet meeting on the Gold Coast, but said his members had bombarded her and her ministers with reports and research to present them with the 'facts' about The Spit development.
Dr Gration said Save Our Spit had harnessed social media to effectively rally the community, together with the experience gained in its successful fight against a Spit cruise ship terminal in the early 2000s, to defeat the casino plan.
He said 'sister' group Save Our Broadwater, led by former Beattie Government Minister Judy Spence, had helped win the battle.
Dr Gration estimated the campaign had cost his members more than $1 million in cash and donated time.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Parliament</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Community Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Steve Gration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Gration</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spit Alliance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Save Our Broadwater</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southport Spit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beattie Government Minister Judy Spence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Save Our Spit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
