<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413830261657225</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/ffa-cup-sydney-fc-beat-minnows-darwin-rovers-80/news-story/d7a4d22a66aae363d3b2290ba5a8b799</url>
  <title>Eight is enough for Sydney FC</title>
  <content>
THE Darwin Rovers fairytale failed to materialise on Wednesday night when reigning A-League champions Sydney FC wrote their own script in front of 2600 FFA Cup fans.
A double hat-trick from the Sky Blues' marquee striker Bobo highlighted the 8-0 thrashing.
The home side came close to scoring in the 80th minute when a Daniel Smith header hit the left upright, but the gulf in class between the two sides proved too much for the part timers.
Sky Blues coach Graham Arnold was a relaxed man after the win, even paying credit to Darwin Rovers for their persistence.
"We had to work very hard to get our first goal, even if it was normal in the back half of the game when we are fitter than them and we did a bit of damage.''
Rovers goalkeeper Matt Ashton, who pulled off a series of breathtaking saves all night, was called into play as early as the sixth minute when he brilliantly blocked a Bobo blast from close in, parrying a goalbound header half a minute later.
The Rovers did find their way down the other end, Chris Rowley's deflected shot creating the home side's first corner that was fisted away by Sydney 'keeper Andrew Redmayne.
But the A-League club's class when in possession meant the ball spent a lot of time in the Rovers' half.
Daniel Smith's late tackle and subsequent yellow card presented David Carney with a free kick 40 metres from goal.
His long ball into the box fell to Bobo, who hooked on goal with power and precision to beat Ashton and give the national champions a 1-0 lead.
Ten minutes later Bobo was on hand again when some over anxious Rovers defending took his legs from under him.
The Brazilian calmly slotted the ball past a wrong footed Ashton to make it 2-0, a score Carney stretched to 3-0 when his right foot shot bent the net in the left hand corner.
Sydney scored a fourth in the 51st minute, veteran Matt Simon beating an acrobatic Ashton from close range after a series of passes.
The goal glut continued when Jordy Buijs' shot was deflected into the net after 54 minutes.
Johnny Warren medallist Milos Ninkovic's strike after 71 minutes was pure class, pouncing on the good work of Sky Blues teammate Charles Lokoli Ngoy to hit the ball first time from 20 metres.
Bobo's third goal made the score 7-0 and his fourth from a spilt ball when Ashton blocked a goalbound shot stretched it to 8-0.
SYDNEY FC 8 (Bobo 24, 34, 75, 82; Carney 40; Simon 51; OG 54; Ninkovic 71) DARWIN ROVERS 0. HT: 3-0
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARWIN ROVERS 0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SYDNEY FC 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Simon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Rowley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovers</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninkovic 71</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DARWIN Rovers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham Arnold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky Blues</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Carney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Ashton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashton</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobo 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OG 54</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney FC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnny Warren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carney 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordy Buijs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Lokoli Ngoy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon 51</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milos Ninkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Redmayne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
