<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414461621864589</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/3866568/man-faces-upskirting-charges/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Man faces 'upskirting' charges</title>
  <content>
File pic

A man has been charged over numerous alleged 'upskirting' offences at Taree.
Police were called to a shopping centre at Taree on Tuesday, April 12, after a woman reported a man had filmed her while she was in a changing cubicle. The woman yelled at the man and he fled the centre.
Officers from Manning/Great Lakes Local Area Command began to investigate.
Investigators viewed CCTV footage which showed the man allegedly following a number of other women and filming them with his mobile phone.
Following more inquiries, police spoke with a 63-year-old man at a home on Bulga Road at Bobin.
They seized his phone and found multiple videos allegedly depicting women being filmed without their consent.
Six cannabis plants were also seized from the home.
The man was arrested and taken to Taree Police Station where he was charged with four counts of filming a person's private parts without consent. The charges relate to dozens of alleged incidents of 'upskirting'. He was also charged with drug offences.
The man was given bail to appear at Taree Local Court on May 10, 2016.
Inquiries into the incident continue and police urge anyone with information to come forward.

Police are urging anyone with information in relation to this incident to call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000 or use the .
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulga Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taree Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bobin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manning/Great Lakes Local Area Command</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
