<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414422967158065</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/lifestyle/why-filmmaker-cline-cousteau-turned-down-3-seats-in-first-class-20170718-gxdzsf</url>
  <title>Why filmmaker Celine Cousteau turned down First Class seats</title>
  <content>
What prompted your love affair with travel and different cultures?
My parents are French but we lived mainly in Los Angeles until I was five, so my earliest travels were between the US and the south of France. When I was nine, I went to the Amazon with my grandfather [the famous French explorer and oceanographer, Jacques-Yves Cousteau]. I spent two weeks on his research ship, Calypso. That solidified my relationship with the Amazon. I call it a "relationship" because it's tumultuous. People think the Amazon is so romantic but it's also hot, buggy; people are dying of hepatitis, malaria. But I still need to be there.
Travel should be challenging rather than easy - even transformative, you've often said.
I get to have incredible experiences through my work, filming in the Amazon or Namibia. These experiences aren't always comfortable. I come home exhausted, but extremely happy. I'm exploring a business idea that would allow people to travel in a more transformative way that shifts your perspective. It's an extension of work I already do with The Travel Corporation as a  [a not-for-profit dedicated to sustainable tourism]. I've had conversations too with Peter Raimondo from  [which facilitates wilderness-based transformational travel] in South Africa. Peter's tours are not for the faint-hearted, in a good way - you strip down to the essentials.

Jean-Michel Cousteau

In a way, you're already in the travel space of sorts. We understand your home is on Airbnb?

Yes - part of it. My husband, young son and I travel so much, it's better to rent out part of the house that doesn't have any of our personal effects while we're away.
As an avid diver, where are your top spots?
Fiji is a great place to dive, but I don't get there often. My father has an eco-resort there [Jean-Michel Cousteau Resort], but from where I live, Fiji is the other side of the planet. My son Felix is 5 1/2, and he's been in the water since the age of six months so he loves it, and my husband grew up in Noosa, Queensland. I went off to Raine Island to film and did some incredible dives with tiger sharks and nesting sea turtles, but it's hard to get access to the island. Both Lady Musgrave and Fraser islands are on my bucket list in Australia. I also loved diving in Cuba, at Gardens of the Queen [marine preserve] and with manta rays in Hawaii.
What do the next six months hold?

I'm working on entries for all the 2018 film festivals for my advocacy documentary, Tribes on the Edge. That began when the tribes of the Vale do Javari in Brazil asked me to tell their story. We did a fundraising drive in 2012 and started filming in 2013. I'm also designing a jewellery capsule for London-based fashion designer Deborah Milner.
Tips for life on the road?
I travel at least once a month but am probably the worst person to get tips on how to travel as a tourist, as I go on expeditions, not to your typical places. But I can tell you what I pack: journals and sketchbooks, one for each of the projects I'm working on. For film work, I also have my Nikon D600 camera. I live in jeans and a T-shirt.
Best Seat 1A story?

I'm usually in economy. Once when I was booked business class (this is only possible when a client flies me), I was bumped to first, where it was just me. As I'm not a demanding person, the crew didn't have much to do, so suggested I should use a number of different seats: one as my "living room", another for sleeping and a third for meals. But who needs more than one seat?

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Felix</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean-Michel Cousteau Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>First Class</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Calypso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>T-shirts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Namibia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lady Musgrave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacques-Yves Cousteau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiji</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Africa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikon D600</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raine Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seat 1A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deborah Milner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celine Cousteau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Raimondo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Travel Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean-Michel Cousteau</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gardens of the Queen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
