<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414380017484032</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/southeast/bianca-sylk-accepted-for-auditions-at-the-australian-supermodel-of-the-year-2017-competition/news-story/090745eb818882a787c04f88e8bd7b7a</url>
  <title>Bianca Sylk in model audition</title>
  <content>
BIANCA Sylk may be a petite teenager but the young woman has a fierce determin-ation to pursue her dream of becoming a model.
The past student of Salisbury-based Brisbane Christian College has been accepted for auditions at the Australian Supermodel of the Year 2017 competition.
The news vindicates Ms Sylk's desire to overcome the setbacks after being rejected by other modelling competition organisers..
"The key is not to give up ... Australian Supermodel of the Year was the last competition/agency I applied for after being rejected by many others,'' she said. "The moral of the story is that there is still hope, whether you can see it or not. I learnt ... to keep persevering until it pays off."
The 19-year-old who loves the great outdoors seemingly has it all - beauty, brains and a heart of gold.
"I am currently studying a Bachelor of Business at Griffith University and working part-time in a law firm in Brisbane city,'' Ms Sylk said.
"I love cooking for people, for me that's my way of showing love.''
"I am also a volunteer event director for my church, Hillsong Brisbane.''
But modelling motivates her most of all.
"I feel as though I can express myself and the way I feel through modelling,'' she said.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffith University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bianca Sylk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Sylk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salisbury-based Brisbane Christian College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Supermodel of the Year</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillsong Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor of Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
