<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413838851592153</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/queensland-government/deputy-prime-minister-barnaby-joyce-to-push-for-clean-coal-power-station-on-rockhampton-visit/news-story/341ace11515ee128319021bae0278829</url>
  <title>Joyce to push 'clean coal' message</title>
  <content>
A NEW clean coal power station and moving government departments to regional Queensland will be on the agenda when Deputy Prime Minister Barnaby Joyce visits Rockhampton.
Mr Joyce will arrive in town today ahead of the National Party's strategic planning meeting on Friday.
A push for a clean coal power station for north Queensland is expected to be high on the agenda. Decentralisation will also be raised ahead of all Ministers reporting back to deputy National's leader Fiona Nash later this month on which parts of their departments and agencies can be moved to the regions.

Deputy PM Barnaby Joyce has rejected a Liberal MP's claims that renewable energy policy will cause deaths.

Joyce rejects Liberal MP's energy death claim
It is understood there will be a push to ensure the decentralisation plan, intended to move jobs to the regions to boost economic growth, can show specific outcomes before the next election.
Senator Matt Canavan, when he was Minister for Northern Australia, previously revealed there had been talks held about relocating the partly government-funded Meat and Livestock Association to north Queensland.
Mr Joyce is also expected to continue to push for investment in the proposed Rookwood weir.
His trip to Rockhampton will also be part of a bid to shore up support for Capricornia MP Michelle Landry, who holds the Government's most marginal seat with a lead of less than 1 per cent.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Joyce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capricornia MP Michelle Landry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy PM Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Nash</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joyce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Livestock Associations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rookwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Prime Minister Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Matt Canavan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
