<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414294118135789</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/banking-and-finance/financial-services/etf-pioneer-plots-lowcost-robot-and-railway-funds-20170802-gxnuas</url>
  <title>ETF pioneer plots low-cost robot and railway funds</title>
  <content>
Exchanged traded fund giant ETF Securities will look to grow assets under management in Australia with a mixture of new products targeting both high growth and stable income producing assets, including a push into robotics and infrastructure. 
Founded by Financial Review rich lister and , ETF Securities pioneered the manufacture of exchange traded vehicles offering exposure to commodities, such as gold and oil, and has grown to attract $30 billion worth of investor capital from around the globe.
F, ETF Securities is plotting the next leg of its growth strategy. It will include the planned release of two ASX-listed exchange traded funds that focus on the robotics and infrastructure sectors.
The releases will build on the ground work laid by ETFS Morningstar Global Tech ETF that was listed in April and will dovetail with the global strategy of providing vanilla exposures to asset classes, such as commodities, currencies and equities alongside supercharged geared or short versions of the same products.

There is around $30 billion worth of exchange traded products on the ASX with $3.3 billion worth of the investments changing hands in June.

ETF Securities was the first to market with its gold exchanged traded fund, which allowed investors to get exposure to the precious metal that  investors have long viewed as a defensive asset in a crisis. ETFS Physical Gold, which runs on the exchange under the ticker GOLD, is worth more than half a billion dollars.
The new products will mark the next phase of growth for the global assets manager after buying out a suite of equity, currency and commodity-based ETFs from joint venture partner ANZ in April.  and withdrew shortly after achieving the milestone of $100 million in assets under management.
The two new products will invest in infrastructure and robotics/artificial intelligence and will seek to capitalise on . As neither segment has a readily available benchmark they are likely to be based on specialist indices.
The infrastructure ETF will be squarely targeted at investors in retirement seeking low volatility returns through combination of steady capital growth and reliable dividends. It will invest in traditional infrastructure assets such as railways, energy utilities and oil and gas pipelines.

It will also invest in companies that generate a material amount of earnings from infrastructure related projects. This will include airlines, transport and telecommunications companies. The portfolio has been described as not very exciting but a stable collection of assets.
It is expected to charge a management fee of less than 50 basis points and will be positioned as a cheaper alternative to active managers of global infrastructure assets such as RARE Infrastructure and Cohen & Steers.
Cohen & Steers is a US-based manager, which has $7.2 billion of assets under management and was a minority shareholder in OHL Mexico,. Cohen & Steers is the underlying manager of Argo Investment's infrastructure listed investment company that was launched in July 2015 and has attracted $266 million. The vehicle charges investors a management fee of 120 basis points per annum.
The sexier of the two funds and the one more likely to attract fund flows will be a fund focused on the world of robotics, automation and artificial intelligence.

The robotics industry, which had an estimated value of $64 billion in 2015, is expected to be worth as much as $1.2 trillion in 2025. It will be pitched as an inexpensive and fully diversified option over a growing mega trend.
Unlike Magellan, which has selectively invested in these themes across household names like Google, Apple, Alphabet, Microsoft and Facebook - ETF Securities will look for emerging names in the sector. The fund will target earnings per share growth that is at least twice that of the S&P 500.
The fund is expected to have as many as 80 constituents with 20 companies accounting for 2 per cent each and the remaining 60 companies accounting for 1 per cent each for the purposes of diversification and the higher risk nature of the investments.
The investment universe is less intuitive that its companion fund and will involve companies selected by a panel and then put through a quantitative screen which will take into account the company's home exchange, trading volumes and market capitalisation. Constituents will be required to generate a material proportion of earnings from either robotics, automation or artificial intelligence.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argo Investment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magellan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETFS Physical Gold</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cohen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETF Securities</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OHL Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RARE Infrastructure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETF</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETFs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ETFS Morningstar Global Tech ETF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Google</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
