<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414349952712116</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/maribyrnong-council-planning-to-transform-footscray-library-into-worldclass-community-hub/news-story/66af908fb334d53c0f777c7799170861</url>
  <title>Grand plan for new western community hub</title>
  <content>
FOOTSCRAY  Library will be transformed into a world-class civic, learning and arts hub under a new vision -announced by Maribyrnong Council.
The council is calling on expressions of interest to put forward early concept designs and a feasibility study on plans for a library and community and cultural hub on the existing library site in Paisley St.
Maribyrnong Mayor -Catherine Cumming said a bigger hub was needed because Footscray's population was expected to double in the next 20 years.
"Council's vision is to create an iconic building with modern innovative community facilities that everyone in the community can use and enjoy now and well into the future," Cr Cumming said.
"Planning for this facility will be a multistage process and council will explore -development partnership -opportunities with government, the development -sector and other compatible agencies."
Cr Cumming said the -council intended to ensure all people had access to quality learning and literary resources, and contemporary digital technology to enhance lifelong learning.
"Our community needs and deserves a library of the future, and this development presents an opportunity to introduce more flexible community space into Footscray that may incorporate much-needed spaces for arts, performance, recreation and social engagement opportunities for all ages," she said.
Through the tender -process, which closes on -August 14, the council wants to attract consultants at the forefront of major civic, learning, and cultural facility planning.
The council had already prepared a draft concept plan for the project in 2015, but it was later scrapped because the council did not think it addressed the full potential of the site.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Cumming</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Footscray</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maribyrnong Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maribyrnong Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paisley St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Cumming</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
