<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414461621864572</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/new-smoking-bans-are-riddled-with-loopholes-20170802-gxno7u.html</url>
  <title>New smoking bans are riddled with loopholes</title>
  <content>
Victoria is just three days into its new smoke-free outdoor dining laws and already it has descended into uncertainty and ineffectiveness. While the state government has claimed that "thanks to our new laws, smoking is off the menu", the reality is somewhat different.
To appease the powerful Australian Hotels Association, the government compromised in its drafting of the new laws to allow smoking to continue in outdoor drinking areas. This has created a loophole for traders to exploit in popular dining strips throughout Melbourne to allow smoking to continue unchecked.
Cafes and restaurants can avoid the smoking ban if they serve only "snacks" and their outdoor areas are just four metres away from any space where food is served.
This carve out to appease pubs with their private beer gardens has significantly reduced the effectiveness of the new laws in shopping strips, malls and activity centres across Melbourne with footpath trading.
With its rich Greek heritage, the bustling cafe culture of Eaton Mall in Oakleigh is widely known as Melbourne's worst place for passive smoke. It has long been impossible to walk down the mall without being blanketed by second-hand smoke emanating from the hundreds of people smoking while enjoying their meal or coffee.
However, smoking continues unimpeded (and legally) through much of Eaton Mall despite these new laws.
By carving out drinking areas, the state government has simply incentivised traders to contrive to avoid the ban. Traders can opportunistically designate their outdoor spaces as "drinking" areas for all or some periods of the day and thereby allow smoking to legally continue. Cafes and restaurants that had always served food in their outdoor areas have simply changed to just serving "snacks" to keep smokers exactly where they were.
But these laws have succeeded in creating discord among traders, confusion for the public and chaos for the hapless councils that must enforce these laws. While some traders can exploit the "drinking area" loopholes to permit smoking by their customers, others are unable to because of their proximity to another trader's dining area. So, it has created arbitrary winners and losers among traders.
The laws also make it possible for traders to "game" the system by changing their outdoor dining area to a "drinking" and smoking area at any time, which can then have flow-on impacts throughout a precinct by affecting neighbouring traders and their customers. A customer who has sat down in a smoking area may, minutes later, find themselves in an area that is converted to a no-smoking area on a whim simply because of the actions of an adjacent cafe owner. This threatens to ignite relations between already fiercely competitive traders.
In hailing the new laws, Health Minister Jill Hennessy said: "The evidence is clear. Second-hand smoke puts the health of non-smoking diners at risk." She is right. But the impact on the health of people drinking a coffee, eating a snack or just walking through these "drinking" areas is no different. By watering down the government's original intent to get passive smoke out of these public areas, the government has failed to live up to the expectations of the 73 per cent of Victorians who want these public spaces to be free of second-hand smoke.
Geoff Lake is a councillor at Monash City Council.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Lake</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Minister Jill Hennessy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Hotels Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oakleigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eaton Mall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
