<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414337067809912</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/talking-point-our-plan-for-water-has-not-been-bested/news-story/bb600c3769c1f2c5947c1cd56059cec6</url>
  <title>Our plan for water has not been bested</title>
  <content>
SINCE we first announced our plan to take control of TasWater in March this year, those opposed have failed to make out a coherent case against it.
While unfortunately there's been a lot of name calling, hyperbole and false claims, the facts remain: our plan will deliver better water and sewerage infrastructure, at a cheaper price to Tasmanians than the status quo while ensuring that councils won't need to increase rates.
Our opponents have called for us to release more information about how we will do this, and we've done so, including an independent view from respected and independent engineering contractors, Pitt and Sherry, confirming our plan to speed up the work plan is achievable. And last week, I released the draft legislation which clearly sets out how our plan will work. The legislation will establish TasWater as a government business enterprise, meaning it will be fully accountable to the Parliament and to all Tasmanians, not 29 separate councils all pulling in different directions.
The legislation is clear - TasWater can't be privatised and prices will be lower under our plan than currently proposed. And, as promised, returns to councils are locked in at the current rates until 2024-25, and after that, councils will get 50 per cent of all future profits - that is, a completely risk-free return to spend as the wish. In contrast, the legislation makes it clear that the Government's 50 per cent share of any future profits will be reinvested into the business to improve water and sewerage infrastructure which will put further downward pressure on prices. For us, it's not about profits, it's about better water and sewerage infrastructure, and cheaper prices, for Tasmanians.
It is a matter of regret that despite the fact that the draft legislation makes it abundantly clear how we will take control of TasWater, our opponents continue to falsely claim that they have legal advice saying it's unconstitutional. Not only is this false, the fact is, the legal advice TasWater received does not say that at all.
Finally, I do need to say a few words about the Labor Opposition's response to our plan. Not only are they opposed to it, they have also proposed a bizarre privatisation alternative which will drive prices even higher, and which they can't properly explain.
From what scant detail Labor have revealed, it seems they want to bring in (presumably union-owned) superannuation funds to set up some sort of joint-venture with the Government to invest in three projects only - Macquarie Point, Camerons Bay, and the Launceston combined system. The rest of the projects won't be sped up, because to Labor, moving the Macquarie Point facility is more important than upgrading water and sewerage infrastructure right across the state.
Worse, as even Ms White has now been forced to admit, "consumers will pay" for this, leading to possible price hikes of up to 18 per cent in their water and sewerage bills. Never have I seen a clearer case of Labor putting the needs of themselves and their union mates ahead of the concerns of everyday Tasmanians.
In contrast, our plan is fair for consumers, fair for councils, and fair for all Tasmanians - and I urge all members of the Upper House to consider it on its merits, not the false claims and discredited hyperbole of our opponents.
Peter Gutwein is the Minister for Local Government.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Upper House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Local Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launceston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor Opposition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TasWater</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camerons Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Government's 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Gutwein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Point</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
