<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414461621864592</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/entertainment/jono-ties-up-a-new-hot-seat/news-story/ea0c967d16e1a97f184af8459482cc3c</url>
  <title>Jono ties up a new hot seat</title>
  <content>
AFTER 19 years in the Top End, Jonathan Uptin is leaving Darwin.
But the Nine newsreader will continue to appear on Territory television screens every weekday.
Mr Uptin is moving to Brisbane to continue reading the Darwin bulletin as the network downsizes its local news service. The cuts, announced last month, will see the Darwin studio shut and up to 12 local jobs lost. One reporter and one camera operator are among those to have taken redundancies. Darwin will be folded into Nine's Queensland operations as part of the restructure.
Mr Uptin will co-host eight regional bulletins with presenter Samantha Heathwood, with local content for each market prerecorded. There will be no local weekend Nine bulletins. Mr Uptin said he made the difficult decision to leave Darwin so he could remain with the network.
"I've invested a fair amount in this news service and in being a local journo for the better part of two decades. I don't want to see a lot of that effort thrown away," he said. "I'm still a Territorian and I think it's really important we still have a Territory face as part of the news service. Even though we've still got local journos, local cameramen and there will still be local news stories, it's nice, in my opinion, to have a familiar face there who gets the local stories, who knows the pronunciation of your local suburbs.
"I know the stories here, I know the people here. I'll still be involved in our bulletin in an active way, even though it's remotely." Mr Uptin said the 2008 death of schoolboy Aidan Bott and the murder of Carlie Sinclair by her partner Danny Deacon were two of the stories that stuck with him during his time covering Territory news.
"(I was) emotionally touched by the raw grief of the families involved and their courage in coming forward and sharing their stories. To see their raw emotion was really powerful," he said.
He thanked the community and other local media outlets for their support after the cuts were announced.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Heathwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Uptin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Deacon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine's Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Uptin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territorians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlie Sinclair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aidan Bott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
