<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414332772842548</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/buckley-st-essendon-level-crossing-moonee-valley-mayor-slams-lxra/news-story/6ad2906d56e5d76ffae785e2c4790236</url>
  <title>Community 'in dark' over crossing</title>
  <content>
THE Buckley St, Essendon, level crossing removal project is riddled with unanswered questions, says the Moonee Valley Mayor.
Cr Andrea Surace said the Level Crossing Removal Authority was keeping the council and the community in the dark.
"As with each stage of this process thus far, it appears the LXRA is trying to push this project through behind closed doors," Cr Surace said.
The LXRA is seeking an amendment to the Moonee Valley Planning Scheme.
The council has recently obtained copies of the incorporated document for the LXRA's planning scheme amendment proposal, showing an area stretching nearly 2km in either direction of Essendon station, which would be under the LXRA's control until 2029.
"What is not clear is whether this 'free pass' also applies to any developments on the surrounding VicTrack land, which could leave us at the whim of developers," Cr Surace said.
Cr Surace said the Planning Minister Richard Wynne ought to refer the entire project to the Victorian Transport Projects Advisory Committee.
Project director Michael Caink rejected Cr Surace's concerns saying the process applied to Buckley St was no different to all other level crossing removal projects approved so far.
He said the LXRA was reviewing all submissions received for the planning scheme amendment.
Meanwhile, questions have also been raised as to whether contracts for the removal of the crossing have actually been signed.
In May, Public Transport Minister Jacinta Allen said contracts for the removal project had been signed, with an alliance led by John Holland and KBR awarded the contract for Buckley St.
But information obtained through the Freedom of Information Act by a member of the public shows on June 25, 2017 the alliance had not been awarded the contract, with the LXRA requesting the alliance commence preparation of a proposal for the delivery of the project.
Mr Caink said a contract was in place, but was dependant on the successful completion of level crossing removals in Frankston and Campbellfield.
He said the John Holland and KBR alliance was finalising a price and design for the Buckley St removal project.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Surace</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedom of Information</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KBR</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Transport Minister Jacinta Allen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LXRA</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonee Valley Planning Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian Transport Projects Advisory Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Caink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Minister Richard Wynne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Level Crossing Removal Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buckley St</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 25, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VicTrack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Caink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Holland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Campbellfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonee Valley Mayor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Andrea Surace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
