<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414388607418872</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/life/rollsroyces-next-phantom-the-top-model-range-rover-plans-sedans/news-story/526b7a5650aaf5036721344565169b93</url>
  <title>Phantom claims superiority</title>
  <content>
Rolls-Royce has unveiled the next Phantom, its flagship limousine, declaring it to be the "world's leading luxury item" that reaffirms its position as "the best car in the world".
Since 1925, it says, when the first Phantom was recognised as superior to all-comers, every new version has set the benchmark thanks to "Rolls-Royce's tireless pursuit of perfection, visionary engineering, aesthetic acuity and deep understanding of what the world's leading luxury item should be". The eighth generation, the second to be produced under BMW ownership, ushers in a completely new platform that will become the basis for all future models, including its first SUV, codenamed Cullinan.
Rather than the monocoque construction of most cars, it features an aluminium spaceframe that is both lighter and stiffer than before. It signals an end to platform sharing with its German parent, with the next version of the Ghost junior limousine and its derivatives moving on to the new architecture when they are overhauled. The existing models share underpinnings with BMW's 7 Series.
The redesign also includes four-wheel steering, new front suspension and "state-of-the-art chassis control systems". The suspension uses a camera to read the road ahead, adjusting the damping proactively. Rolls has dubbed the system Flagbearer in a reference to the early days of motoring when someone carrying a red flag was required to walk ahead of a car.
Phantom also gets a new 6.8-litre twin-turbo V12, replacing the previous naturally aspirated unit. With 420kW of power and 900Nm of torque, it combines "calm low-speed progress associated with state occasions and an unfussed surge of power when one needs to press on".
A satellite assisted eight-speed transmission anticipates the need for gearshifts. The loudest thing in the cabin is the clock, thanks to double-glazed windows, a double-skin floor and 130kg of sound deadening. The huge 22-inch wheels run specially developed tyres that include a foam layer to eliminate noise.

The latest electronic technology makes Phantom "the most advanced luxury motor car available" while the dashboard becomes a gallery to display bespoke artworks, such as "a gold-plated 3-D-printed map of an owner's DNA created by the enfant terrible of German product design Thorsten Franck". There's loads of wood and leather, of course, plus a drinks cabinet, picnic tables and starlight headliner.
From the outside it appears similar to the current model but that overlooks the car's taller, more integrated grille, laser headlights that can project 600m and the "few, if any, visible join lines between body panels, giving New Phantom the appearance of being hewn from a solid block of aluminium". We should see the New Phantom in the Australian market later this year, with pricing in excess of $1 million.
One can't wait to have a go.
British SUV specialist Land Rover could in future make a car, according to design boss Gerry McGovern, who says the brand is going through the most exciting period in its history.
"There are big challenges, but massive opportunities. Land Rover has the ability to create scale and do lots of things people wouldn't expect it to do," says McGovern, who was presenting the new Range Rover Velar in Norway last week.
"Most of the other manufacturers have moved into our territory, but we've got established heritage and we're still the best in off-road capability. We can use that authenticity to do other things - the most capable vehicles in an urban environment, for example. Now our vehicles are operating in the jungle, but it's the urban jungle."
McGovern says the Velar, an SUV that sits between Evoque and Range Rover Sport, is its most car-like vehicle yet but future Range Rovers could converge with sedans. "If Bentley can do an SUV, why can't we do a luxury saloon?"
Porsche has become the latest convert to Formula E, the racing category for electric single-seaters that began just three years ago. The move comes at the expense of its involvement with the top-tier category in the World Endurance Championship after two title-winning seasons and three consecutive victories in the Le Mans 24 Hours, the series' blue-ribbon event.
Porsche says participation in the electric formula from 2019 aligns its motorsport efforts with its road car strategy as it commits to producing a mix of "pure GT vehicles and fully electric sports cars". The first, Mission E, is also due in 2019 and boss Oliver Blume reportedly expects it to be the first of many, with a second battery car based on the Macan SUV already in the works and up to half of all Porsches electric by 2023. Other recent recruits to Formula E include Mercedes and BMW.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>kW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macan SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rovers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phantom</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>V12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Formula E</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mercedes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thorsten Franck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Endurance Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mission E</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUV</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Land Rover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver Blume</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>D-printed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Range Rover Velar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cullinan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Range Rover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>British SUV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Mans 24 Hours</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evoque</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerry McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porsche</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Phantom</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Range Rover Sport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW 7-Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
