<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414165269114117</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/politics/govt-mulls-noncompulsory-postal-plebiscite-on-samesex-marriage-20170801-gxnhqi</url>
  <title>Malcolm Turnbull mulls non-compulsory postal plebiscite on same-sex marriage</title>
  <content>
The federal government is actively exploring a non-compulsory postal plebiscite on same-sex marriage to try and end the crippling internal dispute that threatens MPs' careers and the Prime Minister's leadership.
But with Parliament to resume on Tuesday, there was no sign that a group of rebel MPs who are determined to cross the floor to force a vote on a private member's bill, were going to back off.
Liberal rebel Queensland MP Warren Entsch hit back angrily at threats that his preselection and that of others, including Liberal National Party colleague Trevor Evans, who are preparing to cross the floor will be targeted and their careers snuffed out.
"I have every right to be able to express a view, I have every right to vote according to my conscience," Mr Entsch said.

Richard Wainwright

"I have been working on this issue now for well over a decade. I am proud to say that I am doing it. I am not going to back off on it."

Tony Abbott, whose own leadership fell in part due to party tensions over same-sex marriage, warned the rebels that not only would their actions be "a real breach of faith with the public" and a "dramatic loss of discipline inside the government", they would also be " a serious attack on the authority of the leadership".
Mr Abbott said if a public vote endorsed same-sex marriage, "fair enough, I'll accept that" but if not, "that should settle the matter, if not for all time, but for our time".
Mr Turnbull and other senior moderates have been urging the rebels, both privately and publicly, to reconsider breaking ranks when Parliament resumes next week out of fear it will blow the party apart.
but the Senate blocked the legislation. The rebels argue they have discharged their obligation towards a plebiscite while the conservatives argue any policy change now would be a fundamental breach of an election promise.

.
Leading conservative Peter Dutton has been trying to broker a way through with a postal plebiscite. The government, which is seeking advice, believes it would not require legislation.
Liberal Senator Dean Smith, who is leading the change to force a vote next week, called the proposal "divisive" and "junk".
One senior source said the postal vote would tick the box in that the public would be given a say as promised and, given neither side has already said they would be bound by its outcome, the government could then proceed quickly to a parliamentary vote and resolve the issue before Christmas.

Mr Turnbull continued to dodge questions on whether he supported a postal ballot, but left such a possibility wide open.
"We went to the election with a clear commitment to hold a national vote on the issue and give every Australian a say on the issue of same-sex marriage," he said.
Nationals leader Barnaby Joyce has insisted his party, which overwhelmingly opposes same-sex marriage, wants to be part of the party room discussion.
In 2015, Mr Abbott riled many LIberals by including the Nationals in a party room discussion because it diluted support for change.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland MP Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richard Wainwright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal National Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
