<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414332772842557</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/lifestyle/health/daughter-sells-all-for-dying-mum/news-story/6d4ff230dd0bf54211c4acd454f79cc7</url>
  <title>Daughter sells all for dying mum</title>
  <content>
A DESPERATE daughter has flogged everything she owns in a last-ditch attempt to save her mum from cancer.
Lori Harris, 27, and mum Lisa have sold all their possessions to pay for pioneering immunotherapy treatment not available in the UK.
The mum says the treatment is her only chance of survival and has already halved the size of tumours in her body,
She has undergone treatment every three weeks since February at a cost of £25,000 ($41,328) in Stuttgart, Germany.
Lori and Lisa, from Barley Mow, near Chester-le-Street, have now sold their cars and Lisa sold the family home for funds.
Loving Lori told: "All my efforts are going into raising money for this, I have got to, she's my mam."
Lisa was dealt the devastating blow in 2015 that her ovarian cancer was terminal and she had just two years to live.
Then in January, medics told her it was unlikely she would survive another eight weeks.
Lori began frantically searching for a miracle and read about immunotherapy, which boosts the body's natural defences to fight cancer.
In an update on her mum's Go Fund Me page, Lori wrote: "My mam has had incredible results and we heard from the doctor last week that she is 'almost in remission' and 'if money was not an issue I could get her into remission sooner rather than later'.
"To hear this broke my heart and to think that because she has reacted so well to the immunotherapy treatment, it is only money keeping us away from remission and a chance at a future together.
"I'm in £50,000 ($82,657) of debt myself, I have nothing left to sell but this is what I have to do, I will never ever give up. My mam means more than anything I could ever own."
She said she was left heartbroken when her "idol" mum was first diagnosed with the brutal illness, adding: "I'm an only child and yet to get married and have her grandchildren. So much will be missed if she leaves us too soon."
This article was
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuttgart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barley Mow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lori Harris, 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester-le-Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lori</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Go Fund Me</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
