<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414345657744760</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/opinion/editorial-big-day-for-fish-farmers/news-story/13622ca41c7d0b4211bebbdb3d9df1ca</url>
  <title>Big day for fish farmers</title>
  <content>
BY any measure, yesterday was a landmark day for the state's aquaculture industry.
The State Government announced, under its soon-to-be-unveiled and fairly wordy Sustainable Salmon Industry Growth Plan, that the North-West and King Island had been identified as potentially favourable for fish farming.
Petuna, it said, had expressed a desire to look at areas near Three Hummock Island.

The Government said the expansion would build on jobs and support a North-West region which had been hit hard in recent times, especially by the impending closure of Murray Goulburn's Edith Creek plant.
On the same day, Tassal announced it had received the final tick of approval under the Commonwealth Environmental Protection and Biodiversity Conservation Act, which will enable it to start putting fish in the water at Okehampton Bay.
In the same breath, it was named the No. 2 aquaculture business in the world for transparent corporate, social and environmental reporting, according to seafood industry analyst Seafood Intelligence's Transparency Benchmarking Report.

Meanwhile, on the other side of the debate, a Michelin-starred chef, East Coast winemakers and an oyster farmer joined a protest at the site of the Okehampton Bay fish farm and Environment Tasmania and the Greens hit back at the decision to allow fish farming.
It was a lot to take in.
There is little doubt the Government's first announcement will be welcomed by North-West Coast workers and long-suffering communities, particularly those left reeling by the shock Edith Creek decision.
It also is a strong sign from the State Government that it intends to increase support for an industry it views as vital to the future of the state's economy.
Likewise, it has no intention of backing away from its support for Okehampton Bay.
Its rationale will likely be that, in an election context at least, the community is far more concerned about any loss of jobs than it is about fish farms in general - something which has been supported by recent polling. (It will be nonetheless interesting to see how this plays out in Lyons at the next state poll).
But the challenge still remains for the Government and the industry to bring the community along with it for the ride.
The political heat around fish farming has been immense in recent months. It is attracting, on both sides, everyone and anyone with a barrow to push.
The state is right to support the industry but equally it is duty bound to ensure all processes are open and transparent, that the community is engaged from the start to the finish, that mistakes are not papered over and that the grave errors of Macquarie Harbour are forever etched in the brains of those responsible and no short cuts are ever taken again.
Those at the coalface can never again blame a lack of knowledge or foresight.
From here, it is only through an open, honest and engaging process - and at some point the unification of the industry itself - that many of the divisions and concerns will subside. There is no other way.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sustainable Salmon Industry Growth Plan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Three Hummock Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edith Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelin-starred</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seafood Intelligence's Transparency Benchmarking Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okehampton Bay</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Environmental Protection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>King Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Biodiversity Conservation Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North-West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petuna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murray Goulburn's Edith Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tassal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macquarie Harbour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North West</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
