<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414461621864616</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/opinion/homeless-issue-is-nts-shame/news-story/5eee7d037175d3baf6a1ab3368b0dc23</url>
  <title>Homeless issue is NT's shame</title>
  <content>
IF the best measure of a society is how it treats its most vulnerable, the plight of the Territory's homeless population marks us as a failure.
In some parts of the Territory, the public housing waiting list is six to eight years long.
All up, there are more than 3000 people on the waiting list, most of whom are living pay cheque to pay cheque, if they even have a pay cheque.
The figures released today by Mission Australia show almost 5 per cent of Territorians are homeless.
Many of those people are grappling with other issues in their lives. Some might be fleeing domestic violence, dealing with mental health issues or addiction.
It is particularly concerning that so many young people and children don't have a stable home.
A homeless child is unlikely to be doing well at school, and the issues at home are likely to add extra strain to the Territory's already-troubled education system.
Kids Under Cover chief executive Jo Swift is right when she says taking action isn't just the right thing to do, it also makes economic sense.
It is all too easy for Territorians to become immune to the sheer size of the homelessness issue we live among.
It's easy to forget that every person sleeping rough likely has a deeply troubled life and is living well short of his or her potential.
Sadly, homelessness and all the problems that come with it have plagued the Territory for decades. Many of the good intentions of governments seem to have failed to make a noticeable difference.
The problem now seems insurmountable, and in need of a generation of genuine effort to resolve.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mission Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Swift</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territorians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
