<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414422967158085</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/hyperloop-one-successful-test-192-2017-8</url>
  <title>Hyperloop One's passenger pod almost hit 200 mph in its latest test</title>
  <content>
Startup Hyperloop One had another successful test of its Hyperloop technology.

On Saturday, Hyperloop One completed its second successful test to-date on its 500-meter development track in Nevada, the company said. The startup said the system travelled 315 feet and reached a top speed of 192 mph. The vehicle coasted above the track using magnetic levitation.

Hyperloop One's  in mid-July was much slower; it only reached 70 mph and travelled for 5.3 seconds.

The Hyperloop is a nascent transportation system that works by shooting pods through a vacuumed-sealed tube at speeds that experts say could reach 700 mph. The concept was popularised in 2013 when Tesla and SpaceX CEO Elon Musk released a "" outlining how the system will work.

Hyperloop still has some ways to go to demonstrate a system that can connect cities.

The startup currently has feasibility studies under way in  and  Hyperloop One has also said it is in talks with regulators and city officials about .

The futuristic transit system is also being pursued by Hyperloop One's ousted cofounder, .

Musk said in July his latest venture, The Boring Company, has received "" to build a Hyperloop between New York and Washington DC, but  with the proposal.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boring Company</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SpaceX CEO Elon Musk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyperloop One</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nevada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Musk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyperloop</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
