<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414380017484028</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/the-economy/no-more-cash-wages-says-black-economy-taskforce-20170802-gxnxp8.html</url>
  <title>No more cash wages, says Black Economy Taskforce</title>
  <content>
Australians would no longer be able to receive wages in cash, and industries classified as being at "high risk" of illegally taking secret cash-in-hand payments including cafes and restaurants could be subject to a minimum rate of tax, which they could claim a refund on if they can prove to the tax man that they should be paying a lower rate.
These are some of the options being explored by the federal government's Black Economy Taskforce, which also include naming and shaming tax evaders and replacing $100 notes with new ones to ensure their authenticity.Photo: Michel O'Sullivan
On Tuesday the taskforce released a consultation paper that canvasses a number of additional policy ideas to tackle anand illegitimate welfare payments due to widespread cash economy activity.
Black Economy Taskforce chairman Michael Andrew - who has previously described Australians taking cash-only payments and not - has been holding industry roundtables and public forums across the nation.Photo: Louise Kennerley
Minister for Revenue and Financial Services Kelly O'Dwyer said the 54 ideas outlined in Mr Andrews' paper are not recommendations, but intended for public comment and reaction, before the taskforce hands down its final report in October.
A 'minimum' tax rate

One of the more controversial options in the consultation paper include setting a floor under the tax businesses pay. In some other countries high-risk businesses may be subject to "rule of thumb" tax assessments. "We understand that in Spain, for example, restaurants are taxed according to the number of employees they have," the paper notes.

While the taskforce does not support this particular approach for Australia, the paper raises the idea of an alternative minimum tax for high-risk sectors. "Businesses affected by any such tax would be able to claim a refund if they could demonstrate they should be paying a lower rate," the paper said. "A less radical alternative would be to make greater use of withholding arrangements for problematic sectors."
The paper also suggests non-cash payment of wages. And under this approach no tax deductions could be claimed for cash wages, regardless of whether they were documented or not, it said.Photo: Wayne Taylor
 noting that's mainly what clubs and gaming operators use. But it highlights RBA figures showing the $100 note accounts for 46 per cent (in value terms) of all local currency on issue. "While an outright ban is unlikely to be effective, an organised changeover - requiring all holders of $100 notes to exchange them for new ones - might be considered," it said.
Biometric verification 

Most criminals use encrypted mobile phones and apps to avoid monitoring by the authorities. The paper asked whether possession of these phones should be made an offence. "In effect, they would be treated as contraband," it said.
The paper also called for greater verification of individuals. "In a world where tax, welfare, immigration and commercial fraud is made easier by the use of false identities - there are 150 million identities in various databases in Australia - a more robust, reliable and efficient identity system is urgently needed."
The taskforce's interim report had said the Australian Business Number (ABN) system should be strengthened. "Behind every commercial entity, and straw-man director, is an individual or group of people." Photo: Paul Rovere
It suggested biometric markers or non-biometric personal identifiers to protect against identity theft. Minister O'Dwyer is considering proposals for a company director ID number to tackle phoenixing activity, but has come under fire from Labor for not moving fast enough. "In our view, any initiative in this area should be consistent with (rather than adding another layer to) a broader community ID scheme," the paper said.
Labor's Andrew Leigh urged the government not to walk away from such identification. "It's easier to become a company director than it is to open a bank account," he said. "A 100-point ID check would be consistent with other identification regimes."
Better enforcement, info sharing

The paper also suggested specialist tax tribunals as a "valuable addition to our enforcement armoury" to increase the potential for more prosecutions. "Research shows that if there is a risk of conviction, as opposed to financial sanctions, people are less likely to take compliance risks," the paper noted.
It also suggested a national criminal database for better data sharing between Commonwealth departments and across different levels of government. "Constructing such a database will inevitably entail some cost and take time, but if done well this would be an invaluable resource," it said.
In some cases tax privacy provisions prevent reasonable sharing of information between the ATO and other departments.  "If, for example, some sharing economy operators report contractor payments to the ATO, this information should be able to be shared with the Department of Social Services to identify cases of welfare fraud," it said.
About 70 per cent of Australia's criminal fraternity are either offshore or have very strong links offshore. But there is no requirement to advise other countries' border authorities of large cash bundles seized from people leaving the country. The paper said two-way exchange of this information could bring significant law enforcement benefits.
It also suggested making it easier for Australian authorities to establish beneficial owners who are based overseas, and identify businesses that split their payrolls into two: an Australian one that pays the minimum wage and an undeclared one held offshore that transfers funds into foreign accounts.
The paper said , partly because they did not offer confidentiality. It suggested a whistleblower hotline - a single point of contact for serious black economy-related allegations --not just tax-related, but including immigration and welfare fraud, suspected phoenixing, links to organised crime, illegal tobacco and gambling. It also suggested a Black Economy Ombudsman could be appointed to ensure complaints are properly responded to.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Economy Taskforce</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Business Number</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Services Kelly O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor's Andrew Leigh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Economy Ombudsman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister O'Dwyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Rovere</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Kennerley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Social</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ATO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michel O'Sullivan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
