<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414294118135797</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/chester-bennington-mural-stopped-traffic-on-los-angeles-highway-2017-8</url>
  <title>A memorial mural of Linkin Park's Chester Bennington stopped traffic on a busy Los Angeles highway</title>
  <content>
A California muralist painted a portrait of the late Linkin Park singer Chester Bennington on a wall near the 101 freeway in Los Angeles last weekend, and a congestion of stopped cars on the busy highway reportedly cheered him on with honks and encouragement.

Jonas Never, the muralist, took two days to spray paint a 20-foot mural of Bennington on the back of a new pizzeria in Sherman Oaks, California.

Bennington  of apparent suicide in his L.A. home. 

"I grew up listening to [Chester]," Never told . "When I heard Chester died, I immediately thought of that wall because I knew some of the band members lived in the Valley. I just texted Jim [Conners, the pizzeria owner] and offered to do it for free because it was the right thing to do."

Conners, the owner of Rock N' Pies pizzeria, told Variety that the mural has brought attention to his restaurant and even caused a commotion of sorts on the 101 highway bordering the back of the store.

"I was leaving the kitchen last night at 11:30, and I was greeted by flashing lights, people taking pictures," Conners told the outlet. "When Jonas was working on it, everyone in their cars on the 101 were beeping their horns and cheering him on."

Bennington was laid to rest over the weekend as well. His family held a  Saturday afternoon near the singer's home in Palos Verdes, California.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>L.A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linkin Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conner</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sherman Oaks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linkin Park's Chester Bennington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennington</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palos Verdes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonas Never</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rock N' Pies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester Bennington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
