<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414298413103221</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/harvey-norman-threw-a-mini-snes-sale-and-forgot-to-tell-anyone/</url>
  <title>Harvey Norman Threw A Mini SNES Sale And Forgot To Tell Anyone</title>
  <content>
At approximately 10pm, Harvey Norman . If you didn't hear about the sale, you're not alone - no announcements were made on social media and no press release was issued to media. We only just found out about the sale via a . By then, stock had already sold out.

We're so conflicted about this.

To be honest, we're not sure how we're supposed to feel right now. On the one hand, Harvey Norman refrained from whipping up hype for what was surely a small number of units. This would have resulted in thousands of disappointed customers, just like every other Nintendo mini console sale.

On the other hand, most of us were denied the chance, however small it may have been, to actually nab one. We're trying to decide which is worse - attempting to buy a Mini SNES and failing, or not being informed about the sale at all. At least there are no website crashes this way, we guess.

With ,  and even jumping the gun with pre-orders, most allotted stock within Australia has surely been exhausted.

As we have , attempting to buy a Mini SNES on launch day is going to be hell. Hopefully, the usual retailers will pull some extra units out of their collective sleeve and we'll be treated to another flash sale. And hopefully they'll actually let us know about it this time. The resulting online scrum is going to suck, but at least we'll have a fighting chance.

It's official. after the runaway success of the Nintendo Classic Mini NES, Nintendo is releasing a retro remake of the Super Nintendo video game console. Boasting 21 of the best games from the 16-bit era, two SNES controllers and a nostalgic SNES design, the Super Nintendo Classic Edition is going to be one of the hottest items this Christmas. Here's everything you need to know - including links to pre-order right now!

[Via ]

WATCH MORE: Tech & Finance News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Forgot To Tell Anyone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey Norman Threw A Mini SNES Sale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SNES</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Nintendo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mini SNES</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey Norman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nintendo Classic Mini NES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Nintendo Classic Edition</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finance News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
