<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414332772842500</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/locals-demand-details-on-huge-kingswood-golf-club-development-in-dingley-village/news-story/ad52323e0f9dd6e7bec06bf86697d3b3</url>
  <title>Battle lines drawn over huge estate</title>
  <content>
HUNDREDS of people turned out to quiz developers about a massive residential project that would transform Kingswood Golf Course into a housing estate.
Locals have extensively campaigned against the controversial Dingley Village development but developer ASRP1 said the information session, hosted by Kingston Council, paved the way forward for the huge build.
Plans, first lodged in March last year, were for 800 homes and a community precinct on the golf course, which is just 2km from Moorabbin Airport.
But ASRP1 has since refined their proposal in the hope of winning Kingston Council's support.
It has reduced the number of houses to 760 and doubled the developers' community contributions so the council can improve infrastructure in Dingley Village; and a $15 million investment to combat flooding.
"Our masterplanned community will be an exceptional development and we are determined it will benefit the existing community as well as being a great place to live for newcomers," the project's senior development manager, Anna Martiniello, said.
"This investment will ensure many existing Dingley Village homes never again experience flooding."
But Save Kingswood Group secretary Kevin Poulter said, despite the changes to the plans, the development didn't tie in with existing neighbourhood character and the loss of tree-lined open space would be an "environmental disaster".
"We're against the proposal full stop," Mr Poulter said.
"The golf course is a central part of Dingley Village ... it's the lungs and heart of Dingley Village and they want to destroy it."
Kingston Council's Planning and Development General Manager Jonathan Guttmann said about 175 people attended the public meeting and asked about the traffic impact; ability of local schools to meet growing demand and the loss of the golf club's open space.
Before any development can go ahead, the land must first be rezoned, and councillors are expected to decide in August or September whether to ask Planning Minister Richard Wynne to begin that process.
Property fund giant ISPT bought the 53.4ha in 2014 for $125 million and it is believed the Peninsula Kingswood Country Golf Club would vacate the site in April.
Project details can be found at kingswooddingleyvillage.com.au
Register for the council's updates via email at
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Martiniello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peninsula Kingswood Country Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston Council</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingswood Golf Course</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Save Kingswood Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Development General Manager Jonathan Guttmann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASRP1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dingley Village</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISPT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Planning Minister Richard Wynne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingston Council's Planning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moorabbin Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Poulter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Poulter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
