<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414337067809865</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4797929/bit-by-bit-the-quirks-of-city-become-history/?cs=308</url>
  <title>Bit by bit the quirks of city become history</title>
  <content>
MEMORIES: As Newcastle transforms during a period of rapid revitalisation, some are concerned it is losing all of the historic and quirky structures that made it unique.

WICKHAM station was built in 1936. Instead of dismantling the station's architectural features for resale and recycling and reusing its bricks and timbers, it was simply bulldozed into a heap of rubble that will no doubt end up in landfill, and another small part of Newcastle's history is gone. 
I understand that cities need to develop and adapt but all the high-rise buildings being constructed and touted on billboards around the west end of Hunter Street bear more resemblance to what I saw in Soviet Russia than what I would like to see in a modern rejuvenation of my city. 
Sadly profit in the bank accounts of developers is all that seems to be currently driving Newcastle's redevelopment. We are destined to lose all the quirkiness I love about my home town and that makes me sad because our descendants will have nothing but photographs to show them what was once there and has gone.
Ann Ellis, Merewether

True democracy

POLITICAL independence is the big issue for the coming council election. The role of political parties in local government needs examination. Though it may be accepted that local government is the breeding ground for aspiring politicians, how parties affect local decision-making is the problem.

Over the last two decades we have seen many claims of Newcastle council being 'dysfunctional' or recently 'toxic'. When you examine the underlying causes of these claims I think it almost always comes back to party politics. In my experience, savvy individuals and obsessive minority interest groups are experts at applying pressure on political parties to adopt caucus voting (party-line) to push their narrow view instead of the best interests of the whole community. Every elected person can be accused of leaning in some particular political direction, but only independents can be free to vote as they wish, resulting in true democracy.

The simple message for this election is - vote independent. Taking it further, never give a preference vote to a political party.
Bob Cook, former Newcastle councillor

No excuse for abuse

I READ with interest Hayley New's opinion ('Customer abuse of staff is out of control', Herald, 1/8) and have to agree. Being in retail for 35 years, I've seen and heard it all. It's only a small minority, the ones who expect you to kiss their arse as they are the most important person in the world.

We have trained a lot of apprentices and expect our customers to treat them with the same respect our qualified butchers deserve. In return, the apprentice understands the responsibility of their customer service role. Self esteem and confidence are what our young workers need, the boss has a responsibility to create a harmonious environment. 

Customers, please think about the young person trying to help and if there is dissatisfaction use the right channels to voice your concern. Abusing a worker is not the way and in our business you won't be welcome.
Steve Barnett, Fingal Bay

Bags in demand

EVEN at the risk of the whole of my comment not being recognised but instead only smaller parts incorrectly being a point of focus by some, I must write this. I am fed up with supermarkets and others claiming they are 'listening to their customers' and hence phasing out plastic bags.
Firstly, if customers didn't want them they wouldn't use them. Secondly, we want a product that is less-damaging to the environment but equally practical - time for research and development.
Also, will supermarkets be phasing out the many products that have multiple plastic bags within them, and perhaps also the fruit bags and so on? Unlikely. Seems the easy option is for the consumer to bear the costs (financial and practical).
We still have to buy plastic bags for garbage lining - and these then go to the rubbish tip taking a long time to break down. Currently, we use shopping bags for this - now we will have to pay more for these other plastic bags to fill the same purpose, and with no better outcome for the environment. There's also the issue of increased bacteria growth - reusing bags which have chicken/meat (spills can occur, or even touching against sides) - there is a real chance of this being problematic and spreading bacteria and diseases. Ah, I hear you saying that you can clean the bag, I'd suggest not adequately, or at least the cost and environmental impact of cleaning defeats the purpose. So we end up buying another reusable bag, these also cost the environment and don't break down. I recognise the environmental issue; however, there needs to be better solutions, such as developing plastic bags that break-down much more quickly.
Please remember, cane toads were introduced to eradicate the cane beetle ... and now the cane toad is the problem.
Peter Howley, Adamstown Heights

No justification

IN response to Jeremy Bath (Letters, 2/8), I would like to reasonably request you and Newcastle City Council explain to me how you intend to minimise the disturbance of turning my quiet residential street into a racetrack? I would suggest that is impossible given these cars will be racing three metres from our living rooms. And the crowds, music concerts, helicopters, loudspeakers? Can we live normal lives in our homes during this event? I don't see how.
Claims around economic benefits are grossly exaggerated and in no way justify the imposition. In supporting this event, Newcastle council and the NSW government are abrogating their most basic responsibility to provide amenity to local residents. In response to reasonable objections we are stonewalled and vilified.
This race should be held in an appropriate location - a racetrack.
Brett McFadyen, Newcastle East

East End won't thank you

IN reply to Jeremy Bath (Letters,1/8): Your last paragraph about people in the western suburbs thanking you for bringing the Supercars to Newcastle says everything. You show absolutely no empathy for the East Enders. Inner city dwellers could accept the temporary loss of utility of their neighbourhood for public works improvement, but it's the annual loss of utility that Supercars will inflict for years to come that will be intolerable, including being barricaded in their homes by high fencing, checkpoints, excessive noise and a racetrack metres from their front doors. No wonder they're not lining up to thank you, Jeremy. 

Melissa Graham, Merewether

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brett McFadyen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East End</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Soviet Russia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adamstown Heights</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ann Ellis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Howley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Bath</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hayley New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Barnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Enders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herald, 1/8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wickham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fingal Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
