<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414427262125441</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/bmw-gears-up-for-innercity-future-20170728-gxl2fm</url>
  <title>It's all about mobility: BMW plots an inner-city future</title>
  <content>
Prestige car maker BMW is bucking the trend of many inner-city dealers, with a plan to secure its position in central Melbourne through selling, redeveloping and leasing back at least part of its Southbank site.
The 6000-square-metre plot on the corner of Southbank Boulevard and City Road will hit the market within days, with expectations of $100 million or more.
The catch is that BMW Australia aims not to simply pocket whatever upside it gains and walk away. Instead, as its chief executive in Australia Marc-Heinrich Werner explained, the luxury German brand will hitch its chariot to the rise in inner-urban living.
Disruption, according Mr Werner, is to be embraced, not avoided.   

Wayne Taylor

"It is easy just to sell a site," he told The Australian Financial Review. "You put it on the market, it goes to auction, then you are done with it. We want to take a completely different approach."

For BMW, that means a development deal that will allow it to retain a presence of about 1500 sq m, through a lease or strata title, at the site of its home for the past decade.
It will become part of a larger mixed-use development. Architects Fender Katsalidis have worked up a scheme of two towers joined by a sky-bridge, potentially comprising 800 apartments, 550 hotel rooms and 10,000 sq m of commercial space.
And already BMW is reimagining itself more broadly as a provider of what Mr Werner terms "mobility services".
That includes supplying electric vehicles, autonomously driven cars and even, perhaps surprisingly, car-sharing vehicles.

"This is what we want to tap into, which will happen," Mr Werner said.
Big changes in the automotive industry, broader shifts in inner-city living and the surging residential property market in Southbank are the ingredients of Mr Werner's vision for the site.
"We're connecting the dots: it is a strategy which will future-proof our business in the CBD area," he said.
It is a contrast to other brands such as ,  and , which have given up their sprawling inner-city sites.

Architect Karl Fender is not only a Southbank resident but has worked on some of the precinct's best-known apartment towers, including Eureka Tower and 
BMW's corner site, a position made more prominent by the curve of City Road, will join a trilogy of towers that define Southbank, according to Mr Fender.
"It is even more of a standout than Eureka or Australia 108. It is the focus of the bend in the road."
With approaches from developers already, BMW has appointed CBRE's Mark Wizel, Josh Rutman, Julian White and Lewis Tong to broker the site.

"It's the sort of opportunity that is very likely to draw interest from an offshore group that has not yet made an entry into the Australian market," Mr Wizel said. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Road</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karl Fender</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lewis Tong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBRE's Mark Wizel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southbank Boulevard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Werner</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wayne Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southbank</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Marc-Heinrich Werner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eureka Tower</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wizel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BMW Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fender Katsalidis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Rutman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eureka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 108</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
