<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414375722516685</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/street-talk/anz-bank-gets-flagstaff-partners-to-sail-across-the-ditch-20170801-gxnh9b</url>
  <title>ANZ Bank gets Flagstaff Partners to sail across the ditch </title>
  <content>
Just when you thought ANZ Banking Group's divestment spree couldn't get any bigger there's a new strategic review afoot. 
Street Talk can reveal the Melbourne-based lender has boutique adviser Flagstaff Partners on hand to help it assess strategic options for its life insurance business in New Zealand. 
That unit had net insurance income of $NZ85 million in the six months ended March 31, broadly flat on $NZ83 million in the same period a year earlier. ANZ provides investors with a trading update on August 15, but rules off its financial year on September 30. 
Flagstaff is close to the bank and is chaired by former ANZ chairman Charles Goode. The firm has assisted ANZ on a number of strategic projects over the past three years. They include a sell-side mandate for ANZ's online broking unit which was this year divested to UK-listed CMC Markets. 

The main game for ANZ this year, however, is the sale of its Australian wealth operations which encompass life insurance and funds management. Goldman Sachs is managing that auction and the bank may fetch a price tag in the order of $4.5 billion. 

They include pan-Asia life insurer AIA Group, Swiss insurance behemoth Zurich and US player Metlife, which will be doing their best to put together binding bids over the coming weeks in what is proving to be a highly-complex auction. 
Interestingly, Flagstaff has also quietly scored a role relating to the Australian wealth business. The firm is said to be working on the demerger option should the broader sale process not yield the structure and price that ANZ chief executive Shayne Elliott and the bank's board are looking for. 
Elliott left open the prospect of a demerger when he kicked off the wealth sale earlier this year. While the move appeared to be a strategic one around creating more price tension among bidders, the complex structure of the auction and the fact ANZ has a preference for the wealth unit to be sold in its entirety, has kept the option alive. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK-listed CMC Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIA Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goldman Sachs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flagstaff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shayne Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flagstaff Partners</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metlife</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zurich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Banking Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Goode</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ83</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NZ85</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
