<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414427262125477</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/street-talk/netwealths-fivepronged-pitch-to-save-ipo-market-20170801-gxnh4w</url>
  <title>Netwealth's five-pronged pitch to save IPO market</title>
  <content>
In a sure sign of initial public offering market conditions, it seems one or two growth drivers for an ASX-hopeful are no longer enough. 
Wealth platform owner Netwealth has five. 
As the latest IPO contender meets , it is understood Netwealth management has made a five-way growth pitch which it hopes will see the company overcome scepticism towards new listings and land on the ASX-boards before the end of the year. 
Netwealth told fund managers it operates in the attractive $2.2 trillion superannuation industry and within an addressable platform and wrap market worth $732 billion and growing at 12 per cent a year. 

Then there is the structural shift from bank-backed investment managers and other incumbents like AMP and IOOF to more nimble platform providers such as Netwealth and the already listed HUB24, OneVue and Praemium, and its push to get a higher wallet share from existing clients. 

Lastly is what was dubbed the "managed account growth opportunity" and its scalable technology. 
And to ram home the growth pitch, Netwealth told fund managers that its revenue was up near $50 million in the financial year to June 30, while profit before tax was about $20 million.
It said revenue had grown at more than 20 per cent a year over the past eight financial years, on a compound basis, while profit was growing at more than 30 per cent a year. 
It will be interesting to see whether those numbers are enough to overcome investor sentiment towards new listings. Credit Suisse and UBS are on board to market the offer. 

Fund managers are expected to compare the business to its listed rivals - HUB24, OneVue and Praemium - which are trading at about 30-to-40 times forward profit. Brokers are also expected to put Link Administration Holdings, Computershare and Class Ltd into the comp tables. 
﻿
Elsewhere in the industry, ASX-aspirant Powerwrap has recently commenced an executive search to appoint a permanent managing director. 
Street Talk understands headhunting firm Momentis Group is running the search which will also consider current Powerwrap boss Chris Brant.  

He took the reins in December from Cormac Heffernan who resigned following shareholder angst and upheaval on the board. That included the ousting of chairman Maurice O'Shannassy and director Mitchell Hurley. 
It is unclear if Brant took on the managing director role on an interim or permanent basis in December.
 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netwealth</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Hurley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-hopeful</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OneVue</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maurice O'Shannassy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Class Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Link Administration Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HUB24</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suisse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Street Talk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-boards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Momentis Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Praemium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Powerwrap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-aspirant Powerwrap</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Computershare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cormac Heffernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IOOF</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Brant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
