<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414504571538612</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/world/donald-trump-the-white-house-is-a-real-dump/news-story/34bd7a5352591c1e4fda8b0f5423a3e7</url>
  <title>Trump: The White House is a 'dump'</title>
  <content>
PRESIDENT Trump reportedly told members of his pristine Bedminster Golf Club that he schleps back to New Jersey from Washington DC most weekends because "That White House is a real dump."
The president, an avid golfer, enjoys the club's comfort and fraternising with the members who fork over hundreds of thousands of dollars for the privilege,  .
It was unclear whether the "dump" remark was made in jest. Critics, including Chelsea Clinton, pounced his perceived dig at the White House,
"Thank you to all the White House ushers, butlers, maids, chefs, florists, gardeners, plumbers, engineers & curators for all you do every day," Ms Clinton tweeted shortly after the remarks became public.
Golf Magazine also said that Mr Trump lauded the members during a cocktail party before inviting them to "drop in" on his interviews with potential cabinet members.
"This is my real group. You are the special people," he told members. "I see all of you. I recognise, like, 100 per cent of you, just about."
Mr Trump is slated to spend August 3 to 20 at the club.
The White House does not disclose how many rounds he has played or his playing partners.
This article was
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea Clinton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GOLF Magazine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bedminster Golf Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
