<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414349952712162</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/sport/ignatius-park-college-primed-for-aaron-payne-cup-grand-final/news-story/dd0354996d26051450deeb4484e4ccff</url>
  <title>Iggy Park primed for grand final</title>
  <content>
IGNATIUS Park College coach Christian Quabba believes his players will be ready for anything when they take the field against Rockhampton's The Cathedral College for Friday's Aaron Payne Cup grand final.
The next generation of rugby league talents will get to showcase their skills in the curtain-raiser to the blockbuster NRL clash between the Cowboys and Storm at 1300SMILES Stadium.
Ignatius Park had to produce something special to book their place in this year's schoolboys decider after overcoming St Patrick's College Mackay 25-24 thanks to an extra-time field goal in the semi-finals.
Neither team could break the deadlock in the first period of extra time before halfback Adam Cook calmly slotted his field goal and Quabba said it was the perfect preparation for what shapes as a physical grand final.
"It was definitely a tough game of footy and you always learn a lot about your character and resilience and willingness to turn up for each other in those games," Quabba said.
"Things got tough at stages, but the boys showed their ability to get the job done and they're certainly going to need to call on that on Friday.
"The Cathedral College are coming here having just beaten Kirwan and they'll be very, very confident. We're under no illusions that they're a powerful side and dangerous all over the park.
"We're going to have to be at our absolute best to get the result we're looking for, but it's an exciting challenge and that's why we train to play these games."
The Aaron Payne Cup grand final also doubles as the Queensland semi-final of the GIO Schoolboys Cup and Quabba said the Ignatius Park boys deserved their chance on the big stage.
"Our boys work hard all year and this is opportunity for them to showcase that on big stage. It doesn't get any bigger than an Aaron Payne Cup final at 1300SMILES Stadium," he said.
"It's certainly a very big game for the school and these boys. It's what schoolboys rugby league is all about."
Kick-off for tomorrow's Aaron Payne Cup final is 3.55pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Quabba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SMILES Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iggy Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Payne Cup</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kirwan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IGNATIUS Park College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GIO Schoolboys Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quabba</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ignatius Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathedral College</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday's Aaron Payne Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
