<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414375722516643</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/world/europe/army-cadets-injured-in-mourne-mountains-northern-ireland-as-major-rescue-effort-is-underway/news-story/1bee9d0cda558569f45eedfd1f282356</url>
  <title>Army Cadets injured in Mourne Mountains, Northern Ireland, as major rescue effort is underway</title>
  <content>
A rescue mission is underway for kids who have been hit by bad weather in the Mounre Mountains, Northern Ireland. Picture: Facebook

The SunNews Corp Australia Network

Share

A MAJOR emergency has been declared after 40 army cadets hit difficulties in atrocious weather.
reports that multiple people have reportedly been injured on the Mournes mountain range in County Down, Northern Ireland.

The Mourne Mountains, a granite mountain range located in County Down in the southeast of Northern Ireland, are among the most famous of the mountains on the island of Ireland. Picture: SuppliedSource:Supplied
Between 17 and 20 young people are suffering serious hypothermia and lower leg injuries, the Coastguard said.
At least 17 emergency crews are on the scene, including responders from the Mountain Rescue and Coastguard.
The Coastguard said up to 70 people - including the cadets - are believed to be in difficulty on the mountains.

The Mourne Wall that stretches for 35km across the mountains. Picture: SuppliedSource:News Corp Australia
Politician Colin McGrath said it's a "major emergency incident".
He tweeted: "Major emergency incident in mournes with helicopter, coastguard, medical and ambulance responding. Please God all will be OK."
A Coastguard spokesman told the News Letter: "Three Coastguard helicopters, three Coastguard rescue teams, police and ambulances are involved."
A statement said it was called just before 12pm (9pm AEST) by the ambulance service.

It said: "Initial reports suggest that all members of the group are accounted for, however four people may be suffering from exposure."

The Mourne Mountains or Mournes are a granite mountain range located in County Down in the southeast of Northern Ireland. Picture: SuppliedSource:Supplied
Coastguard teams and search and rescue helicopters are on the scene, along with ambulances and mountain rescue.
Those in trouble are thought to be from one large group.
Some have reportedly been separated from the others.
Mourne Councillor Henry Reilly said around ten ambulances are waiting nearby.
He added: "It is not clear what is happening but it could be young people suffering exposure."
This article originally appeared in
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Army Cadets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SuppliedSource</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mournes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountain Rescue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Ireland</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mounre Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mourne Councillor Henry Reilly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>County Down</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mourne Wall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin McGrath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mourne Mountains</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Letter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
