<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414465916831940</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/comment/hilda-why-were-suddenly-concerned-about-inequality-things-have-stopped-getting-better-20170802-gxnmo1.html</url>
  <title>Peter Martin: Why suddenly we're concerned about inequality. Things have stopped getting better</title>
  <content>
Bill Shorten's on to something. Not the pointless debate over inequality - whether it's rising or not depends on what you measure - but the truth that lies beneath the debate.
It's that, unusually, life is getting harder.
In every year since the turn of the century the Melbourne Institute's Household Income and Labour Dynamics survey has asked the same 7000 households a raft of questions designed to establish whether things are getting better or worse. HILDA is Seven Up.
In all but four of the past 15 years, .

Two of those four years followed the global financial crisis. The other two were the two most recent years for which we have data: the first two full years of the Abbott-Turnbull government.
It means that whereas before the election of Tony Abbott, a typical Australian family took home about what it did in 2009, it now takes home less, after adjusting for inflation.

It's unusual, absent a recession. But it's been bearable because interest rates have been falling. When they climb, as they have just started to for some borrowers, it'll become painful.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

As Shorten put it in a speech that , "It feeds that sense, that resentment, that the deck is stacked against ordinary people, that the fix is in and the deal is done."
We didn't get that sense when ordinary incomes were rising, even though inequality was widening. Only now, when real incomes are slipping, do we feel resentful.
And it's mainly men who are resentful. Female earnings are trending up, especially those of women employed full-time. Male earnings are trending down.Photo: Chris Hopkins
University graduates earn much less than their predecessors used to ($1023 a week, down from $1468) and they are much less likely to be in full-time jobs four years later (73 per cent, down from 91 per cent).
Australians with only a high school qualification are even worse off. When the survey started, 81 per cent of them were employed full-time within four years. Now it's 62 per cent.
It's been bearable because interest rates have been falling. When they climb, it'll become painful.

The survey's custodian, Roger Wilkins, notes dryly that this suggests the payoffs from university education have not deteriorated "relative to the alternatives".
As more and more of us work in part-time rather than full-time jobs, an increasing proportion are combining part-time jobs in order to work full-time. This means that part-time jobs are more common than the Bureau of Statistics survey suggests and that full-time jobs are harder to get.
Home ownership rates for the under-40s have collapsed. In 2002 when the survey began, 32.5 per cent of 18- to 39-year-olds owned a home. It's now 24.9 per cent.
The proportion of men in their early-20s living with their parents has jumped from 43 per cent to 60 per cent. The proportion of early 20s women staying at home has jumped from 27 per cent to 48 per cent.
Those who can buy houses find it hard to pay them off. The average mortgage taken out by a young homebuyer has almost trebled - jumping from $120,813 to $330,687. Going back to the same homeowners year after the year the survey finds that in most years the amount owed climbs as a substantial minority of young homeowners refinance or redraw or fall behind on their loans.
Wilkins says if they continue like this - using their mortgages to fund day to day expenses - there will be "real implications for future aged pension liabilities".
Australians are working longer without waiting for the pension age to rise. The typical retirement age has climbed from 62 to 66 for men, and for 61 to 64 for women. And retirement is less likely to be a one-off event. Thirteen per cent of men who retired between the ages of 60 and 64 find themselves back at work within a year, up from 9 per cent. Seven per cent of the women who retired between 60 and 64 find themselves back at work in a year, up from 4 per cent.
Even now, a quarter of a century after the introduction of compulsory superannuation and 15 years after compulsory contributions of around 9 per cent, the balances of retirees are surprisingly low.
Thirty per cent of men retire without super, and 29 per cent of women.
The men who do have super retire with a typical balance of $325,200; the women with $110,952. That typical balance is the median, meaning half of the retirees will have more, and half less. The mean average is much higher, pushed up by very big retirement balances at the top.
Retirees with low balances are highly likely to use them to pay off debts, obliterating 58 per cent of their super (men) or 70 per cent (women) in one go.
Wilkins says a significant proportion of people with relatively low balances are making the decision "not to use their superannuation to help fund their retirement".
Australia remains a wealthy country. But it isn't absolute wealth (or even relative inequality) that matters most when it comes to our feelings. It's whether or not things are getting better. HILDA suggests they are getting worse.

Peter Martin is economics editor of The Age.

Follow Peter Martin on  and

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilkins</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Hopkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seven Up</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott-Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Institute's Household Income</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Martin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
