<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414633420560497</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/boss/book-review-homo-deus-by-yuval-noah-harari-20170723-gxgu30</url>
  <title>Book review: Homo Deus by Yuval Noah Harari</title>
  <content>
It's a sharp, humbling experience to have a futurist clearly and logically explain how, perhaps, humankind is at one its most crucial pivot points. And the future we can look forward to is one underpinned by unbelievably competent algorithms and, perhaps, eternal life.
Yuval Noah Harari, a historian at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, outlines an alarming future in which algorithms and data offer solutions for humankind's every whim.
In a world in the not so distant future, an intricate, interconnected network, underpinned by sophisticated and intelligent programs designed by humans but self-sustaining, will prompt our species to live limitless lives seeking eternal joy and pleasure.
"In seeking bliss and immortality," writes Harari, "humans are in fact trying to upgrade themselves into gods."

In understanding our own internal algorithms - our behavioural responses to our increasingly comfortable existences - we are able to develop further patterns and networks that will far outstrip our individual capabilities.

"Organisms are algorithms," he writes. "Every animal - including Homo sapiens - is an assemblage of organic algorithms shaped by natural selection over millions of years of evolution ... There is no reason to think that organic algorithms can do things that non-organic algorithms will never be able to replicate or surpass."
While Harari writes tenderly about humankind, the book has an iron core: shortly, we will experience a sharp separation between those with superior intelligence, who control and understand the vast algorithms underpinning our societies, and those locked into these predesigned processes, following strict patterns and whose behaviour provides the data powering these algorithms.
While it throws up thousands of questions about where we are heading as a species, Homo Deus does a remarkable job of answering them. The plausibility of some ideas will leave the reader enthralled, but perhaps very uncomfortable.
Homo Deus: A Brief History of Tomorrow by Yuval Noah Harari, Random House

Like Leadership with the Financial Review on . Follow us on . Join the  conversation.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hebrew University of Jerusalem</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yuval Noah Harari</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homo Deus</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brief History of Tomorrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
