<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414341362777249</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/asia-taylor-back-for-sydney-uni-flames-for-201718-wnbl-season/news-story/7a6da15fa9fee8ac798b4ee815a6cbcc</url>
  <title>Asia coup for Flames' WNBL defence</title>
  <content>
THE Sydney Uni Flames have re-signed prized American import and playmaker Asia Taylor in a coup coach Cheryl Chambers says significantly bolsters the clubs chances of thwarting the WNBL aspirations of big spending rivals from Melbourne and Adelaide.
Opal guard Leilani Mitchell is the only star and starter from the Flames' winning campaign last season not on the roster for the revamped and condensed 2017/2018 season, making the Sydney side the most settled line-up in the competition.
In contrast, the Boomers and Lightning have completely overhauled their line-ups in a wild spending spree which has netted last years cellar dwellers the likes of Liz Cambage, Jenna O'Hea, Britt Smart (Boomers), WNBA centre Ruth Hamblin and Opals duo Abby Bishop and Laura Hodges (Adelaide Lightning).

While they struggled last year, Chambers has predicted the aggressive recruiting of both clubs will see the Boomers and Lightning, along with deep-pocketed Townsville, start the season as favourites.
"The Boomers and Adelaide would have to be the front runners, along with Townsville who have also recruited very, very well and have Suzy (Batkovic) staying,'' Chambers said.
"There has been big spending in the off-season.''

The amount spent on team rosters is unknown but it is understood there is talk of a WNBL salary cap being introduced next season in the wake of rising player payments.
Chambers said she hopes the Flames are able to combat the cash splash with a settled and talented line-up which also includes American tall Jen Hamson.
"The fact we now have Asia and haven't had big changes brings a lot of positives for us with the other teams buying up as they have done,'' Chamber said.
"I think continuity and team spirit, established team work, will help us.
"The others have teams of stars. We have a team that will work very, very well together.''
The Flames' first outing of the 2017/18 WNBL is against Adelaide Lightning in Adelaide on October 6.
The defending champions will host their first game in Round 2, against the Dandenong Rangers in a replay of the last WNBL decider.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>OCTOBER 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong Rangers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flames' WNBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheryl Chambers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ruth Hamblin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leilani Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Lightning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britt Smart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liz Cambage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abby Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Uni Flames</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batkovic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suzy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jen Hamson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia Taylor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenna O'Hea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Hodges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Opals</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Round 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
