<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414075074798749</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/rendezview/why-do-we-think-every-playing-field-needs-to-be-level/news-story/3eeeb07a45f4a0c3d57defce03c4a852</url>
  <title>Big teammate? Quick, get the cotton wool</title>
  <content>
DIVERSITY is what we say we are striving for in our society, to celebrate every person's culture, story and background. It's the message played on repeat loop every Australia Day and drummed into kids while they inhale their sausage and sauce sandwich: Accommodate and appreciate every individual and their differences.
We also have a Diversity Council to foster value and respect for "people of different ages, cultural backgrounds and genders", and numerous other human rights bodies with similar agendas.
There's also the Australian Sport Commission's Clearinghouse for Sport which takes pride in our "diverse multicultural population" and "sport participation in many of its regions reflects this diversity".
But suddenly comes the junior rugby season and footage of a big boy charging across the field away from his miniature opponents before scoring a long-range try.
The "giant" seven year old in question this week is Vaka Tuitupou, a Samoan child who is a Bulldogs junior playing for the St Johns Eagles in Sydney's west and dubbed the Man Child.
In short he is a champion who rinses the opposition, a player who deftly and quickly moves through his rivals before landing over the try line.
His teammates - yes they are half his size - clearly adore and respect him. The opposition youngsters look fairly enamoured too.
But the poor kid has become a flashpoint for the hypocrisy of diversity in this country.
"Shocked" at Tuitupou, there are renewed calls for young rugby players to be uniformly separated in divisions by weight instead of age.
The idea is to push Tuitupou to a higher range with no mind to how he might fit in with an older peer group.
Angst-ridden critics are forecasting destruction and injury because it's unfair for more petite kids.
They'll get squashed, they'll get hurt. There will be tears, maybe even concussions and broken bones.
The physical differences between the other boys and Tuitupou means they don't get a fair go. It's too challenging. Better unroll that wad of cotton wool, then.
As a rugby mum myself, I am not at all dismissing the potential seriousness of injury on the field.
You are on alert every time they lace up their boots and chomp down on a mouth guard.
But isn't this young player Tuitupou a prime example of the diversity and inclusion we claim to cherish?
Sport is meant to be the great equaliser. And even away from the field, small kids are always going to be wary of the bigger kids.
Why not teach them how to deal with this rather eliminating all threat? Make sure the kids are trained in how to tackle, pull their head in right and other vital skills, for example.
And I say this as a mother whose teen son has fielded his share of bigger players because, as he says, "that is the nature of the game".

Sydney's seven year old gentle giant is much bigger than his teammates.

Sydney's seven year old gentle giant of rugby
Junior rugby league and union can be perilous. We know that, as we let our kids play but the skills it teaches them are unmatched.
Often on the field, it is the muscly, quick and short guy who cuts through and causes the damage.
"This boy's a gentle giant. He doesn't just run through the opposition to hurt other kids," Club chairman .
"He's aware of his size. He could pick up kids with one hand if he wanted to but he's just a nice gentle boy. He's a good kid from a good family who just loves playing footy. I don't want the kid to think he doesn't deserve to play footy because of his size."
Yes, rugby is a contact sport. But what's next?
Seven-year-old netballers penalised because they are too tall? Primary school swimmers dumped from squads because their shoulders are bigger than the kid next to them?
This creates a whole new body image curse.
If you look at the post-match photo of both the weekend's under 7s teams, it is a textbook example of diversity brought together by an inspiring sport.
There's the blonde white kids standing side-by-side with kids from Islander, Middle Eastern and Asian backgrounds.
And that's only the differences you can see. Based on the laws of averages, some will have developmental delays and disabilities, like autism, diabetes or asthma.
Should they be excluded too? All share a common thing - that glint in the eye that only comes after you spent the morning chasing each other and a ball around.
These kids are nailing the diversity adults claim to aspire to without even trying.
Why do we want a level playing field? It's a cliche that doesn't exist in any workplace, school or family.
So instead everyone gets a trophy.
Even Sunrise host Samantha Armytage voiced her concern about the attention the boy was getting for his size. "He's fantastic," she said.
My junior rugby contacts tell me that when the SJRU was recently trying to collate height and weight data from club juniors 12 and under, they got a lacklustre response.
How would it be policed anyway - make the kids stand on a scale like a jockey?
The real issue here is paying lip service to diversity but being driven to win at all costs.
Perhaps we are lurching towards to world forecast by novelist Kurt Vonnegut Jr in Harriso Bergeron, a tale about a 14-year-old intelligent and athletic teenager who is taken away from his parents by the government.
The satirical sci-fi story written in 1961 offers up a 2081 where amendments to US Constitution mean that all citizens are fully equal.
It is illegal to be better looking, smarter or more physically skilled than anyone else. You are slapped with a handicap otherwise - masks for those who are too beautiful, distracting radios planted in the ears of the clever and cumbersome weights saddled to the athletic or strong.
Every Australian is different, and that's what makes us interesting. And what better place to practise diversity than kids sport?
@whatlouthinks
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diversity Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man Child</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samoan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SJRU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kurt Vonnegut Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vaka Tuitupou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuitupou</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samantha Armytage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sport Commission's Clearinghouse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harriso Bergeron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Johns Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
