<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414212513755529</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/news/workplace-bargaining-power-disastrously-in-favour-of-bosses-labor-claims-20170802-gxnv1t</url>
  <title>Workplace bargaining power 'disastrously' in favour of bosses, Labor claims</title>
  <content>
Labor has put business on notice that a future Shorten government will allow trade unions back into workplaces to recruit members and demand pay rises, vowing to reverse a "disastrous" tilt in bargaining power favouring employers.
Opening up a fresh front in the , industrial relations spokesman Brendan O'Connor blamed a collapse in collective bargaining for low wage growth, which coupled with rising rates of job insecurity was helping fuel public disillusionment. 
In a speech to the Sydney Institute on Wednesday night that will stoke fears among the business community of , Mr O'Connor identified a number of areas as ripe for reform without going into specific details of what Labor would do if it won the next election. 
He questioned whether enterprise bargaining delivered for low-paid workers, whether awards provided an adequate safety net, how could the Fair Work Act be made more user-friendly for small business and whether the Fair Work Commission had sufficient powers to step in when parties were not negotiating in good faith.

He also signalled it was too hard for average people to have disputes about their pay and conditions resolved by industrial relations institutions and the Fair Work Act may be failing to adequately provide for the rights of workers, including whether there were "sufficient rights" for workers to be represented. 

While Mr O'Connor said workers, employers and unions must be brought together to achieve both flexibility and security, he made clear this would include a greater role for the labour movement.
Push to redress 'imbalance'

"There is no one answer or one solution," Mr O'Connor said according to speech notes.
"Whatever the solution or solutions might be, two things are clear: it must be collective, and it must redress the imbalance in bargaining power.

"The priority of the labour movement and of the ALP starts with jobs and wages and labour markets. 
"That's why we need to reverse the disastrous tilt in bargaining power and rising inequality." 
Citing Fair Work Commission research for its , Mr O'Connor said the impact of enterprise bargaining was diminishing, to the detriment of workers' pay packets.
The percentage of workers covered by collective agreements had fallen from 43.4 per cent in 2010 to 36.4 per cent in 2016. Between 2008 and 2016, reliance on awards had risen from 16.5 per cent of the workforce to 22.7 per cent.

"This is a significant negative change, as award-reliant employees are concentrated at the bottom of the distribution of household disposable income," he said.
"The research attributes the drop in the number of workers covered by enterprise agreements to the fall in union density - an undeniable link."
While technological change, the growth in the services economy, offshoring of jobs and "regressive" tax and spending Coalition policies had contributed to rising rates of inequality, Mr O'Connor claimed dwindling union membership and the shift in bargaining power had played a central role.
"In the absence of unions, the labour market is more brutal, workplaces are more dangerous, workers suffer more exploitation and society is impoverished," he said.

Distrust in democracy

Mr O'Connor said the link between hard work and fair reward had been severed, damaging the social contract and triggering cynicism and distrust in democracy and its institutions.
"When that link is broken, we get disillusionment and disaffection," he said.
"In order to address systemic inequality and insecurity for working and middle class Australians we need to break down the protections of privilege which have been advocated and implemented by the Abbott-Turnbull governments.

​"In an age of hostility, anger and taking sides, it is time for all groups - governments, unions, employers and civil society - to accept that tackling inequality in this country is a shared responsibility."
Mr O'Connor welcomed Reserve Bank Governor Phil Lowe's recent comments that  and  to counter flat wages growth but pointed out this was easier said than done, particularly industries with negligible union coverage.
"In today's institutional environment, it is absurd to assume low-wage workers, in insecure jobs, can just go to their boss and ask for a pay rise," he said.
Men's earnings flatline

Mr O'Connor's speech comes as the latest Household, Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia survey showed that men's weekly earnings had flatlined between 2012 and 2014 and slipped in 2015, while home ownership rates among the under 40s had plummeted. 
But the report's author, University of Melbourne Professor Roger Wilkins, disputed Labor's claim that inequality had worsened.
"I would push back a bit against that very broad sweeping statement that inequality is at a 75-year high, not just because if anything inequality looks like it's been edging downwards since the GFC, but also because 75 years ago we didn't have Medicare, we had a much less progressive income tax system, so I think when you take a broader look at the distribution of economic wellbeing across the community, I think Australia is a more equal place than it was even 40 years ago," Professor Wilkins told Sky News.
Mr O'Connor said Labor had "righted one of the greatest wrongs" by repealing the Howard government's WorkChoices industrial relations regime but in a surprise admission conceded the party had been too blinkered.

"With the vantage point of hindsight it may now be said that we should have recognised that the labour market was changing, at a speed and in ways that would mean that simply restoring industrial relations laws would not be sufficient," he said.
The shadow minister accused the Coalition of waging a "relentless attack" on working people and unions, emboldening some employers to shirk their workplace obligations. 
He said the Coalition was incapable of tackling inequality in the industrial relations system because "they love to let the market rip" and there was a "deep moral flaw" in the view wages needed to be as low as possible. 
Verbal attack on PM

"When you've spent your whole life protecting the privileged and helping the rich get richer, when you get more than your fair share of the benefits of economic change, then globalisation, technological disruption and the free market must look pretty good," Mr O'Connor said in an attack on Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull.
"But labour market changes look very different to those Australians who have to work hard to put food on the table, who juggle work with raising their families, who struggle to hold down a good, reliable job, and who cannot see a place for their aspirations in today's Australia."
In a nod to bipartisanship, Mr O'Connor called for consensus to address the challenges technological changes posed to the future of work and machines replacing people.
"We must ensure that there continue to be good, well-paid jobs with a career path and job security. And we must ensure that all workers are part of our growth story," he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reserve Bank Governor Phil Lowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abbott-Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Commission</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WorkChoices</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Connor</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medicare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Work Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Roger Wilkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
