<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414075074798836</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/bomber-strikes-nato-convoy-in-afghanistan/news-story/4865d2742599283c41f08315bc079b73</url>
  <title>Bomber strikes NATO convoy in Afghanistan</title>
  <content>
A suicide bomber has struck a NATO convoy near the southern Afghan city of Kandahar.
US military officials have confirmed the attack, adding that there were casualties but without providing more information.
The Taliban promptly took responsibility, a spokesman for the insurgents saying Wednesday's bombing had killed 15 soldiers. Similar claims in the past have been exaggerated.
Lieutenant Damien E. Horvath, a military spokesman, could not say how many casualties there were or provide their nationalities.
The NATO mission, known as Resolute Support, "can confirm that a NATO convoy was attacked in Kandahar. The attack did cause casualties," he said.
In their claim of responsibility, the Taliban also said the attack destroyed two armoured tanks.
The insurgents' spokesman for southern Afghanistan, Qari Yusuf Ahmadi, said fighter Asadullah Kandahari was the "hero" who carried out the attack with a small pick-up truck, packed with explosives.
Kandahar province was the Taliban spiritual heartland and the headquarters of their leadership during the five-year rule of the Taliban, which ended with the US invasion in 2001.
Eyewitness Ghulam Ali, who runs a mechanics shop near the attack site on the outskirts of the city of Kandahar, said the intensity of the blast knocked him out.
When he came to, he saw a military vehicle on fire on the road.
He stepped out of his shop but a sudden burst of gunfire drove him back inside, he said.
Then, helicopters arrived and he saw soldiers being taken away from the scene but could not determine the extent of their injuries.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lieutenant Damien E. Horvath</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ghulam Ali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kandahar</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qari Yusuf Ahmadi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resolute Support</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taliban</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NATO</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asadullah Kandahari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
