<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414345657744741</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/unit-owners-could-be-up-for-a-tidy-financial-windfall-after-it-was-revealed-brisbane-had-australias-most-parking/news-story/d385bf4c742fb08c5b503556fe3711e1</url>
  <title>Unit owners could be up for a tidy financial windfall after it was revealed Brisbane had Australia's most parking - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Parking in Brisbane's CBD is the most expensive in Australia.

INNER-city unit owners could be up for a tidy financial windfall of as much as $910 a month after a new report warned Brisbane's CBD was the country's most expensive place to park.
The RACQ's latest parking report, found off-street hourly parking costs in Brisbane CBD averaged $28.32, compared to $28.08 in Sydney and $20.56 in Melbourne.
It also warned that the number of parking station businesses charging motorists the maximum daily rate of $89 had almost tripled in the past year.
The high off-street charges have handed unit owners a windfall, with private car park rentals soaring via online booking businesses such as Parkhound, ParkingMadeEasy, Spacer, Parkey, and FindACarPark but also through "black market" deals via Gumtree and social media.
Realestate.com.au listings show 223 residential properties that are on the market in the Brisbane CBD right now have at least one off-street parking spot, while 521 have two or more including the very centralas well as

You can either pay for parking, or perhaps buy an inner city unit such as this one at 82/29 George St, which comes with parking. Picture: realestate.com.au

Private parking spots in some of Brisbane's elite buildings are available for as much as $910 a month, and range anywhere from $14 to $30 a day - a far cry from the maximum that parking businesses are charging. The demand for CBD parking is so high that private parking has also spread to suburbs neighbouring the city such as Spring Hill, where day rates can be as low as $9.90.
With private parking options growing, motorists can afford to be picky too, filtering out spots by walking distance to CBD, maximum weekly price, space type, access type, and also what sort of amenities will be available to them such as 24/7 access, arranged transfers, car wash, CCTV and even if there are toilets in the car park.
RACQ spokesman Paul Turner urged motorists to search for cheaper parking options in the CBD, calling high parking station charges "an absolute rip off".
"As if the short-term money grab isn't bad enough, when we look at longer stays in Brisbane's CBD there's not much difference between parking for four hours, or staying for the full day.
"Eleven of the 42 off-street parking stations in the city centre charging the maximum daily rate of $89, which is just outrageous."
While Brisbane has the cheapest on-street parking of the major capitals at $4.40 per hour - compared with $5.50 an hour in Melbourne and $7.00 an hour in Sydney - these are notoriously difficult to secure especially during peak periods.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Realestate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spring Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumtree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane CBD</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parkhound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FindACarPark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RACQ</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ParkingMadeEasy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
