<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413984880483509</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:48</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/personal-finance/cba-nab-tighten-rules-amid-identity-theft-warning-20170731-gxmonj</url>
  <title>CBA, NAB tighten rules amid identity theft warning</title>
  <content>
Commonwealth Bank of Australia, National Australia Bank and Westpac Group are tightening identity and financial checks as a federal taskforce pushes for tougher controls, including overhauling of Australian Business Licences.
CBA, the nation's biggest mortgage provider, will demand mortgage brokers, which act as intermediaries between the lender and borrower, personally verify the applicant's identity and provide legible copies of original documents.
NAB is making it mandatory for mortgage brokers to include and verify personal, guarantor, company consent forms and broker declarations about the borrowers' identity.
Westpac Group, which includes Bank of Melbourne, BankSA and St George, is reminding brokers it requires improved analysis of a borrower's financial situation, including detailed expenses and liabilities.

The moves follow warnings by the chairman of the federal government's Black Economy Taskforce that rampant identity theft could "systemically undermine" the nation's financial and banking system.

The taskforce has launched a discussion paper in the lead-up to his final recommendations about strategies for tackling
"A more robust, reliable and efficient identity system is urgently needed," chairman Michael Andrew said. "This is as much about the black economy as it is national security."
Canvassing opinion

Other issues beng canvassed include:

*Plugging gaps in the tax regime with strict liability violations for offences such as phoenixing;
*Specialist tax tribunals to increase the number of cases and convictions;
*Naming and shaming tax evaders and sanctioning unethical tax agents;
*Reverse onus of proof for serious offences, such as trying to smuggle large amounts of cash out of the country;

*Cutting red tape and boosting cooperation between Canberra, states and territories;
*Boosting whistle-blower incentives;
*Using smarter digital technologies to detect breaches; and,
*Requiring non-cash payment of wages, reducing the number of $100 notes in circulation and introducing non-cash wagering.

It also recommends incentives, such as government contracts, for companies with good tax records, introducing minimum tax assessments for high-risk businesses and using education and publicity to promote the importance of "doing the right thing".
Banks seek balance

Major banks, which are prime targets for identity theft, are attempting to balance client demand for easy online access to financial products with the threat of identify theft.
Under the new arrangement being introduced by CBA, mortgage brokers will have to acknowledge they have viewed the original identification documents for borrowers and/or guarantors.

"We are always looking at ways to strengthen our policies and support responsible lending," a CBA spokesman said.
NAB is telling mortgage brokers to self-verify personal consent forms, guarantor consent forms, company consent forms and their broker declaration about the applications bona fides.
Westpac has resent details of its new expense-to-income ratio intended to capture all clients' actual declared expenses. It follows Australian Securities and Investments Commission identifying wide-scale suspected fraud in lenders' expense and liability statements.
John Flavell, chief executive of Mortgage Choice, a listed mortgage brokerage, said he welcomes any security improvements that lower risk of identity theft and increase transparency.
Mr Flavell said: "CBA and NAB are by mandating the broker sights original identification documents and ensures all parties know what they are signing up for."
Fraud fast-growing

Independent bank-sponsored agencies, such as Equifax, estimate identify theft is growing by 80 per cent a year, the fastest-growing source of fraud for banking, superannuation, credit card and insurance providers.
Tyler Harris, chief executive of Armourcard, a cyber security company, said: "It has never been easier to steal personal ID,"

For example, smartphones are being targeted by sophisticated cyber-thieves who can plant Trojan Horse codes for stealing data by using digital signals, he said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armourcard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ID</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler Harris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Investments Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trojan Horse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Black Economy Taskforce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Flavell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Westpac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Business Licences</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Securities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Equifax</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Flavell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mortgage Choice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Australia Bank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BankSA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
