<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414590470886589</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4828785/abuse-on-campuses-enough-is-enough/?cs=308</url>
  <title>Abuse on campuses: enough is enough</title>
  <content>
NO MORE: In 2017 there is no longer a place in universities for 'rites of passage', Caroline McMillen says. Picture: Jonathan Carroll

The release this week of the Change the Course Report on Sexual Harassment and Assault in Australia's universities represents a turning point for higher education. More than 30,000 university students responded to the survey to share their experience of sexual harassment and sexual assault in locations both associated with and not associated with their university. I wish to recognise the bravery of those students who took part in the survey and to thank them for providing critical information and insights into where and how sexual harassment and assault is experienced.
Universities Australia commissioned the national survey, which was conducted by the Australian Human Rights Commission as part of the Respect. Now. Always. initiative. The aim of the survey was to provide universities with a deeper understanding of type of sexual harassment and assault experienced by students in order to provide appropriate education and prevention strategies and support for survivors.
At UON, 623 students responded to the survey, which found that 55% of UON respondents experienced sexual harassment in any location, and that 30% of respondents reported that sexual harassment occurred in a location specifically associated with UON.  The survey also found 8% of UON respondents had experienced a sexual assault at any location, and that 1.4% reported that the assault occurred at a location associated with UON. Approximately half of the UON students knew where to seek support or assistance within the university regarding sexual harassment or sexual assault.
As the President of the Australian Human Rights Commission reflected, going to university is a time for intellectual exploration and for many students it is also the time for sexual exploration. Many students will develop a raft of respectful relationships with friends from different backgrounds and engage in consensual sex and indeed many students will meet their life partner at university.
In 2017 there is no longer a place in universities for 'rites of passage' which include rituals steeped in alcohol where both female and male students are harassed or assaulted. Let's lay to rest practices from another era where women and men are objectified and not replicate them in online or social media environments simply because we can. Every student has the right to live a life free from the fear, experience and memory of sexual assault or sexual harassment. To move forward, UON staff and students will work together to create a different culture.
UON's current support services have been enhanced and now include simplified processes for students to lodge reports and to get support through a single referral system, 'Campus Care'. A new student facing portal provides practical information on consent, reporting and support: newcastle.edu.au/rna.
UON students and staff have also collaborated to develop the Sexual Health and Relationship Program, which provides information on consent, relationships and sexual health and also runs a compulsory Consent Matters course for students who live on campus. Support for staff and student leaders who respond to disclosures of sexual violence include targeted education and training.
The university also has a 24-hour security shuttle service to escort students and staff across the campus to their car, to a specific location, or to public transport, a rolling light upgrade program to ensure coverage for all main pathways and primary car parks, and a Closed Circuit Television (CCTV) system within the Callaghan Campus, which provides live and continuous footage through to a centrally-monitored facility.
We will continue to work with our students, survivors and their networks, and our staff to end sexual assault and harassment on our university campuses. Enough is enough.
Caroline McMillen is the Vice-Chancellor of the University of Newcastle

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexual Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Human Rights Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonathan Carroll</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Universities Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UON</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Callaghan Campus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline McMillen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UON, 623</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Course Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vice-Chancellor of the University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CCTV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Consent Matters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sexual Harassment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Relationship Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Closed Circuit Television</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President of the Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
