<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414212513755569</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/lifestyle/travel/never-seen-magellanic-clouds-try-ulurus-astronomy-weekend-20170720-gxf0nr</url>
  <title>Never seen Magellanic clouds? Try the Uluru astronomy weekend</title>
  <content>
by
Patricia Sheahan

This is a special feature in association with Ayers Rock Resort.
What better location to marvel at the night sky than at the rock?
in October is open for bookings. The weekend offers more than night eye candy with Dr Lisa Harvey-Smith and a crew of astrophysicists on hand to fill in any blanks in your knowledge of black holes, dark matter and supernovas.
There are more than a dozen educational talks over the three days covering topics both perennial - how did the universe begin? - and innovative: astro photography, super telescopes and Aboriginal astronomy and navigation. Plus there's a screening of the 2014 sci-fi epic Interstellar, followed by a debrief on its science.

The event promises to give starry-eyed travellers an immersive experience in Australia's darkest natural theatre.
And for those who fancy dining under the stars, the Stellar Starlit Dinner - held in the desert on the Saturday night with a bush tucker buffet - includes a talk on the night sky and a nightcap under the Milky Way.
Families should make a beeline for the Astro Trivia Lunch, with teams vying for astro-themed prizes.
Of course, if you can't get to the weekend, Uluru is the most perfect location for casual star gazing any time of year. Avoid neck craning and lie back on the desert floor to best admire nature's celestial show.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Interstellar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stellar Starlit Dinner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Astro Trivia Lunch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magellanic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milky Way</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayers Rock Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Sheahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Lisa Harvey-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
