<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414203923820828</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/man-and-shark-hows-this-for-clickbait/news-story/c3ec6f524b7c4fa091cd441cdf2568f6</url>
  <title>How's this for clickbait?</title>
  <content>
IT WAS love at first bite for Port Macquarie diving instructor Rick Anderson and the shark he first met when she was just a few days old, with the now fully-grown fish so enamoured with her human chum, she still swims up for a cuddle years later.
The odd friendship began when Mr Anderson was diving with some dive students and saw a group of Port Jackson hatchlings in the reef off Port Macquarie's Nobbys Beach seven years ago.
"Just to show students how friendly sharks were, I coaxed it into my hand and patted it," he said.
"Then I saw it every couple of months and would give it a pat."
Now a 1.7m adult, the shark swims straight to Mr Anderson whenever he dives that same reef, where she still lives and which the instructor still regularly visits with his students.
Even in the middle of a group, she will swim through the other divers and begin nudging Mr Anderson's leg until he notices and gives her a pat and a cuddle.
These days he sees the shark at least every two months or so, and recognises her through the individual markings on her head.
"Sharks aren't dumb animals, they know what is going on, they know when the weather is going to turn bad," he said.

Courtesy: Taronga Zoo.

Port Jackson Sharks at Taronga Zoo
Each time they enjoy a bit of a hug "hello" and a few pats before getting on with their respective days.
"But last time I saw her, she wrapped her tail around my back, she didn't want me to go."
Still, Mr Anderson is at a loss to explain the enduring nature of the pair's relationship, noting that the species is generally a shy creature that likes to hides in caves to avoid people.
"They're harmless, if they don't like you they'll let you know with a nip," he said.
"This one I have never fed, but it is like a dog you know, it just wants some attention," he added.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Jackson Sharks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Jackson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rick Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Macquarie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Anderson</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taronga Zoo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Macquarie's Nobbys Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
