<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414349952712169</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/outer-east/yarra-valley-chololaterie-hot-chocolate-festival-offers-smashed-avocado-and-other-weird-drops/news-story/c92908443e1362726bd839e25b62ec9d</url>
  <title>Is avocado hot chocolate the last straw?</title>
  <content>
COULD this be the most hipster-influenced hot chocolate in Victoria?
Yarra Valley Chocolaterie & Ice Creamery staff have turned the trendiest brekkie dish into a sweet tooth's delight for their annual Hot Chocolate Festival.
The smashed avo hot chocolate features a quarter of an avocado, smashed, then mixed with steaming hot milk and white chocolate.

It's then topped with white chocolate shavings, a vanilla marshmallow and another dollop of smashed avocado.
Chocolaterie managing director Leanne Neeland said the drink was "breakfast on the run" for millennials.
"We have smashed avo on our breakfast menu and already have a fantastic following for that, so we thought we'd take it to the next level," she said.

"Usually a white-chocolate lover likes something sweet, so this is beautiful and creamy and the avocado complements it perfectly."
The hot chocolate is one of 31 varieties created for the festival, which runs until the end of August.

Up to eight creations will be featured each week including a sweet-chilli hot chocolate with chocolate-coated corn chips, a "Cookie Monster" variety with a handcrafted cup made out of cookies, and a honeycomb-flavoured hot chocolate with exploding marshmallows.

Other flavours to be featured later in the month include mulled wine, salty pretzel, parmesan cheese twist, pumpkin chai and a 'superfood' creation.
Mrs Neeland said the chocolaterie was expecting up to 50,000 people over the month for the festival.
Details:

The restaurant world has embraced the hipster culture, so is traditional dining dead?

RESTAURANT WARS: TRENDY VS TRADITIONAL?
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chocolaterie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Neeland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRENDY VS TRADITIONAL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra Valley Chocolaterie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hot Chocolate Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leanne Neeland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ice Creamery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cookie Monster</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
