<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414723614875660</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>15:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/anthony-scaramucci-breaks-silence-on-white-house-sacking-and-that-ryan-lizza-interview/news-story/c0ca7dd2be37a312149d1df345a3011a</url>
  <title>The Mooch breaks silence on sacking</title>
  <content>
Mr Scaramucci opened up to the about his eventful two weeks in the White House, saying he was upset when journalist Ryan Lizza of The New Yorker tweeted about a private dinner between Fox News host Sean Hannity, former Fox News executive Bill Shine, himself and Donald and Melania Trump.
His anger was not just because the information was leaked but that the guest list was incomplete.
It included, among others, Fox News anchor Kimberly Guilfoyle, who Mr Scaramucci was rumoured to be having an affair with.
The pair say they are "very close friends" and nothing more.
However, after that dinner, Mr Scaramucci, called Lizza and exploded with a range of comments that have since become infamous.
"Most of what I said was humorous and joking," Mr Scaramucci said. "Legally, it may have been on the record, but the spirit of it was off. And he knew that."
In the interview, Mr Scaramucci said then-White House Chief of Staff Reince Priebus "is a f - g schizophrenic" and that "I'm not (White House strategist) Steve Bannon. I'm not trying to suck my own c**k."
He also railed that he would "f**king kill all the leakers in the White House."
Mr Scaramucci said he felt burned by Lizza's piece in the magazine.
"The Lizzas and Scaramuccis have been friends for over 50 years. My dad knew his dad from construction, and we were building a personal relationship," he told HuffPost.

But Lizza said he and Mr Scaramucci are not long-time friends.
"I've only known Anthony in his capacity as a Trump surrogate and then White House communications director. We are not and have never been 'old family friends,' though I think our fathers knew each other, so maybe that's what he's talking about," he told HuffPost.
"But again, that would not be a reason to suppress an explosive on-the-record interview."
Mr Scaramucci also defended himself against reports that he wasn't there for the birth of his son on July 24 and sent his wife, Deidre Ball a "short congratulatory text".
Ms Ball has since filed for divorce.
Mr Scaramucci said he was on air force One on his way to the president's speech at the National Scout Jamboree when Ms Ball had the baby two weeks early.
He says he got a text from Ms Ball asking her for some space.
Ms Ball's lawyer, Jill Stone, told the HuffPost: "Any texts of that nature had nothing to do with the baby or seeing the baby."
By Monday, retired General John Kelly was sworn in as chief of staff and asked Mr Scaramucci for his resignation.
"It was a very polite conversation," Mr Scaramucci said.
He then had separate phone calls with Mr Trump, Ivanka Trump and Jared Kushner.
When asked what he will do next, Mr Scaramucci said, "I am going to go dark. Then I will re-emerge - as me."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lizza</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sean Hannity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Ball</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Lizza of the New</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melania Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox News</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bill Shine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Scaramucci</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberly Guilfoyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HuffPost</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivanka Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jared Kushner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>General John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deidre Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Scout Jamboree</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
