<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414289823168427</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:59</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/south-australia/samesex-marriage-what-happens-next/news-story/f3803e57410cd518f8930fa0e0f2dccc</url>
  <title>What's next for the gay marriage vote?</title>
  <content>
UNDER the heading "personal" in his official parliamentary biography, Victorian federal Liberal MP Tim Wilson lists his relationship status as "engaged.''
The former federal Freedom Commissioner is in the uncomfortable position of being asked by his party to vote against allowing himself to marry his male partner. Mr Wilson and like-minded Liberal MPs have signalled they are ready to take the first steps towards introducing a private member's bill on same-sex marriage when Coalition MPs meet in Canberra when Parliament resumes next Tuesday.
Here are five possible outcomes from the meeting:
1. The Coalition joint party room grants a conscience vote
Pro-marriage equality Coalition MPs believe it's time for the Government to allow them to have a conscience vote in Parliament on the issue. If this were to occur, a same-sex marriage bill would sail through Parliament.
In reality, the majority of Coalition MPs and senators are likely to reject the conscience vote and re-endorse the Government's plan to keep pressuring the Senate to sign-off on a national marriage equality plebiscite.
2. The joint party room rejects a conscience vote and the rebels cross the floor anyway
Liberal and Nationals politicians frequently criticise Labor's strict party discipline, which generally requires ALP MPs and senators to toe the party line even when they don't personally agree with it.
With the exception of ministers, Liberal and Nationals politicians are permitted to defy their party on policy issues they feel strongly about. Deputy Prime Minister Barnaby Joyce crossed the floor dozens of times when he was a junior senator to vote against the Howard Government. Queensland Liberal National Party MP George Christensen recently voted with Labor on weekend penalty rates.
Threats of preselection challenges and appeals against damaging the Government are being used to urge pro-marriage equality MPs to toe the party line on marriage. But if Mr Wilson and MPs Trevor Evans, Warren Entsch, Jason Wood and Trent Zimmerman decided to cross the floor anyway, it is likely a same-sex marriage bill would pass the House of Representatives. The bill would also be expected to pass the Senate, allowing legal same-sex weddings to occur in Australia within weeks.
The danger for Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull - who personally supports same-sex marriage - is that conservative Liberals would blame him for failing to maintain party discipline. There have been suggestions that some conservative MPs could move to the crossbench, costing the Government its one-seat majority and forcing it to seek minor-party support for legislation.
Regardless of their views on the issue, most Coalition MPs and senators hope that if gay marriage is approved by Parliament, the result will be accepted by opponents and the Government will be able to get on with governing.
3. The rebels agree to delay a private member's bill - for now
Pro-gay marriage Liberal MPs argue they've waited long enough for the issue to be resolved.
They might be persuaded to temporarily shelve a private member's bill if the Government makes a genuine fresh attempt to get a plebiscite approved by the Senate or holds a postal vote. The Liberal backers of marriage equality sense their time has come and are unlikely to stay silent for long.

The PM has been warned his leadership will be 'terminal' if party MPs cross the floor on marriage equality

PM urged to resolve same-sex marriage issue
4. The Senate agrees to a plebiscite
At this stage, the Senate seems unlikely to sign off a $160 million national plebiscite. Key Senate crossbenchers, including the three-member Nick Xenophon Team bloc, think a popular vote is unnecessary and would be socially divisive.
If the Government managed to win senate backing for a plebiscite, it could be held before the end of the year.
If a majority of voters voted "yes" to same-sex marriage, changes to the Marriage Act would still have to be endorsed by federal Parliament.
Despite the popularity of same-sex marriage in opinion polls, some opponents still believe a majority of Australians could be persuaded to vote "no" at a plebiscite.
5. The government holds a national postal vote without the approval of the Senate
Some ministers believe a postal plebiscite - which arguably wouldn't require parliamentary approval - is the best way to gauge public support for marriage equality. They point out that a national postal ballot was held by the Howard government to elect delegates to the 1998 republic constitutional convention.
Any attempt to hold a postal vote could face a legal challenge and critics argue that the issue is too important to be decided by a voluntary vote conducted through the mail.
Some Australians would challenge the validity of a close "yes" or "no" vote and Parliament could refuse to honour the result. That would mean the debate would be unresolved at the next election.
An overwhelming "yes" or "no" at a postal vote would have the same status as the result of a plebiscite.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marriage Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon Team</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trent Zimmerman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALP MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro-marriage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>House of Representatives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freedom Commissioner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Wilson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Liberal National Party MP George Christensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition MPs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pro-gay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MP Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Wood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deputy Prime Minister Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Howard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
