<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414345657744764</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/jacob-warner-stars-in-bell-shakespeares-the-merchant-of-venice-at-frankston-arts-centre/news-story/8e84a45483725307d12a2b1cfced7e61</url>
  <title>Classic play explores prejudice and justice</title>
  <content>
AS AN actor, Jacob Warner has no interest in doing what he terms a "museum piece".
So that's why he leapt at the chance to appear in Bell Shakespeare's production of The Merchant of Venice with its universal themes of prejudice, justice and revenge.
"It deals with how we treat people from different backgrounds, skin colour and ethnic backgrounds," he said.
Warner said the theme of prejudice was relevant in today's society.
"The play deals with how we still treat people differently because of how they look and behave."
Warner applauded the famous playwright for highlighting anti Semitism during a time when it was rife.
Bell Shakespeare's production is billed as an "uncompromising and dark production" exploring the "tense relationship and prejudices between those that have and those that don't".
It features Mitchell Butel as the defiant Shylock, and Jessica Tovey as Portia.
Warner, who performs as Launcelot, fell in love with Shakespeare's work during his spell at drama school.
"There's a tendency to put Shakespeare on a pedestal," he noted.
But Warner said that didn't mean cuts couldn't be made to famous texts such as The Merchant of Venice.
Concise cuts made by director Anne-Louise Sarks, he said, had enabled added focus to be placed on Shylock and Portia.
Warner spent his early years in Frankston before his family moved to country Victoria so his father could pursue work opportunities.
Many of his extended family members still live locally and Warner is looking forward to seeing them when he performs for the first time at Frankston Arts Centre.
"I'm excited to be there. Most of the audience are going to be family," he joked.
"They've booked out a few rows."
See The Merchant of Venice at Frankston Arts Centre on Saturday, August 19, at 7.30pm. Tickets $60 to $71. To book tickets, click , or phone 9784 1060.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Launcelot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston Arts Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warner</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bell Shakespeare</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Tovey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Warner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shylock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shakespeare</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne-Louise Sarks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell Butel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merchant of Venice</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Semitism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
