<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414070779831429</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/business/tourism/travel-bug-fuels-webjet-flight-centre-shopping-spree-20170802-gxnjfu</url>
  <title>Travel bug fuels Webjet, Flight Centre shopping spree</title>
  <content>
Online booking group Webjet's dispute with its auditors over full-year accounts is not holding back chief executive John Guscic's global expansion plans as he nails down a.
Mr Guscic's latest big acquisition is confirmation that business is booming for Australia's listed travel companies despite the rise of global rivals such as Expedia and Airbnb, which everyone thought were going to eat their lunch a few years ago.
Webjet, Flight Centre and Corporate Travel Management are among some of the best-performing stocks around. Online travel revenues are booming, partly fuelled by cheaper international airfares and consumers getting more comfortable about researching and purchasing flights and hotel deals on their mobile phones.
It was a different story four years ago. Webjet was in the doghouse in late 2013 as Expedia and other  and Agoda swooped in to gobble up market share. Its shares were down 50 per cent at the time and the acquisition of its Asian bookings business, which it has since sold, was not going well.

Webjet was the leading booking tool for flights while Wotif dominated hotel bookings. Wotif was later acquired by Expedia in a $700 million deal but Webjet has thrived under Mr Guscic who has made some smart acquisitions and continued to invest in technology and growing his business-to-business division.

Global expansion push

, is also expanding globally. On Wednesday it acquired a Quebec City-based travel company called Les Voyages Laurier du Vallon to strengthen its North American business.
Flight Centre is different to Webjet as its network of bricks-and-mortar travel agents are still the heart of the company although it is expanding online.
Flight Centre shares have jumped 60 per cent since April while Webjet's shares have almost doubled in value over the past 12 months. Qantas is also expected to post its second-highest profit on record later this month, partly off the back of strong demand for domestic travel.

The Australian Financial Review's Webjet is planning an equity raising to help fund the acquisition of JacTravel, a business-to-business travel agent.
The potential $200 million deal is part of Mr Guscic's plan to build a large business-to-business division focused on selling hotel products to travel agents, heading off the fierce competition in the consumer travel market.
He is using acquisitions to strengthen the company's global reach in the same way that Flight Centre is gobbling up travel companies in the northern hemisphere.
Webjet's strong share price means he can raise equity to fund these deals although there was a setback last week when the company's shares fell 12 per cent over a disagreement with its auditor BDO over the way it accounts for transactions linked to its supply deal with Thomas Cook.

Webjet says the concerns are contrary to the advice it has received from two big accounting firms. The stock fell from a high of $12.70 to $11.10.
The surge in the amount Australian consumers spend online on hotels, flights and holidays defies the malaise in the discretionary retail industry. This is partly because consumers are more confident about using mobile phones to book holidays then they were several years ago.
While companies such as Webjet and Flight Centre have survived the latest wave of disruption they will have to work hard to stay on top of their game.
Airbnb wants to expand beyond providing accommodation by adding flight, car and tour bookings to its online offerings, which will shake up the industry. Priceline, which owns Booking.com, is using data to offer more personalised travel experiences.

michael.smith@fairfaxmedia.com.au

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BDO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporate Travel Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JacTravel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Agoda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webjet</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quebec City-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vallon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Voyages Laurier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North American</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Guscic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wotif</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review's Webjet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Guscic</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Expedia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priceline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flight Centre</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
