<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414083664733549</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/sprinter-usain-bolt-eyes-hollywood-career-in-action-movies-after-retiring-2017-8</url>
  <title>Usain Bolt wants to be an action movie star after retiring</title>
  <content>
Usain Bolt will have Hollywood on red alert after revealing he has an interest in becoming a movie star.

Bolt is due to compete in the 100-metre race and 4 x 100-metre relay at the London 2017 World Athletics Championships this month, before he retires from the sport.

As an eight-time gold medal winning Olympian, with three world records to his name, Bolt leaves behind an undeniable legacy.

But the 30-year-old does not intend to just disappear from the limelight.

In fact, the Jamaican icon could swap the running track for the silver screen as he eyes a Hollywood career, he said during a press conference on Tuesday. His quotes were cited by  among others.

"You never know. I might go into acting and do some action movies," Bolt said when discussing his options once he hangs up his running shoes.

A long-time Manchester United football fan, he joked that he is still waiting on a phonecall from United manager Jose Mourinho.

"It's going to be hard," Bolt said. "Track and field is everything. I've been doing it since I was 10 years old. I don't know what I want to do. This is why I want to play football... I'm waiting for Mourinho's call!"

Bolt's first race at the London 2017 World Championships is on Friday, August 4 at 8.20 p.m. (BST).

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London 2017 World Athletics Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London 2017 World Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
