<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414178154016429</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>13:33</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/noble-to-test-yancoals-us25b-raising-20170802-gxnzl8</url>
  <title>Noble claims Yancoal deal risk oppression of minority rights </title>
  <content>
Noble Group is reviewing its legal protections following confirmation Yancoal Australia plans to raise $US2.5 billion ($3.14 billion) in new equity to fund its hotly contested, company-changing acquisition of Coal & Allied from Rio Tinto.
From the moment the multiple billion question was always going to be whether managers of China's Australian coal vanguard would be able to manage its noxious minority owner in Hong Kong.
Given the obviously fragile state of Yancoal's balance sheet, its ambitions were always going to be funded by a rights issue. But, given Noble's increasingly existential financial woes, the Glencore mini-me was obviously never going to be able to afford whatever it was going to cost to maintain its 13 per cent stake in China Inc's ambitious and wildly indebted coal outpost.
But, for all it was obvious, the Noble issue ended up being the only issue that was not dealt with in Yancoal's otherwise encyclopaedic collection of announcements and disclosures on Wednesday.

A spokesman for Noble confirmed that  that management is reviewing what has been released and at this stage appears likely to challenge the deal in defence of all minorities including Noble.

So what is Noble so unhappy about? Well, Noble needs $US310 million to sustain a slightly reduced place on the Yancoal register. But it doesn't have the cash and even if it did it would be unlikely to participate in the raising.
Unless Noble manufactures a way to stop Yancoal's progress on Coal & Allied, then the value and influence of its stake in the coal miner will be reduced to utter irrelevance.
On Wednesday Yancoal revealed plans to raise $US2.5 billion of new equity with $US2.35 billion of that being generated by a 23.6-for-one renounceable rights issue that arrives with a rich family of underwriters whose population includes four Chinese state-owned entities and the Anglo-Swiss commodities house Glencore.
What is very good for Yancoal is not that great for Noble. The net effect of the raising is that Yancoal will end up with 23.4 billion shares on issue. Noble currently owns 131 million shares in Yancoal. Noble cannot take up its entitlements so that is where Noble will stay. As a result its currently strategic 13.2 per cent position will be reduced to something less than 0.5 per cent of the massive inflated Yancoal register.

Yancoal's complex of disclosures announced the introduction of four new major shareholders to its register and it explained how major shareholder Yanzhou might retain firm control of its Australian outpost even though it is taking up just 54 per cent of its entitlement.
From the get go back in February it was made very clear that Yanzhou's major shareholder, Chinese SOE Yankuang, was less than willing to carry its weight in whatever transaction Yancoal ended up manufacturing.
In the end, Yanzhou will take-up $US1 billion of its $US1.87 billion entitlement. Its shortfall will be more than covered by China Cinda Asset Management and Shandong Lucion.
Cinda was formed back in 1999 to own underperforming assets of the China Construction bank and has since developed a reputation for making good money out of investments turned bad. And Shandong Lucion is a state-owned owner of infrastructure including ports and trains.

The other newcomers to the Yancoal register are two Chinese coal traders who will together invest $US150 million to earn an equivalent off-take agreement. And all of that serves to suggest that any plans that Yanzhou may once have had to move past the 90 per cent threshold that would allow for compulsory acquisition of minorities and the delisting of Yancoal have been abandoned.
Of course the fact that more than 90 per cent of this business will now rest in the hands of entities owned by the People's Republic served to remind that there is more than one way to skin a commercial cat.
The idea that these associations represent a leakage of control to a single entity, namely the Chinese state, is the fulcrum on which any future Noble case against the Yancoal proposal will swing.
The most opportune theatre for Noble to defend its standing in Yancoal is the Takeovers Panel. Back in 2014 Noble successfully prosecuted a claim that an attempt by Yanzhou to recapitalise Yancoal was a takeover by stealth that represented an oppression of minority rights. The Panel accepted the Noble proposition and Yancoal was left with caveats on how a truckload of convertible notes issued to Yanzhou might be converted.

But to get the Panel to ponder the fate of Yancoal minorities this time around Noble will need first to mount a convincing argument that says this rights issue represents a takeover. And that might be tricky given that the net result of the transaction in play is that Yanzhou's 78 per cent holding will be diluted to something nearer 65 per cent.
But even should the Panel decide to hear the case, the question of minorities and whether the arrangement proposed might represent oppression is far more faceted and debateable than it was three years ago. Indeed, looked at through the Yancoal lens, it is hard to see what on earth Noble might have to complain about.
Yancoal has offered minorities entitlement enough to sustain an only slightly diminished proportional share of the company and it has secured options that mean any shortfall in take up will be covered by new investors. Those arrangements have been made in full knowledge that Yanzhou did not want to take its full entitlement and that Noble was unlikely to be able to afford to.
But what is Yancoal supposed to do about that? Is the Corporations Law really framed to force strategic stasis on a company like Yancoal just because one of its two major shareholders cannot afford to continue to be the most sensible mechanic for funding growth?

Good times in Rio

If we ignore the personal and regulatory calamity of Guineagate, then it looks for all the world like JS Jacques could not have picked a better time to inherit Rio Tinto.
Unexpectedly buoyant iron ore markets, the continued strong recovery of its returns in aluminium and an amazing final fling from its rapidly diminishing coal business has
While underlying earnings ran slightly lower than consensus, first-half cash flows surged by 95 per cent to $US6.3 billion on the back of higher commodity prices and cost improvements.
As a result, Rio has been freed to outperform expectations for the weight of capital it would direct back to shareholders at the mid point of its financial calendar.
That Rio would throw free cash at an improved interim dividend and another buyback was widely anticipated by the market. But the market had expected a buyback of maybe $US500 million and that dividend would consume about 40 per cent of interim profit. Instead the payout ratio is 50 per cent, leaving Rio paying a record interim dividend of $US1.10 and the board has determined it will invest a further $US1 billion on buying itself.
To be clear, Rio is just past the midpoint of the $US500 million buyback launched on the back of the 2016 results, which means it will actually pump $US1.2 billion back to the market over the next six months or so.
And there is little more certain on planet Earth than that this financial genuflection to shareholders' demands for a greater share of the miners' spoils will be amplified substantially when Rio delivers its full-year earnings.

Jacques and his jolly CFO Chris Lynch readily accepted reminders that their board would weight their dividend and capital management to second-half performance.
The portents for year end are strong, not least because Rio fully expects to be paid the $US2.45 billion that it is owed for the sale of Coal & Allied. But management also expects to maintain the pace of productivity gains and cost outs, which ran at $US2.1 billion through the June half. And Jacques offered no reason whatsoever to anticipate a material change of circumstance in his core market of iron ore or in the recovered standing of his aluminium business.
"Six months ago I said I was confident about China. That remains true. The Chinese economy has performed well in 2017 and the early signs for 2018 are positive," he said. "The outlook is stable. But price volatility will remain a feature of the market," Jacques added, as if seeking a little caveat to a bullishness that no one could blame him for.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>US150</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday Yancoal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>People's Republic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Construction</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yancoal</name>
    <count>22</count>
    <score>-9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$500</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese SOE Yankuang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JS Jacques</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China's Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Cinda Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cinda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yanzhou's 78</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporations Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anglo-Swiss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guineagate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFO Chris Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>11</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shandong Lucion</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noble</name>
    <count>19</count>
    <score>-19</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Takeover Panel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glencore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.87</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yanzhou</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Inc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacques</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yancoal Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US310</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.35</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.5</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
