<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414345657744702</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/tasmania/maverick-tasmanian-senator-facing-compo-claim-by-former-chief-of-staff-rob-messenger/news-story/fc1f9e9dcfae95eacb123bdaef9bb79e</url>
  <title>Ex-adviser suing Lambie over book</title>
  <content>
Senator Jacqui Lambie's former chief of staff Rob Messenger has launched more legal action against the no-nonsense Tasmanian MP.
The latest action concerns a book that one publisher apparently described as "like nothing I've ever read by a politician".
Mr Messenger is already suing Senator Lambie and the Commonwealth for unfair dismissal and has threatened to subpoena the Prime Minister.
Now, in a separate case, Mr Messenger is seeking $4000 for a ghostwritten - but unpublished - autobiography he claims to have penned about his former boss.
In his statement of claim against Senator Lambie, Mr Messenger said he agreed to write the book for three instalments of $4000 after she allegedly received a $20,000 advance by publisher Allen & Unwin.
In documents lodged with the Burnie Magistrates Court, Mr Messenger claims his drafts were well received by Allen & Unwin.
"[They said] I think you've absolutely nailed the voice. I could hear Jacqui in every word I read," Mr Messenger alleged.
In another email, Mr Messenger claimed Allen & Unwin said Big W's head buyers "loved it" and the publisher's "biggest book buyer had doubled their order".
However, after Mr Messenger and his wife Fern left Senator Lambie's office in May, the book deal went south.
Mr Messenger, who was paid the first instalment, is seeking a further $4000 from Senator Lambie for the manuscript he said his solicitor delivered to her and Allen & Unwin. Senator Lambie said it would be inappropriate to comment on the court action.
Mr Messenger announced his separate industrial court action against Ms Lambie and the Federal Government in a graphic Youtube video that contained threats depicting decapitation by terrorists that had been sent to her office while he worked there.
Mr Messenger has accused the Prime Minister's office "or another government department" of leaking a complaint he made about Senator Lambie to the press.
He claims the leak prompted threatening anonymous calls to his home phone.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BIG W</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unwin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Jacqui Lambie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lambie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ex-adviser</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Messenger</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allen</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Lambie</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YouTube</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rob Messenger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmanian MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnie Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
