<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414375722516656</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/energy/this-is-the-climate-risk-jolt-that-super-funds-need-20170802-gxnwst.html</url>
  <title>Enough gentle nudging, this is a jolt super funds need</title>
  <content>
Enough of the gentle nudges and warning signs from regulators and leaders in the investment community. Superannuation fund trustees are legally obliged to consider climate change risk and that's that.
That at least is the opinion from Noel Hutley SC and James Mack, as reported by Fairfax Media today. The opinion makes it clear that climate change is a financial risk and trustees have a duty to consider it as such.

Up Next

Suicide attackers grenade Shi'te mosque

00:48

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Timelapse of Arctic icebreaker with not much ice

More than a century since the first successful transit of the treacherous Northwest Passage, the impacts of climate change can be seen with the Arcticas melting sea ice.

Earlier this year,  described climate as "distinctly financial in nature", "foreseeable, material and actionable now", and having "potential system-wide implications".
If this view is shared by Australian super funds, they do a great job of hiding it from the public. Market Forces reviewed public disclosures of the 100 largest funds in Australia and found that 82 per cent had disclosed little to no evidence that they were considering climate risk.

In fact, 60 funds showed no evidence whatsoever. Including the words "climate change" in an environmental, social and governance (ESG) policy, publishing a blog post on the topic of climate change or putting your name to the Paris pledge would have been enough to get a fund out of the do-nothing category.
We set the bar so low it was practically on the floor, yet funds managing the retirement savings of 8.8 million Australians still failed to do the bare minimum.

Not that doing the bare minimum is going to earn a fund any points. In fact, treating climate change as something to be dealt with through an ESG policy is more reflective of how poorly the industry understands climate risk.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Summerhayes' speech, the Financial Stability Board's Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures and the view from Hutley and Mack all talk about climate change as a financial risk.Photo: Nicolas Walker
They're not asking funds to consider the global climate's ability to sustain anywhere near today's population levels, or to worry about whether today's children will grow up in a world dominated by resource depletion, mass migration, conflict and disease.
They're asking trustees to fulfil their duties and consider the financial implications of climate risk.Photo: Jessica Hromas
Having an ESG policy that includes climate change might mean a fund considers whether they're invested in companies with the capacity to reduce their own emissions over time, or demonstrate "best practice" operations. Exposure to a coal export terminal might mean a fund has weighed up the ethical implications of that investment alongside all the other arguments for or against it.
That's fine, but it doesn't help a fund determine whether that oil and gas company is going to suffer major devaluation as the world transitions away from a high-carbon economy, or the financial loss sustained if that coal terminal is put out of action from storm surge damage, or flooding preventing train lines from transporting coal to port.
You'd think the funds that are taking this issue seriously would put some evidence in the public domain about it.

These are the sorts of risks that trustees need to consider, and super funds would do well to make sure that investment managers are looking as closely at climate risk as sustainability teams.
There is a caveat to our research - we're relying on what's in the public record. Just because a fund hasn't disclosed climate risk considerations doesn't mean they're ignoring it.
But Hutley and Mack's opinion that trustees are expected to "record their decision-making processes, including any considerations of climate change risks" means if trustees are considering climate risk they should have something to show for it.
Even if trustee deliberations are too sensitive for the public record, you'd think the funds that are taking this issue seriously would put some evidence in the public domain about it.
It's the same principle that investors themselves are taking with the companies they hold. Last month, the Australian Council for Superannuation Investors produced a study finding that .
Important though it is to scrutinise companies over their climate risk disclosure, it would be easier to take seriously if all ACSI members got their own houses in order. REST, for example, discloses no evidence of considering climate risk, while QSuper's climate risk disclosure consists of a lonely blog post from 2015.
Trustees deal in risk on a daily basis, and are welcome to construct portfolios and investment options that bear a very high level of climate risk if they want. But not knowing or considering climate risk - that's simply not good enough.
Julien Vincent is executive director of Market Forces
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACSI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hutley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mack</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Market Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arctic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Stability Board's Task Force</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noel Hutley SC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julien Vincent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolas Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QSuper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Hromas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northwest Passage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Mack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arctica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESG</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Summerhayes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superannuation Investors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Climate-related Financial Disclosures</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
