<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414341362777368</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/rugby/brad-thorn-to-coach-queensland-country-in-national-rugby-championship/news-story/037c58e5e616ea437a3f286e16f9508c</url>
  <title>Thorn to take helm of Qld Country</title>
  <content>
TWO-CODE titan Brad Thorn is to tackle the biggest coaching job of his blossoming off-field career with Queensland Country in the National Rugby Championship.
The head coaching role for the eight-round tournament with the competition's underperformers will be a true test of Thorn's ability to pass on technical and mental strengths.
Thorn was assistant coach with Country last season and has already shown he can imbue teams with extra steel as coach of the undefeated Queensland Under-20s this year.
Thorn was a conspicuous presence on the sidelines at the recent Wallaby camp in Newcastle as an invited guest of coach Michael Cheika.
The one-time Origin forward-turned-All Black has already generated plenty of support for his coaching style based around high standards, team spirit and no unnecessary words.
Meanwhile, The Queensland Rugby Union on Wednesday knocked back a bid by Wests to have former Wallabies lock Mark Chisholm cleared to play in Sunday's minor semi-final against Sunnybank at Ballymore.
It's disappointing to see a drawcard rubbed out of the finals but playing just two games for the Bulldogs was short of the six required under the eligibility rules.
"We tried to get a dispensation based on Mark being a Wests junior and clubman before his Wallaby days and time overseas but unfortunately we were turned down," Wests coach Pat Byron said.
With the 35-year-old Chisholm ruled out, Connor Anderson will shift from the back row to lock, which allows key flanker Jeremiah Lynch to slot in.
Classy teenage hooker Joe Cotton will sit on the bench after playing for Wests Colts in their major semi-final.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Under-20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballymore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qld Country</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chisholm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Rugby Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cheika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Chisholm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremiah Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Colts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pat Byron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunnybank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Cotton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connor Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Thorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Country</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Rugby Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
