<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413821671722454</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/nsw/fruiterer-waeil-rustom-sentenced-to-five-years-jail-for-running-sydney-cocaine-syndicate-20170802-gxnnsf.html</url>
  <title>Fruiterer Waeil Rustom sentenced to five years' jail for running Sydney cocaine syndicate</title>
  <content>
A drug and gambling-addicted fruiterer who ran a Sydney cocaine syndicate servicing the city's well-to-do has been sentenced to five years' jail.
to fuel his ongoing addictions, unbeknown to the fact he was about to be stung in an undercover operation. Photo: NSW Police
The father-of-four supplied bags of cocaine to his right-hand man, Robert Max Vernon, who delivered the drugs to customers across the city. 
When the demand was high, other men, including a taxi driver, were recruited to carry out deliveries. 

The clientele ranged from sport stars to young professionals and well-known media identities, Fairfax Media understands. 
Rustom, from Ashcroft in Sydney's south-west, was sentenced to five years and three months jail on Wednesday for drug supply.

The fruit market stall-holder will be eligible for parole after three years and three months. 

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In sentencing Rustom, Judge Garry Neilson said the syndicate was neither sophisticated nor overly elaborate.Photo: Fairfax Media
"The codes used for description of drugs are obvious codes and ones which the courts and law enforcement agencies are quite familiar," he told the Downing Centre District Court. 
"This syndicate was not the importer or manufacturer or ultimate supplier of the drugs."Photo: NSW Police
Rustom had been a "user of cocaine who found it convenient to become a supplier" because he could obtain drugs for "nothing", Judge Neilson added. 
The money made from drug sales went back to Rustom.
When the Middle Eastern Organised Crime Squad raided his house in September, 2015, they found $10,200 in cash and 54 grams of heroin in a pillowcase. 
As part of his role as "manager" of the cocaine syndicate, Vernon, 42, was given a car for deliveries and a phone to receive orders. 
Customers would text or call their orders before the cocaine, ranging from a single gram to a 15 gram per order, was dropped off to spots around Sydney. 
A lot of the work was in the eastern suburbs, including Woollahra, Waverley and Vaucluse. 
Much of the clientele were city professionals, including an eastern suburbs businessman, talent agency employee and interior designer. 
According to a statement of agreed facts, an undercover police officer purchased cocaine from Vernon in Coogee in August, 2015. ​
Before his arrest in 2015, Rustom was consuming about 3 grams of cocaine a day and spending his money on gambling and prostitutes, the court heard. 
Tracing back the origins of his drug addiction, Rustom highlighted the stress linked to the imprisonment of his younger brother for murder in 2002 as a contributing factor. 
Mohamed Rustom was swept up in a police crackdown on prolific drug activity and the infamous Telopea St gang in the late 1990s. 
Despite his dissolute lifestyle, Rustom's wife was prepared to stick by him, the court heard.
"He clearly wants to rehabilitate himself, he clearly wants to be free from alcohol and drug addiction," Judge Neilson said. 
The judge said there may be many that use cocaine and only a small number that developed real social problems but that was still too many.
Stressing the importance of Rustom having support once he left jail, Judge Neilson said Rustom would be subject to supervised parole under the control of community corrections. 
"... to ensure he steers clear of drugs and gambling addictions and a life of crime," he said.
Rustom was given a 25 per cent reduction in his sentence for pleading guilty to the charges at the earliest opportunity. 
His co-accused Vernon, a former aged care nurse, was sentenced to three years and nine months jail with a non-parole period of two years. 
The drivers in the syndicate are due to be sentenced in October. 
Rustom's brother, Abdul Rustom, 26, was charged with supplying 33 grams of cocaine as part of the syndicate. 
Driver Cabdiqure Gure used his Combined Services taxi to take part in the supply of 42 grams of cocaine.
Fellow drivers Denial Sfeir and Ahmed Naaman have also pleaded guilty to taking part in the drug supply.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vaucluse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fruiterer Waeil Rustom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vernon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Garry Neilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judge Neilson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denial Sfeir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waverley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Rustom</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ahmed Naaman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vernon, 42</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downing Centre District Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Max Vernon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Rustom, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashcroft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coogee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabdiqure Gure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern Organised Crime Squad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woollahra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rustom</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telopea St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Police</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Combined Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
