<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414848168929769</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/2615611/emma-seeks-biker-who-stayed-with-her-after-horrific-crash/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Emma seeks biker who stayed with her after horrific crash</title>
  <content>
Emma Regan, 17, from Corrimal is laid up in Coledale Hospital after a motorbike crash in the Royal National Park last month. Picture: KIRK GILMOUR

With a metal plate in her hip, her legs in traction and her wrist in a cast, Emma Regan seems like she has little to be thankful for.
The 17-year-old, however, wants to thank the motorcyclist who came to her aid after a horrific bike crash last month.
While riding her own motorcycle near the Royal National Park on September 21, the Corrimal resident misjudged a corner and ploughed head-on into a car. Fracturing her knee, wrist and pelvis, Emma thought she had spinal damage, but was comforted by an unknown good Samaritan until paramedics arrived.
Emma, and her mum Roz Elliott, now want to find that man, to say thanks.
"He gave me his jacket and kept me calm, because I was really freaking out," Emma said.
"He told me I was doing well, reassured me, and stayed until they put me in the ambulance."
Ms Elliott said she was not told of the crash until after Emma had been flown to St George Hospital.
"Knowing someone was with her, that she wasn't just lying in a ditch somewhere, I can't even measure it in words," she said.
"Just to think someone cared like that, when these days people don't want to get involved, is amazing."
The search is now on for the rider. Emma described him as in his late 20s, with short brown hair, tattooed arms, and riding a red Honda motorcycle.
"I'm just so thankful. If he wasn't there, I don't know what state I would be in now," Emma said.
"I'm so grateful someone did that for me. You don't realise how helpful some people are."

If you have any information please call the Mercury on 4221 2206.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George's Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Samaritans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coledale Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Regan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emma Regan, 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KIRK GILMOUR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal National Park</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roz Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Elliott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
