<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651413860326429012</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>12:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/entertainment/television/the-bachelor-matty-j-has-puckered-up-with-jewellery-designer-laura-byrne-in-his-first-kiss-of-the-season/news-story/7dafa1fa574b012847b94dd933e32d88</url>
  <title>Matty J seals date with first kiss</title>
  <content>
FORGET the body language experts, it's the bookmakers who may just be on the money when it comes to this year's Bachelor - predicting Sydney jewellery designer Laura Byrne would be the first to win a kiss from this year's most eligible man.
With the sun setting on a perfect solo date, it was the 30-year-old from Rushcutters (via Wollongong) who  - as well as a rose keeping her in the contest for his heart.
Their lingering and passionate liplock sealed weeks of internet gossip that the pairing will go the distance on Channel 10's reality romance series, which sent social media into meltdown on Wednesday night.
And if previous Bachelor form is any guide, the first kiss has proved a fast-track to the final rose, with Sam Wood pashing his now fiance Snezana Markosi on their first date; while Tim Robards also puckering up with his bride-to-be, Anna Heinrich early on in their 2013 season.
While love rival Leah Costa made her move last week to claim first kiss, her efforts were embarrassingly brushed by
"I did kiss more than one person [but] I was very selective with the kiss," he told TV Guide.
"I wouldn't just kiss purely because I went on a date with somebody, I only kissed if I really felt it," he said.
It certainly looked like they both "felt it" with Johnson running his hands through Byrne's hair, after they'd laughed their way through a creative outing where the Bachie challenged his artistic date in a sketching contest.
While she joked she was highly offended by his amateur efforts, all seemed forgiven when the pair cosied up on a harbourside couch and she admitted: "Matty makes me feel a little bit giddy."
Johnson seemed impressed by his decision to kiss Byrne, telling viewers: "I wanted to kiss Laura since the first moment I saw her today."
"Today has probably been one of the easiest first dates I've ever been on," he swooned.
She agreed, adding: "Best. First. Date. Ever."
It propels the Georgia Love lookalike to the lead in the race for Johnson's heart, ahead of early favourite Elora Murger and Lisa Carlton, who have both enjoyed single dates but Matty J minus the smooch.
* The Bachelor airs 7.30pm, Wednesday and Thursday, on Ten.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia Love</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leah Costa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty J</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Byrne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elora Murger</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura Byrne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Johnson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TV Guide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Robards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snezana Markosi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Heinrich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rushcutters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
