<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414341362777348</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/frankstons-violet-freeman-100-reflects-on-rich-life-including-stint-as-first-female-licenced-real-estate-agent-in-peninsula-region/news-story/d42d909b5e74fcfa44f0ddcc9a4929bc</url>
  <title>Trailblazing Violet reflects on long life</title>
  <content>
AFTER losing her real estate agent husband Ted following a long illness, Violet Freeman did the only thing that seemed sensible.
It was the late 1950s and Mrs Freeman set herself to the task of taking over her husband's Frankston business - W.E. Freeman Real Estate.
Supported by family and friends, the widowed mother of three worked to become qualified as the first female licenced real estate agent in the Mornington Peninsula region.
Now 100 years old, Mrs Freeman smiles when she recalls the backlash she copped then from some male real estate agents who weren't enamoured with the thought of a woman entering their domain.
"They said it's a man's job," she said.
Undeterred, Mrs Freeman drew strength from those telling her the opposite.
"I had to do it - it was a busy time for me," she said.
But while male real estate agents were unimpressed, Mrs Freeman said her clients were overwhelmingly supportive.
"I liked those years," she said
One of eight children growing up on a Baxter farm, where parents George and Maude had cattle and chickens, there was no electricity or running water and she did her school homework by the light of a kerosene lamp.
Mrs Freeman's first trip in a car was memorable, particularly as it involved going to hospital in her early teens to be treated for diphtheria.
She completed the equivalent of Year 8 at the Baxter school before embarking on a rich and varied working life that included a stint as the governess to three children at the Darling Downs, Queensland.
Later, she met Ted Freeman, a cabinet-maker and builder, at a dance in Langwarrin.
"He was very good looking," she recalled. She married her beau at St Paul's Anglican Church, Frankston, in 1938.
Three children followed - John, Jenny and Joanne. Ted spotted an opportunity in real estate, setting up his firm in early 1950.
Mrs Freeman ran the firm for a decade after taking it over following the loss of her husband in 1958 - the other major focus being her children.
Her daughter Joanne recalled: "She stayed single and devoted herself to the family all those years. It was all about family."
In retirement, her interests included sport, travel and, of course, family.
These days, Mrs Freeman is a keen member of the Baxter Village Friendship Club and enjoys socialising and outings with the group.
Mrs Freeman lived in her own home until a few years ago before moving in with Joanne and son-in-law Maurice at their Frankston property.
She reckoned her longevity might have something to do with her genes, particularly as sister Ivy lived to 98 years.
Surely there's some great secret? A nightly nip of brandy or a bit of chocolate?
"It just happened. I just lived a normal life. I seldom eat chocolate," she said with a chuckle.
Mrs Freeman celebrated her 100th birthday recently at a gathering with family and friends.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baxter Village Friendship Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Violet Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Freeman</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baxter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maurice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Year 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LANGWARRIN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darling Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joanne</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Paul's Anglican Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ted Freeman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maude</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W.E. Freeman Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Violet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
