<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414843873962416</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/donald-trump-signs-russia-sanctions-bill-but-says-its-seriously-flawed-20170802-gxo69i.html</url>
  <title>Donald Trump signs Russia sanctions bill but says it's 'seriously flawed'</title>
  <content>
Washington: US President Donald Trump has signed , ending immediate hopes of a reset of US relations with the Kremlin and marking a defeat for his administration.
In a statement outlining his concerns, Mr Trump called the bill "seriously flawed," primarily because it limits his ability to negotiate sanctions without Congressional approval.

Up Next

Suicide attackers grenade Shi'te mosque

00:48

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Russia to expel 755 US diplomatic staff

Russian President Vladimir Putin says Moscow will expel 755 US  diplomats and could impose additional measures against the United States in response to new US sanctions against Russia.

"By limiting the Executive's flexibility, this bill makes it harder for the United States to strike good deals for the American people, and will drive China, Russia, and North Korea much closer together," he said in a statement on Wednesday morning.
"The framers of our Constitution put foreign affairs in the hands of the President This bill will prove the wisdom of that choice."

White House officials said that the President signed the measure on Wednesday morning, nearly a week after it was passed by the Senate with a veto-proof majority. The bill was also approved in the House last week by an overwhelming bipartisan majority.
Mr Trump said that he signed the bill, despite his reservations, for the sake of "national unity."

In a second statement accompanying his signing of the legislation, Mr Trump called some of the provisions in the legislation "clearly unconstitutional."

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

And he questioned Congress' ability to negotiate sanctions based on their inability to approve the Republicans' healthcare legislation.Photo: AP
"The bill remains seriously flawed - particularly because it encroaches on the executive branch's authority to negotiate," Mr Trump said.
"Congress could not even negotiate a healthcare bill after seven years of talking."Photo: AP
Russia has already retaliated against the US for the new sanctions, announcing that  and seize US diplomatic properties.
In addition to new sanctions, the bill requires congressional review for any actions the administration might seek to take to lift sanctions in the future.
The measure also imposes sanctions against North Korea and Iran for those countries' nuclear weapons programs.
The White House had expressed concerns publicly and directly to lawmakers about the provision embedded within the bill that essentially prevents Mr Trump from lifting existing sanctions without congressional approval. The administration had signalled that it hoped to ease tensions with Russia.
The administration also said it was worried about the impact of the bill on US businesses doing business in Russia.
The sanctions also further retaliate against Russia for its alleged meddling in the 2016 election.
Mr Trump has called the ongoing investigations in Congress and by a special counsel into Russian interference in the 2016 election a "witch hunt." He has also repeatedly insisted that while Russia could have been responsible, other countries might also have been at fault.
That Congress would tie Mr Trump's hands on this issue reflects a deepening concern about the administration's posture toward Russia, which critics have characterised as naive.
In a statement late last week, the White House signalled that Mr Trump would eventually sign the measure, and a White House official added that the administration had worked to negotiate critical elements of it.
Despite Russian President Vladimir Putin moving quickly to retaliate against the US, Mr Trump has not issued any statement - written or otherwise - on the Kremlin's actions.
Washington Post
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian President Vladimir Putin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.75</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President This</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
