<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414345657744704</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>14:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/north-west/moonee-ponds-women-who-have-been-friends-since-school-celebrate-80th-birthday-together/news-story/d37675c538c3020b55b762c91d29438c</url>
  <title>Friends celebrate close bond of 75 years</title>
  <content>
WHEN  school started at St Monica's Primary School in Moonee Ponds in 1942, a group of eager young school girls started what was to become a lifelong journey of friendship and sisterhood.
A group of 15 women from Moonee Valley formed a friendship during their primary school years that has lasted for more than 70 years.
For the past 20 years, the women have met twice a year to reconnect and catch up.
Last week they met at Legends bistro at the Moonee Valley racetrack, to celebrate their collective 80th birthdays.
Marg Mogg from Moonee Ponds is one of the women in the group, and grew up on Homer St in Moonee Ponds. "There were about five of us who started together in Prep, and then over the years we all just became friends," Ms Mogg said.
"There's a great bond between us all. There's one lady who went on to become a nun, the others all married and had children. A lot of us stayed in the same area, and we all still mostly live in the Moonee Valley area."
The women undertook a commercial course for three years once they completed their primary education.
"We had a wonderful nun who taught us, she really worked on getting us ready to go out into the work force. She was a bit ahead of her time. She was just wonderful," Ms Mogg said.
"We all joined a youth group at St Monica's, and that helped keep us together.
"No one had cars, we all lived locally, and we'd all meet up at the youth group. So many of the girls met their husbands in the area."
While the bonds of their friendship haven't changed during the past 75 years, life in Moonee Ponds is different.
"All the apartments that are being built, and all the houses being pulled down, like my old home in Homer St. It all looks so different," Ms Mogg said.
But she noted some things have stayed the same.
"Queens Park has stayed the same, which is beautiful," she said. "It's a wonderful park, and we used to meet up there regularly."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mogg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queen's Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonee Ponds</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marg Mogg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moonee Valley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Monica's Primary School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Monica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homer St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homer St. It</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
