<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415449464363453</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/leadership/entrepreneur/postit-notes-get-reinvented-by-uts-hatchery-startup-wallsync-20170801-gxmsly</url>
  <title>Post-it note reinvented by Sydney start-up</title>
  <content>
The momentum produced by a brainstorming session with Post-it notes can be lost just as quickly in the chore of transcribing them into a project management program - but a Sydney start-up claims it has the solution.
WallSync, a , has produced a software-as-a-service product that uses augmented reality to maintain a link between a physical wall of Post-it notes, and the images of them taken by users' smartphone cameras.
Those photographs have the handwriting in them recognised and converted into a text note in the project management program being used by the team.
"Once that link is established, the physical note and the digital note are kept together," said Geoff Bullen, who co-founded WallSync with brother Alex.

Daniel Munoz

"If you move the paper note on the wall, you just need to take another photograph and the note gets reassigned in the project management system too".

The Bullen brothers previously ran an IT consultancy and often found themselves or one of their senior staff typing up and organising the post-it notes created by a strategy session.
"At $1000 a day it wasn't a very efficient use of our time," he said.
Augmented reality is used to add perspective to the Post-it notes captured inside WallSync, Mr Bullen claimed. For instance a note appears to be on fire if the deadline for the action it describes is looming, while changes in assignee can also be overlaid.
"And if someone else needs the wall that the paper notes were on, a record of them remains that can be searched and re-categorised as the project continues," Mr Bullen said.

More integrations on the way

Atlassian's flagship, JIRA, is the only project management program that WallSync integrates with to date, but Mr Bullen said integrations with Trello, now , and Asana were on the way.
The Bullen brothers were previously heavy users of JIRA at their IT consultancy Centrum, which they  to ASX-listed managed services provider RXP for $4.15 million in October 2014.
WallSync is  to digitise Post-it notes but Mr Bullen hoped its augmented reality features would prove a differentiator.

He admitted the problem WallSync solved was "niche", but important all the same.
"Nothing beats the collaboration benefits of a group of people sitting together, communicating with each other and getting ideas down with pen on paper," Mr Bullen said.
"Computer interfaces are designed for one person interacting with a monitor, so as soon as you introduce that to a group situation, people stop paying attention to each other. We're trying to combine the best of both worlds."
Learning while working

Mr Bullen is completing an , and said running a start-up at the same time had helped him get the most out of the course.
"I've found the mentors helpful, they'll come in occasionally and ask the most pertinent question - like why don't you have a customer yet?" he said.
Mr Bullen said 80 teams had applied to beta-test WallSync, which will be officially launched at Atlassian's user summit in San Jose on September 12.
Meanwhile discussions with potential investors had been sparked by WallSync's victory at Hatchery's demo day last month, which included a $5000 prize, Mr Bullen said.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trello</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Post-it</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlassian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAN JOSE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bullen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WallSync</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JIRA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Munoz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RXP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bullen</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Bullen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 12</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
