<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415642737894861</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/new-life-for-katie-rose-cottage/3207324/</url>
  <title>New life for Katie Rose Cottage</title>
  <content>
FOLLOWING the sad closure of Sunshine Hospice in December 2015, a decision was made by a group of former financial members and volunteers to establish a new charity to re-introduce palliative care services in our community.
Katie Rose Cottage Ltd was formed and the company applied for a charity licence, which was granted in November 2016.
Katie Rose Cottage a not-for-profit charity and in January 2017 we were granted Public Benevolent Institution status and registration with the national charity register, ACNC
The opening of Katie Rose Cottage op shops in Cooroy and Tewantin in early December 2016 was a significant step in our plan to provide "bread and butter" funding for the provision of our service and we have plans for more op shops later this year and other income-generating initiatives.
We have more than 140 dedicated volunteers from within our community, including op shop volunteers, gardening teams, housekeeping teams, administration volunteers and personal carers.
We recognise the invaluable community support for Katie Rose Cottage and its impact on the lives of those in need of palliative care. Support that is provided by donations and income from the op-shops enables us to make a difference "when every moment matters".
What a privilege it has been to be a part of this charity's start-up and witness the enormous effort put in by the volunteers and their belief in the new hospice.
I knew the community wanted their much-loved hospice to return and said on many occasions "the community will vote with its feet for the type of hospice it wants".
It certainly has done that!
The community support has been overwhelming and that is evident by their support and the $1 million donation we received from a local benefactor to enable the purchase of a property. There have been many other significant donations of money and goods and services.
Our new facility in Doonan is undergoing some minor modifications and will soon open for day hospice care as we work to prepare rooms for 24/7 end-of-life care. The purchase of this facility gives us security and means we can use monies raised to fund the services rather than paying rent.
Katie Rose Cottage offers guest and families a respectful and compassionate contribution to the end-of-life care and is based on a "one step from home" model. Our hospice is modern and fresh, with beautiful gardens along with being homely, comforting and welcoming, not only for our guests but also for their family and friends.
In all that we do, ethics, trust and transparency are vital to our vision. Katie Rose Cottage staff and volunteers acknowledge that they cannot change the journey that our guests and their family and friends are on, but we can assist in changing the experience.
We thank you for your interest in our charity, enabling a choice for palliative care in our community.
Carol Raye is chairperson of Katie Rose Cottage Ltd.
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
TOO many kids aren't getting a chance to reach their full potential.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACNC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Benevolent Institution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Rose Cottage Ltd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tewantin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doonan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie Rose Cottage</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Hospice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carol Raye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
