<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415629852992802</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/hotel-plans-spark-fears-tourist-hub-wont-cope/3208045/</url>
  <title>Hotel plans spark fears tourist hub won't cope</title>
  <content>
HOTEL manager Selwyn Lutz fears a "develop at all costs" approach will hurt the beachfront tourist hub he has worked in for more than a decade.
Mr Lutz's objection to the extension of building height limits at specific sites in Mooloolaba was one of 1393 submissions Sunshine Coast Council received last year opposing its amendments to the Coast's planning scheme.
They outweighed the 536 in support but the council pressed on, with State Government approval making its proposal a reality late last week.
Mr Lutz manages Aegean Apartments, which neighbours the site at the intersection of Mooloolaba and River Esplanades where Aria Property Group plans to build an international hotel.
Heights were raised there from 37.5m to up to 47.5m above ground level, which Cr John Connolly said was on the condition Aria built a five-star hotel.
Aria development director Michael Hurley said the company was progressing plans with its architects and consultant team.
"We are excited by the opportunity to bring a new luxury offering to Mooloolaba incorporating an international standard five-star hotel, high-end residential apartments and Aria's quality food and beverage offerings," Mr Hurley said yesterday.
Mr Lutz doesn't think Mooloolaba has the infrastructure to cope with it.
"It is just going to be one big, overpowering building at the end of the Esplanade," Mr Lutz said.
He said the road network was already choked up and parking was a major difficulty in the area.
"Get your infrastructure in place and then think about changing heights.
"The council is on a path to develop at any cost."
Cr Connolly said the council had been buying property along Brisbane Rd to widen the busy thoroughfare.
"We have really moved up incredibly in the last six months (with) more blocks, more blocks, more blocks," Cr Connolly said.
He said the Brisbane Rd bridge where traffic was reduced to two lanes was a "pinch point".
"That will have to change.
"It is no good having... a pinch point bridge at four lanes so we are very aware of that having to be done."
Cr Connolly said Aria had agreed to start construction in about February 2019.
Aria plan to lodge an updated development application by the end of the year.
"They've got time because it's a February 2019 start so there is a time factor there," Cr Connolly said.
He said the hotel would open in October 2020 to align with the opening of the international airport.
Mr Hurley said the project would serve as a great boost for the Coast's economy and a catalyst for reinvigorating the Mooloolaba Esplanade precinct and the surrounding tourism industry.
Cr Connolly said changes to Mooloolaba had to be managed correctly.
"My history goes back to the late '60s in Nambour so I'm not somebody who has been here for five minutes," Cr Connolly said.
"You've seen the growth and you can't ignore what is going to happen in the future.
"We have just got to be responsible in how we grow it."
He said he wanted the region to be a green, liveable place.
"We want a place here that as our university grows and our schools grow... these kids can live here and work here.
"If we don't make change, we will have a problem."
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2019</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2020</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hurley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ARIAs</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aegean Apartments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hurley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolaba Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>River Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Lutz</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Connolly</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selwyn Lutz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aria Property Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
