<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415243305929540</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/03/32/turnbull-pushes-ahead-with-media-bill</url>
  <title>Turnbull pushes ahead with media bill</title>
  <content>
The Turnbull government appears hopeful of getting its media reforms through the Senate, listing the bill for debate when parliament resumes next week as crossbenchers hatch a package of amendments.
The key sticking point is the repeal of the two out of three rule, which bars a person owning licences for TV, radio and newspapers in a single market.
All non-government parties have expressed concern about the change, saying it could reduce Australia's media diversity, which is already concentrated in a few hands.
The Senate program released on Wednesday evening listed the legislation for debate on August 9.
South Australian senator Nick Xenophon has been using the winter break to come up with a package which he says would improve the quality of journalism and breadth of news coverage.
He hopes to hold talks with Communications Minister Mitch Fifield by the end of this week, before taking a final proposal to a meeting of crossbench senators in Canberra next week.
"I want there to be a position where there could be a package of measures ... that will mean more journalists on the ground, more camera operators, more local content and better coverage of news," the senator told Sky News.

Related Articles

Senator Fifield insists the law changes will improve the viability of Australian media organisations while maintaining diversity.
The government needs 10 extra votes to get its bill through the Senate.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Communications Minister Mitch Fifield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Fifield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
