<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415647032862333</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/wishlist-changes-lives-on-the-coast/3207309/</url>
  <title>Wishlist changes lives on the Coast</title>
  <content>
THE year 2001 was an interesting time for the world.
Most of us were still recovering from the shock of 9/11, the first version of this thing called the iPod had just been released and Donald Trump was still a relatively unknown reality TV personality.
But 2001 was also the year I started a new job at the Sunshine Coast Health Services Foundation.
I spent a lot of time in hospitals growing up as my brother was very unwell for a while. So when the opportunity presented itself, I jumped at the idea of being able to help families like mine.
With no experience in fundraising and lots of enthusiasm, I embarked on what would be a rewarding journey.
Over the past 20 years, Wishlist, as it is known today, has raised over $16 million for our local public health services.
From buying equipment to funding research grants, I have been lucky enough to see first-hand the impact our support can have.
Some of our proudest moments include the opening of our $1.4 million Cancer Centre. Another is Reed Charity House, the 20-room facility that provides a safe haven for families needing accommodation to be close to a loved one in hospital.
From every House The Coast Built to the annual Wishlist Spring Carnival lunch, our Coast community generously donates time and money to a hospital they hope they will never need to use.
So much has changed since 2001 but Wishlist remains committed to its vision to help provide the best possible health services to our local community.
And with the unwavering loyalty of our supporters, I can only imagine what we will accomplish in the years to come.
There is a lot of noise in the world today and at times it is easy to believe that evil prevails.
But if my time at Wishlist has taught me one thing, it's that the human spirit is fundamentally good, and it is in our nature to help those around us who are in need.
This, I see time and time again.
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reed Charity House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast Built</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cancer Center</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Health Services Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wishlist Spring Carnival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
