<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415642737894937</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/my-heartbreak-was-life-changing/3207329/</url>
  <title>My heartbreak was life-changing</title>
  <content>
MY son Curtis was born 13 weeks premature and, while still a baby, was diagnosed with cerebral palsy and epilepsy.
It was heart-breaking, challenging and life-changing but it also resulted in me forming a not-for-profit organisation, charity and disability service to help Sunshine Coast people support their sons and daughters living with a disability.
That organisation is called Sunshine Butterflies.
When I first found out I had a child with a disability, I went on a roller-coaster of emotions that was hard to cope with.
Curtis is now a beautiful 22-year-old man with a funny sense of humour who loves music, motorbikes, sport and earthmoving machines.
When we finally brought Curtis home from hospital, he was on oxygen while his lungs developed. He was often sick and would spend numerous days and nights in hospital. Our life became a constant round of attending doctor and hospital appointments which left us exhausted, sad and lonely.
It was really hard to find the sort of support I really needed and the frustration led to me to establish Sunshine Butterflies to help other families by creating and providing everything I wished I could have accessed when I was a new mum.
It all started with a support group, which quickly developed into numerous other services and programs that were flexible, innovative and dynamic, as I felt this was lacking from existing programs that were being offered.
Sunshine Butterflies does not receive government funding and relies on sponsorship, fundraising, donations and its own business initiatives to fund its programs and operation costs.
Our latest project is Our Backyard - a two-hectare (five-acre) education and recreational facility in the Noosa countryside that provides life skills and recreation and learning opportunities to young people of all ages with disabilities. Activities include music, art, woodwork, cooking and drama classes, while early-intervention therapy programs are offered to younger members.
We also cater for siblings who are often forgotten while mums and dads spend hours caring for their disabled child.
The newest concept at Our Backyard is farm therapy: an animal enrichment program which also includes therapeutic horticulture that teaches life skills to build self-esteem and confidence and shapes positive behaviours.
Animals have an incredible impact on our members, with both emotional and physical benefits.
The goal is to develop skills using a different form of learning through something they enjoy.
Just stroking, grooming or talking to any of our farm animals soon has the most agitated child or young adult relaxed.
It is truly life-changing and I am so happy to know I have been able to play a role in changing the lives of other people.
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
TOO many kids aren't getting a chance to reach their full potential.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Butterflies</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtis</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
