<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415634147960169</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/our-blood-is-definitely-worth-bottling/3207318/</url>
  <title>Our blood is definitely worth bottling</title>
  <content>
THE Australian Red Cross Blood Service officially began in 1996 but its origins go back more than 80 years.
In 1929, the first blood was collected in Australia and for decades after, state and territory Red Cross groups collected, processed and distributed their own blood supplies.
Blood collection began in earnest in Queensland in the early 1930s and by 1941, a dedicated commitment was made to establish collection centres across the state to ensure a blood supply for all Queenslanders.
Blood collection began on the Sunshine Coast in the late 1940s, when the Red Cross Blood Transfusion Service would visit the Nambour Hospital asking people to donate blood.
Within a few short years, giving blood had woven its way into the community's spirit and Nambour residents set a new record of 183 donations in seven hours.
The 1940s also saw the first Red Cross mobile blood bank make its maiden journey through Western Australia, though it would be another 50 years before the Sunshine Coast had one to call its own. Launching on February 14, 1990, the much-loved "blood van" quickly became one of the Blood Service's most recognisable icons on the Coast.
The "vans" have come a long way since then and in 2009, the Sunshine Coast's Mobile Donor Centre was the first in Australia to be able to collect Apheresis Plasma.
The Red Cross Blood Service Nambour Donor Centre opened in its current location in 1996 and sees around 150 donors rolling up their sleeves every week.
In 2009, the Maroochydore centre opened its doors to the first blood donor and in that time has collected more than 100,000 donations.
The Blood Service's longest-serving volunteer, Margaret Andrews, has witnessed four decades of history.
"Back then, everyone was a volunteer - even the doctors and nurses," she recalled. "We collected at various locations: Coolum, Maroochydore and Kawana. Then came the first caravan and then paid staff. Now we have a much bigger van and many more venues.
"In the early days, each donor had a volunteer beside them holding the donation bag. We were called 'twirlers', because we moved the bag around to mix the anti-coagulation. These days, a machine takes care of that."
Jacqui Hooke, a nurse at the Nambour Donor Centre, has worked with the Blood Service for more than 20 years.
"Back in 1997 when I started, we were a collection, production and distribution centre," she said. "All blood collected on the Sunshine Coast was processed and kept here for local use."On any given day, I could interview a donor, take their blood, then process, label and dispatch it to a patient whose life depended on it. All in a day's work!"
One in three Australians will need donated blood in their lifetime, yet less than 3% of the population donates. We all expect blood will be available if we need it, but our blood supply rides on the back of a small group of dedicated and generous donors.
In the past year, more than 11,000 Sunshine Coast residents have collectively made nearly 30,000 blood donations, saving up to 90,000 lives.
"What I love most about working for Blood Service is the same now as it was then - the donors: those dedicated locals who come back time and again and give their precious blood and time," Jacqui said.
Giving blood takes less than one hour, and each donation saves three lives. 750 Sunshine Coast residents need to donate blood every week to ensure our blood supply is maintained.
Please call 13 14 95 or visit www.donateblood.com.au to find out more and make an appointment.
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Andrews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Red Cross Blood Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Cross Blood Service Nambour Donor Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui Hooke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kawana</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 14, 1990</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast's Mobile Donor Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacqui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Cross Blood Transfusion Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apheresis Plasma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Donor Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Cross</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blood Services</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
