<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414934068277977</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/605975/clairvoyants-water-vision-over-missing-man/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Clairvoyant's water vision over missing man</title>
  <content>
Clairvoyant's water vision over missing man

Leslie Hicks

Karen James fears the worst after her father Leslie Hicks, disappeared from a Woonona retirement village 50 days ago. Picture: KEN ROBERTSON

exit
Woonona's Karen James has hired a clairvoyant in a desperate bid to find her father who disappeared exactly 50 days ago.Leslie Hicks, 81, vanished without a trace from his Woonona Retirement Village hostel on March 23 and despite two massive police searches at Bellambi and Corrimal, there are still no clues to his disappearance. "The clairvoyant said more or less that he is near the water, not in the water or on the water but near the water," Mrs James said."But she couldn't say whether he was with us or not."On Wednesday Wollongong Police conducted a search for the missing great-grandfather in bushland near Broker St in Bellambi and the following day police divers searched a nearby dam. They found nothing.Meanwhile Mr Hicks's apartment at the Woonona Retirement Village remains exactly how he left it. Staff turn his lights on each night and security guards check the room every hour, just in case he returns.Mr Hick's bank account has not been used since he disappeared, leaving Mrs James to think the inevitable. "For the first five or six weeks I was feeling really positive that more than likely he was lost, that he would come back, that we would find him," she said."But now I am starting to realise that there is a good chance I have lost him."Her theory is that her father headed to Newcastle to visit his son, but became lost on the way.Mr Hicks suffers from diabetes, low-level dementia and macular degeneration. The last official sighting of him was on March 25, two days after he was reported missing. A friend, Lindsay Newton, saw a grass-covered Mr Hicks on Robson Rd in Corrimal, but was unaware that he was considered missing.Mr Newton's sighting sparked a full scale air and land police search of the area.Mr Hicks is 168cm tall with grey hair, wears glasses and was last seen wearing dark blue track pants, a blue and white polo shirt, dark blue jumper and black shoes. People with information are urged to contact Wollongong Police on 4226 7899 or Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karen James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindsay Newton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robson Rd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bellambi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday Wollongong Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woonona Retirement Village</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Newton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KEN ROBERTSON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie Hicks</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Hicks</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woonona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs James</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broker St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meanwhile Mr Hicks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woonona's Karen James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
