<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414856758864681</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/tesla-stock-price-sliding-ahead-of-earnings-2017-8</url>
  <title>Tesla is slipping ahead of earnings</title>
  <content>
is down 1.58% on Wednesday as investors prepare for its second-quarter earnings report to be released after the bell.

The electric automaker is expected to lose $US2.34 a share on revenue of $US2.51 billion, according to data from Bloomberg.

Analysts are mixed on the company. 44% of analysts surveyed by Bloomberg are neutral while 32% are bullish and 24% are bearish. The company's high valuation is one of the primary criticisms from investors. Even CEO .

Bullish investors are pricing in a successful launch of the company's newest car, the Model 3. , and is starting to ramp up its production schedule to meet the 500,000 cars in its preorder backlog.

The Model 3 is widely . The company has lost money in nearly every quarter since its 2010 initial public offering. The mass-marketed Model 3 is the first car to be priced at the lower end of the auto market, at $US35,000 before tax incentives.

Tesla hopes to be producing 20,000 vehicles a month by the end of the year. Customers who order a Model 3 today will be looking at a mid-to-late 2018 delivery date, according to the company.

Bearish investors find it hard to see past the company's history of losses. David Einhorn, the hedge fund billionaire who is perhaps the loudest bear on Tesla, has said the company has only . Tesla is expected to burn through $US2 billion this year, according to Einhorn.

Short sellers have been taking it on the chin as of late. Tesla has risen 44.75% this year, while maintaining its status as the most shorted stock on the market.  though, and short interest is at its lowest point in years.

NOW WATCH: Money & Markets videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Einhorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$35,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model 3</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Einhorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.34</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2.51</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
