<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415651327829685</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/bloomhill-is-making-a-difference/3207310/</url>
  <title>Bloomhill is making a difference</title>
  <content>
IN the 50th anniversary year of the Sunshine Coast, one of the much-valued health and wellness organisations in our community will also be celebrating a significant milestone.
Bloomhill Cancer Care in Buderim will commemorate its 20-year celebrations in October.
Chief executive officer Mervat Quirke, Bloomhill patron Raelene Boyle and Bloomhill's manager of volunteer services Alex Bert sat down together to reflect on the past two decades.
Bloomhill Cancer Care had its origins in Eumundi, founded in 1997. The first op shop, known then as Angels Op Shop, was established in Nambour that year.
The move to the current location on Ballinger Rd, Buderim, took place in 1999, originally under a lease agreement. Angels Op Shop became the Nambour Bloomhill Op Shop and two more were opened at Buderim and Maroochydore.
The Volunteer Transport Services started in 2001 and more op shops and a distribution centre followed.
Bloomhill patron Raelene Boyle has endured the roller-coaster ride of emotions and experiences that can come with a cancer journey. The former sprinter and Olympic medallist has battled breast and ovarian cancers and came to have a close association with Bloomhill in its early stages.
Raelene moved to the Sunshine Coast following her diagnosis in 1996 and became involved with Bloomhill because she valued the idea of cancer care outside the conventional medical environments.
"Bloomhill had only recently started, and I was invited to come take a look and see the services on offer," she said.
"It was a comforting place. Everything about it was restful and not clinical. I warmed to it and appreciated the support and gentleness shown to me."
Bloomhill has also played a significant role in the life of Bloomhill CEO Mervat Quirke and her family.
"In 2005, my husband passed away from brain cancer, and during the period from his diagnosis until his passing, both of us and our five young children experienced Bloomhill's amazing support services," Mervat said.
That knowledge and understanding had driven her to ensure Bloomhill made a positive difference in the lives of people touched by cancer and continued to look for new ways to address how cancer affected people's lives.
In 2006, the Bloomhill Property Trust bought the premises and grounds in Ballinger Rd. A major refurbishment in 2011 tripled the floor space and as the building grew and the organisation evolved, it was time to make structural changes.
Having started as a small, not-for-profit organisation, providing all services for free, Bloomhill was under a volunteer management committee.
In 2011, Mervat was appointed as the first paid general manager and set about restructuring the organisation.
Other significant milestones included opening the Cooroy Op Shop in 2012, taking on management of the Cotton Tree Markets in 2013 and opening the Brightwater (2014), Maleny (2015) and Tewantin (2016) op shops.
Volunteers remain a significant part, with volunteer services manager Alexsandra Bert monitoring the team, which offers transport services, gardening, administration support, cafe service, laundry, cleaning, a buddy program and more.
Alex said most volunteers had either experienced a cancer diagnosis in their immediate family or felt compelled to help because of the work the organisation did.
"There is something very special about each and every one of our volunteers," she said. "They really do want to be able to help in whatever way they can."
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raelene Boyle</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ballinger Rd</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tewantin (2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooroy Op Shop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Bert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomhill CEO Mervat Quirke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brightwater (2014</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Volunteer Transport Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomhill</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mervat</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny (2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Bloomhill Op Shop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mervat Quirke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexsandra Bert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eumundi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cotton Tree Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Angels Op Shop</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olympics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomhill Property Trust</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raelene</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomhill Cancer Care</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
