<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415664212731769</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/before-the-bell/asx-poised-for-flat-open-on-rio-wall-st-pause-20170802-gxo6c4</url>
  <title>ASX poised for flat open on Rio, Wall St pause</title>
  <content>
by
Timothy Moore

Local struggles appear set to open flat in the wake of Rio Tinto's mixed results and profit-taking on Wall Street. ASX futures were up 5 points. The Australian dollar was little changed.
The early story will be how investors reposition after , which surged and yet missed expectations.
Surging earnings from Rio's iron ore division helped boost underlying earnings for the six months to June 30 by 152 per cent to $US3.9 billion. Still analysts had expected earnings of $US4.15 billion.
On a positive note however, Rio said it will pay an interim dividend of $US1.10, up from US45¢ for the first half of the 2016 year. It's previous highest interim dividend was US96¢, at the height of the mining boom. The payout sets the scene for any even bigger windfall in February 2018, when Rio will pay its final dividend.

Overnight however, the London-traded shares of Rio slid 2.8 per cent. The company's US-listed shares were 2.7 per cent lower in afternoon trade in New York. In comparison, BHP was 0.6 per cent lower in New York.

Also not helping overall sentiment was  after its recent strong rally. Prices may be hitting some resistance as the spot price nears the $US75 a tonne mark, according to Metal Bulletin.
Gold was flat, oil edged higher, aluminium and copper also advanced.
As for Wall Street, ,  at the open, rising as much as 6.5 per cent, and lifting the Dow Jones Industrial Average above the 22,000 mark. The Dow was holding above that mark in afternoon trade even though profit taking pared earlier gains and kept both the S&P 500 and Nasdaq in tight ranges.
for the Dow's historic moment.

Today's Agenda

Local data: AiG performance of services July, Trade balance june; New Zealand ANZ job ads July
Overseas data: China Caixin services PMI July; Japan Nikkei services PMI July; Euro zone Markit services PMI July, Retail sales June; UK Markit/CIP services PMI July, Bank of England policy statement; US Markit services PMI July, ISM non-manufacturing July, Factory orders June, Durable goods orders June
Capital Economics on the pending BoE decision: "We expect the vote (among BoE policymakers) to be split 5-3 again in favour of keeping policy unchanged. While a tightening in monetary policy before the end of the year cannot be ruled out, we continue to think that the MPC will err on the side of caution."

Market Highlights

SPI futures up 5 points or 0.1% to 5686
AUD +0.1% to 79.75 US cents (Overnight range: 0.7942 - 0.7993)
On Wall St, Dow +0.2%, S&P 500 -0.1%, Nasdaq flat

In New York, BHP -0.6%, Rio -2.7%
In Europe, Stoxx 50 -0.5%, FTSE -0.2%, CAC -0.4%, DAX -0.6%
Spot gold flat at $US1268.70 an ounce
Brent crude +0.8% to $US52.18 a barrel

US oil +0.6% to $US49.44 a barrel
Iron ore -1.7% to $US72.30 a tonne
Dalian iron ore -0.2% to 540 yuan
LME aluminium +1% to $US1926 a tonne
LME copper +0.1% to $US6352 a tonne
10-year bond yield: US 2.27%, Germany 0.48%, Australia 2.70%
From Today's 
Financial Review
: A dearth of floats and the availability of ultra-cheap debt means the sharemarket's function as a platform for providing capital is being seriously undermined.

: Rio Tinto CEO JS Jacques has delivered a bullish assessment of the outlook for the Chinese economy for the next two years.
: Rather than being viewed as a company in decline with a grim earnings outlook, Genworth can be seen as a capital-generating machine.
United States

: The Dow Jones topped 22,000 points. Better corporate profits and improving global economy are helping.
The Dow peaked above the 22,000 mark for the first time overnight, powered by Apple's healthy quarterly iPhone sales, while weakness in other tech stocks pulled the Nasdaq and S&P 500 lower. The relative weakness also was linked to profit taking.
after the world's largest publicly listed company reported strong results. It is up about 36 per cent this year.
That helped push the Dow to a record high, although tech heavyweights Microsoft, Facebook and Alphabet all lost ground following recent strong gains that have made the sector the strongest performer in 2017.
"Apple, at he heart of it, has a lot of consumer exposure, and the consumer is in great shape. But we would like to see some capex," said Mike Baele, managing director at US Bank Private Client Wealth Management in Portland, Oregon.

The Dow hit the 20,000 mark in late January and crossed the 21,000 mark in just over a month on March 1.
Two-thirds of S&P 500 companies have reported their second-quarter earnings so far and 72 per cent of them have beaten Wall Street's expectations, according to Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S. In a typical quarter, 64 per cent of companies beat expectations
Europe

Respite proved brief for European stocks, which fell for the fourth time in five days as the euro strengthened against the dollar.
The Stoxx Europe 600 Index lost 0.4 per cent at the close, following US equities lower. Miners tumbled the most in two weeks, extending losses in afternoon trading. Rio Tinto Group slipped 2.8 per cent after its profit missed analysts' estimates. Banks were also among the worst performers.
Earnings revisions have turned negative in recent weeks as an advance in the euro threatens the region's profit recovery. Analysts predict profits for Stoxx 600 firms will climb 13 per cent on average this year. The single currency on Wednesday strengthened to its highest in 2 1/2 years against the dollar.
The Stoxx 600 has lost steam in recent months, falling 4.4 per cent since a mid-May high.
Deutsche Lufthansa climbed 3.2 per cent after second-quarter earnings doubled and the carrier said ticket prices rose in March, May and June.

Hugo Boss AG jumped 6.5 per cent after the apparel maker said comparable store sales climbed for the first time in two years.
Asia

Hong Kong shares rose for a third straight session on Wednesday, as investors continued to chase mainland financials and materials firms. The Hang Seng index finished 0.2 per cent higher at 27,607.38 points, while the China Enterprises Index gained 0.3 per cent to 11,055.42 points.
Most sectors advanced, led by materials and industrial firms.
Aluminium Corporation of China (Chinalco) rose 4.9 per cent to close at a more than 26-month high. The stock has surged over 60 per cent this year, as the state-owned aluminium giant is expected to benefit from China's supply-side reforms.
Japan's Nikkei share average rose to a 1-1/2-week high on Wednesday, supported by strong domestic earnings as well as a rally among Apple's suppliers after the iPhone maker reported robust profits.
The Nikkei ended 0.5 per cent higher at 20,080.04, its highest closing level since July 21.
Apple suppliers soared, with Murata Manufacturing rising 4.9 per cent, Taiyo Yuden rising 4.4 per cent and TDK Corp gaining 2.8 per cent after Apple delivered surprisingly strong third-quarter earnings and signalled that its upcoming 10th-anniversary iPhone lineup is on schedule.

Honda Motor Co gained 2.8 per cent after Japan's No.3 auto maker raised its full-year operating profit forecast thanks to solid demand in Asia.
Currencies

St. Louis Federal Reserve boss James Bullard is opposed to further US interest rate increases by the central bank and warned that more hikes could hinder domestic inflation from achieving the Fed's 2-per cent goal, Market News International reported on Wednesday.
Sterling traded at its highest in almost 11 months against a broadly weaker dollar on Wednesday, as a two-day Bank of England meeting that should provide investors with clues on whether interest rates could be hiked in coming months got underway.
Thursday's PMI for Britain's dominant services sector will be followed by a policy decision, the quarterly Inflation Report, and then a press conference with Governor Mark Carney, in what has been dubbed "Super Thursday".
At the last meeting, three out of eight policymakers voted to hike rates immediately. But one of those - Kristin Forbes - has now departed and has been replaced by a rate-setter who has in her previous roles appeared more dovish, Silvana Tenreyro.
"This week's BoE meeting will be closely watched for signs that the hawkish caucus, which seemed so rampant last time, has had its wings clipped," said Chris Beauchamp, market analyst at brokerage IG.
"Overhanging (everything) is Brexit, the issue that won't go away for a very long time."

Commodities

: ​Iron ore futures in China retreated after a three-day rise that pushed prices to their highest in more than four months.
There were relatively fewer offers and bids involving seaborne iron ore seen on trading platforms during the day, according to Metal Bulletin. Buyers are dodging fixed-price cargoes at levels close to the $US75-per-tonne-cfr mark, "which could be a ceiling", a trader in Tianjin told Metal Bulletin. Few shipments linked to the August average of indices have been heard to have changed hands, as those tied to September indices are preferred, he added. Trading activity also dipped at Chinese ports, with prices there having risen to about the same as seaborne levels.
Aluminium prices rose on buying from investors expecting capacity cuts in top producer China, but analysts say supplies may not fall significantly as any cuts could be offset by new capacity. Benchmark aluminium on the London Metal Exchange ended up 1 per cent at $US1926 a tonne.
The LME price of nickel gained 0.6 per cent to $US10,350 a tonne. Earlier this week it touched a four-month high on worries about supplies from the Philippines, which is cracking down on mining pollution.
Copper ended up 0.1 per cent at $US6352, zinc gained 0.8 per cent to $US2801.5, lead rose 0.6 per cent to $US2353 and tin added 0.3 per cent to $US20,590.
Australian Sharemarket

The benchmark S&P/ASX200 index fell 0.5 per cent to 5744.2 points, with a 1.6 per cent slide in BHP Billiton weighing heaviest.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOE</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Enterprises Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PMI July</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London Metal Exchange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Bank Private Client Wealth Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristin Forbes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News International</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomson Reuters I/B/E/S. In</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto CEO JS Jacques</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LME</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP -0.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silvana Tenreyro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Beauchamp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinalco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TDK Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sterling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Bullard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ISM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hang Seng</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Louis Federal Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bank of England</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US52.18</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inflation Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's Nikkei</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metal Bulletin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 21</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500 -0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAIYO YUDEN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAX -0.6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US20,590</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan's No.3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hugo Boss AG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sharemarket</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London-traded</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deutsche Lufthansa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oregon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February 2018</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 50 -0.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio -2.7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Markit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Baele</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow +0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2353</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tianjin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia 2.70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China Caixin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BHP Billiton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brexit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK Markit/CIP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SPI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US2801.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday's PMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio Tinto Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rio</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murata Manufacturing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nikkei</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US72.30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones Industrial Average</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx Europe 600 Index</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPhone</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUD +0.1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1268.70</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Timothy Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Honda Motor Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10,350</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US49.44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany 0.48</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NASDAQ</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US 2.27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAC -0.4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genworth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US6352</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US4.15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoxx 600</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FTSE -0.2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AIG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P/ASX200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Markit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US3.9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Super Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corporation of China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1926</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor Mark Carney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand ANZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$96</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$75</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
