<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415629852992815</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:11</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/lifestyle/get-a-ninja-warrior-body-outdoors-with-free-cairns-workout-spots/news-story/737e6b7dd462cbad7ccc7bcd6224c3cf</url>
  <title>Core values for warriors</title>
  <content>
PEOPLE across Cairns are wondering just how they can get fit enough to take on the Australian Ninja Warrior obstacle course.
Women's Fitness For All personal trainer Eleonora Hawkins said focusing on core strength and taking advantage of the many outdoor exercise spots in Cairns was the key to getting Ninja Warrior-like fitness.
"Completing a course like that relies on a lot of strength, so you'll want to be doing a lot of body-resistance weight training," she said.
"Abdominal muscles are essential, so doing planking outside and timing it will increase those core muscles.
"Also getting out and using monkey bars or even climbing a rope connected to a tree is a great idea for using the whole body for a workout."
She said the countless parks in Cairns were a great place to start the workout journey.
"There are lots of parks here that have training stations, and there's plenty of space to do tabata sessions, which are really high intensity and will definitely increase fitness," she said.
"The most important thing is to stay motivated."
JUMP INTO THE GREAT OUTDOORS AND DEVELOP ALL THOSE NINJA MUSCLES
Climbing skills: To test your climbing skills try the free bouldering park at the Cairns Esplanade.Body weight resistance:Find balance: Keep up cardio fitness: Climb a tree:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitness For All</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ninja Warrior-like</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eleonora Hawkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DEVELOP ALL THOSE NINJA MUSCLES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Ninja Warrior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GREAT OUTDOORS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Esplanade.Body</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
