<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415277665668652</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/us-coast-guard-boss-admiral-paul-zukunft-rejects-transgender-ban-tweeted-by-donald-trump/news-story/3621a594542b3e8a22c9869ccc398bfa</url>
  <title>Coast Guard boss rejects trans ban</title>
  <content>
THE commandant of the US Coast Guard has said that he will continue to support transgender people in his service despite US President Donald Trump's tweet last week barring them from the military.
The reports that Admiral Paul Zukunft said the first thing he did after learning about Mr Trump's surprise tweet was to reach out to the 13 guard members who have come out as transgender, including a woman who was featured in a profile in The Washington Post.
"I reached out personally to Lt. Taylor Miller," Admir. Zukunft said at the Centre for Strategic and International Studies, Military.com reported.
"If you read that story, Taylor's family has disowned her. Her family is [now] the United States Coast Guard. And I told Taylor, 'I will not turn my back. We have made an investment in you, and you have made an investment in the Coast Guard, and I will not break faith.'"
Mr Trump's tweets caught the Pentagon by surprise - and prompted the chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to announce that there would be no policy changes until the services get clearer guidance from the administration.
Lt. Miller, 27, is believed to be the first openly transitioning member of the Coast Guard, a process she began in 2016 after the Pentagon removed its ban on openly transgender service members, the website reported.
"That is the commitment to our people right now," Admir. Zukunft said. "Very small numbers, but all of them are doing meaningful Coast Guard work today."
The president, in three tweets posted on July 26, said that "the United States Government will not accept or allow transgender individuals to serve in any capacity in the US Military. Our military must be focused on decisive and overwhelming victory and cannot be burdened with the tremendous medical costs and disruption that transgender in the military would entail."
US Coast Guard - Future Priorities

No additional guidance has been issued by the White House, leaving the fate of the estimated 4000 or more transgender service members now serving in limbo.
While the president said he consulted with military experts, Congressional sources said the ban came in response to conservatives who were threatening to hold up a budget bill that contained funds for his border wall and other priorities.
This article originally appeared in the
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joint Chiefs of Staff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miller, 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pentagon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Coast Guard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Future Priorities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast Guard</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Admiral Paul Zukunft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Military</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Studies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Admir</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States Coast Guard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zukunft</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
