<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415234715994824</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/03/33/terror-suspect-s-life-turned-upside-down</url>
  <title>Terror suspect's 'life turned upside down'</title>
  <content>
A day after a man arrested over a terrorist plot to bring down an aircraft was released, forensic officers continue to comb the homes of the remaining suspects.
Abdul Merhi, 50, was released without charge on Tuesday night, more than three days after his arrest during a series of police raids across four Sydney suburbs.
Three other men remain behind bars after Australian Federal Police were granted the power to hold them for up to seven days, which expires on Sunday evening.
Mr Merhi's solicitor Moustafa Kheir says he's concerned his client's identity was revealed and has declared he'll "review what basis police had to do what they did".
"It's just unfathomable that he would be associated with anything like this."
Police have searched properties in Lakemba, Wiley Park, Punchbowl and Surry Hills in search of evidence.
Officers remained at the Surry Hills residence on Wednesday night, a witness told AAP.

Related Articles

Little has been confirmed officially but authorities have said the plot involved plans to "bring down" an aircraft using an "improvised device".
The alleged plot has led to heightened security at airports across Australia, and on Wednesday the peak body for commercial pilots demanded permanent change.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Federal Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moustafa Kheir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
