<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415647032862293</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:15</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/planning-for-a-new-buderim-hospital-began-over-din/3207317/</url>
  <title>Planning for a new Buderim hospital began over dinner</title>
  <content>
WHEN Elsa Wilson hosted a dinner party at her Sunshine Coast home in the mid-1970s and revealed her dream of establishing a new hospital in Buderim, Ngaire Roberts was several thousand kilometres away in Papua New Guinea.
She never could have imagined later spending more than half her life closely associated with the facility.
The Sunshine Coast Private Hospital at Buderim, formerly known as Buderim Private Hospital, was established by members of the local community including Mrs Wilson, a local GP's wife, who felt it unnecessary that her husband and his patients should have to travel to Nambour for hospitalisation.
At the dinner in 1977, the guests included two general surgeons, two GPs, a solicitor and an architect. Mrs Wilson's idea to establish the hospital was met with considerable interest. This party of six became the initial committee tasked with establishing the facility.
Mrs Wilson's dream became a reality when the hospital officially opened in July 1980, thanks in part to shareholders like Mrs Roberts who were inspired to invest in the project.
"It was a very exciting venture and I was proud to be an original shareholder, along with many other ex-government officers from Papua New Guinea," Mrs Roberts said.
"It has been amazing to be a part of the hospital community over the past four decades and watch first-hand how it has been able to help so many people.
"We started with just 48 beds and now we have grown to include 190 and developed many other services for outpatients.
"It has been quite incredible to witness the dramatic advances in technology to help patients and the introduction of new facilities, such as the peri-operative complex and the Cooinda Mental Health Service."
In addition to being one of the original shareholders in the hospital, Mrs Roberts has been connected with the Ladies Auxiliary for 26 years, was a hospital board member for six years and remained with the charity committee after the Uniting Church purchased the hospital in 2000.
"As the only non-profit private hospital on the Sunshine Coast, it has been my great privilege to help raise funds to purchase items for our patients care and comfort over and above what the hospital already supplies," she said.
After surviving her own battle with ovarian cancer, Mrs Roberts considers herself one of the lucky ones and has focused her fundraising efforts on supporting the hospital's Breast Clinic and Cindy Mackenzie Breast Cancer Program.
"I truly understand what people are going through and I feel so sorry for those who are sick and have young families and how terribly traumatic it must be for all concerned.
"When I originally invested in the hospital, it was nice to think we had the facility there to take advantage of - I didn't think of myself getting sick or growing old at that stage.
"But now, almost 40 years on, it provides me even more comfort to know we have this fantastic hospital on our doorstep."
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cindy Mackenzie Breast Cancer Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ngaire Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uniting Church</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ladies' Auxiliary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breast Clinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim Private Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooinda Mental Health Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Wilson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elsa Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Papua New Guinea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Roberts</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 1980</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
