<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415191766320916</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/1409925/haunting-music-of-the-andes-mountains/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Haunting music of the Andes mountains</title>
  <content>
Haunting music of the Andes mountains

Bass player Fernando, like other Pukara musicians, is a multi-instrumentalist.

exit

PUKARA
Friday, April 5
City Diggers Club
Tickets: www.trybooking.com/CHLZ
Musician Patricio Espinoza, a member of Latin American band Pukara, knows why the music of South America's Andes mountains has won fans around the world.
''It is the haunting sound of the pan pipes and the way that Latin American people play them,'' he says. ''I assume this is the reason people love the Andean music.
''It is a really unusual and unique way of playing music. You cannot perform a song with one pan pipe - a typical song will have two members playing the pan pipes. Some notes are played by one pan pipe and other notes are filled out by the other pan pipe player.''
After some crowd-pleasing performances at the Illawarra Folk Festival and the Diggers Club, Pukara are gaining a firm following in the Illawarra.
The band plays a fusion of traditional, original and contemporary Latin American songs - ranging from ambient instrumental pieces to ''up-tempo Latin American dancing tunes with a lot of oomph''. But it is traditional Andean music and instruments that they are best known for.
Along with the pan pipes - made from a row of bamboo cane - Pukara's band members play a variety of acoustic instruments from all over Latin America, with up to 20 instruments on display.
''Each member plays a variety of instruments,'' Espinoza says.
''We have Spanish guitar, bass guitar, charango, Andean flutes and pan pipes and lots of percussion from different countries like Peru and Colombia.
''Charango, an instrument that I specialise in playing, was originally made from an armadillo shell but now is made of wood. It is a very weird instrument that originated in Bolivia, a tiny little instrument that resembles a mandolin type of sound.
''The drums are very traditional. They are made in Latin America from a special wood done up in a barrel shape, like a beautiful oak wine barrel, and on top is a goat skin.
''Andean music is identified throughout the world through the pan pipes but for us Latin American people, Andean music cannot be played without charango, the drums and the Spanish guitar - that is a complete, traditional Andean music.''
As well as Latin American music,Espinoza says the band also reinterprets other styles of music.
''Sixty or 70 per cent of our music is our own compositions, but as well we produce music from other composers, famous composers from Latin America, and we have decided to play some music from composers from around the world that will sound unusual and good with our instruments,'' he says.
''For example, recently we have decided to give a taste of how music from [jazz guitarist] Django Reinhardt will sound with our instruments.
''As a musician I am pretty sure most musicians want to go to different places and play different styles. I remember one time someone asked me if I could play something Australian and I didn't hesitate, I played Waltzing Matilda on my charango.
''The person said, 'Wow, that sounds completely weird'. For us it is fun and a good thing to do,'' Espinoza says.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin America</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diggers Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pukara</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andean</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City Diggers Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin American</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricio Espinoza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra Folk Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fernando</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charango</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Django Reinhardt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colombia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Espinoza</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waltzing Matilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolivia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South America's Andes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CHLZ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
