<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415634147960147</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/lifestyle/hair-oil-choice-essential-for-cairns-beauties-wanting-maximum-shine/news-story/d9bf63d48fccb904add0933d233c2735</url>
  <title>Oils make your hair a shining example</title>
  <content>
VISITING the hairdresser almost always ends with a little bit of oil being gently dispersed through hair and leaving it shiny and fresh.
The Hair Studio hairstylist Michael Medeiros has revealed to Well and Good the secret behind picking the right hair oil for your hair type.
"I find in Cairns there is such a bohemian, natural population here. People really like using things if they can eat it. They won't put it in their hair if they can't eat it," he said.
"You have cultures, like Indian culture, which have been using coconut oil forever and now it's the biggest trend."
He said there were lots of household oils that could be used cosmetically.
"You can definitely use different oils, like olive oil is one that you can use in your hair," he said.
"I find coconut oil doesn't have much of a scent, whereas olive oil is quite strong, and those are probably the two healthier oils you can turn to when it comes to cooking or using them in your hair.
"I wouldn't recommend everyone use coconut oil in their hair because it is so heavy. People would look like they haven't washed their hair in eight weeks."
He said using salon professional oils usually meant turning to an argan-based oil, which sat more lightly throughout the hair and was more suited to everyday use.
"If you have fine hair you should try to use a more watery oil, whereas if you have thicker or more curly hair you'd want to use a heavier oil," he said.
He said coloured hair also needed different types of treatment to natural hair.
"With trendy colours, such as ombres, your ends are bleached but your roots stay dark," he said.
"So your roots will get oily quite quickly on their own but you can put oils through the ends just to keep it hydrated."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Medeiros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hair Studio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
