<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415655622797085</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/miracles-of-modern-medicine/3207246/</url>
  <title>Miracles of modern medicine</title>
  <content>
IMAGINE a world where the miracles of modern medicine which we take for granted today were still 10, 20 and even 50 years away from becoming a reality.
A world where cancer was still a mystery, smoking was allowed in hospital wards and nurses had to resign from their jobs if they wanted to have a baby.
It's a far cry from the technology and facilities available today, not only in the big-city hospitals but also right here on the Sunshine Coast.
The change has been as monumental as it has been rapid.
People such as Mary Kiernan and Jean Haimes have not only seen the changes take place but also have been part of the process. It was a very different world when they began their nursing careers in the 1970s.
They could hardly have forseen the transformation of the Sunshine Coast health care sector which now sees us enjoy access to a multi-million-dollar ultra-modern hospital which will not only provide first class health care but also train the health staff of the future.
We are now home to several private hospitals while research under way at the USC Clinical Trials Centre may one day find a cure for cancer, asthma and other illnesses.
We are also home to a world-class mental health institute, a rescue helicopter service which has saved countless lives, numerous wonderful health-based charities and a host of clinics which take advantage of our naturally healthy environment.
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Kiernan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean Haimes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC Clinical Trials Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
