<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415651327829737</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:16</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-is-now-a-centre-of-research/3207252/</url>
  <title>Coast is now a centre of research</title>
  <content>
WHEN the region's leaders were supporting calls for the name "Sunshine Coast" to be adopted, they could hardly have imagined the technological advances to come or the role the Coast would play.
Today, our role in ongoing medical research is significant and growing, with the University of the Sunshine Coast's Clinical Trials Centre conducting ground-breaking studies into everything from medical marijuana and cancer to asthma, epilepsy, emphysema and influenza.
The centre began operating in 2016 and is based at the Ochre Health Medical Centre at Sippy Downs.
In one of its greatest coups, it is partnering with clinicians from the Sunshine Coast Haematology and Oncology Clinic to research treatment options for cancer.
Oncologists and haematologists at the Buderim clinic will join with a USC team led by USC Clinical Trials Centre director Lucas Litewka to investigate options such as new drugs or combination therapies.
Mr Litewka said lung cancer and breast cancer were likely to be the first diseases targeted. Other studies could investigate melanoma and cancers of the prostate, bladder, ovaries and blood, as well as less-common cancers.
"The aim of these trials is to further medical research to improve outcomes for cancer patients, present and future," he said.
"We've already had 10 novel drug trials presented to USC for feasibility assessment, so the signs are promising for a trial to start soon."
Meanwhile, asthma research at the centre is testing new medicine which combines corticosteroids that help reduce inflammation and bronchodilators that help open up and relax the muscles in the airways of the lungs.
"Asthma is a long-term lung condition that cannot be cured, but for most people it can be controlled with a daily management plan," Mr Litewka said.
The USC centre has partnered with Golden Beach Medical Centre on the medical research.
General practitioner Dr Peter de Wet is the principal investigator on the clinical trial.
He said the once-a-day treatment might reduce the need for patients to carry around multiple puffers and undergo complicated treatment regimes.
The centre has also started a new clinical trial to test the effectiveness of applying a synthetic cannabis gel to the skin of people suffering osteoarthritis of the knee.
It is the second trial of the derivative of medicinal cannabis conducted by the centre.
The first, which involved applying the pharmaceutical-grade cannabidiol (CBD) to patients with epilepsy, expects findings early next year.
"This trial aims to find out if the cannabidiol, when applied regularly to patients' shoulders, can reduce the pain suffered from osteoarthritis of the knee," Mr Litewka said.
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sippy Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of the Sunshine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucas Litewka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Peter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ochre Health Medical Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USC Clinical Trials Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Haematology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Golden Beach Medical Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast's Clinical Trials Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oncology Clinic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Litewka</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
