<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415801651687442</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:51</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/queensland/the-young-queenslanders-most-at-risk-of-homelessness-20170802-gxo52r.html</url>
  <title>The young Queenslanders most at risk of homelessness</title>
  <content>
Serious mental illness may increase young Queenslanders risk of homelessness, a new study has found.
Mission Australia's Youth Mental Health and Homelessness Report found young people aged 15 to 19 with a probable mental illness were 3.5 times more likely to spend time away from home than those without.Photo: Andrew Quilty
In Queensland, that number was the same.
Hudson* may be just 16, but he has already experienced homelessness after running away from a residential care home in Melbourne.
"I ran away because I didn't want to be bullied," he said.
Now living on the Gold Coast with his mum and his grandmother, Hudson said he would fight a lot with his mum and had ended up in residential care again after returning to Queensland.

"I wouldn't have run away from home, because I was homeless in Melbourne so I didn't want to do that again."
Mission Australia's Queensland state director Darren Young said it was important to identify potential issues with young people before they lead to homelessness.

You will now receive updates from

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Spencer Howson AM / PM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"It does happen gradually over time," he said.
Nationally, 57.7 per cent of those with a probable serious mental illness and rated their family functioning as poor had spent time away from home, compared to 37 per cent who did not have a probable serious mental illness.
The report found young people who spent time away from home reported they were highly concerned about family conflict, depression, coping with stress, and thoughts of suicide.
Mr Young said Mission Australia's Reconnect program aims to identify those sorts of concerns for young people and intervenes early.
"It is looking at ... really preventing homelessness in the longer term it's a service that offers counselling, mediation, practical support for younger people," he said.
Hudson has been in the Reconnect program for a year, and he said it has helped his relationship with his mum "a lot".
"We get along much better now," he said.
"Somethings I can't talk to my mum about - I just can't - and I can talk to (my social worker) Darren about it.
As well as improving his relationship with his mum, Hudson said it has just been good to have someone to talk to.
"I get really lonely sometimes and depressed and I don't have many people to talk to," he said.
"I think of him as my friend now: I used to think of him as a social worker but I think of him as a friend."
The pair go on drives and hang out at the beach, but Hudson said Darren had also been helping him prepare for work.
"At the moment we're looking to do my cert 1 in hospitality," he said.
"Just to get a job at like McDonalds or something, I know I can apply for McDonalds now but I know if I get a cert 1 it makes my chances even greater."
Mission Australia collected responses from more than 17,000 young Australians - including 3722 Queenslanders - aged 15 to 19 on their thoughts on a broad range of issues. The survey is open until August 11, and Mr Young encouraged young people  and have their say.
"I think young people tend to be a bit of a marginalised voice in society," he said.
"Those that are under 18 don't have a voting right, we are quite aware that it's very easy to overlook young people. So this is a national approach to giving voice to young people."
*Surname withheld to protect privacy
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spencer Howson AM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonalds</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Young</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hudson</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Homelessness Report</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mission Australia's Reconnect</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Youth Mental Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
