<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415638442927517</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sunnykids-is-protecting-our-kids-from-harm/3207321/</url>
  <title>Sunnykids is protecting our kids from harm</title>
  <content>
TOO many kids throughout Australia simply aren't getting a realistic chance to reach their full potential.
Each year the Sunshine Coast community alone identifies more than 5000 children who are at risk. But the most alarming statistic locally is the increase in domestic violence in our region, which impacts everyone.
Each week, 15 new families desperately need help locally, yet on any night, there may be only a handful of vacancies available in emergency accommodation centres across Queensland.
Organisations such as SunnyKids are working hard to start the conversation and provide emergency accommodation while partnering with health, education and child protection agencies to keep these families safe.
I founded SunnyKids in 2009 after conducting a three-year action research project, because I wanted to shed some light on the real and growing issue of domestic violence.
I had no idea how successful we would be.
SunnyKids' first program began through working with a Sunshine Coast women's shelter, as we saw patterns in the people who were using the service.
There was nearly 20 kids running around and I recall thinking it made sense to support them, but the real focus was on the adults in a women's refuge.
Then I learned that 50% of the mums in the refuge were kids themselves when grandma attended a refuge. There is a pattern and I just really wanted to make a difference and stop that next generation from ending up in that situation.
SunnyKids now has more than 100 corporate partners and helps more than 220 community agencies connect with kids in need. Our work falls into two general divisions: domestic violence services and family support services.
Through both divisions, SunnyKids delivers our nationally-recognised model called the SunnyKids Virtual Village to ensure kids and families receive support across any area of need they may be experiencing.
The model is really about community development and coordination. It provides enhanced access to services for vulnerable families and avoids the duplication of services through the coordination of any number of partner services from the 220-plus services which make up the SunnyKids Virtual Village.
Our award-winning programs are designed to promote wellbeing in children and young people by creating "virtual villages" that help them to reach their full potential.
In 2016 alone, SunnyKids helped families with financial and emergency relief, counselling, parenting and mentoring courses, substance abuse, social and community housing assistance, medical and physical support, immigration and legal advice referrals, mental health, sexual assault and kids' programs.
Last year, we supported: almost 300 children experiencing violence at home; over 300 with behavioural issues; 140 with medical and mental health challenges; 140 who were homeless; and almost 400 with emotional issues.
While I am proud of what we have achieved over the years, I know the work is far from done. Having worked in this sector for more than 14 years, it is great to see how far we've come, especially when it comes to addressing domestic violence. In 2003, we couldn't speak openly about the issue and nobody wanted to listen, but today we still have a long way to go.
The Sunshine Coast Domestic Violence and Family Support systems have evolved ad hoc and now it's time to act strategically. It is simply time to "make it stop" when it comes to domestic violence and to work together to truly provide an effective family support system for vulnerable kids and families.
Our community simply can't reach its full potential if our kids aren't given the chance to reach theirs.
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Support</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SunnyKids Virtual Village</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunnykids</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Domestic Violence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
