<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415878961100230</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Australian</source>
  <url>http://www.theaustralian.com.au/in-depth/us-politics/australia-cited-as-model-for-donald-trumps-immigration-reforms/news-story/6df0caa59db692f80cad5971c956f83a</url>
  <title>Australia model for US migration reforms</title>
  <content>
The Trump administration has cited Australia as a model for a sweeping proposal to dramatically revamp America's immigration system to accept skilled, wealthier English speaking migrants over unskilled applicants.
The proposed change to a merit-based system, which still requires Congressional approval, has been strongly backed by Donald Trump who today called it 'the most significant reform to our immigration system in half a century."
"The RAISE Act will reduce poverty, increase wages, and save taxpayers billions and billions of dollars," he said.
The bill invokes sweeping changes to the US Green card system, cutting out automatic Green Cards for extended family members while introducing a merit points-based system.
"This competitive application process will favour applicants who can speak English, financially support themselves and their families and demonstrate skills that will contribute to our economy," Mr Trump said.
He said the plan would end America's 'low skilled immigration system' which had hurt American workers.
However the bill as it currently stands has little prospect of being passed by Congress with Democrats opposed to it and Republicans divided over it.
Senator David Purdue, who has the reform bill, said Australia and Canada were the model for the bill.
"What we're introducing today is modelled on the current Canadian and Australian systems," he said. "It's pro-worker, pro-growth, and its been proven to work. Both have been extremely successful in attracting highly skilled workers to those countries."
White House adviser Steven Miller said: "We looked at the Australian system, the Canadian system we took things we liked, we added things that made sense for America where we are as a country right now."
" One of the things that's most telling about the Australian system is the efforts to make sure immigrants are financially self-sufficient and make sure they are able to pay for their own health care and things like that."
The bill would halve legal immigration into the US from one million people a year to 500,000 a year over ten years.
Critics say the changes would undermine America's long tradition of welcoming immigrants regardless of their status.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raise Act</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator David Purdue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Green</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steven Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Green Card</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
