<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415848896328603</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:02</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/my-say-conservative-libs-scared-of-minority/3207915/</url>
  <title>MY SAY: Conservative Libs scared of minority</title>
  <content>
CHARACTER, conviction, fairness.
All words pretty commonly spouted by most politicians as traits needed, qualities required, to govern for the people.
So it seems odd that those on the furthest of right wings of the Liberal Party appear set to light the fuse and self-destruct if some of their party colleagues display some of these traits.
Eric Abetz made some veiled threats, declaring the prospect of Liberal MPs crossing the floor to bring on a marriage equality debate as an "exceptionally grave matter" while Education Minister Simon Birmingham warned backbenchers to "exercise carefully, with caution and with consideration for all of the consequences" their right to cross the floor on a conscience vote.
Sage advice given the catastrophic consequences at stake.
I mean, geez, what a disaster if out of the process, people in long-term, loving relationships, were able to get married, while the rest of us continue to do whatever we please.
It's time the conservatives got their advisors and rusted-on, aging memberships out of their heads.
They don't represent a cross-section of the voting public.
Personally, if an MP has the fortitude to cross the floor, show some conviction, go against a party commandment and vote for what simply is the right thing to do, my respect for them would only ever increase.
I don't think I'm alone in that.
Grant Kenny asks council to ditch Maroochy River rock wall concept
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conservative Libs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Kenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
