<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414977017951880</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4290763/maitland-woman-pleads-guilty-to-animal-abuse-photos/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>Maitland woman pleads guilty to animal abuse | PHOTOS</title>
  <content>
Maitland woman pleads guilty to animal abuse | PHOTOS

Grizzly was emaciated upon arrival at the RSPCA. Picture: RSPCA

Grizzly was emaciated upon arrival at the RSPCA. Picture: RSPCA

Grizzly was emaciated upon arrival at the RSPCA. Picture: RSPCA

Grizzly was emaciated upon arrival at the RSPCA. Picture: RSPCA

Grizzly was emaciated upon arrival at the RSPCA. Picture: RSPCA

A progress update of Grizzly in March, showed weight gain and signs of increased health. Picture: RSPCA

A progress update of Grizzly in March, showed weight gain and signs of increased health. Picture: RSPCA

A progress update of Grizzly in March, showed weight gain and signs of increased health. Picture: RSPCA

A progress update of Grizzly in March, showed weight gain and signs of increased health. Picture: RSPCA

exit

A Maitland woman has been handed a 12-month good behaviour bond, a ban from owning animals for five years and a fine after she pleaded guilty to animal cruelty charges.

Jessica May Carless appeared in Maitland Local Court on November 11 on two charges of animal cruelty in relation to a male black and tan rottweiler named Grizzly. 

On January 28, 2016, an RSPCA inspector attended an address in East Maitland in response to a cruelty report of an emaciated dog in a weak condition.

On arrival, the inspector found the rottweiler crawling with fleas, anaemic, weak and unsteady on his feet when made to stand. 

The rottweiler was seized and rushed to the RSPCA Hunter Valley Veterinary Hospital. The veterinarian's findings were that Grizzly had the highest score of emaciation (5/5 where 1/5 is healthy), had not been fed properly in at least four weeks, weighed 31.8 kilograms and hadn't received treatment for the serious flea infestation for more than 28 days.

A seizure notice was left at the address and all other attempts to contact Ms Carless were ignored, according to a statement from the RSPCA .

Microchip information revealed the rottweiler's name was Grizzly, he was 2.5 years old and registered to Ms Carless. 

Grizzly has since fully recovered under the care of the RSPCA.

The RSPCA has found a new loving home for Grizzly and he is doing extremely well.

The attending inspector is in touch with Grizzly's new family and has been told he now has his very own special "man cave" and is a loved member of the family.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Carless</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maitland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 28, 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Maitland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA Hunter Valley Veterinary Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RSPCA</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica May Carless</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
