<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415707162405397</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/concerns-of-financial-abuse-raised-in-wake-of-hilda-survey/8768682</url>
  <title>HILDA report: Welfare experts put spotlight on financial abuse in wake of national debt survey</title>
  <content>
Welfare experts are raising concerns about rising levels of financial abuse among couples in the wake of a national survey showing Australians are suffering from increasing levels of financial stress.

Key points:

Welfare expert says households are "struggling on multiple fronts" financially
Keeping debt secret from other partner is a form of abuse, she says
Financial counsellor advises partners to be financially literate and reach out for help

Welfare policy expert Lauren Levin said financial problems usually begin with men, and they often keep their debt a secret.
"They set up their affairs so that the partner doesn't see what's happening," Ms Levin said.
"So there's a poor woman out there who, for months and months, hasn't known that their entire marital wealth has been lost."
Ms Levin, who is often employed to train financial counsellors, said it is a form of abuse.
"We call that financial or economic abuse, because it has very severe consequences for the partners," she said.
Ms Levin was responding to findings from the latest annual Household, Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia - or HILDA report - based on a survey of the same 17,000 people each year.
The survey is conducted by the University of Melbourne on behalf of the Federal Government.
This year it revealed mortgage debt for 18- to 39-year-olds has almost doubled since 2002, and it is stressing people out.
"We certainly see people doing it tough," said Ms Levin.
"There's a call line called the National Debt Helpline, and the trend is upward of the number of people calling to get help with their financial affairs - so having debts that they can't pay: electricity bills; phone bills; mortgages; credit cards."
Households 'struggling on multiple fronts' financially

One thing that has recently hurt couples with children is rising childcare costs, with median weekly expenditures rising 75 per cent for couple families and by 104 per cent for single-parent families.
But Ms Levin said it is often not just one bill that causes a household budget panic.
"So it's not a single thing that's pushing them over the edge, it's really struggling on multiple fronts," she said.
Kristen Hartnett, a Salvation Army financial counsellor who has frontline experience with desperate people struggling to cope, said financial problems can simmer before boiling over.
"People actually not knowing what the options are, not knowing how to handle it, not thinking they have anything in their tool kit to remedy the situation," she said.
"It can be a big bill or a small bill that tips them over the edge, but it's sometimes a little cocktail that's been happening to people for a while."
Ms Levin said the worst thing someone can do when they think they are running out of options is to bury their head in the sand.

More on the HILDA survey:

"I'd like to send a message to partners out there who don't take an active role ... that is that they really should be across what's happening because it's in their own best interests to be financially literate and to understand what's going on because it impacts their life," she said.
"They're really hard conversations to have with people, but I guess we are grateful that people do come forward because then we can start having discussions and putting some realistic strategies and plans in place to help them and their families."
Ms Hartnett encouraged those struggling financially in regional areas to reach out if they need help.
"They can reach us in the country on 1800 007 007 for a free service," she said.

External Link:

HILDA statistical report, 2017

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Debt Helpline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lauren Levin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Levin</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hartnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Salvation Army</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kristen Hartnett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
