<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415848896328637</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:02</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/sex-threat-900-coast-locals-catch-chlamydia-gonorr/3206916/</url>
  <title>SEX THREAT: 900 Coast locals catch chlamydia, gonorrhea, syphilis, hepatitis and HIV</title>
  <content>
A TRIPLE threat of chlamydia, gonorrhea and syphilis is on the march across the Sunshine Coast with almost 900 local cases of sexually transmitted and blood-borne diseases reported to the state's health bosses in the past seven months.
Chlamydia is the most virulent sexually transmitted infection in our region and the number of Sunshine Coast residents infected with the "silent" disease could be three times higher than official data shows.
NewsRegional analysis of Queensland Health statistics shows 773 new notifications of chlamydia since January 1 across the Sunshine Coast health district that covers the Sunshine Coast, Noosa and Gympie.
In the same period, our region recorded 102 cases of gonorrhea and 19 of syphilis.
Hepatitis C is the region's most common blood-borne virus with 67 notifications in 2017.
There were 17 hep B transmissions and two HIV notifications.
Chlamydia is known as the "silent infection" because symptoms are rare, but if left untreated it can cause chronic pain and infertility in women.
STI expert Professor Basil Donovan warned our region's young sexually active residents to get tested for chlamydia.
"We're only actually diagnosing a quarter of the number of cases of chlamydia because we are only testing about 10% of young people each year," the UNSW Kirby Institute Sexual Health Program head said.
"Kids are embarrassed to go to the doctor and often the doctors are embarrassed to ask about it."
Sunshine Coast Hospital and Health Service Sexual Health and HIV Service clinical director Dr Kuong Taing  said the data showed transmission rates were stable but there was still cause for concern.
"Chlamydia is one of the most common STIs and one of the most common notifiable STIs in Australia and this is reflected in the region," Dr Taing said.
"This is because individuals with chlamydia infection may have no symptoms, or minimal symptoms, and not seek treatment while continuing to have unprotected sexual contact, leading to the spread of the infection.
"People who are sexually active should get regular STI screens and get treated quickly if infected, contact sexual partners to come for testing and treatment, should practise safer sex (condom) to avoid catching STIs, especially with casual partners."
Queensland Q-PrEPd HIV Prevention Trial operational manager Simon Doyle-Adams said removing the stigma associated with sexually transmitted diseases and making treatment easily accessible would reduce transmission significantly.
"Regular screening and offering new treatments and preventions is the key," Mr Doyle-Adams said.
The State Government's $62 million Queensland Sexual Health Strategy 2016-2021 aims to reduce transmission rates of STIs and blood-borne diseases.
About $5.27 million will be spent promoting safe sex across the state with $3.7 million of that allocated to regional sexual health services.
"The Queensland Government is aware of increasing numbers of sexually transmissible infections and blood-borne viruses," a Department of Health spokesman said.
Don't let 'stigma, fear or embarrassment' stop hepatitis testing, treatment
SUNSHINE Coast drug users are at most risk of getting hepatitis C.
In the past seven months, 85 Sunshine Coast and Gympie residents have been infected with hepatitis C or B.
Hepatitis C is the most common blood-borne virus in our region and is often spread by injecting drug users, sharing of shaving equipment and occasionally through sex.
Antiviral medications can eliminate hep C in 12 weeks and there is a vaccine for hep B.
"A large number of intravenous drug users share needles, syringes and paraphernalia," Sunshine Coast Hospital and Health Service Sexual Health and HIV Service clinical director Dr Kuong Taing said.
"The number of new infections is decreasing.
"This is attributed to better health promotion (and) users are more aware of the need for safe injection and tattooing practices."
Hepatitis Queensland CEO Michelle Kudell said early detection could save local residents from deadly liver complications.
"We cannot allow ourselves to be stymied by unwarranted stigma, fear or embarrassment," Ms Kudell said.
"Game-changing hepatitis C treatments, an effective vaccine and treatments to prevent and control hepatitis B and quick and painless diagnostic and liver health tests are already available as we work towards elimination of these viruses.
"Yet we are in the unbelievable position where many people remain undiagnosed and only a small proportion are currently accessing and receiving the treatment they need."
HOW TO TELL IF YOU HAVE
Chlamydia
In women, if symptoms are present, they may include:
In men, if symptoms are present, they may include:
Quick facts
Gonorrhea
Quick facts
Syphilis
Quick facts
Hepatitis C
Quick facts
If you inject drugs, never share needles and syringes or other equipment such as tourniquets, spoons, swabs or water. Always use sterile needles and syringes. These are available free of charge from needle and syringe programs and some pharmacists. To find out where you can obtain free needles, syringes and other injecting equipment visit
Disclosure for all of these diseases
It is important to let your sexual partners know that you have a disease. Your local doctor and sexual health centre can help you to do this.
Source: .
- NewsRegional
Grant Kenny asks council to ditch Maroochy River rock wall concept
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kudell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>THREAT: 900 Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government's $62</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNSW Kirby Institute Sexual Health Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Basil Donovan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Q-PrEPd HIV Prevention Trial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TELL IF YOU HAVE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Taing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STI</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hepatitis Queensland CEO Michelle Kudell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Doyle-Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NewsRegional</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STIs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hepatitis C</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HIV Service</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Health</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Service Sexual Health</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Doyle-Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Kenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Kuong Taing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
