<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415642737894833</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:14</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/the-coasts-a-beacon-for-healthy-lifestyles/3207291/</url>
  <title>The Coast's a beacon for healthy lifestyles</title>
  <content>
THE Sunshine Coast has always been a beacon attracting those wanting to live a happier, healthier, more fulfilling life.
Its natural beauty and corresponding fresh mountain air, cool rainforests walks, therapeutic saltwater and mild climate and glorious sunshine do wonders for the mind, body and soul.
Its what attracted me and my surfing husband to bite the bullet and buy a block of land near the beach in 1983 - when interest rates were a whopping 15.5%and rising.
Nearly 35 years and five renovations and extensions after building our home, we're still there and loving it.
Tens-of-thousands of other visitors to the region also have seen the light, and put down roots, creating new businesses and raising families.
Many of those businesses also have tapped into the Sunshine Coast's health and wellness attributes, harnessing their potential and improving our quality of life in the ;process.
Earlier this year, tourism officials confirmed what we all knew to be true: the Sunshine Coast is poised to set itself up as the "wellness capital of Australia".
A strong balance of natural scenery plus health-conscious businesspeople are combining to attract visitors from around the nation and overseas to the region, as well as meeting the well-being needs of locals.
Adding to our claim to the lucrative tourism title are the fact we grow quality fresh produce, host a myriad cooking classes across the region, offer a wide range of exotic spa treatments, give lessons in adventure sports such as surfing and stand-up paddleboarding, put on well-regarded yoga and music festivals, and have access to walking and bicycle paths including the Coastal Pathway and hinterland walks.
Visit Sunshine Coast CEO Simon Latchford believes we already have the credentials.
"A lot of regions offer yoga and spa treatments, but there's something about the landscape of the Sunshine Coast that makes us such a 'natural' destination for health and wellness holidays," he told the Daily in January this year.
"To some extent, it is in our DNA - our tagline is 'naturally refreshing'.
"And it doesn't really matter whether you're doing yoga on a paddleboard, meditating on Mt Coolum as the sun rises, or trekking along the Hinterland Great Walk - the setting contributes as much to the experience as the healthy activity itself."
As well as businesses, festivals with a core health focus but offering a little something for everyone are attracting big followings - especially in the growing yoga market.
On the last Saturday in January this year, the 6th annual Yoga Day was held at Currimundi State School.
The yoga festival billed as the biggest in the country - YogaFest - took place last October at Lake Kawana Community Centre with nearly 70 workshops and presentations, while Wanderlust (also in October) is another huge wellness drawcard.
After the 2016 Wanderlust festival at Novotel Twin Waters Resort, organiser Jonnie Halstead said attendance had increased more than 35% on 2015.
He said close to 3000 people had watched Xavier Rudd perform as part of the music component to the festival.
"It's been great. We get nothing but support here on the Sunshine Coast," Mr Halstead said at the time.
He said Wanderlust would return to Twin Waters for the next few years and would build on the musical aspects.
Venues such as the Chenrezig Buddhist Institute, Calm Living Meditation Retreat, Mt Ninderry Healing Retreat and a wide range of indulgent spas have helped build the Coast's wellness reputation and others are coming on board to give the concept a new spin.
Lift Gallery in Maleny, for example, includes a sound spa, natural healing rooms, music performances and Live Cafe serving plant-based food (https://www.facebook.com/experiencealift).
"I think it is about 'balance'. The Sunshine Coast is not some isolated area where you feel as if you're locked away in a health camp," Mr Latchford said.
"Here, you can enjoy such a rich range of activities from a complete detox through to a more blended program that can include a range of fun though healthy activities.
"For instance, a cooking class at the Spirit House might seem indulgent to some, but it offers incredibly healthy food that feeds the mind as much as the body.
"You get a real feeling of 'zen' when you visit there.
"That's why the Sunshine Coast has been so popular for Asian-inspired cooking schools and restaurants - we have the climate, the scenery and of course the produce to be a leader in this field.
"Our region's reputation for organic fresh food is a natural complement to health and wellness holidays.
"We have some of the largest organic health food centres, organic restaurants and, of course, our markets, which are among Australia's best for their range of quality produce and health-related items.
"The Glass House Mountains and the hinterland really help define the spirituality of the destination.
"That's why there are so many health, spa and meditation retreats located in these areas.
"They're a natural fit. A walk up Mt Ngungun or a relaxed trek through Mary Cairncross Reserve gives you these million-dollar vistas that actually cost nothing and yet provide such an uplifting experience."
Mr Latchford said our "naturally refreshing" marketing message resonated with Europeans, who could be attracted to hundreds of east-coast beach destinations in Australia but chose us because with "our rich landscape and our health and wellness profile, we offer something very different".
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glass House Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Halstead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chenrezig Buddhist Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hinterland Great Walk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twin Waters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mary Cairncross Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Currimundi State School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast CEO Simon Latchford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Ninderry Healing Retreat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coastal Pathway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maleny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Living Meditation Retreat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jonnie Halstead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Novotel Twin Waters Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spirit House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Latchford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Live Cafe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DNA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Kawana Community Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xavier Rudd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>YogaFest</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yoga Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Ngungun</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
