<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415247600896924</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>17:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/03/33/vic-strike-could-affect-prison-drug-tests</url>
  <title>Vic strike could affect prison drug tests</title>
  <content>
Corrections Victoria is "making arrangements" for prisoner drug testing after workers at its pathology provider announced they will walk off the job over a pay dispute.
More than 500 Dorevitch Pathology staff have voted to take protected industrial action on Monday over what the Health Workers Unions says is a "zero per cent pay offer on the table".
The organisation is responsible for urine drug testing in the state's prisons and community correctional services.
The union believes Dorevitch will use temporary and agency staff during the industrial action and has concerns it will affect compliance with national standards.
"They can try and bring in untrained replacement and agency staff as strike breakers, but we know from past cases that Dorevitch management take a cavalier approach to complying with national standards," union secretary Diana Asmar said in a statement on Wednesday.
"We've written to the legal fraternity relaying our concerns."
A Corrections Victoria spokesman said the department was "making arrangements to limit to impact of the proposed industrial action".

Related Articles

Striking employees will include pathology collectors, couriers, clerical staff, laboratory assistants, cleaners and maintenance staff.
The union says Dorevitch's owner, Primary Health, has posted more than $1.2 billion in profits since the last pay deal, with wages remaining stagnant over a decade.
"Right now, they are the lowest paid and unhappiest pathology workers in Australia by a country mile. Enough is enough," Ms Asmar said.
Dorevitch said it only foresees minimal disruption to services.
"There will be no impact to the services we provide public and private hospitals, and our laboratories will continue to process tests and work with GPs to deliver results as per normal," a company spokeswoman told AAP.
"A number of contingencies have been implemented to limit the impact to patients and GPs."
The pathology giant has more than 300 sites across the state and contracts with many public and private hospitals - with only a small number of collection centres to close on Monday.
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Asmar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorevitch Pathology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Workers Unions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diana Asmar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrections Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dorevitch</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
