<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415977745350021</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/mayweather-agrees-megafight-shake-/3208131/</url>
  <title>Mayweather agrees to megafight shake-up</title>
  <content>
Defiant Floyd Mayweather has given Conor McGregor a huge boost by agreeing to fight using lighter gloves.

The Irishman is desperate to have as little padding as possible - improving his odds of scoring a KO victory when they meet on August 26.

And Money has shocked fans by agreeing to wear 8oz gloves instead of the normal 10oz.

It is a big move from the American, who McGregor believed chose to fight at 154 lbs because bouts above 147 lbs are usually fought with the heavier mitts in Nevada.

Mayweather said: "McGregor, let's fight in 8oz gloves. Don't believe what you hear in the media. Don't believe what you hear on blog sites. If it's not coming directly from me, then it's not true.

"I'm telling McGregor 'let's fight in 8oz gloves".

McGregor can fight in any brand he prefers or chooses.

"I'll be wearing 8oz Grant gloves. Whatever advantage McGregor needs to feel more comfortable in the ring, I'm willing to accommodate.

"Let's give the boxing and MMA fans what they want to see."

Mayweather has only fought at 154lbs in three of his 49 bouts - against Oscar De La Hoya, Miguel Cotto and Saul Alvarez.

He wore 10oz gloves for each of the victories, which all came via the judges' scorecards.

In the UFC, glove size ranges from 4oz to 6oz and McGregor has requested in the past that they change the weight of the gloves for their cross-code match-up.

Last month, Mayweather hinted he was open to the move to which McGregor replied: "Don't fool the public.

"All these rules, all these restrictions, it doesn't faze me, it amuses me. The gloves, they have to be 10-ounce for 154 pounds.

"He's never fought at 154. I think he's fought at 154 maybe once. He wants the gloves up. No problem. Give him the gloves up. I'll wear 10 ounces.

"No Mexican-made gloves. OK, no problem. No gloves made out of horsehair. All right, no problem. I don't give a f***.

"We're only wearing gloves in our game about five years, so I don't give a s*** about gloves or any of that.

"I'm just enjoying it. It's funny to me, all these rules. All I need is a gum-shield, line me up to the ring and I'm good to go."

Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
IT was heart-breaking, challenging and life-changing.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor McGregor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGregor</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miguel Cotto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UFC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayweather</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saul Alvarez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nevada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irishman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexican-made</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oscar De La Hoya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Floyd Mayweather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
