<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415930500708781</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/03/05/52/sacked-white-house-communications-director-anthony-scaramucci-breaks-silence</url>
  <title>Sacked White House communications director Anthony Scaramucci breaks silence</title>
  <content>
Former White House communications director Anthony Scaramucci has opened up about an expletive-laden rant he made, resulting in him losing his role.
The former hedge fund manager, nicknamed "the Mooch", The Huffington Post his comments - published in the New Yorker by journalist Ryan Lizza - were not meant for publication.
"Most of what I said was humorous and joking," Mr Scaramucci said.
"Legally, it may have been on the record, but the spirit of it was off. And (Ryan Lizza) knew that. The Lizzas and Scaramuccis have been friends for over 50 years.
"My dad knew his dad from construction, and we were building a personal relationship."
Lizza has denied the claim the pair were old friends, asserting he only knew Scaramucci "in his capacity as a Trump surrogate and then White House communications director".

"We are not and have never been 'old family friends', though I think our fathers knew each other, so maybe that's what he's talking about," Lizza said.

Related Articles

"But again, that would not be a reason to suppress an explosive on-the-record interview."
Scaramucci's emotive phone rant saw him name then-White House Chief of Staff Reince Priebus a "paranoid schizophrenic", while suggesting chief strategist Steve Bannon practiced a lewd act on himself.
The former White House staffer's call was then followed by a tweet from Lizza regarding information leaked by a "senior White House official".
The interview, which pulled back the curtain on rumoured tension within the White House's West Wing, left US President Donald Trump unimpressed.
White House spokeswoman Sarah Huckabee Sanders said Mr Trump thought the remarks were "inappropriate".
Scaramucci tendered his resignation as a result but Mr Trump refused to accept the offer, instead putting the communications director on notice, The Huffington Post claims.
Days later the new White House Chief of Staff, retired Marine General John Kelly, requested Scaramucci's resignation.
Scaramucci, who sold his own business to work for Trump, had been on the job for just 10 days.
Scaramucci did not confirm what his plans were following his dismissal, but told the publication he intends to temporarily retreat from the public eye for the time being.
"I am now going to go dark," he said.
"Then I will re-emerge... As me."
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lizza</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House's West Wing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Yorker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marine General John Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scaramucci</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Scaramucci</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Lizza</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reince Priebus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House Chief of Staff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huffington Post</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Scaramucci</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
