<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415921910774009</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/adelaides-city-of-churches-label-spreading-thin/8763330</url>
  <title>2016 Census: 'City of Churches' label spreading thin across Greater Adelaide communities</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

When you think of Adelaide, does the label, City of Churches, ring to mind?
It's a label that has become synonymous with South Australia's capital for the best part of two centuries.
And while it does boast its fair share of cathedrals, census data shows only a quarter of its inner-city residents (26 per cent, or just under 4,000 people) are Christian.
When you combine all suburbs in Greater Adelaide, just under half the population on average is Christian, which is still less by percentage than those in Sydney.
The ABC has  to work out who, exactly, is an "ordinary" Australian.
Associate Professor Gour Dasvarma from Flinders University said the "ordinary Australian" in Adelaide was becoming harder to find.
"We are changing, that's for sure," he said.
"Like the rest of Australia and other metropolitan cities, Adelaide is a big, diverse community and there could be nothing typical about it."
Christianity numbers varying by suburbs

Christianity was one of the broad measures used by the ABC to determine what could be deemed as "ordinary".
But the figures in Adelaide vary drastically depending on what suburb you live in.
For instance, 73 per cent of residents in the northern suburb of Shea-Oak Log are Christian, as well as a high number in the Adelaide Hills, but at Bowden in the city's inner-north it's under 30 per cent.
Adelaide Christians

The number of Christians in the western suburbs, including Lockleys and West Lakes, is also high in the 60s percentage range.
Associate Professor Dasvarma said the size of variation was interesting but the trend was no surprise.
"Many residents of the inner-city comprise of short-term arrivals who have come from non-Christian countries," he said.
If you live in Adelaide's city centre, you're also less likely to be married but it's again the opposite story if you're in the Adelaide Hills.
Adelaide married people

About 60 per cent of adults based in many hills suburbs like Paracombe have tied the knot compared to 16 per cent in Hindmarsh, 24 per cent in Bowden and 23 per cent in Adelaide.
Adelaide ancestry

Typical income, family and ancestry - British or Australian - were also dropping.
Adelaide home sizes

Only about 7 per cent of residents in Adelaide now live in the "ordinary" three-bedroom, free-standing house with a mortgage.
"I think the changes that are happening are in relation to the government policy that encourages apartment-style living and sub-division of large blocks into smaller units," Professor Dasvarma said.
"It also relates to the character of the recent immigrants.
"Nowadays there are many people coming on short-term working visas or students coming on short-term student visas who really don't live in an ordinary dwelling or three-bedroom house."

Adelaide household income

Adelaide families with children

The typical family of two kids and a partner is also disappearing.
Census data showed no-one in the suburb of Bolivar had that family setting and only 2 per cent did in Adelaide, but that jumped to 28 per cent at Kangaroo Flat and Craigburn Farm.
Associate Professor Dasvarma said like many other cities around the world, "diversity" is the new "ordinary".
"We live in a dynamic society where change is inevitable," he said.
Australia's most and least 'ordinary' suburbs

Video by  and

Data notes

For privacy reasons, the Australian Bureau of Statistics introduces small random errors to Census data. This can reduce the reliability of small numbers and produce minor discrepancies in totals and subtotals
Ordinary ancestry means a person of English ancestry who speaks only English at home, was born in Australia and whose parents were born in Australia
Ordinary dwelling refers to a free-standing house with three bedrooms and two cars, owned with a mortgage
Ordinary family means a married couple with two children
Maps were created in Tableau Public

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Dasvarma</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockleys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shea-Oak Log</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craigburn Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greater Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tableau Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Hills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paracombe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Christians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Churches</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kangaroo Flat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christianity</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Gour Dasvarma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hindmarsh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolivar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
