<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416037874893377</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:46</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/what-its-like-to-retire-early-2017-8</url>
  <title>A man who retired at 34 says he 'freaked out' on the first Monday he didn't have to go to work</title>
  <content>
Brandon's last day of work was Friday, July 29, 2016.

He was 34.

The software developer and blogger behind the  - who doesn't use his last name online for privacy reasons - had been .

Living frugally and working in rural Vermont, he managed to save and invest , and saved enough to leave his job in spring 2014. However, when his employer offered to make his position remote, he stayed on for a few years more than planned, intermittently travelling with his wife Jill until they relocated full-time to Scotland in May 2015. There, he continued working, blogging, and saving .

On a new post on his site, Brandon wrote that since his last day of work was a Friday, it didn't feel that different from the end of any other week.

"It wasn't until I woke up on Monday, August 1st that it really hit me," he wrote. "And boy did it hit me."

He continued:

"You would have expected it to be the best morning ever but it was actually the only time in the entire first year that I freaked out about the whole thing.
"I had escaped the normal life script but now I was in uncharted territory.
"I was staring into the vast unknown and the immense gravity of the situation freaked me out (much more than I expected).
"It's crazy that I wasn't mentally prepared for it, considering early retirement was something I had been thinking about and working towards for over five years."

Brandon wrote that "[Financial independence] was something I talked about and thought about so much that it just became this abstract concept in my mind and didn't relate to anything in real life. It was a long-term goal that I guess I never actually pictured achieving."

The "first morning of freedom was tough," he said, "because I couldn't process it all."

To distract himself from the existential angst of early Monday, he put in some time working on something fun: his blog. "I was happy to be making progress on things that were important to me and I started getting really excited about the idea of doing that every day," he wrote. He continued:

"Maybe life wouldn't look so different, after all? I would still be working but I'd just be working on things I'm passionate about.
"That was the  so I'm not sure why I didn't think about that when I woke up that day."

However, he settled into his new reality after that first, jarring day. A year later, he's thrilled with his post-job lifestyle. "Have you ever woke up thinking it was Sunday morning but it was actually Saturday instead?" he wrote of his later months as a "retiree." "It was like that but 1,000 times better because it wasn't just an extra day off that you didn't expect but the rest of your life!"

NOW WATCH: Ideas videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brandon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29, 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vermont</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
