<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415964860447889</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/no-light-horizon-young-regional-queenslanders-hoping-to-buy-home/8768592</url>
  <title>Home ownership: 'No light on the horizon' for young regional Queenslanders hoping to buy</title>
  <content>
Home ownership rates among Queenslanders who live outside Brisbane, aged 18 to 39, are plummeting.
The latest survey of Household Income and Labour Dynamics in Australia or HILDA has shown the huge number of regional Queenslanders who do not own their own home is rising.
Sunshine Coast mother of two Sonnie Mather reflects on the challenges she faces while sitting on the back porch of her rental, her first chance to sit down after the daily school run.
"It's easy to get left behind, or miss the boat altogether," she said.
Between 2002 and 2014 the rate of ownership for regional Queenslanders fell 17 per cent to 21.1 per cent, the second worst result in the country behind regional New South Wales.
Ms Mather receives rental assistance and said home ownership was just not within her reach.
The part-time receptionist said she was not surprised by the results of the survey.
"I basically had to start all over again close to four years ago now," she said.
"I've got two kids, one's in high school, one's in primary school, there's sport, excursions, camps, things like that.
"Teenagers with extra hot water when they're showering, it's just every day there's something."

Struggle to get mortgage without a job

Shelly Peach and her partner have just bought a house in Townsville, a town with massive unemployment problems.
The 33-year-old has two small children, and admits mortgage repayments are difficult while also shelling out for child care.
"Day care is probably the biggest cost when owning your own home," Ms Peach said.
"My boy goes four days, and my daughter goes two days, and it's $300 a week out of our pocket, which is pretty much what our mortgage repayment is for the week."
Ms Peach and her partner both have full-time jobs, and believe it is the only reason they were able to borrow to buy a house.
But she believes many people in regional Queensland, especially in Townsville where the unemployment rate is 9.7 per cent, are not as lucky.
"I think probably the hardest thing these days is the people that don't have permanent jobs," she said.
"It's just so hard to get a secure permanent job these days and the banks look for a couple that are both working and have permanent jobs."
'No light on the horizon,' REIQ boss says

Chief executive of the Real Estate Institute of Queensland Antonia Mercorella said there were several factors locking young people out of the market.
"This is not simply affordability issue because the houses in regional Queensland are among the most affordable in the country," Ms Mercorella said.
"It's more a case of employment and wages levels not supporting home ownership.
"Regional Queensland has some of the highest unemployment levels in the country, with Townsville at 9.7 per cent, Fitzroy at 7 per cent, and parts of the Outback at more than 13 per cent."
Ms Mercorella said the Global Financial Crisis and the mining downturn were also to blame.
"Recovery from these events is proving slow, staggered and unreliable for most of regional Queensland's housing markets," she said.
"Unfortunately, we don't know when the light will appear on the horizon."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HILDA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour Dynamics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Household Income</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mercorella</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonia Mercorella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>REIQ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Global Financial Crisis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shelly Peach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queenslanders</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Estate Institute of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonnie Mather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Peach</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
