<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415964860447864</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/world/light-plane-kills-sunbathers-in-emergency-beach-landing-in-portugal-20170802-gxo6il.html</url>
  <title>Light plane kills sunbathers in emergency beach landing in Portugal</title>
  <content>
Lisbon: A light plane has made an emergency landing on a packed beach near Lisbon on Wednesday, killing a 56-year-old man and an eight-year-old girl who were sunbathing, authorities said.
Hundreds of sunbathers were on the popular beach at Sao Joao de Caparica, 30 kilometres south of Lisbon, and witnesses said some sunbathers ran into the sea to avoid the plane.

Up Next

Suicide attackers grenade Shi'te mosque

00:48

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Portugal: Plane kills sunbathers in emergency landing

A light plane has made an emergency landing on a packed beach near Lisbon, killing a 56-year-old man and an eight-year-old girl who were sunbathing.

The National Maritime Authority said the man and girl died on the beach. Officials said they were not aware of any other people who were injured in the incident.
The small aircraft, reportedly a Cessna, carrying two people appeared to be in difficulty and wobbled as it skimmed low over the sunbathers, scattering them and spreading panic on the beach, witnesses said.

Local television showed dozens of beachgoers crowding around the airplane, which had come to a stop near the water with minor damage, including a broken left wing. 
Officials said the accident occurred at 4.50pm local time.

The dead girl was with her parents, who were unhurt, witnesses told local television channels. The plane passed over the man who was killed as he sunbathed on a towel, they said.

You will now receive updates from

Breaking News Alert

Breaking News Alert

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The two occupants of the plane were unhurt and were being questioned by police.Photo: AP
Sao Joao de Caparica beach is one of the closest to Lisbon and draws big crowds in August, when the Portuguese take their main summer holidays. 
APPhoto: AP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Maritime Authority</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caparica</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisbon</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Alert</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sao Joao</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portuguese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
