<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415926205741373</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:20</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/what-is-a-typical-west-australian-australian-census/8749416</url>
  <title>In Western Australia, the 'ordinary Australian' is rather extraordinary</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

No one likes to be ordinary. And the good news is, most of us aren't.
An
As the country becomes more diverse, the proportion of people who share the most common demographic characteristics is shrinking.
In Western Australia, the suburb where you are most likely to meet the "ordinary" Australian is Boyup Brook, where three of the population of 911 people have at least 10 of the typical traits.
But in most suburbs and towns across Western Australia, zero Australians tick all the boxes for "ordinary".

The 'ordinary' Australian

English ancestry, born in Australia, both parents born in Australia and speaks only English at home
Lives in a freestanding house, owned with a mortgage, with three bedrooms and two motor vehicles
Is married with two children
Identifies as Christian
The family earns $2,000-$2,999 a week ($104K-$130K a year)

Perth home sizes

Perth Christians

Perth ancestry

Perth married people

Perth family income

Perth families with children

Demography and population researcher Dr Amanda Davies said Western Australia was more likely to have people who had migrated from England to work in the manufacturing industries in the post-war period and the 1970s.
"That has meant the population is more English than anywhere else in the country, in terms of its ancestry, and therefore speaks English at home more," she said.
"Also [they have] a propensity to prefer a certain type of housing over another, so the things link together."
Australia's most and least 'ordinary' suburbs

The most 'ordinary' West Australian suburbs

Religion:
Most - (Christian) suburb in Perth is Coogee, at 68 per cent (pop 4,597)
Least - (Christian) suburb is Rottnest Island (10 per cent), followed by Wooroloo - (pop 2,642) 15 per cent.
Marriage:
Most - Neerabup with 69 per cent over 15 married. (pop 104)
Least - Northbridge with 23 per cent married. (pop of 1,307)
English Ancestry:
Most - Meelon, 26 per cent. (pop 201)
Least - Rottnest Island (4 per cent), then Northbridge and Mirrabooka (5 per cent each)
Three-bedroom mortgaged dwelling:
Most - Hilbert, 14 per cent (pop 1,552)
Least - Anketell, 0 per cent (pop 248), followed by Dalkeith, Bentley and Burswood at 1 per cent
Families with two kids:
Most - Burns Beach, 31 per cent (pop 3,377)
Least - East Rockingham (pop 263) and Northbridge, both 0 per cent.
Typical income:
Most - Whitby, 17 per cent (pop 319)
Least - Neerabup (0 per cent) and East Rockingham (3 per cent)

Social researcher and writer, and self-described "census nerd", Dr Rebecca Huntley said the term "ordinary Australian" was constantly invoked.
"When you spend time with people asking them to define what that is ... people push back. They say: 'What is the average Australian?' They question what that is," she said.
"Even though we have lots of different kinds of people trying to force us into imagining there's one position on anything or one reasonable centre view on anything, there often isn't.
"It obscures some of the complexities about what people feel about certain issues."

The "ordinary" and the "extraordinary"

Dianella makeup artist Brie Treasure-Hilder said she was surprised she met all the criteria for "ordinary" - when she pictured a quintessential Australian she didn't picture herself.
"For me it's probably a pair of thongs, and stubby shorts, and a can of beer in their hand, which isn't me at all," she said.
"It is interesting, I don't feel like we live an average life."

Fatuma Mohamed, 40, ticks none of the "ordinary" boxes, but said that didn't affect how Australian she felt.
Ms Mohamed, who migrated to the country 17 years ago from Somalia as a refugee, said four of her six children were born in this country.
"Maybe everyone, they have different backgrounds, same [as] me," she said.
"My kids they're saying they're Australian because they grew up here. They study [here].
"We are Australian, I feel Australian."

Teacher Jenny Findlay, 55, from the small southern coastal town of Denmark, fits the bill as an "ordinary" Australian on all but one category - income.
But she said she felt far from ordinary.
"I think I'm unusual being married. I think I'm unusual having a couple of kids," she said.
"Not that any of those things are bad.
"It's changed so much since I was a child too. Children I teach now, just in one generation, it's changed so significantly."
According to census data, Denmark's population of 2,637 included no people who ticked all the boxes as a typical Australian.

Mirrabooka was another WA suburb that recorded no "ordinary" Australians. Mirrabooka local Alfred Noti, 32, has six children and only ticks a few of the other "ordinary" Australian boxes.
He said defining "ordinary" was hard to do.
"That's kind of a tricky question," he said. "The thing is, Australia is a great place.
"It's not like only on one side, it's a diverse culture
Video by  and

Data notes

For privacy reasons, the Australian Bureau of Statistics introduces small random errors to Census data. This can reduce the reliability of small numbers and produce minor discrepancies in totals and subtotals
Ordinary ancestry means a person of English ancestry who speaks only English at home, was born in Australia and whose parents were born in Australia
Ordinary dwelling refers to a free-standing house with three bedrooms and two cars, owned with a mortgage
Ordinary family means a married couple with two children
Maps were created in Tableau Public

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brie Treasure-Hilder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dianella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neerabup (0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tableau Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dalkeith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Somalia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirrabooka</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northbridge</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wooroloo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fatuma Mohamed, 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>K-$130K</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Amanda Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rottnest Island (4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mirrabooka (5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hilbert, 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denmark</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coogee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Rockingham (3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Rockingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Ancestry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Rebecca Huntley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitby, 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred Noti, 32</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anketell, 0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neerabup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rottnest Island (10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meelon, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burns Beach, 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Christians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Mohamed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burswood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Findlay, 55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boyup Brook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
