<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415655622797069</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:17</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/keeping-up-with-the-needs-of-our-aging-population/3207307/</url>
  <title>Keeping up with the needs of our aging population</title>
  <content>
BROMILOW Home Support Services opened its doors in 1993 out of a growing need for in-home care and support on the Coast.
Twenty-five years ago, community care was an emerging industry and had nothing like the mainstream services that we now take for granted.
Bromilow CEO Paul Hawting has been with the organisation every step of the way.
"We raised a few eyebrows back in the day as a new kid on the block," he recalls.
"We didn't come from a nursing or clinical background. However, we came to the industry with one major asset that has continued to serve us very well - a clear client focus."
From humble beginnings working from a home office in Buderim, Bromilow today employs 100 staff including care workers, registered nurses, cleaners, gardeners, dementia champions and administration staff.
It delivers a broad range of in-home support options for the elderly and younger people with disabilities, assisting them to maintain their independence and remain living in their own homes.
"The most enjoyable aspect of my role is visiting clients in their homes," Paul said.
"Sitting one-on-one and just talking with them, listening to their stories, hearing about their fascinating lives, playing with their pets and sharing a cuppa.
"One of my most memorable clients was Eric, an elderly bushman who had lived in Tewantin for many years. Eric lived in an old timber home, surrounded by his many beloved cats and a python in the ceiling.
"Interestingly, one of our first clients, grandparents in Buderim, who wanted some support to care for their young grandchildren, contacted us 20 years later needing support for themselves as their health declined."
With the government-initiated reform agenda, the industry is becoming more market-driven and highly competitive.
Consumers now have more choice than ever and Bromilow can support its clients in new and innovative ways.
A clear client focus and good old-fashioned customer service has enabled it to successfully enter its 25th year as a community care service provider in the Sunshine Coast community.
"It has been a privilege to assist the older and younger disabled population on the Sunshine Coast for the past quarter century," Paul said.
"Bromilow has enjoyed a wonderful journey but there is still much more to come."
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twenty-five</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BROMILOW Home Support Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bromilow CEO Paul Hawting</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buderim</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tewantin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bromilow</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
