<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415964860447849</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/new-app-to-help-parents-spot-risky-online-behaviour/8768600</url>
  <title>CyberParent app teaching migrant parents to spot dangerous online behaviour, radicalisation</title>
  <content>
A new app called CyberParent is being launched today by the Australian Multicultural Foundation to help parents from culturally diverse backgrounds understand what their children are doing online, including looking at possible radicalisation of young ones.
The app is available free online in 17 languages including English, Arabic, Chinese and Indonesian.
The foundation's executive director Hass Dellal said it was developed after two years of workshops with various community groups showing there was a great need to make many migrant communities more computer literate.
"The app is designed to teach parents what their children are doing online, including social media," he said.
"During community consultations, many parents told us they did not understand how their children used their devices online. It will equip parents to identify some of the early warning signs.

"Parents, particularly mothers, are a very important and underutilised resource in this sort of prevention space.
"Parents were very anxious about the risks the internet poses and want to protect their children from things such as online grooming, cyberbullying and radicalisation."
Mr Dellal said there was some very simple but effective information on the CyberParent app, including a list of some of the code words children used to sometimes hide what they were doing.
"For example, a lot of young people use acronyms like 'POS' meaning 'parent over shoulder'."
'He knows mum isn't totally blind about things'

Sri-Lankan born Australian Muslim mother of two Asiya Rodrigo said she had taken part in the workshops to help develop the app, and found it filled an important gap for her.
"I am not all that familiar with a lot of the social media platforms young people use regularly," she said.

"I have had to warn my son about the kind of language and pictures he might put up online because other people can access that and use that against him. He knows mum is not totally blind about things.
"So it is really good to have a bit of extra information so that you know what to look out for and also how to protect your family."
Ms Rodrigo said the knowledge she had gained had helped promote discussion with her 10 and 13-year-old boys.
"The app makes you aware of features of various apps that young people use and the kind of discussions you need to have with your child.
"I think parents in general and Muslims as well, we do not necessarily worry about terrorism per say affecting our kids, but we are worried about bullying, we are worried about drug use, we are worried about people that they might access online that may lead them away from the community or their families.
"So general negative influences ... terrorism or extremist groups are just one small fraction of that worry."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Rodrigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indonesian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arabic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sri Lankan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Multicultural Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hass Dellal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asiya Rodrigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Dellal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CyberParent</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
