<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415969155415201</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/celebrity/rumours-are-circulating-richie-strahan-and-alex-nation-have-split-after-10months-together/news-story/bb2835329c8bd1e9341ad06a012af772</url>
  <title>Have Bachelor's Richie, Alex split?</title>
  <content>
IT appears another Bachelor love affair may be over.
Speculation is mounting Richie Strahan and Alex Nation have called time on their relationship, 10-and-a-half months after he
When contacted by phone last night, a downcast Strahan danced around the issue and refused to shut down speculation that the couple had broken up. Nation too was silent, not responding to calls for comment.
They're both represented by Chadwick Celebrity, the agency saying it would not comment on the couple's "personal lives" despite having signed them because of their national profile from the reality dating show.
There has been radio silence online from the pair, who previously posted regular images together on social media. And they've not been seen together in public since the Logie Awards in April.
Confidential understands the pair were due to travel to South East Asia together recently. Instead of going as a couple, they took separate holidays.
While Matty Johnson is currently wooing women on the new season of The Bachelor, the show has had a mixed degree of success in previous seasons.
The first Bachelor,  from the show, Anna Heinrich, while

Sam Frost wasn't so lucky, having first been dumped by Blake Garvey before her stint on The Bachelorette and subsequently splitting from Sasha Mielczarek.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Garvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chadwick Celebrity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logie Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matty Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richie Strahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sasha Mielczarek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Heinrich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South-east Asia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Nation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelor's Richie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strahan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
