<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414938363245296</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4273648/ardent-leisures-new-chairman-faces-big-challenges/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Ardent Leisure's new chairman faces big challenges</title>
  <content>
Ardent Leisure's new chairman faces big challenges

New Ardent Leisure chairman George Venardos (left) arrives at the recent controversial general meeting with chief executive Deborah Thomas. Photo: Louise Kennerley

Ardent's new chairman George Venardos.

George Venardos was on the risk and compliance committee of IOOF when the company was plunged into turmoil last year. Photo: Jessica Shapiro

Venardos will have to work closely with the Ardent management over any issues of insurance claims. Photo: Glenn Hunt

exit

It wasn't meant to be like this. When Ardent Leisure announced in September that long-serving director George Venardos would take over from the even-longer serving chairman Neil Balnaves, all it took was a simple press release.
Balnaves assured investors that Venardos would "ensure that the board remains focused on maximising value for shareholders".
Not now. Now Venardos faces the challenge of preserving any value at all for shareholders, not to mention restoring the company's social licence in the wake of the deaths of four people at its Dreamworld theme park.
When he takes the reins formally on Monday he will sit atop a company in crisis.
Now, having been a director with the embattled leisure and entertainment company since 2009, Venardos - a once high-flying corporate accountant named Insto Magazine's CFO of the Year in 2003 while at insurance giant IAG - is going to need to call on all his 30 years of senior executive experience.
One especially pertinent piece of experience comes through his time at IOOF, a company which was plunged into crisis following a Fairfax Media investigation last year. Venardos stepped in as a chairman of that company last month.
The 58-year-old got a front-row seat to just how hard the job would be at the Ardent annual general meeting in October.
Held just two days after the fatal accident at the group's theme park, Dreamworld on the Gold Coast, the company's leadership was panned over its decision to hold the meeting and then to press ahead with awarding chief executive Deborah Thomas her bonus. That decision barely lasted the afternoon.
Venardos is also a member of the group's Safety, Sustainability & Environment Committee - putting him right in the eye of the Dreamworld storm.
At the, at times fiery, meeting the quietly spoken deputy chair, told investors that his committee took the safety of patrons "very seriously".
Fairfax Media requested an interview with Venardos, but Ardent directors have said they will refrain from making any comments to allow the families of the four victims of the accident to hold their funerals.
There have been calls from investors, most of who decline to be named, for a broom to go through the Ardent board. When the park will re-open remains in limbo. It will be the new chairman's job to convince patrons to return.
"Mr Venardos is an experienced director, however taking over the reins from the current chairperson, Neil Balnaves, against the backdrop of last week's tragic event will surely test his capabilities," managing director of Folkestone Maxim Asset Management, Winston Sammut, said.
"Given the board's responses to date, the incoming chairman may well have to consider taking more of a hands-on approach and be proactive rather reactive in dealing with the many issues the company will face over the months ahead," Mr Sammut said.
Venardos will have to work closely with the Ardent management over any issues of insurance claims and possibly even director culpability. As one investor has said if the directors are found to have been negligent, then heads will roll.

Experience of scandal

Venardos was on the risk and compliance committee of the IOOF board when the company was plunged into turmoil last year after Fairfax Media exposed a series of issues and misconduct. He is now the chairman.
ASIC identified a number of serious concerns in IOOF's research division, including compliance arrangements, breach reporting, management of conflicts of interest, staff trading policy, disclosure, whistleblower management and protection and cyber security.
The investigation followed a series of stories by Fairfax Media that exposed misconduct in the research division, including allegations of front-running, an insider trading incident that wasn't reported to ASIC, misrepresentation of performance figures, faulty research reports, getting junior staff to cheat on compliance exams on behalf of a senior executive, bullying and victimisation of a whistleblower.
Prior to joining the IOOF and Ardent boards in 2009 he served as the chief financial officer of Insurance Australia Group for a decade from 1998. In the same year he joined the board of listed financial services company, Australian Wealth Management.
Former chief executive of Insurance Australia Group, Michael Hawker, is a vocal advocate of Venardos.
Earlier this year he said: "I relied totally on George for advice, and I had to be able to have absolute trust in him ... I don't know how you would deal with the job [of CEO] if there wasn't a good personal relationship [with the CFO]."
No doubt those good credentials will come in handy with any insurance, corporate culpability or finance issues that could come Ardent's way.
Amid the Dreamworld tragedy, the group has been looking at shifting more focus to its more lucrative Main Event Entertainment division, which operates in the United States.
At the annual meeting shareholders approved the group's name change to Main Event and the board made it clear that strategy was to be pursued. It will be his job to help steer that course.

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Folkestone Maxim Asset Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hawker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IAG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George Venardos</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Sammut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insto Magazine's CFO of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insurance Australia Group</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venardos</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deborah Thomas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environment Committee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Event</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASIC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Balnaves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dreamworld</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Ardent Leisure</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ardent Leisure</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Balnaves</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise Kennerley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>George</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Wealth Management</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main Event Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Winston Sammut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jessica Shapiro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Hunt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Venardos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CFO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IOOF</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
