<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414848168929760</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/3069486/the-man-the-moustache-the-murders-ivan-milats-story-comes-to-tv/?cs=4173</url>
  <title>The man, the moustache, the murders. Ivan Milat's story comes to TV</title>
  <content>
The man, the moustache, the murders. Ivan Milat's story comes to TV

Mal Kennard is the serial murderer Ivan Milat.

exit

One of the many factors that contributed to Ivan Milat's downfall was his distinctive "Merv Hughes" moustache, which helped fix his appearance in the minds of witnesses.
So when Mal Kennard got the lead role in Catching Milat it was inevitable he'd have to grow facial hair in the signature Milat style.
But when we  visited him on set, with just four days' shooting to go, the actor can't wait to break out the razor.
"I won't be keeping it," he says. "I'll be quite happy to shave it off. I won't be keeping the look."
And the look is pretty creepy. Put that moustache together with Kennard's penetrating gaze and the effect is slightly unnerving. The reaction from those around him - especially women - has been interesting, he says. "I do get treated differently but not all in a negative way. It's bizarre. I don't know whether it's just the vibe or whatever but there has been a different kind of thing going on."
The last time I saw Kennard he was in full Milat mode on location at a brick bungalow in Wattle Grove in Sydney's south-west. They house was standing in for the real Milat home in Eagle Vale and the scene was Milat's arrest in 1994.
Kennard/Milat was caught, literally, with his trousers down as the cops surrounded the house, but even in his Y-fronts, Kennard exuded an air of desperate menace as he barked orders at his girlfriend, Chalinder Hughes, and tried to hide evidence.
"It was actually difficult to do that with all the props," says Kennard. "I had to put the phone down in one place, pick up the pants, hand the dress to my girlfriend and inform her that the cops were here - which was big news - and do all that on a pirouette and turn and run away to the garage."
That chaotic scene is close to the climax of Catching Milat, a retelling of a story indelibly etched on the psyche of anyone who lived through the terrible series of killings that have come to be known as the Backpacker Murders.
Ironically, considering how he has made the part his own, Kennard was originally not in the frame to play Milat.
"I was looking at a different character," he says. "Things changed when I was told I was seriously being considered for Ivan. It's something that happens to me a lot with characters."
Once he knew he had the lead part, Kennard read what he could about Milat and the killings, in particular the book Sins of the Brother by Mark Whittaker and Les Kennedy on which the miniseries is based.
Kennard became fascinated by the fact that even a monster like Milat could have a human side.
"When I read the script I saw that it was very different from what I thought it was going to be," he says. "My knowledge, and I think most people's knowledge, of Ivan Milat as a person is very different from a lot of the facts that are out there. It was ostensibly a character study of a person who was capable of doing extraordinarily terrible things but then how does the personality express itself in other ways like having a relationship?"
Shortly after Milat killed his last victims, he met and settled down with Hughes.
"A lot of people were saying, 'Great, Ivan has found someone he can be with' which is a great irony. It's ironic that on the one hand you've got this attempt to have a really fulfilling relationship and on the other hand there is all this other stuff going on - the heinous acts. To me this is fascinating. How does this happen? It's really satisfying from a character point of view for an actor."
Kennard has his own theory as to why Milat made such poor attempts to cover up his crimes, leaving evidence, including trophies from his victims, barely hidden.
"A lot of people would say that criminals self-sabotage because they need the boundary to be spelt out for them because they don't have that capacity themselves."
Inevitably, when Catching Milat goes to air, there will be those who question whether it is acceptable to make a TV drama from such recent and terrible history, especially as the victims' relatives may well encounter the miniseries. It's something Kennard has considered, but he is satisfied Catching Milat strikes the right balance.
"You either tell the story or you don't," he says. "The crimes still exist. I come down on the side of saying you should tell the story as long as it's done sensitively and with intelligence. As for the effects of that, I hope they are positive."
But he remains deeply affected by his research into the life and crimes of Milat, especially when forced to consider the terrible toll on the victims' parents.
"When I came across some of the information about the parents I was deeply, emotionally affected by it. I was really upset, to tell you the truth. What can you say? They are the sort of things people never get over.
"I really think this is not a sensationalised production and if it was I wouldn't have done it. It's got merit and I do have a deep empathy and concern for the parents of the victims. You can't say anything more than that, really."
Catching Milat, Seven,  (to be confirmed)

The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wattle Grove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merv Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Milat</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sins of the Brother</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennard/Milat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Whittaker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chalinder Hughes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Backpacker Murders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Milat</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Les Kennedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mal Kennard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catching Milat</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y-fronts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kennards</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagle Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
