<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415883256067561</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/youth-homelessness-is-australias-national-disgrace-with-44000-kids-sleeping-rough-right-now/news-story/fe6bbcfa9dd1be01f221e0c00bfed52e</url>
  <title>Youth homelessness is Australia's national disgrace, with 44,000 kids sleeping rough right now</title>
  <content>
Why are so many Aussie kids homeless?
0:38

Mental illness and family conflict put young people at significantly higher risk of homelessness in Australia, a new report has found.

August 3rd 2017
6 hours ago

A new report by Mission Australia released today identifies the major risk factors that lead to 44,000 youth without a safe place to sleep.

Shannon MolloyNews Corp Australia Network

Share

YOUNG people with a mental illness are three times more likely to wind up homeless, after which their prospects of positive health and social outcomes dwindle significantly.
A new report by the  will be released today, identifying the major risk factors that leave 44,000 young people without a safe place to sleep.
It paints a picture of a national crisis that  every year - much more than governments spend on tackling the problem, experts say.
"It is unacceptable in 21st century Australia that there are (so many)  on any given night," Mission Australia chief Catherine Yeoman said.
"They deserve a safe home and we have the means to provide it. All that is needed is the political will and the commitment from us all as a community."

There are an estimated 44,000 homeless people under the age of 25 in Australia, representing about half of all people without a safe space to sleep. Picture: ThinkstockSource:News Limited
Young people with a probable mental illness are 3.5 times more likely to have spent time away from home and twice as likely to have done so on six or more occasions, the report found.
"The link between homelessness and mental health among young people works in both directions," Ms Yeoman said.
"Young people who are experiencing mental illness are at increased risk of homelessness, while those who are homeless are at increased risk of mental illness."
In addition, almost half of all those surveyed - some 17,000 in total - who had slept rough reported high levels of concern about family conflict.

Those two risks combined presented a double whammy, Ms Yeoman said, with a staggering 57 per cent of young people with mental illnesses and family instability experiencing homelessness.

Young people with a probable mental illness are 3.5 times more likely to experience homelessness, a new report has found.Source:News Limited
"Couch surfing is often the first way young people experience homelessness," she said.
"We know that (many) adolescents stay for short periods of time on couches, floors or in other insecure housing situations ... with relatives or friends."
Those who spend time away from home are much more likely to battle depression and be at risk of suicide, the report identified.

Source:Supplied
The organisation  said the longer someone spends on the streets, the more likely they are to develop severe and persistent mental health problems.
And youth who experience long periods of time away from home are likely to remain homeless without the right support.

Those who spend time away from home are much more likely to battle depression and be at risk of suicide.Source:News Corp Australia
boss Jo Swift said the long-term consequences of youth homelessness were widespread.
"It's just not about a roof overhead - it's about having a stable and secure place to call home, it's about having a solid foundation ... the support, security and care they need to explore their potential and become happy, healthy and productive members of society," Ms Swift said.
Young people who sleep rough for long periods are less likely to stay engaged with school and employment, she said.
They are also more likely to experience substance abuse, poor nutrition and unhealthy social behaviour.

Family conflict is another major risk factor when it comes to youth homelessness.Source:News Limited
Taking action isn't just the right thing to do, Ms Swift said, but it also makes economic sense.
Independent analysis has shown that in many cases, every dollar spent on intervention and support initiatives had a two to threefold return in benefit.

The cost of youth homelessness

Ahead of , which kicks off next Monday, Ms Yeoman called on governments to reach a bipartisan commitment to halving youth homelessness rates by 2020.
"This issue is closer to us than we like to think. Young people at risk often go unnoticed and don't receive the early help they need to prevent future homelessness."
If you are a young person who needs help or you know someone who does, call Kids Helpline on 1800 55 1800 or Headspace on 1800 650 890.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Yeoman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mission Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon MolloyNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Catherine Yeomans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jo Swift</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Swift</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Limited</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kids Helpline</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ThinkstockSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
