<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416140954110412</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/rugby-league/canterbury-bulldogs/des-hasler-has-five-games-to-save-his-job-as-bulldogs-coach-20170802-gxo0eq.html</url>
  <title>Des Hasler has five games to save his job as Bulldogs coach</title>
  <content>
Des Hasler has five matches to save his skin at the Bulldogs. It's that simple.
This is the unspoken task at hand for the Canterbury coach and board, starting with 1980s arch-rivals Parramatta at ANZ Stadium on Thursday night.

Up Next

Cherry-Evans: Defence the issue for Manly

00:43

More Rugby League Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Panthers pile more misery on Hasler

The Bulldogs season is all but over after Penrith ground out a 16-8 win.

Bulldogs chairman Ray Dib is adamant Hasler will not be terminated any sooner than that, despite a torrent of criticism from his members and annoying white noise from other factions wanting to seize control of the club at next February's board elections.
"We won't be making any rash decisions at all," Dib told Fairfax Media. "We do an extensive and thorough review at the end of every season and this one will be no different. We will want to know what has gone wrong."Photo: AAP
Sooner or later, something will have to give at Belmore: coach or board?
Hasler hasn't been told he must win all remaining matches, or even some of the matches, to ensure he sees out the remaining two seasons of his contract, which was only extended four months ago.
When he fronted the board last week, hard questions were asked but he was essentially given support. If ever there was a time for solidarity, this is it.

You will now receive updates from

League HQ Newsletter

League HQ Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

But everyone involved at the Bulldogs - including Hasler - has been around long enough to know the score: a poor showing in the final month of the home-and-away season will likely end in Hasler's sacking, regardless of what the payout figure is.Photo: AAP
Parramatta are flying right now but after that the Bulldogs face South Sydney, Manly, Gold Coast and St George Illawarra - four sides that are hardly banging down the door as the finals approach.
Unfortunately, Hasler's side is nowhere near the door. Not even in the same suburb as the door. Given the Bulldogs' inconsistency, they are no certainty of singing the victory song again this year.
While the coach must wear the results, and certainly the mind-numbing attack that puts old men to sleep in the stands, the board must wear the blame for the sickness that's taken over.
When Penrith bundled the Bulldogs out in the first week of the finals last year, the look of disgust on the faces of some directors at the NRL's official function said it all.
With Hasler off contract at the end of 2017, this was the perfect time to make their move. Get rid of the coach in October and usher in a new one, whether it's Dean Pay, Jim Dymock ... or Ivan Cleary.
The alternative was to start looking like the Wests Tigers.
Instead, the board took the easier option of waiting to see how the side performed under Hasler in the early stages of the 2017 season. The Bulldogs lost two of their first five with the constant speculation about Hasler's future already strangling their season.
Something had to give: coach or players?
Hasler was re-signed and a player clean-out was under way. Favourite son Josh Reynolds was shoved out the door to the Tigers. Kieran Foran and Aaron Woods were snapped up.
Listen to the detractors and they will tell you the Bulldogs' eyeballs are about to pop out because the salary cap pressure is so intense.
In reality, other clubs are also struggling to make the cap fit following news it will be $9.2 million next season instead of the $10 million some have been working from.
This column understands Woods has assured the Bulldogs he's still coming, despite mounting speculation he'll backflip and stay at the Tigers. Foran has declared publicly he will be at Belmore next year, whether Hasler is there or not.
What about the players? Has Des lost the dressing room, as they say?
Publicly, they back him. Privately, there are a few murmurs. "They either love him or they are scared of him," is how one describes it.
Dib is close to Roosters chairman Nick Politis and his philosophy has always been succinct, "Losing is bad for business, baby".
The Dogs' crowds are down. So, too, memberships and merchandise sales. The football club posted a $1.25 million loss last year and are headed for a similar result this year.
Meanwhile, the knives are out.
In his new role as Fox Sports analyst, former Bulldogs hooker Mick Ennis called for Hasler to be sacked and questioned the signing of Woods.
They were strong words, although some point out that Ennis was bitter when Hasler refused to re-sign him two years ago. He's also great mates with Reynolds.
For some, junior development is as much a concern as recruitment and retention. Of the NSW under-16s, 18s and 20s sides that beat Queensland this year, none of them featured a Bulldogs junior.
Yet that loud barking you keep hearing in the background comes from familiar places. Namely, a few disaffected members who have been vocal on social media and select radio programs prepared to give them as much air-time as they want.
Former Bulldogs prop Paul Dunn is expected to run a ticket against Dib at February's board elections, but some are already scoffing at the suggestion a coup is on the cards.
The football club has 900-or-so voting members. It will take a well-organised and funded campaign from a strong, powerful group to oust Dib.
The campaign against him is already heating up. Someone recently posted his business card, which included his mobile number, on a Bulldogs fansite.
He brushed off the anonymous abuse but reverted to an old number after he lost his phone during a trip to Lebanon.
Dib remains a highly influential character who has risen above the nepotism and politics that have dogged Canterbury in the past. They were applauded for snatching Hasler from Manly less than a week after he won the premiership in 2011.
Now, he and his board have an important job at hand if they remain in power.
The Bulldogs have a heaving leagues club that tips in $4 million of funding a year. They will never die as long as water is still flowing through that massive waterfall out the front.
But just as we keep hearing this week that rugby league needs a strong and thriving Parramatta, the same must be said of Canterbury.
Along with the Eels, Souths and the Dragons, it's considered one of the most valued brands in the game.
It's been damaged this season.
The easy option for the Bulldogs would be to sack the coach now. It won't happen. Perhaps in five matches. Five matches.
By then, something will have to give.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canterbury</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Cleary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Woods</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Des Hasler</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League HQ Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lebanon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PAUL DUNN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hasler</name>
    <count>14</count>
    <score>-12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Roosters</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Politis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dragons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panther</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wests Tigers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St George Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ennis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran Foran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penrith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray Dib</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parramatta</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim Dymock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherry-Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dean Pay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DIB</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mick Ennis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby League Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foran</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Belmore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bulldogs</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANZ Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manly</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
