<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415887551034981</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/home-with-decked-out-man-cave-to-be-auctioned-this-weekend/news-story/ec57b94d27030c15a51f9e2477bfc5db</url>
  <title>Home with decked out man cave to be auctioned this weekend - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Check out this super rad man cave at 15 Justin Street, Holland Park West.

A four-bedroom, two-bathroom home at Holland Park West with a super rad man cave is set to sell under the hammer this weekend.

15 Justin Street, Holland Park West.

15 Justin Street, Holland Park West.

The property at , is perfectly suited for a stylish family that loves to entertain.
Professionals Style Real Estate - Brisbane selling agent Peter Elisseos said the property came with a man cave, however the Harley Davidson motorbike was not included in the sale.

15 Justin Street, Holland Park West.

Mr Elisseos said the home had the perfect fusion of art deco elegance with a modern twist.
Other features of the home include a deck and low maintenance garden.
The property goes to auction at 11am on Saturday.

36 Tingal Rd, Wynnum.

After 85 years in the one family, this two-bedroom, one-bathroom home at will go to auction.
The property, which features VJ walls and ceilings, original window hoods and a bathroom with an original cast iron bath, goes under the hammer at 10am on Saturday.

36 Tingal Rd, Wynnum.

36 Tingal Rd, Wynnum.

36 Tingal Rd, Wynnum.

Century 21 selling agent Nina Adams said: "This centrally positioned local treasure is in need of a buyer who is prepared to sink their teeth into this unique opportunity".
The home on this property was moved to the current location from the Wynnum North area some time between 1910 and 1920.

14 Zeehan St, Wavell Heights.

The owners of  are investors and want to sell their property so they can fund the build of their family home.
Ray White Albion selling agent Kylee Dallimore said the property, which goes to auction at 9am on Saturday, could be renovated, demolished to rebuild a dream home or kept as an investment.

14 Zeehan St, Wavell Heights.

The property is on a 668sq m block of land and within walking distance to cafes, shops and cycling tracks.

10 Lugg St, Bardon.

After five years at the owners have decided to downsize.
SPACE Property Agents selling agent Nick Penklis said the five-bedroom, three-bathroom home was a family-friendly home in an ideal location.

10 Lugg St, Bardon.

Mr Penklis said the couple had three daughters, and their eldest Riley, had been accepted to attend Parsons School of Design in New York.
He said the couple once used the top level for their office/Au Pair which they have no need for any more.

10 Lugg St, Bardon.

Mr Penklis said what he loved about property, on a 551sq m block, was the surprise on buyers faces when they came inside.
"The front exterior is fairly modest and offers no reflection of the size and open-plan styling," he said.
"The oversized ground level living with polished concrete flooring is the best."
Outside there is a saltwater swimming pool, while a grassy area at the back provides enough space to rear chickens, jump on a trampoline or grow veggies.
The property goes to auction at 10am on Saturday.

9 Halland Terrace, Camp Hill.

This home at has been enjoyed by the current owners for the past eight years.
The four-bedroom, three-bathroom home is spread across two levels with a choice of living areas featuring polished timber floors upstairs and easy-care tiles downstairs.
Ray White - Stones Corner selling agent Ben Cannon said the owners liked the area so much they had not moved far to their new home.

9 Halland Terrace, Camp Hill.

9 Halland Terrace, Camp Hill.

Mr Cannon said the property was about 10 years old and was built by Bruce Bell, a local well known builder.
"The home offers easy access to local schools and city public transport," he said.
The property goes to auction at 10am on Saturday.

19 Picasso Cres, Bridgeman Downs.

This two-storey home at is on a 2561sq m allotment.
The six-bedroom, three-bathroom a tennis court and swimming pool.
Ray White Bridgeman Downs selling agent Sonya Treloar said: "This impressive and stately home would suit a large family, blended family or those looking for additional parental living".
The property goes to auction at 10am on Saturday.

36 Needham St, Fig Tree Pocket

At noon on Saturday, former Linc Energy founder Peter Bond's grand property at will go under the hammer.
Known as "Rivergum Retreat", the seven-bedroom, nine-bathroom property allows easy accommodation for large functions, entertaining or decadent intimate gatherings.

36 Needham St, Fig Tree Pocket.

36 Needham St, Fig Tree Pocket

The property has a climate-controlled wine cellar, fully equipped gym, a boardroom, meeting rooms, gold class cinema, a horizon heated swimming pool complete with outdoor teppanyaki bar, a championship size tennis court, and water sports facilities.
Linc Energy went into liquidation in May 2016 with $320 million in debt.
Ray White - New Farm selling agent Matt Lancashire has marketed the property as an "irreplaceable opportunity".
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Bridgeman Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VJ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Needham St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nina Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stones Corner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Elisseos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holland Park West</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zeehan St</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Lancashire</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Cannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ray White Albion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Penklis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Bell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bardon</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justin Street</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wavell Heights</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Bond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tingal Rd</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Penklis</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wynnum</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kylee Dallimore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linc Energy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wynnum North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Parsons School of Design</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Agents</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sonya Treloar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Halland Terrace</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Elisseos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Cannon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bridgeman Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Au Pair</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Picasso Cres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Style Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Hill</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harley Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lugg St</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rivergum Retreat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fig Tree Pocket</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
