<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415887551034904</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/moreton/the-masters-building-at-north-lakes-on-track-to-become-giant-home-retail-complex/news-story/746034f7ceb9310d5ec5465d34b2b20f</url>
  <title>Masters site rebirth in works</title>
  <content>
The former Masters Home Improvement site at North Lakes may be given a new lease on life in the near future, with the prospect of more jobs for the area.
Moreton Bay Regional Council has received an application for a material change of use to convert the building into a multi-tenant complex specialising in "domestic retail goods".
The application was from Urbis, on behalf of the Home Investment Consortium Com-pany, which acquired the Masters property portfolio.
The proposed use includes consolidating national retail brands within a multi-tenant large format with a focus on homemaker-style uses and supporting domestic retail wholesale goods.
"(It) proposes a series of physical changes to the existing building to facilitate the proposed repurposing and rebranding of the store by Home Consortium," the application stated.
"(It) seeks to fully reactivate a currently disused building and provide significant local employment opportunities."
A Home Consortium spokesman said the company would make an announcement on its plans later this month.
A council spokeswoman confirmed the council received the application for the Masters site on June 27.
"The application is currently in the information -response phase of the assessment, with the applicant to provide a response to council's request for further information issued on July 19," she said.
Further information regarding this approval is publicly available via the council's planning and development online tool.
Changes to the building include:
■ Filling in the roof above the current Masters garden centre
■ Internal fit-outs for tenancies (various sizes and configurations) and creation of a central mall
■ Creation of a cafe tenancy and associated seating area
■ New loading areas and associated service corridors
■ Creation of a new entry awning
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Consortium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Lakes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masters</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Urbis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masters Home Improvement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Home Investment Consortium Com-pany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
