<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414977017951864</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/617665/shoalhaven-jets-centre-of-racial-vilification-complaint/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Shoalhaven Jets centre of racial vilification complaint</title>
  <content>
Group Seven is preparing to hear two racial vilification cases after the Bay and Basin Sharks lodged an official complaint in relation to Sunday's drama-charged game against Shoalhaven.The round-10 match finished amid ugly and frightening scenes as furious Bay and Basin supporters tried to surround Shoalhaven second-rower Adam Tracey, the player at the centre of the allegations.Jets captain-coach Geoff Johnson said Tracey denied making a racial slur. His team-mates were forced to form a protective circle around Tracey as both teams walked to the dressing sheds after the game.Tracey then jumped into a car parked beside the sheds and made a hasty exit from the ground.Calm was eventually restored and the angry mob moved on without violence erupting.But the Sharks were still fuming yesterday and are demanding Group Seven takes action.Bay and Basin second-rower Kieran Stewart is the player who claimed to be the victim of the alleged racial slur, which took the gloss off Shoalhaven's comeback victory.Stewart wrote a formal statement on Sunday night, which Bay and Basin president Kim Lynch faxed to Group Seven headquarters.Stewart alleged he was called a "black c..." by Tracey after the pair became entangled late in the match.The pair was sin-binned and tensions escalated as they left the field when a mother of a Sharks player alleged she was also racially abused."That's when the situation became inflamed off the field," Lynch said."One of the players heard what was allegedly said to his mum and he went troppo."Group Seven is already dealing with a racial discrimination case involving the Sharks.On May 30, Bay and Basin's reserve-grade clash with Jamberoo erupted in an all-in-brawl after Superoos centre Jamie Parrish allegedly called Sharks hooker Doug Seymour a "black c...", an incident which has left Seymour facing a raft of charges and a possible 23-week ban. A hearing for the reserve-grade melee is scheduled for Thursday night."The club is very concerned that this is the second alleged case of racial abuse in two weeks," Lynch said. "The whole thing has to be nipped in the bud so it doesn't happen again."Group Seven general manager Jim McAuliffe said Sunday's incident would most likely be dealt with in a fortnight."Group Seven takes this issue very seriously and we'll certainly be looking to get to the bottom of it," McAuliffe said."We'll be seeking an explanation from the Shoalhaven Jets club on the alleged incident and what the ground official saw, and it will be followed up as per Country Rugby League due process."Racial vilification is absolutely unacceptable in Group Seven. It has no place in society, let alone a football field."The matter will be thoroughly investigated and if either of the allegations prove to be true, the appropriate punishment will be handed down."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven Jets</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superoos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharks.On May 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Lynch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McAuliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Country Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basin Sharks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Tracey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tracey</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Johnson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seymour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Parrish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doug Seymour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shoalhaven</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group Seven</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Basin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamberoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jim McAuliffe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
