<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415883256067589</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/amazon-echo-dot-sleep-sounds-alexa-skill-2017-8</url>
  <title>My favourite Alexa skill has made the $50 Echo Dot worth every penny</title>
  <content>
For the last two months, I've been living with five new roommates: Four guys, and an Amazon Echo Dot.

The Dot was something of a housewarming present purchased by my boyfriend when I moved in at the end of May, and it lives nestled on the bedside table. While I've only been living with the Dot for a short time, I've already found my favourite way to use the device: Sleep Sounds.

is an Alexa skill that's free to enable on any Alexa-enabled device. The skill essentially acts as a white-noise machine, playing sounds like cicadas, frogs, city rain, and grandfather clock.

My personal favourite is thunderstorms, which provides a soothing backdrop of steady rain and rolling thunder as I sleep.

Alexa has  in all, and I've only sampled a few. In the months and years to come, I look forward to testing out all the device has to offer and getting used to having another computer in my home. Right now, I'm just slowly working on getting used to talking to Alexa and having her handle basic tasks for me. (Yes, I call it a "her." I live with four guys, it's nice to have some female company!)

But for now, I couldn't be more satisfied with the Dot acting as a white-noise machine. Sure, there are cheaper machines on the market, and I've tried a  that I loved. But the Dot is small and unobtrusive, sounds good, and I can activate Sleep Sounds from bed (or even from across the room) with a simple phrase.

For $US50, you get what you pay for - along with  of owning an Alexa device.

NOW WATCH: Tech Insider videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexa</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexa-enabled</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Echo Dot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Echo Dot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sleep Sounds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
