<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415449464363419</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/markets/dow-22000-can-trump-take-credit-20170802-gxo6gz</url>
  <title>Dow 22,000: can Trump take credit?</title>
  <content>
The Dow Jones Industrial Average briefly topped 22,000 points for the first time in history in the United States and President Donald Trump quickly took credit for the milestone.
But most investors and analysts argue Mr Trump is no longer the driving force behind the bull market rally like he was soon after the November election.
Rather, better US corporate earnings and a steadily improving global economy are the chief factors propelling stocks higher, taking the baton from the post-election "Trump bump".
Nevertheless, President Trump was happy to bask in the glory.

"Today the stock market hit the highest level that it has ever been and our country is doing very well," Mr Trump said overnight.

Earnings growth for the S&P 500 is on track for a robust 9.7 per cent year-over-year pace for the second quarter according to FactSet, following a 15 per cent surge in the March quarter.
Of the 300 or so US-listed companies that have reported June quarter earnings, about 73 per cent have beaten consensus expectations.
The Dow's outperformance against the S&P 500 is evidence that the accelerating global economy is helping fuel the rally on Wall Street.
The 30-stock Dow Jones is up 10.9 per cent since President Trump was inaugurated on January 20.

The broader S&P 500 is 8.7 per cent higher and has been virtually flat over the past two weeks of earnings season.
Boeing, McDonald's and Apple

The Dow is dominated by large multinational companies with a higher-than-average share of international earnings.
Airline maker Boeing, fast food chain McDonald's and iphone maker Apple have been three of the four largest points contributors to the Dow's surge from 21,000 on March 1 to 22,000 this week.

Certainly, President Trump's pro-business attitude has boosted consumer and business confidence. The Dow has surged 20 per cent in the nine months since his shock election victory.
His planned tax cuts, deregulation, higher defence spending and infrastructure investment initially helped lift stocks.
But investors have more recently largely discounted most of these policies being implemented, because of the Republican-controlled Congress's failure to overhaul healthcare.
The less optimistic view on government stimulus is reflected in an unwinding of the Trump reflation trade. The US dollar index has dropped to a 15-month low and the 10-year US Treasury yield has retreated to 2.25 per cent from a post-election high of 2.6 per cent.

The International Monetary Fund is  is on track to grow 3.5 per cent in 2017, even though it slashed US growth prospects in July to 2.1 per cent due to US fiscal policy looking likely to be less expansionary than it believed soon after President Trump took office.
US GDP rebounded to a robust 2.6 per cent in the second quarter, after a disappointing 1.4 per cent in the first quarter - an average of 2 per cent in the first half of the year under President Trump.
GDP, employment and wages are holding at around the growth levels recorded by president Barack Obama during his final years in office.
Valuations 'stretched', says Wells Fargo

Robert Shiller's cyclically-adjusted price-to-earnings (CAPE) ratio, a closely watched stock valuation measure, has only ever been higher twice - in the late 1990s before the dotcom bubble burst and before the Great Depression of the 1930s.
Wells Fargo Investment Institute senior global equity strategist Scott Wren says stock valuations are "stretched" and investors should be ready for a market pullback.
"We're looking for a five to eight per cent pullback between now and the end of the year," he said.
"Besides the valuation situation you're in a Fed hike cycle which is a headwind and really a lack of fiscal progress in Washington which I don't think is going to change any time soon."
Investors are keeping a watchful eye out for the looming political showdown over lifting the federal government's $US20 trillion debt ceiling by late September.
There could also be market upside if President Trump can surprise by overcoming Congress inaction to enact a larger-than-anticipated corporate tax cut by the end of 2017.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Wren</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>International Monetary Fund</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Shiller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boeing</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wells Fargo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Treasuries</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>P 500</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FactSet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fargo Investment Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow Jones Industrial Average</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican-controlled Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GDP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Depression</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow 22,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
