<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415930500708729</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/data-reveals-baking-board-as-queenslands-most-ordinary-town/8767304</url>
  <title>Census 2016: Data reveals Baking Board as Queensland's most 'ordinary' town</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A tiny locality of 97 people on Queensland's Western Downs is home to the highest percentage of "ordinary" Australians in the country, according to census data.
So what is an ordinary Australian?
An  has revealed the proportion of people sharing the most common demographic characteristics is shrinking and the ordinary Australian is something of a rarity.
A typical Australian ticks the following boxes:

Are you an 'ordinary' Australian?

You speak only English at home
You were born in Australia
Your parents were born in Australia
You're Christian
Your family has English ancestry
You're in a registered marriage
You live with your spouse and two children
Your home is a free-standing, three-bedroom house, which you own with a mortgage
You have two cars
Your family income is $2,000-$2,999 a week (or $104,000-$129,999 a year)

These were the most common answers (known in statistics as the "mode") to key questions in the 2016 census.
Australia's most and least 'ordinary' suburbs

The analysis reveals the rural locality of Baking Board, on the Western Downs, 300 kilometres north-west of Brisbane, is home to the most ordinary people in the country, on a percentage basis.
In a population of 97, there are three.
Its close rival is the NSW town of Boomanoomana, 100 kilometres west of Albury, which also counts three ordinary Australians among its 99 residents.

Queensland in a snapshot:

Queensland has the second highest percentage of "typical" Australians, after Tasmania
Baking Board ties with Boomanoomana in New South Wales as the places with the most 'ordinary' Australians
Kullogum, inland from Hervey Bay is the second most "ordinary" with three in 118 residents filling the criteria
Anthony, south of Ipswich in the south-east is the most Christian, with 86 per cent of people identifying as such
77 per cent of people in Rush Creek, in the Moreton Bay region, are married
South Ripley near Ipswich is representative of the 'typical income' with more than 20 per cent of families earning $104,000-$129,999 a year.

The nation's most ordinary town used to have a pub, a rail siding, a graveyard and a town centre.
But over the years people and business have moved away, leaving dirt roads, a few home-based businesses and a community of young and old property owners, farmers and retirees.
Gathered around coffee and scones at Baking Board resident Glenn Beasley's dining table, a group of locals discussed their unique statistical claim to fame.

"Some of our friends had doubts but at least now it's confirmed statistically. We are ordinary," Mr Beasley joked.
Saddler Cliff Killeen said trying to find the ordinary Australian had no purpose.
"We've got 10 people here," he said, gesturing around the dining table.
"Every one of us would have a different lifestyle and have different interests and have different perspectives."
'We have no intention to leave'

Life seems pretty ordinary for the Gray family, which lives in Baking Board but runs a business in the nearby town of Chinchilla.
Jason Gray, his wife Sheerie and young son Fox are descendants of one of Baking Board's founding families.
"We're an old family, been here four generations.
"This is the fifth generation," Mr Gray said, gesturing to his son Fox.
"We had no intention to leave, we love it.

External Link:

Baking Board map
"We wanted to bring our kids up here and that's what we've done," he said.
Despite being part of Baking Board history Jason doesn't tick the English ancestry box.
"My mother migrated from the Philippines 40 years ago when she met my dad and all that. That's what gives me my good looks," he laughed.
When asked what ordinary Australia meant to them, Ms Gray said it wasn't clear.
"Ordinary Australian today ... it's sort of..." she says, before Jason cuts in.
"What's ordinary?" he asked.
"It's a big term," Ms Gray said.
A 'microcosm' of the national picture

The statistics suggest that while having Australian-English heritage, two children, two cars and a mortgaged home makes you the typical Australian, just 6,000 people in Australia fulfil all the criteria.

So does the country's most ordinary town feel that way?
Mr Beasley said he had spent the last several years trying to ward off a coal seam gas industry waste dump set to be built adjacent to his property.
He said the mining industry had surrounded Baking Board.
"If we were to stand on Baking Board hill we would be able to look to the west and at night time we would see the lights of Cameby Downs coal mine.
"If we were to look to the east we would see the silhouette of Kogan Creek Power Station.
"On the south we would see the start of a solar farm."
"In many ways while we are a microcosm in ourselves we are also typical of what's happening nationally," Mr Beasley said.
Video by  and
Data notes: For privacy reasons, the Australian Bureau of Statistics introduces small random errors to Census data. This can reduce the reliability of small numbers and produce minor discrepancies in totals and subtotals.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saddler Cliff Killeen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kullogum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moreton Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Downs, 300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Beasley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baking Board</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland's Western Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Ripley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rush Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kogan Creek Power Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boomanoomana</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Grey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameby Downs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian-English</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hervey Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinchilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines 40</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ipswich</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheerie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Bureau of Statistics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beasley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Census 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Gray</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
