<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651414981312919209</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>16:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/postmates-driver-leaves-threatening-letter-for-customer-who-didnt-tip-2017-8</url>
  <title>'I'm probably gonna rob you': Furious pizza delivery driver leaves 4-page letter on the doorstep of customer who didn't tip</title>
  <content>
A delivery driver with Postmates threatened to "rob" a woman after she failed to leave him a $US4 tip on a $US20 pizza order.

found a four-page letter on her doorstep in Redondo Beach, California, after she didn't leave a tip for a Postmates driver who had delivered a pizza to her home the week before.

In the letter, the driver threatened to come back and rob Ledford if she does not tip in future.

"I'm only joking, but not really. Don't risk it though. Who knows what a disgruntled delivery driver who can't afford to eat that day is capable of," the letter read.

He then went on to make racist and derogatory comments about women and claimed that he was "high."

Ledford, who describes herself as a model on her Facebook page, posted the letter to social media after complaining that , an app that connects independent delivery drivers and couriers to customers to order almost anything - from restaurant meals to groceries - had not addressed the issue or called her back.

Ledford wrote  that she thought a tip was included in the delivery charges that had been added to her order by Postmates.
She also confirmed that the order was indeed booked via Postmates, since this was the only pizza delivery she had received in the past two months.
In the letter, the driver identified himself as a man and confirms that he had delivered pizza to her house the week before.

Postmates confirmed to Business Insider that it had suspended the driver and contacted Ledford personally to apologise. The company said that all of its contracted drivers go through background checks.

Ledford contacted local police to get a restraining order, but Postmates has refused to release the driver's full identity.

"It's really scary knowing that they have suddenly cut this man's income off and will not help to ensure my protection from this psycho," Ledford wrote on her Facebook page.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Redondo Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Postmates</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ledford</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Furious</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Business Insider</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
