<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415621263058080</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/questnews/logan/landlords-v-tenants-in-battle-for-free-tip-vouchers/news-story/4520168a4cd1e1b455d4b150630f7ad5</url>
  <title>Who should get free tip vouchers?</title>
  <content>
THE  rights of the humble Logan renter were championed at a Logan City Council committee meeting last week when landlords were told to hand over their free tip vouchers to tenants.
Division 3 Cr Steve Swensen postured whether it would be beneficial to send all residential addresses tip vouchers rather than just mailing them to ratepayers.
"We have quite a number of owners who own multiple properties who don't pass on the tip vouchers and I guess that's up to them ... But the challenge we have is we have one kerbside collection for the whole city and we have residents who are renting properties who never see a tip voucher," he said.
Division 4's Laurie Koranski and Division 2's Russell Lutton, both landlords, opposed the idea. Both councillors said they deserved to get the vouchers as they were paying the rates.
But Division 5's Cr Jon Raven said tenants were paying the price for keeping rental properties tidy and there were issues with strata-titled properties.
"The challenge with sending vouchers to the properties is that some ... have 50 dwellings at the site but it is still only considered one property in the rating system," he said. "Council's system is blind to this."
Cr Raven said those living in high-density units or townhouses were less likely to need tip vouchers but should still be able to get access to the tip if needed.
The issue arose after a question about vouchers for those who received their rates notices by email.
Crestmead homeowner Cherie Massey said landlords should share vouchers with tenants. "Tenants have to maintain the properties," she said.
An officer told the meeting this year's vouchers were posted in July but, next year, a separate mailing system would allow vouchers to be sent to ratepayers registered under email addresses.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>LOGAN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Koranski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Jon Raven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Logan City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr Raven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crestmead</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cherie Massey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russell Lutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Division 3 Cr Steve Swensen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
