<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415638442927488</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:13</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/mountains-of-charity-offered-to-paramedics-familie/3207769/</url>
  <title>Mountains of charity offered to paramedics' families</title>
  <content>
HE HAS overcome cancer, started his own charity, trekked some of the world's tallest mountains and works as a paramedic saving lives.
Some might call Rhys Greedy an everyday superhero.
Now the 29-year-old is taking on yet another venture with the goal of raising more than $10,000 for the families of Queensland Ambulance Service employees who have lost their lives while still employed by the QAS. If you need any more inspiration to donate to his cause, Rhys will be trekking Mera Peak's 6476m this November in Nepal - a feat he hopes to achieve in 10 days.
"When you consider that Mt Coolum is only 220m, it puts it well and truly into perspective," Rhys said.
"The training I need to do is almost stone-age, focusing on building the legs and the lungs. We will fly out on October 29, land in Kathmandu and within 16 hours we will be on the mountain.
"Luckily the nerves don't really kick in until you're flying over the peak of the mountain and see it poking through the cloud line - that's when you have a little moment of panic."
This time, Rhys's overseas adventure will coincide with The Nomadic Chefs Table fundraiser at CORB-NS on August 9.
He said combining an overseas challenge with a fund-raising event was a way to tick things off his own bucket list while doing so for a cause.
"Every time I do something like this, I reflect back to 2009 which was such a dark year for me," Rhys said. "I was 21 when I was diagnosed with Hodgkin's Lymphoma and it was a scary period in my life.
"I set up Peak4Paramedics so I can kick my own goals while helping others."
CORB-NS co-owner and head chef Sam Pregnell said The Nomadic Chefs Table events had been set up 18 months ago as a way to support local charities and bring some of the Coast's best chefs together for a fun night in the kitchen.
"This will be event number eight and so far we have raised over $30,000 for different charities," he said.
"We really want to reach the $40,000 mark with this event, especially because the cause is close to our hearts: our mother is a paramedic."
The Nomadic Chefs table will cater to up to 70 people, feature five courses including a vegetarian dish, seafood dish, white meat dish, red meat dish and dessert.
The event will be held at CORB-NS at 34 Duporth Ave, Maroochydore, from 6pm on August 9.
Cost is $90 per person including a five-course dinner and drink on arrival.
Visit gofundme.com/peak4 paramedics and www.corbins.com.au
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mera Peak's 6476</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Pregnell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CORB-NS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nomadic Chefs Table</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 9</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peak4Paramedics</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhys</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Ambulance Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kathmandu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nomadic Chefs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duporth Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hodgkin Lymphoma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhys Greedy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nepal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
