<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415668507699114</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:20</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/cairns/wearecairns-exhibition-celebrates-age-gender-and-religious-diversity/news-story/92a54e1dbb064003bec42c0e3400335c</url>
  <title>Picture yourself as part of exhibition</title>
  <content>
IF a man walked up to you, introduced himself as Regular Rick and took your photo in the last 12 months, chances are you're featured in the #wearecairns exhibition.
The collaboration between Centacare and Regular Rick, also known as artist Ricky Beresford, is a comment on age, gender and religious diversity in Cairns.
"Within the exhibition there's just under 1000 Cairns residents represented. It's been an effort," Beresford said.
"In some cases the people are the subject of the artworks, and in other cases they actually made the artwork."
He said the representation of Cairns' diversity was hung on every wall at Tank 4 and would also be projected and sung about.
"There's a celebration of cultural difference in the exhibition, there's a representation of age, our youngest participant was 18 months and our oldest was just short of 90," he said.
"There's a music component ... the idea was world music from your own backyard. There's also film that celebrates movement in Cairns, we filmed 120 dancers."
#wearecairns opens with a free event at 6pm tomorrow night at the Tanks Arts Centre.
The exhibition will run until Tuesday, August 22.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beresford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tank 4</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centacare</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ricky Beresford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tanks Arts Centre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regular Rick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
