<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415634147960137</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/we-had-to-resign-if-we-wanted-to-have-children/3207267/</url>
  <title>We had to resign if we wanted to have children</title>
  <content>
I WAS a fresh-faced 17-year-old when I first joined Nambour General Hospital.
In 1976, I became a nurse in the 40-bed medical ward (2A) in Block 1. Today I am a nurse manager, based in the very room where I attended my job interview: the matron's office.
When I first joined Nambour General Hospital, I worked as a registered nurse in the medical ward for 12 months then moved to the surgical ward which consisted of 30 surgical beds and 10 paediatric beds.
In those days, there were no staff in the Emergency Department (ED) and the registered nurse in the Surgical Ward had to answer the ED buzzer, leave the ward and process the patient or patients in ED.
In the 1970s, patients had a much longer stay in hospital than they do now. Of course, the techniques and equipment used in procedures are now much more sophisticated, providing for a much faster recovery.
One of the biggest changes from a nurse's perspective is all the consumables (instruments, bandages etc) that are now disposable because it's safer for our patients. Back in 1976, everything was sterilised.
Of course, maternity leave did not exist when I first began my career. So in December 1977, I had to resign from my position to have children. By May 1978, I was put on the casual "on call" list and stayed as a casual, working at least one or two shifts a week until 1984.

As the hospital became busier the Matron employed additional staff to manage the facility after hours. The position of night supervisor was created and I worked two nights a week as permanent part-time from September 1984. As the hospital further expanded, the supervisor role gradually went to 24 hours a day.
Over the years, I've seen many changes in nursing. The training of registered nurses has changed from being hospital-based to university-based. When I first began my career, nurses used to stay in the nurses' quarters, although this was gradually phased out.
The nurses at Nambour General have always been excellent and very patient-focused. The rapid growth of the Sunshine Coast region has meant we have had to grow to keep up with this demand.
Medical science has also gone ahead in leaps and bounds. We now have greater ability to prolong the life of the community but this is also bringing the challenge of caring for an ageing population.
I have loved every minute of my time as a nurse. I always loved the clinical aspect and the patient contact and now in my present role, I feel I am looking after the nurses who are looking after the patients and helping to provide the skill mix and nursing ratios needed to have the best outcome for the patients.
The transition to Sunshine Coast University Hospital (SCUH) has been amazing for our health service.
I have remained at Nambour General Hospital but see SCUH as a great move for the future of health care on the Sunshine Coast. It has amazing equipment and a great education facility in the Sunshine Coast Health Institute.
IT'S all in the eye of the beholder.
Skilled migrant speaks out about employment difficulties
A NEW centre has opened in Nambour to help kids in care.
THE community support has been overwhelming.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
The brief ads tease that the beloved mother-daughter duo "are back".
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surgical Ward</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 1978</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour General Hospital</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1984</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Block 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 1977</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Health Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
