<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415844601361172</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/rugby-union/union-news/wallabies-skipper-michael-hooper-claims-he-was-surprised-by-fulltime-role-20170802-gxnzj6.html</url>
  <title>Michael Hooper surprised by Wallabies captaincy, wants to strengthen team culture</title>
  <content>
Returning Wallabies captain Michael Hooper says he was surprised by the news of his full-time appointment and wants to create a team culture where players are "willing to die to get the job done".
In the wake of news last week that Stephen Moore will retire from international rugby at the end of the Test season, the Wallabies confirmed on Wednesday that Hooper will take over the captaincy permanently with an eye to the 2019 Rugby World Cup.

Up Next

Sam Mitchell retires

02:57

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Hooper steps up as Wallabies skipper

Michael Hooper has been appointed Wallabies captain, with long-serving Stephen Moore stepping down from the role ahead of his international retirement at the end of the season.

The 25-year-old has already captained the side on 15 occasions, including twice this year against Fiji and Scotland, but has been handed the reins to impart his own leadership style on the team.
Even though a succession plan was on the cards before Moore pulled the pin on the captaincy role, Hooper said he was surprised when told by coach Michael Cheika.Photo: Daniel Munoz
"When this came across in front of me it was a bit of a shock," Hooper said. "I'm hugely privileged to learn so much off him [Stephen Moore] and then for Cheik to give me this honour. I feel very special.
"It does feel different and I'm a bit older. I've grown a lot. I've been around a bit longer. A few more scars and the hair's a bit shorter. I've learnt a lot in those couple of years and I'm super excited to learn more."

Cheika, who elevated Hooper to the Waratahs captaincy in 2014 when Dave Dennis was ruled out through injury, said the decision was an easy one.

You will now receive updates from

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Rugbyheaven Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"When you're asked to be in a leadership position, the biggest prerequisite is respect and if there's one thing that not just the players - I'd say all players in Australian rugby do - they respect Michael Hooper," Cheika said.
Hooper has the unenviable task of getting the Wallabies mentally ready to tackle the All Blacks in the first Bledisloe Cup match on August 19. 
The back-rower has previously led Australia three times against New Zealand, but failed to clinch a win in those outings.
Hooper wants the Wallabies to instil a ruthless mindset in their upcoming Tests as they look to improve on an average 2016.
"I don't want this to be my team, I want the Wallabies to be driven by 50 players just keen-as, just absolutely willing to die to get the job done," Hooper said. "New Zealand are the benchmark team to beat. They are consistent performers week in, week out and to have the opportunity to face them back-to-back as the first time as captain in this situation is hugely exciting.
"Personally, I love playing the All Blacks and I know the guys who have been around here for some time in the squad ... guys are keen to test themselves."
Hooper made his debut for the Wallabies in 2012 against Scotland and has notched up 68 Tests.
By the time the next World Cup comes around he will be nearing 100 Tests and Cheika believes he will be coming into the prime of his career.
"You get to the World Cup and Hooper is going to be pretty much in his peak at 27 or 28," Cheika said. "He will have had a few years experience as the captain of the team and I expect him to improve as a player as well."
Cheika will name Australia's new vice-captains on Friday when he trims his squad ahead of the Bledisloe Cup opener.
"There's a lot of younger players who are starting to find their voice," Cheika said. "We weren't scared back in the day to keep the standards on our teammates and that's something I think we've lost.
"I see a new breed of player who is starting to stand up and voice the standard to their teammate and make them accountable for the effort." 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheika</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugby World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All Blacks</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Dennis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Moore</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Hooper</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rugbyheaven Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bledisloe Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Munoz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cheika.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiji</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Waratahs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
