<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415715752340269</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>19:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Gizmodo</source>
  <url>http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2017/08/that-photo-of-einstein-sticking-his-tongue-out-just-sold-for-a-bunch-of-money/</url>
  <title>That Photo Of Einstein Sticking His Tongue Out Just Sold For A Bunch Of Money</title>
  <content>
The image of Albert Einstein sticking his tongue out adorns the racks at gift stores everywhere. But now, one lucky patron of the arts finally owns one of the first prints of the physicist having a grand ol' time - at an auction on July 27, the image sold for $US125,000 ($156,914). The buyer's identity has not been revealed.

According to the Nate D. Sanders auction house in Los Angeles, which made the sale, the iconic image was snapped after Einstein's 72nd birthday party at The Princeton Club in 1951. Einstein - probably tipsy or something - stuck his tongue out at a group of photographers trying to take his picture. While the photographer  - Arthur Sasse - was initially nervous about publishing the somewhat unflattering photo of the famed physicist, Einstein was simply tickled. According to , he ordered several copies of the photo and signed the original "A. Einstein .51".

The action house that sold the photo the other day was expecting $US100,000 ($125,531) for the piece. It's unclear how the auctioneers came into possession of the photo. Gizmodo reached out for comment but had not heard back at time of writing.

If you don't have $157k to shill out but still love this iconic image, no worries. You can buy a similar version at literally any shopping centre.

[]

WATCH MORE: Science & Health News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sticking His Tongue Out Just Sold For A Bunch Of Money</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Princeton Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Sasse</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Einstein .51</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Einstein's 72</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US100,000 ($125,531</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Einstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gizmodo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US125,000 ($156,914</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo Of Einstein</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Einstein</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nate D. Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
