<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415844601361232</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>20:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/sport/soccer/matildas-ambassadors-for-2023-womens-world-cup-bid-in-usa-20170802-gxnzmx.html</url>
  <title>Matildas doing Australia's chances of hosting World Cup no harm</title>
  <content>
In many ways, the Matildas mission in America is becoming ambassadorial. Beneath the backdrop of Australia's bid to host the 2023 Women's World Cup, the Matildas are winning over fans and doing so at the expense of heavy-hitters and potential bidding rivals.
A 1-0 win over rivals and world number one, USA, caught the attention of onlookers, neutrals and decision-makers. A 4-2 win over Japan days later showed the Matildas' competitive argument at the expense of their impending bid rivals.

Up Next

Hooper steps up as Wallabies skipper

01:13

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Matildas demolish Japan as Kerr hits hat-trick

The Matildas have notched up a 4-2 win over Japan at the Tournament of Nations thanks to a first half hat-trick from Sam Kerr.

Matildas coach Alen Stajcic is only focused on the series in America being the vital preparation for looming major tournaments - the 2018 Asian Cup and 2019 Women's World Cup - but knows that every positive result and eye-catching performance plays a small, significant part in bolstering Australia's case to FIFA.
"We've got a lot of positive reviews from fans, local administrators and other countries. I think a lot of people would love to see a World Cup in Australia and playing well on the field will only help that," he said.Photo: AP
The Matildas are set to attend a function on Wednesday night in Los Angeles with diplomats and consulate officials where it's understood the 2023 World Cup bid will be the main item on the agenda. While visits from diplomats aren't anything new, it's the first that will take place since the federal government announcement pledging funding towards the bid.
"We generally get a visit from the Australian consulate and diplomats but I guess it has that extra meaning with the World Cup bid in the background. Anything we can do to win that world cup, we'll be putting our front foot forward," Stajcic said.

Australia play their third match of the series against Brazil on Friday morning and while pleased with their two big results against powerhouse countries, Stajcic says it counts for little unless the Matildas can turn those into long runs of form.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"The challenge isn't to just win one-off games but four or five in a row. Our goal is to win the World Cup and that's the challenge for this group to develop the consistency. We've proven over the last few years we can match anyone and beat anyone on their day," he said. "Our goal is to string together three, four, five, six matches in a row like that so we can be a real world cup contender."
Stajcic believes the tournament has proven Australia has significant depth to test the best, are tactically versatile and, most importantly, a young group is experiencing a coming of age.
"I definitely see a lot of maturity in this group that's developed over the last couple of years. There's still a lot to develop on but the best part for our results this week it's that we still have so much potential but we still didn't even play our best football at times. There's still so much to come," Stajcic said. For Matildas forward Sam Kerr, that's definitely been the case. The 23-year-old scored a hat-trick in Australia's 4-2 win over Japan in the second match of the tournament, continuing her rich vein of form in front of goal. She is second in the scoring charts in the National Women's Soccer League behind USA star, Megan Rapinoe.
The West Australian says her clinical finishing is simply down to her added maturity.
"I've still got a lot of learning and growing to do. Hopefully my finishing and crossing can improve. It's just a part of growing up and learning more while training," she said. "I think I've taken on a bit of a leadership role with my club so it's maturity, confidence and it's always nice and easy to perform when you're confident. It's just about keeping my mind healthy."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alen Stajcic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stajcic</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Women's Soccer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Kerr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asian Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megan Rapinoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matildas</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tournament of Nations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Japan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
