<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416136659142905</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/03/06/47/nz-inmate-king-hit-with-pool-ball-by-prisoner</url>
  <title>Sickening prison yard assault leaves New Zealand man with hole in head</title>
  <content>
A New Zealand man who was the victim of a sickening prison yard assault has released images of his ordeal.
Security video from Mount Eden Corrections Facility in Auckland shows former inmate Benjamin Lightbody being king hit to the side of his head with a pool ball in 2013 while in the gym yard.
Lightbody was on remand and had been in the unit for less than an hour when attacked, reports
Footage showed him standing in the exercise area when a powerful-looking man dressed in grey track pants and strikes his head with his fist.
Lightbody crashed to the ground and remained there for minutes as other inmates and prison officers simply ignored his plight.
Three minutes after the attack he attempted to stand but was unable to. Eventually he managed to stagger out of the yard.
He suffered a traumatic brain injury as a result of the incident and had to undergo surgery leaving him with a hole in his head.

Related Articles

Police later charged a 36-year-old man with wounding with intent to injure over the incident and he was jailed for three years and eight months.
Lightbody is planning to sue the New Zealand Department of Corrections over the assault.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Eden Corrections Facility</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Benjamin Lightbody</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Department of Corrections</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lightbody</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
