<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416145249077808</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/horseracing/john-oshea-henry-plumptre-charged-in-godolphin-strangles-probe-20170802-gxnrud.html</url>
  <title>John O'Shea, Henry Plumptre charged in Godolphin strangles probe</title>
  <content>
Godolphin's former head trainer John O'Shea will be asked to answer a charge of giving false or misleading evidence to stewards, while Sheikh Mohammed's former Australian boss, Henry Plumptre, also faces sanctions before the resumption of the strangles inquiry later this week.
Fairfax Media understands the legal teams of O'Shea and Plumptre have been served notice of the charges stewards intend to bring before the pair on Friday, when the hearing into a controversial cover-up of a horse that was displaying signs of the contagious disease continues.Photo: Eddie Jim
Apart from being charged with knowing of Plumptre's decision not to tell stewards Polemic was carrying the condition, it is believed O'Shea has been hit with a further charge of giving false information to stipes.
Plumptre, who resigned last week as the Australian head of the global breeding and racing giant after 16 years with Sheikh Mohammed's organisation, has been charged with not reporting the strangles case to stewards last year, which is required under the country's rules of racing.Photo: Edwina Pickles
O'Shea quit perhaps the most lucrative training role in Australian racing in April, which preceded months of upheaval in the northern and southern hemispheres at the most recognisable brand in world racing.
O'Shea has been allocated boxes at Randwick to resume his career as a public trainer and tendered evidence at the initial strangles inquiry, which lasted for three hours, that he did not know Polemic was showing symptoms of the condition.

He said he was only concerned with the training of healthy horses in the racing team and had nothing to do with those not in work.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Godolphin head vet Trevor Robson gave evidence that he had told O'Shea of the results of Polemic's test and reminded him he needed to tell stewards, while maintaining it was Plumptre's decision not to inform officials.
The inquiry will cap a turbulent few months for Godolphin, which has appointed Ross Cole as its interim Australian boss and James Cummings as O'Shea's successor.
Cummings started the new season where he finished the last after a race-to-race double with Piracy and Alizee at Warwick Farm on Wednesday, following on from Philosophy's year-ending win at Rosehill on Saturday.
Alizee, in particular, looks to have a bright future after ranging up on the outside to beat Songlike in a three-year-old fillies maiden with Cummings declaring "there's clearly improvement in her".
"There's a lot to like [about her]," Alizee's rider Glyn Schofield said.
"She presented a bit fresh in the yard, but we came to the three wide line and she quickened up well when the second horse [Songlike] had skipped away.
"I nursed her through it and when she hit the line she was a comfortable winner and there's plenty of improvement to come."
Schofield copped a six-meeting suspension for causing interference early in his winning ride on Alizee and will miss the Rosebud meeting on Saturday week.
Jason Collett's spring carnival was delivered a huge blow when he was suspended for 13 meetings for tightening Rachel King's mount Puppet Master in the first, causing it to clip heels and dislodge the apprentice a stride after the post.
Collett will be out from Sunday and won't return until September 2.
Josh Adams (Sir Barb) will also miss four meetings for hampering Dream Lane in the sixth event at the 100-metre mark after a busy day in the stewards room.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>O'Shea</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Randwick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warwick Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plumptre</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosehill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glyn Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Schofield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwina Pickles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cummings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henry Plumptre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sheikh Mohammed</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Godolphin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puppet Master</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Jim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Robson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dream Lane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Barb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross Cole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John O'Shea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alizee</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cumming</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jason Collett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
