<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651415578313384409</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>18:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/3106287/two-charged-over-500000-gong-drug-bust/?cs=4110</url>
  <title>Two charged over $500,000 drug bust spanning three Wollongong suburbs</title>
  <content>
Simultaneous police raids on Tuesday netted two arrests and the seizure of over $500,000 worth of ecstasy and ice.
A three month investigation by Lake Illawarra detectives, under Strike Force Bayli, culminated in the arrests of a 30-year-old man at Cringila and a 44-year-old man at Warrawong.
Around 2000 ecstasy pills were seized during a police operation at Cringila, while later in the day, police launched two further operations at Warrawong and Cordeaux Heights.
The 44-year-old was arrested at a Todd Street, Warrawong address, while a search of a house on Plumwood Crescent at Cordeaux Heights turned up 10,000 ecstasy pills, two vehicles, and a quantity of crystal methamphetamine (ice).
Police say the street value of drugs seized is about $500,000.
The two men were taken to Lake Illawarra Police Station. The 30-year-old was charged with five counts of supplying prohibited drugs, supplying prohibited drug on an ongoing basis, supplying prohibited drug indictable quantity and supply prohibited drug large commercial quantity.
The 44-year-old was charged with six counts of supplying a prohibited drug on an ongoing basis, supply prohibited drug indictable quantity, supply prohibited drugs commercial quantity, and operate drug house.
Both men were refused bail, to appear at Port Kembla Local Court on Wednesday.
Strike Force Bayli investigations continue.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plumwood Crescent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warrawong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cringila</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Todd Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra Police Station</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Force Bayli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strike Force Bayli</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cordeaux Heights</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Kembla Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
