<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416140954110370</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/melbourne-express-thursday-august-3-2017-20170802-gxnoao.html</url>
  <title>Melbourne Express: Thursday, August 3, 2017</title>
  <content>
Two sadistic thugs robbed an elderly man riding a mobility scooter in Rosebud - before taking the scooter's keys and forcing the man to hobble to safety.

The 69-year-old man was using his mobility scooter to walk his dog along the chilly Rosebud foreshore about 6.15 Wednesday morning when the pair struck.

They confronted him near the rear of a local bowling club and demanded his wallet.

The elderly victim told them he was not carrying a wallet, so the offenders pulled him from his scooter and stole his jacket, watch, mobile phone and ring.

As a last insult, they grabbed the scooter's keys and told the old man to walk.

He eventually made it to a shopping strip nearby and called police, who are now appealing for anyone who might have seen the crime to call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
There has been a crash in the car park of Wyndham Vale station. 

Fortunately, nobody has been badly hurt and trains have not been affected, police said. 

Emergency services are on the scene and the area is already clearing.
The weather bureau has issued a frost warning for the North East, West and South Gippsland and East Gippsland forecast districts.

There does not appear to be a fog warning today, however. Still, be careful on the roads out there. 
Let's take a look at today's page one:

Page one of The Age on August 3, 2017. Photo: Craig Butt

It's another cold morning, with the temperature sitting on just 3.4 degrees right now.

There will be patchy fog this morning, although probably nowhere near as thick as yesterday's.

Otherwise, it will be a cold and rainy day. A top of 11 is expected and it will almost certainly rain. 

The next couple of days will also be on the cold and rainy side.

I reckon I'll start using the bureau's weather graphics again. Photo: Craig Butt

Good morning and welcome to the Melbourne Express blog. 

I'll be keeping track of breaking news, trains and traffic until 9am. Let me know via email or Twitter if anything happens on your way into work. 

I'm afraid I haven't had time to prepare a new Mystery Melbourne or brainteaser today, so Thursday's blog will be a bit lighter on puzzles than usual. 

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Butt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Express</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mystery Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Gippsland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3, 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Gippsland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North East</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Twitter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosebud</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyndham Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
