<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416394357186008</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/sport/football/manchester-united-v-sampdoria-video-highlights-bizarre-mkhitaryan-goal-daley-blind-backpass/news-story/fcf7fe7b68c4addc178650ff3c5293c9</url>
  <title>Watch: United score staggering 100m breakaway</title>
  <content>
JUAN Mata scored the winner as Manchester United's pre-season ended with an encouraging 2-1 victory over Sampdoria in Dublin.
In a game that will be remembered for Nemanja Matic making his first United appearance, Jose Mourinho's side took the lead inside nine minutes thanks to Henrikh Mkhitaryan's third goal of pre-season.
United controlled large parts of the friendly at the Aviva Stadium but were made to work for the victory as Dennis Praet's 63rd-minute strike set up a tense finale.
Manchester United vs Sampdoria 2-1

But substitute Mata made the workout worthwhile with the decisive strike nine minutes from time as United signed off their preparations for the new campaign with a sixth win from seven.
After what has been a heartening pre-season campaign, United made an uncharacteristically nervy start in the Irish capital as Daley Blind's wayward backpass drew a desperate save from David de Gea, handing Sampdoria an indirect free-kick six yards from goal.
But after the Serie A club's route to goal was blocked, United sprung on the counter as Antonio Valencia's cross-field pass released Matteo Darmian, and his inch-perfect cross set up Mkhitaryan for a devastating breakaway goal.
After Fabio Quagliarella's looping effort had drifted wide, Mkhitaryan should have doubled his tally on 22 minutes, but his header from Valencia's cross was well saved by Sampdoria stopper Christian Puggioni.
Two minutes later, Romelu Lukaku's curling effort whistled inches wide before Andreas Pereira lashed a long-range effort over.
Valencia set up Mkhitaryan with another chance to extend United's lead on 36 minutes but the Armenian glanced a header wide.
It was not all plain sailing for United as Sampdoria ended the half strongly, Victor Lindelof's deflection before half-time going close to levelling the contest.
Four changes at the break halted the momentum of Mourinho's men but two of the substitutes looked to have overcome that as Marouane Fellaini's chest down set up Ander Herrera for United's second on 62 minutes.
However, the goal was ruled out for offside - and a minute later Praet was found in space on the edge of the area to stroke home the equaliser.
Anthony Martial came off the bench as United pushed for a winner, the Frenchman's cross setting up Herrera whose header was saved by Puggioni on 80 minutes.
And it was Martial who set up the winner, rolling the ball into path of Mata, who caressed a shot low into the bottom left-hand corner.
UNITED TEAM NEWS
Nemanja Matic made his Manchester United debut in Dublin following his £40m switch from Chelsea. There were starts for fellow summer recruits Romelu Lukaku and Victor Lindelof, who lined up in a back three alongside Chris Smalling and Daley Blind in the Aviva Stadium.
MAN OF THE MATCH
Antonio Valencia - the only man in red to play 90 minutes. Handed the captain's armband, the Ecuadorian, who turns 32 on Friday, put in a performance that belied his age. On this display, it looks as though the full-back's ninth season at Old Trafford will be as strong as any of those that have come before.
WHAT'S NEXT?
All roads lead to the Macedonia for United, where they contest the UEFA Super Cup against European champions Real Madrid in Skopje on August 8. After that, attention turns to the new Premier League campaign, with West Ham the visitors to Old Trafford on the opening weekend.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Madrid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Armenian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henrikh Mkhitaryan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Romelu Lukaku</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sampdoria</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Herrera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mata</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UNITED TEAM NEWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mkhitaryan</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S NEXT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dennis Praet's 63</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ecuadorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matteo Darmian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Martial</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frenchman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Irish</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christian Puggioni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victor Lindelof</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ander Herrera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juan Mata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nemanja Matic</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aviva Stadium</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Serie A</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fabio Quagliarella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Valencia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Macedonia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daley Blind</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Trafford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Puggioni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marouane Fellaini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andreas Pereira</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GEA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Ham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Smalling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valencia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skopje</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Praet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
