<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416351407512228</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/travel/plane-making-emergency-landing-on-portuguese-beach-kills-two/news-story/350629c82997bfb1a9302d4616814120</url>
  <title>Sunbathing girl killed by plane</title>
  <content>
A FUMING mob branded a trainee pilot a "killer" after a man and young girl were killed when a plane made an emergency landing on a beach in Portugal during a flying lesson.
The victims, aged 56 and eight, were sunbathing on packed Sao Joao beach near Lisbon when the incident unfolded on Wednesday, reported
Terrified holiday-makers were left running for their lives after the light aircraft landed on the beach and skidded across a football pitch where children were playing.
Witnesses claim the trainee, who was on a flying lesson with a 56-year-old pilot, was confronted by furious sunbathers after they realised the young girl and man had died.
One, known only as Mafalda, told a Portuguese paper how she was forced to grab her children and flee as the plane came down over the packed beach.
She said: "Those first moments were very tense. People wanted to attack the pilot and began to shout at him that he was a killer.
"Everyone was really disgusted."
Police chief Paulo Isabel confirmed the two men on board the plane had been arrested and were being questioned.
Police and psychologists were scrambled to the scene to calm the baying mob, witnesses reported.
Mr Isabel said: "Any loss of life is to be regretted but given the fact this plane came down on a beach with hundreds of people on it at the height of summer, we could have been looking at many deaths and many injuries.
"What happened today in terms of [only] two people dying in the circumstances can be considered a real miracle."
Maritime police chief Pedro Coelho Dias, added: "The victims are a man and an eight-year-old girl.
"They were hit by the plane and died at the scene."
A 45-year-old woman was treated for minor arm injuries.
The tragedy struck on a stretch of coastline known as Costa da Caparica.
Portuguese TV station SIC reported the pilot had made a Mayday call before signalling he had to land because of engine failure.
He was released after questioning tonight along with his pupil pending an ongoing investigation. The pair are due to be quizzed in court tomorrow.
Both the youngster and the adult man are believed to be Portuguese - although there was no official confirmation of their nationalities - but not related.
Shocking pictures show the aircraft in the sea surrounded by horrified onlookers.
The plane is said to have come from an air club in the Lisbon neighbourhood of Torres Vedras.
It was described as a Cessna-152 aircraft - capable of a cruising speed of 145km/h.
Investigators are now believed to be probing a possible mechanical failure.
Journalist Enrique Pinto Coelho, who was playing on the beach with his son near the spot where the plane came down, told TV station SIC: "I've just seen this plane make an emergency landing.
"It came down and advanced around 100 metres in the wet sand after it landed, taking two people who were lying on the beach with it.
"We were unfortunately very near the landing spot and were playing football. It passed over the football pitch and we had to move back to avoid being hit ourselves.
"A large group of people surrounded the plane immediately. One of its wings was broken."
One witness, author Joao Quadros, who was on the beach with his son, said he had a bad feeling moments before the plane landed.
He wrote: "I had a shiver minutes before, and I decided to go and get my son. We missed it by metres."
This story first appeared in  and is reproduced with permission.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pedro Coelho Dias</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caparica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torres Vedras</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portugal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joao Quadros</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portuguese TV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cessna-152</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisbon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Enrique Pinto Coelho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paulo Isabel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sao Joao</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Isabel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Costa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mafalda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Portuguese</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
