<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416402947120745</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/theres-plenty-of-depth-in-our-midfield-sam-mitchell-backs-west-coasts-depth/news-story/bf8c1b9514806ad152201a0ec10d64aa</url>
  <title>'There's plenty of depth in our midfield'</title>
  <content>
SAM Mitchell has strong faith in West Coast's midfield depth, anointing Luke Shuey and Andrew Gaff as the new leaders of the generation next engine room.
Mitchell yesterday confirmed he would join fellow Brownlow medallist Matt Priddis in retirement at the end of the season, leaving a gaping hole in the much-maligned Eagles midfield.
Mitchell said his passion had drifted more towards coaching in the past 12 months and another year playing would have been one too many.
The 34-year-old four-time Hawthorn premiership star could take charge of the midfield when he begins as a full-time coach from next year.
"On the weekend we had seven players who did 10 centre bounces or more," he said.
Has recruiting Sam Mitchell been a success?

"That's more than I think anyone in the competition would have at the moment.
"There's guys like Andrew Gaff and Luke Shuey, who are at that age where they're ready to take hold of the place.
"Without being disrespectful to Pridda or myself, I think it's their midfield now. They're the guys you look to. Then there's Jack Redden and Dom Sheed, Liam Duggan is playing in the back half at the moment, but he grew up a midfielder, Jackson Nelson the same.
"There's plenty of depth in our midfield and I'm really excited to work with them in the future if that's what the role ends up leading towards."
Mitchell said he hoped his arrival had not affected Priddis' career adversely.
"I don't think so," he said.
"If I did, I hope it was for the better. We worked really closely together in the pre-season.
"We learnt a lot from each other. I'm sure we're going to play some games together in the latter part of the year that will show that we can do that.
"He's the best inside mid I've ever played with."
Mitchell said he was far from giving up on 2017, declaring eighth-placed West Coast well and truly in the flag race.
He said all his focus was on Sunday's crucial clash with 11th-placed St Kilda at Etihad Stadium on Sunday.
"I don't look at this as four games to go," Mitchell said.
"There's a lot of life left in this season and I'm really excited to pursue that.
"This season has been crazy. No one is the dominant force consistently through a season.
"I've been a position before where you just have to have the right form at the right time of year. Is our form good enough right now to go and win a premiership? No.
"Do we have the capability within our four walls to do that? It's not out of the question.
"I'm far from giving away anything in this season."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dom Sheed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eagles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Kilda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Gaff</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Redden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitchell</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Shuey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Priddis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pridda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liam Duggan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson Nelson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
