<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416437306859623</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/tv/radio/kate-langbroek-shocks-dave-hughes-with-photos-of-her-vampire-facial/news-story/2d5f1bf3cfcc08bd97e6dbfebc928351</url>
  <title>Kate Langbroek shocks Dave Hughes with photos of her Vampire facial</title>
  <content>
Kate Langbroek's vampire facial
4:40

KIIS FM radio host Kate Langbroek gets a vampire facial and Hughsey did not like the pictures... Audio: Hughesy and Kate

August 3rd 2017
44 minutes ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment - syndicated/

Dave Hughes was shocked by Kate Langbroek's facial.

Share

WE'RE not being mean but Kate Langbroek's face is shocking!
The  star had a Vampire facial and the photos are truly disturbing.
As her radio co-host Dave Hughes explained, a Vampire facial is where they "suck blood out of your veins and throw it in your face".
The man who carried out the procedure, Doctor Mikhail from , joined the radio duo on their national drive show yesterday for a chat about the bizarre beauty treatment that was made famous by Kim Kardsahian in 2013.
Langbroek revealed that 20ml of her own blood was injected into her face and at one stage during the procedure Dr Mikhail joked to her, "at this moment you look like roadkill".
Hughes saw the photos of Langbroek's facial for the first time on air yesterday and he could not believe his eyes.

Bloody hell!Source:Supplied

Halfway through the procedure.Source:Supplied
"My god!" he screamed when he saw the shocking pictures. "It looks like a horror movie, it looks like a crime scene!"
Langbroek told Hughes that "Dr Mikhail gave me an anaesthetic so it wouldn't be as painful and it made one of my eyes droopy," and added that she "had a lovely" time and "a good laugh" when she was getting the facial.
But what exactly is the point of the treatment, Hughes asked his co-host.

"Oh I don't know, it's supposed to make me beautiful," Langbroek laughed.
According to Dr Mikhail, the procedure will eventually make the popular KIIS FM star look "at least five years younger".
It will take a few weeks for the results to become apparent, so it's a case of WATCH THIS FACE.

Kinda looks like a scene from the movie Carrie, doesn't it?Source:Supplied
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vampire</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dave Hughes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughesy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oh I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Entertainment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughes</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Kardsahian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hughsey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikhail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Mikhail</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Langbroek</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH THIS FACE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KIIS FM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Langbroek</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
