<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416312752805840</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/clive-palmers-assets-could-be-frozen-liquidators/3208130/</url>
  <title>They're coming after Clive Palmer's 'big boy' toys</title>
  <content>
FEDERAL Government-appointed liquidators have sensationally applied to freeze hundreds of millions of dollars in assets owned by Clive Palmer - including luxury big boys' toys and 15 properties - in a shock move to help recoup taxpayer money.

In a surprise move never before flagged, special purpose liquidators PPB Advisory yesterday filed a Mareva injunction in the Supreme Court of Queensland to stop Mr Palmer splurging away at least $200 million in personal wealth and selling off his businesses.

The application also aims to stop him from driving his businesses in the ground.

The latest salvo fired against Mr Palmer is one of the most significant steps to recoup almost $70 million in taxpayer cash paid out to gutted Queensland Nickel employees, who were left without entitlements when the refinery went bust last year.

Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
IT was heart-breaking, challenging and life-changing.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Palmer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Nickel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Clive Palmer</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mareva</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Supreme Court of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FEDERAL Government-appointed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPB Advisory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
