<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416308457838420</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/factcheck/2017-08-03/fact-check-is-it-cheaper-to-fly-overseas-than-alice-springs/8754958</url>
  <title>Fact check: Is it cheaper to fly overseas than get out of Alice Springs?</title>
  <content>
Australians living in big cities are used to seeing great value offers for travel to exotic locations. But regional Australia seems to miss out.
In an  broadcast from Alice Springs on July 3, guest Dale McIver of Tourism Central Australia suggested "it's cheaper to fly overseas than it is to get out of Alice Springs. I'd love to see the airlines come and justify how they can actually do that".
Is it really cheaper to fly internationally than to an important regional centre like Alice Springs? RMIT ABC Fact Check takes a look.
The verdict

Ms McIver's claim is a fair call.
Regional air travel within Australia can be expensive, whether you are travelling from Alice Springs or elsewhere.
Depending on when you book and dates of travel, it can be more expensive to fly out of Alice Springs even to Darwin than it is to make an international trip from a capital city.
Flights from Alice Springs are also comparatively expensive when considering the distances travelled.
But it must also be recognised that there are some lower-priced Alice Springs airfares available, if booked in advance, and there are many international airfares that are more expensive than flying out of Alice Springs.
The comparison

Ms McIver does not specify the routes she uses for her price comparison.
She was responding to a question from an audience member who said:

"My wife and I are going on our honeymoon at the end of this month and it is costing us more money to fly from Alice Springs to Adelaide return than Adelaide to Croatia return.

Tourism would be higher and more people would live in Alice Springs if the prices weren't so expensive. Is there anything that can be done to lower the costs?"

The cost of flights is an issue both for residents of Alice Springs who wish to travel further afield, and for inbound tourists who have a choice of destinations to fly to.
So, when considering the cost of "getting out of Alice Springs", Fact Check has looked at direct return airfares on Qantas and Virgin Australia.
Virgin Australia flies direct from Alice Springs to Darwin and Adelaide.
Qantas and its subsidiary QantasLink fly to Darwin, Adelaide, Perth, Sydney, Melbourne, Brisbane, Cairns and Ayers Rock Airport.
Given there are no regularly scheduled international flights from Alice Springs, Fact Check considered a selection of international flights from Australian capital cities including Sydney, Melbourne and Darwin.

Experienced travellers would appreciate that a comparison of airfares is not straightforward, even on the same route.
A spokeswoman for Virgin Australia tells Fact Check: "Airfares on any given route, including Alice Springs flights, are driven by a combination of factors, including demand, competitive activity, time of booking, seasonality, operating costs, airport fees and taxes."
Prices for the same flight can even change between searches conducted on the same day.
Fact Check has considered various fare types to and from Alice Springs:

The standard lowest everyday return fare on each Qantas and Virgin Australia direct route, also known as the "lead-in" or "lowest non-sale" fare.
The lowest return fares to or from Alice Springs for bookings around seven days and three months in advance, as found by actual internet searches conducted by Fact Check.
For international fares, Fact Check has chosen a selection of direct international routes from Australian capital cities, using an internet travel site to find the lowest return fares for travel around seven days and around three months in advance.
Fact Check has chosen to check return airfares, given that most international fares are sold on that basis.
Other than the lead-in fares, the prices obtained by Fact Check are real results of internet searches conducted at a point in time. However, given the many factors that impact demand and pricing (and the fact that not all routes operate on the same days) the prices listed may not be typical of the prices regularly available on a particular airline for a particular route.
How much does it cost to travel from Alice Springs?

The lowest non-sale (or lead in) fares for the individual airlines are those prices that, in theory, should be available to all travellers who book sufficiently in advance.
Fact Check has assembled the following table of lead-in fares for direct (non-stop) flights out of Alice Springs on Qantas and Virgin Australia.
Not all of these routes are operated on a daily basis - for example, Qantas only operates a direct service to Brisbane on weekends.
It can be seen that the lowest return fare to a capital city is the route between Alice Springs and Adelaide, where both airlines provide direct flights.
The details are as follows (based on return travel):

From Alice Springs to...
Qantas (return)
Virgin Australia (return)
Distance (one way) (km)
Flight time (one way)

Adelaide
$470
$444
1,320
1:55

Darwin
$672
$636
1,310
2:00

Melbourne
$618
No direct flights
1,850
2:35

Sydney
$630
No direct flights
2,010
2:40

Brisbane
$738.50
No direct flights
1,960
2:30

Perth
$826
No direct flights
1,980
3:05

Ayers Rock (Uluru)
$412
No direct flights
336
0:50

Cairns
$858
No direct flights
1454
2:30

Sources: Qantas, Virgin Australia website, Webflyer.com
Taking into account the distance travelled, it is possible to calculate a rudimentary price per kilometre.
Ayers Rock is clearly the most expensive destination at 61 cents per km, but looking only at capital cities the most expensive is Darwin at 26 cents per km on Qantas and 24 cents per km on Virgin.
The route that proves the best value per kilometre travelled is Alice Springs to Sydney on Qantas at 16 cents per km.
While prices available online may occasionally be lower than these lead-in fares due to promotions, in most cases prices will be higher once the cheapest fares are purchased by other travellers.
Fact Check undertook searches for return flights between Alice Springs and capital cities on specific dates around one week and three months in advance from the time of search.
The results were:

Alice Springs and...
Return price (seven days advance)
Return price (three months advance)

Darwin (Virgin)
$686
$438

Darwin (Qantas)
$1,048
$571

Adelaide (Virgin)
$594
$662

Adelaide (Qantas)
$711
$631

Perth (Qantas)
$1,090
$826

Sydney (Qantas)
$887
$711

Melbourne (Qantas)
$698
$618

Sources: Qantas & Virgin Australia websites, Expedia.
Taken as a general guide, these searches demonstrate that prices can be considerably higher than the lead-in fares, particularly if booked with short notice.
How do these prices compare?

In assessing Ms McIver's claim, Fact Check has looked at a selection of return international economy class journeys from major capital cities that are available when booked around a week and three months in advance.
There is little similarity between a route such as Sydney to Auckland - which has multiple flights a day on several different airlines - and routes such as Alice Springs to Brisbane which is operated by one airline twice a week.
However when a tourist chooses a holiday destination, the comparative prices are likely to come into consideration.

Route
Airline
Return price (seven days adv)
Return price (three months adv)
Distance (one way) km
Flight time (one way)
Price per km ($)

Darwin - Singapore
SilkAir
$850.80
$554.27
3,330
4:40
0.13/0.08

Melbourne - Hong Kong
Qantas
$1,006.74
$947.55
7,440
9:40
0.07/0.06

Sydney - Singapore
Scoot
$747
$427
6,290
7:45
0.06/0.03

Perth - Denpasar
Jetstar
$392.31
$372.22
2,570
3:45
0.08/0.07

Adelaide - Doha
Qatar
$2455.59
$1545.59
11,300
14:00
0.11/0.07

Sydney - Auckland
Virgin Australia
$417.86
$457.86
2,160
3:05
0.10/0.11

Sydney - Los Angeles
Virgin Australia
$1151.56
$1151.56
12,100
13:35
0.05/0.05

Sources: Expedia, Virgin Australia & Qatar Airways websites
Even from this small sample of routes, it can be seen that there are flights - whether booked with seven days or three months notice - that in simple dollar terms are cheaper than some flights from Alice Springs.
Unsurprisingly given the greater distance flown on international routes, on a per kilometre basis, all of the international flights in the sample were less expensive than domestic flights from Alice Springs.
The impact on regional communities

Alice Springs is not the only regional city that faces higher airfares than its capital city counterparts.
Regional Express airlines, which flies on regional routes in all Australian states but not to the Northern Territory, tells Fact Check "Regional aviation is inherently more expensive than domestic or international aviation due to poor economies of scale and high operating costs".
A spokeswoman for Qantas similarly says "We can understand it's frustrating when regional fares can be higher than other parts of the network, and that has a lot to do with economies of scale".
But the level of competition on particular routes may also play a part.
For instance, Regional Express is the only airline serving the NSW regional city of Broken Hill.
Fact Check found that the cheapest direct return flight between Adelaide and Broken Hill (a 425 kilometre journey), when booked a week in advance, was $413.29 return.
A flight from Sydney to Broken Hill was $973.50 return.
By contrast the cheapest return flight for the 457 kilometres between Melbourne and Mildura - around three hours drive from Broken Hill but served by three airlines - was around 40 per cent cheaper at $256 return.
A direct Sydney to Mildura flight was $590.78 return (more than 40 per cent cheaper than flights to Broken Hill, only 100 km further from Sydney).
High airfares can deter local and international tourism, as well as limit business opportunities.
Ms McIver tells Fact Check:

"The high cost of airline travel to and from Alice Springs certainly has an impact on tourism numbers for the region.

We have seen a big decline in the backpacker market over the past few years and business tourism is another area we have seen the decline in numbers that has been partly attributed to the high cost of flights.

Tourism Central Australia has the cost of flights and increasing routes and competition on its radar as an ongoing concern. Whilst we are only one regional voice, we believe it's important to keep this very important issue at the forefront."

Sources

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>10</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar Airways</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qantas</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RMIT ABC Fact Check</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayers Rock</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denpasar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Express</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>30</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SINGAPORE</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SilkAir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broken Hill</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin Australia</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QantasLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McIver</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scoot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Virgin</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fact Check</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mildura</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Expedia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Webflyer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tourism Central Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dale McIver of Tourism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Auckland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Croatia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayers Rock Airport</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
