<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416351407512288</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/news/donald-trump-approves-russian-sanctions-over-meddling-in-the-2016-election-that-he-won/news-story/a5405412bce3ce0a6bb25727903f9223</url>
  <title>Moscow shreds Trump's ego</title>
  <content>
RUSSIA has sought to drive a wedge through the US government, stating the "establishment fully outwitted Trump" with the intention to "remove him from power"
Russia's Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev posted the inflammatory statements to social media in response to the passing of tough new sanctions aimed at punishing Moscow for interfering with the 2016 US election.
The President reluctantly signed the sanctions into law overnight after the US Congress passed the motion by a margin Trump could not overrule.
Moscow is seeking to exploit this internal dissent.

The Trump administration has shown its total weakness by handing over executive power to Congress in the most humiliating way
"It ends hopes for improving our relations with the new US administration," Medvedev states, targeting President Trump's repeated assertions that he wishes to do exactly that.
"Second, it's a declaration of a full-fledged economic war on Russia," he adds.
But Medvedev's sting was in an attack on the US democratic process - and Trump's ego.

"The Trump administration has shown its total weakness by handing over executive power to Congress in the most humiliating way. This changes the power balance in US political circles."
He goads the President by saying: "the US establishment fully outwitted Trump; The President is not happy about the new sanctions, yet he could not but sign the bill."
Medvedev states the move was a "way to knock Trump down a peg".
"New steps are to come, and they will ultimately aim to remove him from power."

The US establishment fully outwitted Trump. The President is not happy about the sanctions, yet he could not but sign the bill
The Kremlin had been encouraged by Trump's campaign promises to improve the Russia-U.S. ties that had grown increasingly strained under President Barack Obama. With the White House preoccupied by congressional and FBI investigations into links between the Trump campaign and Russia, the hoped-for relationship reset has not materialised.
Trump was scornful of the sanctions legislation, but signed it anyway.
"As president, I can make far better deals with foreign countries than Congress." Still, he said, "despite its problems, I am signing this bill for the sake of national unity."TRUMP LOOKS TO AUSTRALIA ON IMMIGRATION
PRESIDENT Trump has thrown his weight behind an immigration overhaul aimed at dramatically reducing the number of low-skilled migrants in the US and introducing a merit-based points system.
The proposals would prioritise English speakers for green cards, and would put a cap on the number of refugees able to gain permanent residency at 50,000 a year.
Mr Trump endorsed the proposal in remarks at the White House, flanked by Senators Tom Cotton and David Perdue, who drafted the legislation.
The president said the plan would represent "the most significant reform to our immigration system in half a century."
"Our system does not prioritise the most highly skilled immigrants - just one out of every 15 immigrants to the United States comes here because of their skills," the White House said in a statement previewing Mr Trump's remarks.
"On average, one million immigrants are accepted into the United States for legal permanent residency annually, and most of them are low or unskilled workers. This influx is the equivalent of adding more than the population of San Francisco to the country every year."
Mr Trump said the new system, if approved, would "help ensure that newcomers to our wonderful country will be assimilated, will succeed and achieve the American dream," while also protecting "struggling American families."
Senator David Purdue said Australia and Canada were the model for the bill.
"What we're introducing today is modelled on the current Canadian and Australian systems," he said. "It's pro-worker, pro-growth, and its been proven to work. Both have been extremely successful in attracting highly skilled workers to those countries."
Critics say that the proposals would result in an actual reduction of wages across the board, by slashing the number of migrants creating jobs.
"High-skilled immigrants are huge economic multipliers," the libertarian CATO institute said in a recent report claiming every skilled migrant coming to the US creates 1.8 jobs for native-born Americans.TRUMP SIGNS 'FLAWED' RUSSIAN SANCTIONS
It came as Mr Trump signed a bill to impose new sanctions on Russia.
Two White House officials said that the president signed the bill on Wednesday morning Washington DC time.
In response, Russian Prime Minister Medvedev said the new US sanctions were tantamount to a full-scale trade war.
The package of stiff financial sanctions against Russia passed Congress with overwhelming support.
However, Mr Trump called the bill "seriously flawed" in a statement.
"By limiting the Executive's flexibility, this bill makes it harder for the United States to strike good deals for the American people, and will drive China, Russia, and North Korea much closer together," Mr Trump said in a statement. "The Framers of our Constitution put foreign affairs in the hands of the President."
"This bill will prove the wisdom of that choice," he added.
The sanctions were in response to information that Russia meddled in the US elections, however it has denied doing so.
Moscow responded to the sanctions by ordering a reduction in the number of US diplomats in Russia.
The officials spoke on the condition of anonymity because they were not authorised to speak publicly before an official statement.TRUMP'S APPROVAL RATINGS HIT NEW LOW
Mr Trump's approval rating sank to a new low in the latest Quinnipiac University poll, which was released on Wednesday.
The poll showed that just 33 per cent of US voters approve of his job performance while 61 per cent disapprove.
Republicans remain the president's strongest backers, with 76 per cent approving and only 17 per cent disapproving.
Men were evenly divided, with 47 per cent approving and 48 per cent disapproving.
White voters with no college degree, a key part of the president's base, disapprove by 50 per cent to 43 per cent.
In the university's last poll on July 29, 55 per cent disapproved while 40 per cent approved of his job performance.
And by a 71 per cent to 26 per cent margin, voters do not believe that the volatile president is level-headed.
"It's hard to pick what is the most alarming number in the troubling trail of new lows for President Donald Trump," said Tim Malloy, assistant director of the Quinnipiac poll.
"The daily drip of missteps and firings and discord are generating a tidal wave of bad polling numbers."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinnipiac University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Perdue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Medvedev</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator David Purdue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington DC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FLAWED' RUSSIAN SANCTIONS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian Prime Minister Medvedev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Barack Obama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Quinnipiac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americans.TRUMP SIGNS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cato</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia-U.S</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Congress</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FBI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Malloy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators Tom Cotton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>S APPROVAL RATINGS HIT NEW LOW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRUMP LOOKS TO AUSTRALIA ON IMMIGRATION</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
