<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416308457838469</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/universities-unite-against-government-funding-plan/8769362</url>
  <title>Universities unite against Government funding plan</title>
  <content>
The Federal Government is set for another fierce battle with the university sector as it tries once again to overhaul higher education.

Key points:

Some groups worried changes will put students off studying
Universities say cut to funding will negatively impact on quality of education
Government argues fee increases strike the right balance

The Government wants to increase student fees and cut some funding to universities as part of a package of measures.
But the sector is overwhelmingly opposed to the plan, warning it could have devastating consequences, particularly in regional Australia.
The Government wants to increase student fees gradually from next year up to a total rise of 7.5 per cent by 2021.
It says that will add an extra $700 to the total cost of a three-years arts degree.
For a six-year medical course, it is almost $4,000 extra.
Students will not have to pay upfront, but they will have to start repaying their student loans sooner.
The Regional Universities Network represents institutions in regional Queensland, New South Wales and Victoria.
Its executive director Caroline Perkins is worried country students will be put off studying.
"We do have a fundamental issue about needing to lift the participation of regional Australians at university," she said.
"At present our participation rate is about half that in the regions compared to capital cities and really we do need to address that if regional Australia is going to have a fair share of the modern smart economy."
The Government argues the fee increases strike the right balance between how much students and taxpayers contribute to the cost of higher education.
The Grattan Institute's higher education director Andrew Norton was a member of the Government's expert advisory panel, which was appointed to come up with proposals for change.
"I think these changes to student charges in themselves will probably let us achieve most of our higher education goals but at much lower cost," he said.
"This can't change the fundamental economics of going to university so therefore I expect no change in student behaviour."
Anger over proposed funding cuts

The changes to student fees are just one part of the package.
The Government has abandoned its previous policy to cut university funding by 20 per cent.
Instead, universities will be hit with an efficiency dividend for the next two years and some Commonwealth funding will be contingent on universities meeting performance standards.
Education Minister Simon Birmingham said it would make the sector more sustainable.
But submissions to the Senate inquiry looking into the changes reveal the extent of opposition.
The grouping called Innovative Research Universities, which includes La Trobe, James Cook, Murdoch, Charles Darwin, Griffith and Flinders universities, says the Government's package will harm education and research.
Its chair, Colin Stirling, is scathing of the Government's plans.
"The changes are described variously as modest, they're not modest at all," he said.
"The financial impact on the university sector will be profound."
He said universities would have to cut funding per student.
"That will have a negative impact on the quality of the education that they can be provided," Professor Stirling said.
University funding been a challenge for the Coalition Government since 2014 when it announced plans to introduce fee deregulation and the 20 per cent funding cut.
The education minister at the time, Christopher Pyne, failed to win enough crossbench support to get the changes through Parliament and ultimately the policy was dumped.
The Group of Eight universities supported the Government when it tried to introduce fee deregulation, but not this time around.
It argues the current package is incoherent, contradictory and will leave students paying more for less.
Labor and the Greens have already expressed their opposition to much of the package, which means Mr Birmingham will once again have to negotiate with the Senate crossbench to get the votes needed to put his plan into action.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coalition Governments</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group of Eight</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Griffiths</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovative Research Universities</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Stirling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Universities Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Colin Stirling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Cook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Trobe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caroline Perkins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Norton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grattan Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Education Minister Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
