<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416274098099373</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/is-microsoft-getting-into-the-ipad-accessory-business/</url>
  <title>Is Microsoft Getting Into The iPad Accessory Business?</title>
  <content>
Some sleuthing by German website  has found a listing from an iPad Touch Cover on documentation relating to the shipment of devices with Lithium Ion batteries. Microsoft released the Touch Cover as an option for some early Surface devices but eventually dropped it in favour of the more popular, and better to type with, Type Cover. Does this listing signal that Microsoft is looking to enter the iPad accessory business?

I find it hard to believe Microsoft is serious about producing an accessory for the iPad given how crowded that part of the market is. But there are very few devices that take advantage of the iPad Pro Smart Connector. Perhaps Microsoft has found a way to use that port for more than connecting and charging.

My suspicion is this was a product that was in development but unlikely to see the light of day. Or it may have been a test product used internally or part of another project. Perhaps they are looking at a keyboard that has extra keys or controls to get more from Microsoft Office.

Whatever the case is, I'd be very surprised to see Microsoft get in the iPad keyboard business.

Do you agree? Or do you think this is a viable product for Microsoft to release?

WATCH MORE: Tech News

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft Getting Into</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lithium-ion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Microsoft Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tech News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad Touch Cover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad Accessory Business</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Touch Cover</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iPad Pro Smart Connector</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
