<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416437306859548</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Radio Australia</source>
  <url>http://www.radioaustralia.net.au/international/2017-08-03/donald-trumps-new-us-immigration-plan-to-be-based-in-part-on-australias-skilled-workers-system/1690816</url>
  <title>Donald Trump's new US immigration plan to be based in part on Australia's skilled workers system</title>
  <content>
The White House has unveiled a new legal immigration plan based, in part, on the Australian immigration model.
President Donald Trump introduced the plan alongside two Republican senators in the White House today.
The bill, called the "Raise Act", would overhaul the rules for legal immigrants and focus on skilled immigrants.
Under the plan, legal immigration would be reduced by 50 per cent over the next 10 years.
The White House said it based its plan in part on the Australian and Canadian immigration models.
"The competitive application process will favour applicants who can speak English, financially support themselves and their families, and demonstrate skills that will contribute to our economy," Mr Trump said.
"The Raise Act prevents new migrants and new immigrants from collecting welfare, and protects US workers from being displaced".
The bill faces difficult passage through Congress - Democrat Senate Minority Leader Chuck Schumer says the proposal "doesn't make much sense".
Later, when asked by the ABC, the White House explained what about the Australian policy it had adopted.
"We looked at the Australian system, the Canadian system, we took things we liked, we added things that made sense for America where we are as a country right now," senior White House adviser Stephen Miller said.
"One of the things that I think is most compelling about the Australian system is the efforts to make sure that immigrants are self-sufficient, and make sure they're able to pay for their own health care and things of that nature, and that's certainly one of the things we took from that.
"Obviously the points-based system that Canada has, has a lot to recommend it and actually we took that and we added things that were all new to it and were released today and that make sure we have a highly competitive application process."
The White House believes the changes proposed by the senators would raise wages for Americans and create jobs.

Photo:(AP: Pablo Martinez Monsivais)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Raise Act</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pablo Martinez Monsivais</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Democrat Senate Minority Leader Chuck Schumer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.5</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
