<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416480256533377</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/politics/prime-minister-malcolm-turnbull-under-siege-from-liberal-party-colleagues-on-samesex-marriage/news-story/9a1250d3613d7e0cd07bcf3a2d527a17</url>
  <title>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull under siege from Liberal Party colleagues on same-sex marriage</title>
  <content>
Government seeks advice on postal plebiscite
4:02

The government is seeking legal advice on the preparation of a postal plebiscite on same-sex marriage.

August 2nd 2017
17 hours ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull plans to use a secret ballot to canvas the opinions of his party room on marriage reform.

AAP, Staff writersNews Corp Australia Network

Share

PRIME Minister Malcolm Turnbull will reportedly use a secret ballot to canvas the opinions of his party room on marriage reform.
Mr Turnbull may use a ballot of MPs at next week's party room meeting to find out where the majority stand, and to stop infighting over the issue that threatens his leadership, reports.
The vote could be used to deter moderates from crossing the floor of the lower house in support of same-sex marriage, with the prime minister told just one in five MPs support the reform advocates.
It comes as former prime minister Tony Abbott issued a stern warning that Liberal MPs crossing the floor would be engaging in a "serious attack" on Mr Turnbull's authority.

Malcolm Turnbull is coming under increasing pressure on the issue of same-sex marriage. Picture: AAPSource:AAP
West Australian Senator Dean Smith is working on a marriage equality bill while his lower house colleagues Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson and Warren Entsch have flagged crossing the floor to support it.
With the bill to enable a plebiscite failing to pass parliament last year, some Liberals want the bill recommitted to parliament, while others say a voluntary postal ballot could achieve the same aim without the need for legislation.
Mr Abbott said the coalition should take its existing policy of a plebiscite to the next election and stand by it now.
MPs pushing for marriage equality argue they have discharged their duty to support a plebiscite and it's not their fault the Senate blocked the legislation.

But Minister Zed Seselja said that argument was nonsense, pointing to the government's persistence over workplace relations laws.

Warning of 'consequences' of marriage vote
3:33

Cabinet minister Simon Birmingham has warned of the consequences of crossing the floor on same-sex marriage.

August 2nd 2017
a day ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

PM 'GONE BEFORE CHRISTMAS'
Mr Turnbull won't celebrate Christmas as Prime Minister, because he won't be able to bring the Liberal Party together on same-sex marriage, according to political commentator Peta Credlin.
Tony Abbott's ex chief of staff Ms Credlin has told Sky News, Mr Turbull needs to use the "safety valve" of a postal plebiscite on same-sex marriage.
However she said it won't simple be the issue of marriage equality that would bring down Mr Turnbull.
Instead it will also be the Finkel review of Australia's energy market.
I don't think that Malcolm Turnbull will be here at the end of the year, but I suspect it won't be just this issue (of same-sex marriage) that brings him down," Ms Credlin told Sky News.
"I think the response to Finkel which will be due by Christmas as well, the combination of these two matters will significantly weaken his leadership to the point that he is untenable."
Ms Credlin was asked if Mr Turnbull would have to resign or be "blasted out".
"Either, or" she replied.

Peta Credlin predicts Malcolm Turnbull could be finished as PM by Christmas. Picture: John Feder/The Australian.Source:News Corp Australia
"It's interesting that the postal vote matter is the one that's pushed forward very much by the conservatives: Mathias Cormann and in particular Peter Dutton, and but for those two men Malcolm Turnbull would not be Prime Minister. They very much hold him in that seat," she said.
"You can see when there's any issue it's not Julie Bishop or Scott Morrison or indeed Christopher Pyne who go out there now to defend Turnbull, it's very much the two senior conservatives, Senator Cormann and Minister Dutton who are out there defending him.
"If they were to withdraw their support, I don't think Malcolm Turnbull is prime minister."
Ms Credlin advised Mr Turnbull to push for a postal vote.
"I think if the Prime Minister was canny, he would go to cabinet on Monday with a proposal for a postal vote, he would announce that immediately as cabinet broke on the Monday night, and he would use that to push into party room on Tuesday, because the party room will happen before parliament opens again on Tuesday afternoon," she said.

Conservative Liberals push for plebiscite
1:46

Conservative senator Eric Abetz has insisted the government must hold a national vote on same-sex marriage.

August 2nd 2017
a day ago
/display/newscorpaustralia.com/Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National/

"He would then be able to hold his people and say, look, whatever games Labor might play, we will have a postal vote, we'll have it before Christmas and these are the conditions."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Credlin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Web/NewsNetwork/Network News/National</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conservative Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peta Credlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAPSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Zed Seselja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GONE BEFORE CHRISTMAS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 2</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Feder</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staff writersNews Corp Australia Network</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
