<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416523206207057</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/richmond-youngster-jack-graham-set-for-afl-debut-ahead-of-this-weekends-clash-with-hawthorn/news-story/295f5ff5cb1e6ce21d50c8c068a7979d</url>
  <title>'She's a big fan': Tiger gets Mrs Hardwick backing</title>
  <content>
RICHMOND could unveil its fifth debutant of the season in Sunday's clash with Hawthorn - and the young AFL hopeful already has the all important backing of Mrs Hardwick.
Big-bodied youngster Jack Graham will be in Richmond's extended 25-man squad when the teams are released on Thursday, having earned his place on the back of strong VFL form.
The 19-year-old won 28 disposals and laid seven tackles as Richmond's VFL side defeated North Ballarat on Sunday and will now vie for a place in the senior team as it looks to retain its spot inside the top four against Hawthorn with weekend.
Graham captained South Australia's under 18s national champions side in 2016, winning the Larke Medal for the carnival's best player having averaged 25 disposals and six clearances per game. He was later recruited to the Tigers with Pick 53 in the national draft.
"He's in the squad at the moment," Hardwick told SEN Breakfast.
"I'm not sure if I'm allowed to give out that information, but he's in the 25.
"He had a terrific game at VFL level last week and I've been really excited about him for a little while.
"When he does debut, whether that's this week or not - we're not quite sure at this stage - he'll be a really good player for us."
LIVE stream every game of every round of the 2017 Toyota AFL Premiership Season on FOX SPORTS. Get your free 2-week Foxtel Now trial and start watching in minutes.

AFL: Superstar Dustin Martin will make a decision about his

Dusty to make call on future
And, importantly for both Graham and Hardwick, the youngster already has the full and crucial support of Mrs Hardwick.
"I'm just staring into the lovely Mrs Hardwick's eyes right now," Hardwick laughed.
"She's a big Jack Graham fan as well. He's hard and tough and he's certainly a Richmond player. We like him and we're lucky he was still available with the draft pick we got him with."
Should Graham be named to play this weekend, he will become Richmond's fifth debutant of a successful season for the Tigers.
Dan Butler, Ivan Soldo, Shai Bolton and Tyson Stengle have also been blooded at AFL level, while three more - Josh Caddy, Toby Nankervis and Dion Prestia - have made club debuts.
According to Hardwick, those youngsters coming through the system has re-energised the club and helped Richmond surge to its impressive 12-6 record on the season.
"It's really excited as a coach and as a club overall," Hardwick said.
"Every coach and every club in the AFL loves to see a new player come into the system and see what they can produce.
"They're never quite ready, but it's always a great experience for those guys to come in and play and to get a glimpse of what's required at AFL level.
"It's such a hard game these days and the jump from VFL to AFL is quite significant, but it's really exciting to see those players come in.
"We've debuted three or four of those guys this year, with the possibility of a couple more going forward, so it's an exciting time."

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hardwick</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Hardwick</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dion Prestia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shai Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Graham</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toby Nankervis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tigers</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>VFL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond's VFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Larke Medal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ivan Soldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Caddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toyota AFL Premiership Season</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pick 53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Ballarat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Superstar Dustin Martin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel Now</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyson Stengle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEN Breakfast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dan Butler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
