<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416480256533347</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4812748/98-apartments-on-bishopgate-street/?cs=305</url>
  <title>98 apartments on Bishopgate Street</title>
  <content>
CONCEPT: 25-31 Bishopsgate Street Wickham has the potential for a development like this 98-apartment building design.

IF the location at Wickham, a current hot spot for developers, wasn't enough to inspire buyers, then agent Adam Leacy is hoping the architectural concept design for 98 apartments, plus commercial or retail space, will.
Colliers international is selling 25-31 Bishopsgate Street via expressions of interest with Mr Leacy keeping an "open mind" on the price.
"We know Wickham is in pent-up demand with the uni coming, so we're keeping an open mind," he said.
The 2641-square-metre site has extensive frontages to Bishopsgate, Railway and Lindus streets and comprises a multi-level masonry brick building that is currently divided into three separate tenancies.
However Mr Leacy believes the potential for the property is in the possibility of a combination of retail or commercial space with residential living above. The concept plan features 98 apartments over 13 storeys with ground floor commercial accommodation.
"The good news is clearly [Newcastle City Council] wants to see more density in that outer rim of Wickham to create a thriving precinct," he said. "That's evident on the drafter master plan they have come up with."

PARK AVENUE, KOTARA
Prime exposure

A SIZEABLE 8300 square metres in the centre of Kotara's busy business district is on offer with this listing through Castle Properties Newcastle.
The property 2/154 Park Avenue comes with a building ideal for a medical or veterinary practice according to selling agent Stuart Foate.
The building is 359 square metres with temporary walls, garage facilities and airconditioning.
"It's located in the original home makers centre there near Cellarbrations and Reece Plumbing," Mr Foate said.
And with more than 7000 vehicles passing the area daily, there's the potential for substantial exposure.
"You're 10 minutes from Charlestown, Cardiff, Lambton then 15 to 20 minutes from Mayfield and Hamilton. It's within a decent little hub," he said.

The property is being sold via expressions of interest with Mr Foate confident of meeting the vendor's expectations of a sale of $1.1 million or more.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Park Avenue</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KOTARA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle City Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishopgate Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reece Plumbing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lambton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Foate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cellarbrations</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishopsgate Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishopsgate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardiff</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlestown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Foate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bishopsgate Street Wickham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castle Properties Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wickham</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SIZEABLE 8300</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Leacy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Leacy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
