<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416561860913395</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:48</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/fatal-dog-attack-dog-that-killed-perth-woman-sue-lopicich-was-aggressive-often-locked-away/news-story/802f4b054d69eae698bce1fed67be3e0</url>
  <title>Killer dog 'locked away from visitors'</title>
  <content>
A DOG that mauled a woman to death at her home in Perth's south-east was known by neighbours to be aggressive and was almost always locked away from visitors.
Sue Lopicich was found dead in the backyard of her Southern River property on Terrier Place about 1.45pm on Tuesday.
She had several bites to her legs and an arm.
The property where Ms Lopicich lived alone doubled as a dog boarding kennel and refuge for unwanted and abandoned pets and her business, Barko's Boarding and Rescue.
The bullmastiff dog responsible for the 58-year-old's death was understood to be a pet she had had for the past four years.
Authorities said it would be euthanised.
The dog was so aggressive towards those who found Ms Lopicich that rangers had to remove it before emergency services could reach her body.
It is believed Ms Lopicich was found after she failed to turn up for work.
Neighbour Greg Ball said the dog taken away was named Stirling and that he was saddened but not surprised by the fatal attack.
"If someone went in there, those dogs would have to be locked away," he said. "Very few people could get near them.
"There have been a number of incidents there. If I'm honest, we had been waiting for something like that to happen.
"Some dogs just can't be saved."
Another neighbour said hearing of the attack was "horrendous" and described Ms Lopicich as passionate and committed to dogs, rescuing and rehabilitating them before finding them new homes.
The bullmastiff was taken to the council pound with a Staffordshire bull terrier, which was also acting aggressively.
The second dog was later released to its owner.
City of Gosnells acting chief executive Grant Bradbrook said police asked for the dogs to be taken away so they could get to Ms Lopicich's body.
"The rangers haven't said they are particularly aggressive dogs," Mr Bradbrook said.
The city later released a statement saying police had told the council they believed the bullmastiff had killed Ms Lopicich.
"The bullmastiff will be humanely euthanised by a vet," the statement said.
"Police advised the Staffordshire bull terrier was not involved, and he will be returned to the family. The city extends its sincerest sympathies to Ms Lopicich's family and friends."
Mr Bradbrook said rangers had no previous complaints about the dogs and both were registered and microchipped.
The two rangers who collected the dogs had received counselling, he said.
Detectives investigating Ms Lopicich's death spent about an hour at the property yesterday.
One of Ms Lopicich's two adult daughters and other friends who are believed to have volunteered at the kennel were at the property for several hours. Police will prepare a report for the coroner.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Ball</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Staffordshire</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Terrier Place</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barko's Boarding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Bradbrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Lopicich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lopicich</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stirling</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bradbrook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City of Gosnells</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
