<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416531796141829</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/local-afl/top-northern-territory-2017-afl-draft-prospects/news-story/1832f02313aee0f278d4b8f444914607</url>
  <title>Top Territory 2017 AFL draft prospects</title>
  <content>
WITH the 2017 NAB AFL Draft just months away, a new crop of future stars is beginning to emerge from the Northern Territory.
AFL scouts have inquired about seven Territory prospects so far, with several of these rated a strong chance to be picked up by a club in late November.
Zac Bailey and Adam Sambono are two of the standouts and have been selected for this year's NAB AFL Draft Combine.
Tony Olango is part of Hawthorn's Next Generation Academy, while Jamie Hampton has strong bloodlines with brother Curtly currently based at the Adelaide Crows.
Dominic 'Junior' Grant, Francis Kinthari and Rodney Baird all have the skill-sets to be successful at the highest level, however injury has quelled their ability to have a major impact on the field this season.
AFLNT High Performance Manager Wally Gallio has kept a close eye on all seven prospects and said the current crop was difficult to gauge compared to previous years.
"It's been a funny group because we've had more injuries in the under 18 program than ever before," he said.
"It's hard to gauge, Zac and Adam have been invited to the combine so they should be strong chances.
"Rodney, Junior and Jamie Hampton could go again (into the 2018 AFL Draft) next year if they overcome their injuries and string some good games together."
Gallio said he was hopeful more NT representatives would be selected for testing at the State Combines but those won't be known for a few weeks yet.
"We are extremely pleased with the two players we've got in so far," he said.
Zac Bailey
Bailey in the most likely of this year's crop to find his way to an AFL club. The 17-year-old inside midfielder was a standout while playing for the Allies in the recent NAB AFL Under 18 Championships. Bailey was best on ground in his side's shock upset of champions Vic Metro, a performance that helped him earn a spot in the Under 18 All Australian side.
The Southern Districts product approaches his football with professionalism and a willingness to win the contested ball and tackle hard. He also possesses a powerful burst of speed that allows him to break away from a contest and create space for himself. A good kick on either side of his body, Bailey has the attitude, skills and work-ethic to make it at AFL level. It is little wonder clubs are already beginning to circle on the kid who has flashes of attacking Collingwood midfielder Adam Treloar and Adelaide Crows hardnut Rory Sloane.
PLAYS LIKE: Adam Treloar, Rory Sloane
Adam Sambono
The sky's the limit for the rangy Darwin Buffaloes forward. Sambono boasts freakish skills and unbelievable athleticism that make him an incredibly unique package. A latecomer, the boy from Daly River only played his first game of competitive football at age 17. But he has developed rapidly, winning the
NTFL rising star in 2015/16 and kicking six goals on debut for the NT Thunder earlier this year. Given his short exposure to the game, he could take some time to find his feet. But if he can flourish, the 20-year-old is a potential AFL star in the making.
PLAYS LIKE: Jeremy Howe, Cyril Rioli, Darryl White
Tony Olango
Already a member of Hawthorn's Next Generation Academy, Olango will again attract the interest of the Hawks and other AFL clubs in this year's draft. The St Mary's tall is the modern-day athletic ruckman-tall forward prototype who can be equally as effective swapping in between the two positions.
Born in a Kenyan refugee camp to Sudanese parents, the 18-year-old converted from soccer, where he was good enough to at one stage trial for the Glasgow Rangers, to Australian football three years ago and remains a project ruckman.
PLAYS LIKE: Nic Naitanui, Majak Daw, Jack Watts
Jamie Hampton
A member of Port Adelaide Magpies' development team this season, Hampton will put his hand up for AFL selection this year after missing out in last year's draft. The younger brother of Adelaide Crows star Curtly, Jamie plays more of an outside game than his brother and is most effective on a wing, half back or half forward flank.
Originally from the Pioneer football program in Alice Springs, Hampton has been working on improving his ball use in a bid to make the next step to AFL level. His form for Port Adelaide Magpies has been steady this season.
PLAYS LIKE: Dane Rampe, Zac Williams
Dominic Grant
Like Baird, "Junior" Grant has had his season ruined by stress fractures in his foot. He has not been able to get on the park for the majority of the season, something that may deter AFL clubs from taking a chance on him.
The Wanderers midfielder-forward is known as a smooth mover who delivers the ball with polish. The 18-year-old can also drop back in defence or move to a wing, making him a perfect fit for the ever-adaptable nature of AFL life.
PLAYS LIKE: Leigh Montagna, Taylor Duryea, Jed Anderson
Francis Kinthari
An explosive small forward in the Eddie Betts and Cyril Rioli mould, Kinthari is another Territory prospect with X-factor written all over him. Kinthari kicked 47 goals in 15 NTFL Premier League games for St Mary's last season, his first playing in the NTFL, and is best known for his fast pace and impressive goal sense.
Hailing from Wadeye, a remote area of the NT 400km southwest of Darwin, Kinthari is often referred to as having a touch of 'Wadeye magic'. He has been plying his trade for the NT Thunder this season and has booted eight goals from five games.
PLAYS LIKE: Eddie Betts, Cyril Rioli, Charlie Cameron
Rodney Baird
A versatile utility who can play back, forward or through the midfield, Baird earned a name for himself in the NTFL for Palmerston as a star defender. Blessed with the ability to play as a lockdown or offensive defender - on either small or tall players - Baird's ability to read the play is an additional string to his bow.
His defensive assignments in the NTFL have included fellow draft prospects Sambono and Kinthari. Stress fractures to his foot have curtailed his season this year, where he has only managed a handful of games, something which could impact his draft chances.
PLAYS LIKE: Nakia Cockatoo, Cameron Guthrie
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hampton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Combines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dane Rampe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Majak Daw</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB AFL Draft Combine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyril Rioli</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daly River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFLNT High Performance Manager Wally Gallio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bailey</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Guthrie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rory Sloane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB AFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nic Naitanui</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Buffaloes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Olango</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Olango</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NTFL</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Duryea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wadeye</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamie Hampton</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Montagna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palmerston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Watts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Treloar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanderers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT$400</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dominic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Marys</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NTFL Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jeremy Howe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kinthari</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT Thunder</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Bailey</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>X Factor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darryl White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide Magpies</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vic Metro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jed Anderson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn's Next Generation Academy</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nakia Cockatoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northern Territory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Junior' Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francis Kinthari</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern District</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dominic Grant</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sambono</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NAB AFL Under 18 Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kenyans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Territory 2017 AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Sambono</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Baird</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sudanese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baird</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glasgow Rangers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
