<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416660645162897</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>SBS</source>
  <url>http://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/2017/08/03/hanson-blames-staff-electoral-breaches</url>
  <title>Hanson blames staff for electoral breaches</title>
  <content>
Pauline Hanson has blamed incompetent staff for One Nation's breaches of electoral disclosure laws in Queensland.

3 MINS AGO  UPDATED 2 MINS AGO

One Nation leader Pauline Hanson has blamed "staff incompetence" for her party's breaches of electoral laws in Queensland.

Senator Hanson and her chief of staff James Ashby have both blamed incompetent staff for multiple breaches under investigation by the Electoral Commission of Queensland (ECQ).

Those breaches included failing to properly disclose party spending, lodge returns on time, and notify donors of their disclosure requirements, according to documents obtained by the ABC.

Senator Hanson says she's "had to pick up the pieces from an organisation that was run incompetently and by people who were not up to doing the job".

"Since then those people have gone and they've been sacked," she told the ABC on Thursday.

Mr Ashby says ECQ officers, who've been investigating One Nation's compliance, now have a favourable relationship with the party after incompetent workers were axed.

"One Nation officials identified the incompetency of internal staff in 2016 and subsequently moved those people on," he told AAP in a statement on Thursday.

"Documents revealed by the ECQ support the parties' view that former staff were incompetent."

He says that since the appointment of office administrator Greg Smith, the ECQ has "expressed a favourable working relationship with the party".

Documents obtained by the ABC under freedom of information detail correspondence between Mr Smith, One Nation's Brisbane office manager, and the ECQ.

In March, Mr Smith wrote to the ECQ seeking more time to disclose 2016 donation details due to computer system upgrades.

Later that week he blamed the closure of the party's office when Cyclone Debbie hit for failing to meet the extended deadline, the ABC said.

Branch staff also said they'd been unable to access receipts for gift disclosure because the former party secretary Rodney Evans allegedly left without providing passwords for accounting software, the broadcaster reported.

The ECQ has ordered One Nation to improve its systems, the ABC said.

AAP has contacted the ECQ for comment.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nation's Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UPDATED 2 MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Smith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Nation</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cyclone Debbie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Electoral Commission of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINS AGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rodney Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ECQ</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Ashby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Ashby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
