<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416652055228065</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/03/08/58/airbnb-sued-us-woman-sexual-assault</url>
  <title>Woman sues Airbnb after US host sexually assaulted her</title>
  <content>
Airbnb is facing a lawsuit after a guest says the company failed to do a background check that would have uncovered the criminal history of a host who she claims sexually assaulted her.
The property owner, who had earned the upper-tier status of "superhost", has said the assault never happened, .
Airbnb has defended its screening measures but also barred the owner from listing on its site.
The lawsuit, filed by Leslie Lapayowker, argues a background check would have uncovered the fact the owner had previously been arrested and charged with battery, and therefore prevented him from listing property on Airbnb.
According to the suit, in July 2016 Ms Lapayowker rented a studio apartment in Los Angeles attached to the home of Carlos Del Olmo.
While she had rented the property for a month, the suit says she had stayed only three nights because Mr Del Olmo's behaviour.
She claims he made sexually suggestive comments, used drugs in front of his underage son and pounding on her windshield while she was in her car.

According to the suit, the assault occurred when she returned a week after leaving the studio, to retrieve belongings she had left behind.
Ms Lapayowker says Mr Del Olmo told her he wanted to show her something inside the studio and he locked the door after she followed him inside.
According to the suit, she was held in a chair against her will, as he masturbated in front of her.
She says before she managed to flee the scene, he said to her: "Don't forget to leave me a positive review on Airbnb".
Airbnb did remove Mr Del Olmo as a host from its site when Ms Lapayowker complained about the attack a month later, the peer-to-peer rental site said.
Mr. Del Olmo told the New York Times he was not happy with Airbnb's response.
"I have not done anything wrong, and have lost between $30,000 and $70,000 a year in income, because Airbnb abandoned me," he said.
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leslie Lapayowker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Del Olmo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lapayowker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Airbnbs</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016 Ms Lapayowker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlos Del Olmo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
