<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416695004901992</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/centralian-advocate/alice-springs-radio-host-says-its-hard-work-finding-a-single-woman-in-alice-springs/news-story/9095cd2a7777f4abf385ee07e106bef7</url>
  <title>Picky Alice ladies 'losing out to porn'</title>
  <content>
Alice Springs men have dismissed the notion of a "man drought" in the town as rubbish, saying that there are no available women locally.
Breakfast radio host Sandee Beech criticised a story in the Centralian Advocate about the lack of single men in town, as he believes it's harder for an unattached gentleman. Mr Beech said while he knows that census data shows there are 500 more women in Alice Springs than men, he claims that most of them are in committed relationships - either heterosexual or same-sex.
And of those women who are single, the radio host said that he thinks that they have standards that are too high.
"I think they're immeasurably more picky," Mr Beech said. "I think women in general in Australia compared to women in Europe or other places, are far more picky."
The radio host also claimed that women should stop being so picky as technology may make them irrelevant to men.
"What's happened is that there's a separating of the sexes based on the fact that once upon a time a man would go out of his way to actively chase and pursue a woman, right to the end of the earth so to speak," Mr Beech said.
"But men now have become lazy. We've become very lazy because what once was an effort to acquire relief, men can now just go home and press play on porn and get terabytes of free stuff." When asked if he believed that men have come to react better to pornography than real life women, he said no. "It's never preferable but it's certainly preferable than the hoops you've got to jump through in this day," Mr Beech said. "[Porn] has become more accessible, men feel it's a lot easier to go straight home and look after yourself."
Mr Beech's friend, John Bridgefoot, disagreed that men prefer porn to a relationship but he said that he did find it difficult to meet available women. "They're narrowing down who they're possibly going to see, because unless that person is on the internet as well they're not going to meet," Mr Bridgefoot said.
"In order to get the relationship you've got to start the chase and if women put up too much of a barrier that chase becomes too much of an issue, it becomes too hard," Mr Beech agreed.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Centralian Advocate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bridgefoot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alice Springs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Bridgefoot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandee Beech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Beech</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
