<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416570450848175</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-council-revealed-as-top-dog-for-registration/3208187/</url>
  <title>Coast council revealed as top dog for registration fees</title>
  <content>
SUNSHINE Coast dog owners are coming out on top.
News Corp analysis has compared the Sunshine Coast's pet registration fees with nine other councils across the southern Queensland coast, showing just how little we fork out for our furry friends when compared with our neighbours.
Annually, the Fraser Coast Regional Council charges the general public $57 to register a dog and $52 for concessions.
Although a discount of $20 applies to those who pay early, Sunshine Coast council and Gympie council offer further discounts and incentives for responsible animal owners.
In Gympie, residents can register a microchipped and desexed dog for free, while registering a desexed dog was $25.
The Sunshine Coast Council charges a meagre $13 to register a desexed and microchipped dog.
Noosa council charges $38.50, and both councils waive fees completely for pensioners.
In Rockhampton a desexed and microchipped dog can be registered for $17 or $8.50 for concessions, while the Livingstone Shire Council and Gladstone Regional Council also offer considerable discounts for responsible pet owners.
Other councils also had similar fees for a third dog, with Gympie Regional Council charging $266 for an application.
The North Burnett Regional Council charged a fee of $208 and Bundaberg Regional Council charged $217 for an application fee for a third dog.
On the Sunshine Coast having more than two pooches on your property will cost you slightly less than neighbouring regions.
To apply to register an extra dog, Sunshine Coast council charge a non-refundable fee of $194 before they will consider your application.
Noosa charges a non-refundable fee of $130.50.
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
HOW Legacy helps families
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundaberg Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Burnett Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rockhampton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gympie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Livingstone Shire Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fraser Coast Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gladstone Regional Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
