<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416652055228085</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/royal-adelaide-show-flags-extra-security-measures/8769614</url>
  <title>Royal Adelaide Show flags extra security measures</title>
  <content>
Bag checks and staff scanning patrons with security wands before they enter the Royal Adelaide Show is a sign of the times, the event's general manager has said.
The Royal Adelaide Show's Michelle Hocking said the beefed-up security was being put in place as a precautionary measure, saying "we don't expect there to be any issues".
"You will be slowed down at the gates a little bit compared to what you normally are, especially if you pre-purchase your tickets," she said.
"Normally you just scoot straight through, you have your ticket scanned and off you go.
"But this year you will be asked to stop, we will have a look in your bag just to ensure that there is nothing there that is untoward and [there will] also [be] wanding.
"That's not walking through scanners as such, it is actually what you see at other major venues now.
"It's at airports, it's at ovals ... unfortunately I think it is a sign of the times with world events."
She said the show always had a security and police presence and the biggest issue for them was reuniting lost children with their carers.
Ms Hocking said there was no rush to get through the showground gates as events ran all day and to avoid queues people should consider not arriving when the gates open at 9:00am.
The show runs from September 1 to 10.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Show's Michelle Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Hocking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Royal Adelaide Show</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
