<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416609105554369</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/real-estate/class-action-looms-for-aveo-20170802-gxnuhi</url>
  <title>Class action looms for Aveo</title>
  <content>
Retirement village operator Aveo will be hit with a Federal Court class action next week, based on claims its contracts with residents were misleading and unconscionable.
Law firm Levitt Robinson has taken expressions of interest from 100 or more residents and families of former residents in Aveo villages afterwere raised in a joint Fairfax Media and Four Corners investigation.
Lawyer Stuart Levitt said the action would be lodged next week in the Federal Court in Melbourne with the backing of New York litigation funder Galactic.
The core of the case will rest on the claims over the complex contracts residents signed that allegedly enabled their freehold property, or property held 99-year leases, to be transformed into leasehold property.

"They effectively set about deliberately converting, without people's full realisation or knowledge, a unit entitlement in a strata establishment into something that was worth considerably less," Mr Levitt said.

"It's case about misleading and deceptive conduct and unconscionable conduct."
Aveo said it was yet to be contacted by Levitt Robinson and has not been advised of the claims against it.
"We have and always will act with the best interests of our residents first and foremost in our minds and actions," said chief executive Geoff Grady.
"We vigorously deny any suggestion to the contrary. Aveo will strenuously defend the matter and we are confident that we can show that we have at all times met our statutory and other obligations and our commitment to residents."

The average loss faced by residents on their property is said to be around $150,000, with the litigation, if successful, potentially worth hundreds of millions of dollars, according to Mr Levitt.
Lead applicants in the case are Michael and Meredith Luke, the children of a former Queensland village resident, Robert Luke, who has since passed away.
Ms Luke said her hope was that successful litigation contribute to a "far less stressful" situation for village residents and their families and enable "far more ethical and equitable practices and policies that would benefit everybody concerned"

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Levitt Robinson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoff Grady</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aveo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meredith Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Levitt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Four Corners</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Levitt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Luke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
