<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416613400521829</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/inside-the-extravagant-3-day-wedding-of-feiping-chang-and-lincoln-li-2017-8</url>
  <title>Inside the extravagant 3-day millionaire wedding of a Hong Kong it-girl and her financier fiance in a stunning Italian setting</title>
  <content>
Hong Kong "it girl" and fashionista Feiping Chang married her financier fiance Lincoln Li in an elaborate three-day affair in June.

The ceremony took place in front of 130 guests at an idyllic setting in Capri, on Italy's Amalfi coast - the bride's favourite holiday destination.

A cover shoot and in-depth interview with the couple has recently been published in Hong Kong Tatler, giving readers an insight into the lavish event.

"I've always loved Capri - it's one of my favourite summer destinations. It's my happy place," Feiping, who is a fashion and lifestyle blogger in Hong Kong, told .

"It's a really beautiful and magical spot, and I always knew that one day if I were to get married, I would want to do it there."

The three-day bash consisted of a Capri-style "welcome dinner" at renowned restaurant Da Paolino, followed by a beach day at glamorous club Nerano, and culminating in the big day at a stunning secluded villa on a clifftop overlooking the harbour, where they were the first people ever to be allowed to marry.

Scroll down for a sneak peek inside the luxurious affair, complete with four stunning designer dresses, a dessert room, wedding cake made from 15 kilos of fresh wild strawberries and an incredibly glamorous guestlist.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feiping Chang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nerano</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Feiping</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lincoln Li</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capri-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Da Paolino</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hong Kong Tatler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italy's Amalfi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
