<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416660645162952</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/crafty-residents-come-together-to-give-warm-gift/3205850/</url>
  <title>Crafty residents come together to give warm gift</title>
  <content>
AFTER running for only one week so far, the Guardian Angels Knitting Program has already received over 2000 donations in Nambour.
Now in its 19th year, the program has teamed up with the St Vincent de Paul Society to give back to the tens of thousands of Australians facing hardship this winter.
From July 17 to August 31, Guardian Pharmacies across the country will distribute knitted garments including beanies, scarves, jumpers and gloves to Vinnies shops and services in a bid to provide each of the 105,000 homeless Australians with warm winter wear.
Kym Gillespie, manager at Tim Logan's Nambour Pharmacy, said the community was always supportive of the initiative.
"A lot of our ladies are extremely talented, so they like to get an idea of the criteria and add their own creative flair to each item... they are really proud of what they do," she said.
"As a business, we like giving back to our community and that's why we try to get ourselves involved and support causes people are passionate about."
The donations have been comprised of a variety of items, with the most common including blankets, beanies and jumpers.
Ms Gillespie said they currently had a database of around 150 ladies.
"There are also a lot of people who can't knit but want to help, so we encourage them to buy wool and we can give that to one of the ladies to turn into something beautiful," she said.
"We love everything about this campaign and the knitters and really appreciative of the thought that goes into it."
For more information on the  program, visit www. .
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
HOW Legacy helps families
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St. Vincent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian Angels Knitting Program</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vinnie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Guardian Pharmacies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Gillespie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kym Gillespie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Logan's Nambour Pharmacy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
