<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416664940130295</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:12</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/armed-man-flees-coast-bank-empty-handed/3208201/</url>
  <title>Armed man flees Coast bank empty handed</title>
  <content>
A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank by knife point yesterday afternoon.
The man, 37, will appear in the Maroochy Magistrates Court this morning charged with attempted robbery and possession of a knife in a public place.
Police allege he entered a bank on Lowe St, Nambour about 1pm and demanded cash, but fled empty handed and was arrested on Ann St where a knife was found in his possession.
No one was injured.
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lowe St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ann St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
