<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416579040782837</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/its-been-a-time-of-amazing-change/3207271/</url>
  <title>It's been a time of amazing change</title>
  <content>
I BEGAN my nursing career in 1973 and joined the staff at Nambour General Hospital in 1981, as part of the casual nursing pool.
After a short period, I was made permanent and today am a nurse manager at the hospital.
Every day is different and that's exactly what I love about my job. A lot has changed in the 40 plus years of my career.
I initially worked in the surgical ward. In those days, we had a small paediatric ward in the middle of the surgical ward and also looked after the emergency department at night.
I have worked in a number of positions, including maternity ward, acting nurse unit manager of maternity at one stage and also the bed manager for a number of years.
Technology has changed significantly. I've witnessed the introduction of computers, advancements in surgery, medical imaging and the growth of the hospital at Nambour.
When I first started at Nambour General Hospital there was a small operating theatre, combined surgical and paediatric wards and a medical ward. The hospital then grew with the addition of Block 2 and the opening of a psychiatric ward, ICU and a renal unit and other wards.
Bed numbers increased and services increased significantly throughout the hospital.
Advancements in health care have also been amazing. For example, manual intravenous fluid sets have been replaced by electronic infusion devices with guardrails to maintain medication safety.
We also now have disposable items such as catheters and syringes, which used to be cleaned, sterilised and re-used.
The fact we now have CT scans and MRI and ultra-sonic imaging to help in diagnosis is wonderful. We've also advanced the way we care for our patients by implementing innovative models of care using evidence-based practice.
The past few years have been an exciting journey for the staff at all the facilities within Sunshine Coast Hospital and Health Service, with the preparation for the transition, the anticipation and excitement of the transfer to Sunshine Coast University Hospital.
Now, we are all looking forward to refurbishment of Nambour Hospital and the further expansion of SCUH.
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
Grant Kenny asks council to ditch Maroochy River rock wall concept
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICU</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour General Hospital</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Health Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Block 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Kenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
