<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416652055228089</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/football/the-aussies-set-to-start-their-uk-season-in-the-championship-and-scottish-premiership/news-story/9ecd2e7655c64136c39571228584ea36</url>
  <title>The Socceroos stars set for UK season opener</title>
  <content>
KEY members of Ange Postecoglou's Socceroos squad start their seasons this weekend as the English Championship and Scottish Premiership get underway.
Australia skipper Mile Jedinak's Aston Villa are joint Championship title favourites as the club rebuilds following their ignominious relegation in 2016. Jedinak will sit out Saturday's clash with Hull as he recovers from a groin injury that ruled him out of the Confederations Cup.
The weight of expectation is firmly on manager Steve Bruce, who has spent over $41 million on his squad since taking over last year.
PROFILE: Scroll down for a look at all the Aussies plying their trade in The Championship and Scottish Premiership
That investment could see Jedinak with a fight on his hands to regain his place in the side following the arrival of Republic of Ireland midfielder Glenn Whelan from Stoke last month - one of four central midfielders signed by Bruce since January.
Jedinak is not the only Australian on the books at Villa Park with Perth-born 21-year-old Jordan Lyden targeting a breakthrough season after missing last year through injury.
Lyden, who can play right back or midfield, debuted for Villa in 2016 and has featured throughout Villa's pre-season campaign.
But his best hope of regular action could in be in a loan move at the end of this month.
Elsewhere in the Championship Massimo Luongo's QPR are at home to a Reading side who were beaten in the playoff final by Aaron Mooy's Huddersfield last season Bailey Wright's Bristol City face Barnsley at Ashton Gate with Jackson Irvine's Burton Albion hosting Cardff City.
Newly-promoted Millwall will hand a debut to Socceroos international left-back James Meredith who has signed from Bradford City.
Albury-born Meredith, 29, has enjoyed a circuitous path in the English game since arriving in England as a 16-year-old at Derby.
Bradford's run to the League Cup final in 2013 put him in the spotlight but it was Millwall who finally took the plunge and signed him after the Lions beat the Bantams in last season's League One playoff decider.
In League One, Socceroos great Harry Kewell cuts his managerial teeth with Crawley Town against Port Vale.
The former Leeds and Liverpool star is the first Australian to manage an English club after his surprise appointment in May but insists he's more than ready for the task after coaching Watford's under-23 team last year.
"My passion for coaching is immense," Kewell said in a recent interview with ESPN.
"I've fallen in love with it. I enjoy the structure. I love the hard work.
"To be able to get a young player to perform a drill or execute a phase of play - that's satisfying. I get happy and think he's learned, and that's what I enjoy. I actually prefer coaching to playing."
In Scotland, Tom Rogic's Celtic open their title defence at home to Hearts. Former Perth Glory midfielder Ryan Edwards will be in action for Partick Thistle at Hibernian.
RYAN EDWARDS - Partick Thistle Position: Midfield Games played in 2016/17: 45 Goals: 1
Despite helping Glasgow's third club to finish sixth last season - their highest finish in 36 years - Edwards is still waiting for his first international cap. The energetic midfielder was named in a 30-man extended squad for the World Cup qualifiers against Iraq and the UAE but failed the make the final cut. The 23-year-old will be hoping another strong season will put him in Ange Postecoglou's thoughts once again.
JACKSON IRVINE - Burton Albion Position: Midfield Games played in 2016/17 season: 41 Goals: 10
Enjoyed an outstanding 2016/17 for both club and country, helping Burton defy the odds and avoid relegation while cementing his spot as Socceroos regular. Turned down a new contract last season but remains at the Pirelli Stadium despite regularly being linked with moves elsewhere. Almost certain to sign with a bigger team if he continues from where he left off last season in what will be another year of struggle for the Championship minnows.
MILE JEDINAK - Aston Villa Position: Midfield Games played in 2016/17: 33 Goals: 0
The Socceroos skipper will miss the start of the season as he recovers from the groin injury that kept him out of the Confederations Cup. Villa are red-hot favourites for the title, boasting a squad loaded with talent and experience augmented by John Terry's arrival from Chelsea. Jedinak will know his spot in the side is far from guaranteed following Ireland international Glenn Whelan's move from Stoke with Henri Lansbury, and the talented Conor Hourihane also competing for a centre-midfield berth.
MASSIMO LUONGO - QPR Position: Midfield Games played in 2016/17: 38 Goals: 1
Luongo redeemed himself from his horror show against Germany in the Confederations Cup with a magnificent display in the 1-1 draw against Chile. Signed a new contract with Rangers in March and the club are expecting big things from the 25-year-old, whose inconsistent displays mirrored that of the team last season. A better all-round midfielder since moving from Swindon two years ago, but needs to rediscover his scoring touch.
JORDAN LYDEN - Aston Villa Position: Midfield Games played in 2016/17: 0
After breaking into Villa's first-team squad in the Premier League two seasons ago, Lyden's progress was stalled last year due to injury. The Perth-born 21-year-old can play right-back or right midfield and has caught the eye of Steve Bruce during Villa's pre-season campaign. However, he has a battle on his hands to break into the team and could find himself being loaned out before the transfer window shuts on August 31.
JAMES MEREDITH - Millwall Position: Left-back Games played in 2016/17: 48 Goals: 2
Finally gets the chance to play in the Championship at the age of 29 having done the hard yards in the English lower divisions. The Albury-born left-back counts Cambridge, York City, Sligo Rovers and Telford United among his former employers. Came to prominence in the Bradford City side that beat Arsenal on their momentous run to the 2013 League Cup final. Meredith will be hoping his recent move to newly-promoted Millwall can help him add to the two Socceroos caps he won in 2015.
BAILEY WRIGHT - Bristol City Position: Central defender Games played in 2016/17: 45 Goals: 1
Endured a mixed time since swapping Preston for Bristol last January as the Robins left it late in the season to preserve their Championship status. An out and out defender and one of the better man markers in the division, Wright has never looked comfortable in Ange Postecoglou's switch to a back-three. However, he'll be a first-team regular at Ashton Gate and certain to feature in the Socceroos' crucial World Cup qualifiers later this year.
TOM ROGIC - Celtic Position: Midfield/Forward Games played in 2016/17: 37 Goals: 13
An impressive Confederations Cup campaign further enhanced his reputation as Australia's most talented player since Mark Viduka. Rogic has thrived under the guidance of Brendan Rodgers after injuries blighted his first two years at the club. Was sidelined for three months last season due to an ankle injury but returned to score the winning goal in the Scottish Cup final to secure the treble for the Bhoys. Has already scored twice in Celtic's Champions League qualifiers against Linfield and will be a crucial figure for club and country this season.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pirelli Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Preston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Meredith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swindon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villa</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bristol City Position</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Meredith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnsley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bantams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAILEY WRIGHT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goal's 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goal 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Villa Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsenal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Partick Thistle Position</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leeds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Rodgers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aaron Mooy's Huddersfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millwall Position</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Henri Lansbury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conor Hourihane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stokes</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradford City</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UAE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MASSIMO LUONGO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telford United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midfield/Forward Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mile Jedinak's Aston Villa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English Championship</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iraq</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edwards</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Linfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chile</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Viduka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kewell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Confederations Cup</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cambridge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republic of Ireland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sligo Rovers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>League One</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Germany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bailey Wright's Bristol City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hibernian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bristol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celtic's Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ange Postecoglou's Socceroos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aston Villa Position</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Rogic's Celtic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Socceroos</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scottish Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jackson Irvine's Burton Albion</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albury-born Meredith, 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scottish Premiership</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tom Rogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QPR Position</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albury-born</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JACKSON IRVINE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Championship Massimo Luongo's QPR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Lyden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ange Postecoglou</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Celtic Position</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry Kewell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burton Albion Position</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Bruce</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cardff City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goals: 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goals: 0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goals: 1</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 31</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Midfield Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ryan Edwards</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jedinak</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashton Gate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Left-back Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luongo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenn Whelan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scotland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bhoys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mile Jedinak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bradford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth Glory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Terry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glasgow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crawley Town</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lyden</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Partick Thistle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millwall</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
