<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416652055228158</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/weekend-rainfall-forecast-for-townsville/news-story/f507b9a4e4328fdd6ed42ecb464d8114</url>
  <title>BIG WET: Rain coming to Townsville</title>
  <content>
TOWNSVILLE is set to get a drenching this weekend according to weather forecasters.
A trough in the upper atmosphere is expected to bring up to 20mm of rain on Saturday and 45mm on Sunday.
Some forecasts in recent days predicted as much as 150mm of rain could fall.
The forecast comes after 73 bone-dry days in Townsville with the Ross River Dam level at 20.3 per cent capacity.
Bureau of Meteorology forecaster Julian de Morton said the system would impact large swathes of north Queensland from the peninsula to the Capricornia district.
The bulk of the system is expected to concentrate over the Townsville area.
The upper trough, considered a major driver of weather, means there is an 80 per cent chance of rain in Townsville on Saturday and 90 per cent on Sunday.
The trough is coming in from western Queensland and will combine with increased moisture from the coast to produce rain.
Rain forecast
Friday: 0 to 0.2mm
Saturday: 8 to 20mm
Sunday: 20 to 45mm
Mr de Morton said the forecast amount of rain could change.
"There could be more, there could be less," he said.
Forecasting group Central and North Queensland Weather is also predicting a "substantial rain event from Friday until Sunday".
The group predicted rainfall of up to 150mm yesterday, but spokesman Peter Turner said the models had changed and he was now expecting between 40mm and 50mm of rain.
He said the rainfall may only have a minimal impact on Townsville dam levels.
"It will go up a few per cent. But that kind of rainfall is not heavy enough to cause major inflows into the dams - particularly considering where the dam is situated," he said.
Mr Turner said Townsville was in a mostly dry period of the season.
He said cool conditions in the Indian Ocean meant mostly dry conditions for the region.
The last major rain event in Townsville was on May 19 when 120.8mm was recorded in the official gauge.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Capricornia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday: 0</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queensland Weather</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bureau of Meteorology</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ross River Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian Ocean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
