<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416531796141942</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:41</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/us-bans-travel-to-nkorea-from-september-1/news-story/9cbc01c44e4b6a55b25fe094ab2834b5</url>
  <title>US bans travel to N.Korea from September 1</title>
  <content>
A ban on travel by US passport holders to North Korea will take effect on September 1 and Americans in the country should leave before that date, the US State Department says.
Journalists and humanitarian workers may apply for exceptions to the ban, the department said in a public notice.
The US government last month said it would bar Americans from travelling to North Korea due to the risk of "long-term detention" there.
The ban comes at a time of heightened tensions between the US and North Korea, which has been working to develop a nuclear-tipped missile capable of hitting the United States.
North Korea will become the only country to which Americans are banned from travelling.
American student Otto Warmbier, sentenced last year to 15 years' hard labour in North Korea, returned to the US in a coma on June 13 after being released on humanitarian grounds, and died June 19. The circumstances surrounding his death are not clear, including why he fell into a coma.
North Korea has said through its state media that Warmbier's death was "a mystery" and dismissed accusations that he had died as a result of torture and beating in captivity.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Otto Warmbier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September 1</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US State Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>N. Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warmbier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 19</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 13</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
