<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416785199217087</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/news/politics/world/donald-trumps-aussie-immigration-plan-fuels-tensions-20170802-gxo7qb</url>
  <title>Donald Trump's Aussie immigration plan fuels tensions</title>
  <content>
President Donald Trump is pressing lawmakers to adopt a wide-ranging immigration overhaul based on what the White House said is similar to Australia's "merit-based" rules. The moves has triggered a political storm in Washington because such as system would favour skilled workers and English speakers.
The Republican-drafted bill that backs up President Trump's hardline election campaign pledge also proposes slashing legal immigration in half from the more than 1 million foreigners annually who are granted green cards for permanent legal residence in the US.
The Reforming American Immigration for Strong Employment (RAISE) Act, drafted by conservative Senators Tom Cotton and David Perdue, faces stiff resistance in Congress and from immigration advocates. They have criticised cuts to the overall immigration intake and have argued that foreign workers boost the economy.
President Trump argued on Wednesday (Thursday AEST) that "merit-based" immigration would stop low-paid unskilled foreign workers depressing the wages of Americans and save taxpayers billions of dollars in immigrant welfare claims.

AP

"This competitive application process will favour applicants who can speak English, financially support themselves and their families and demonstrate skills that will contribute to our economy," Mr Trump said, flanked by the two Republican senators leading the bill.

"This legislation will not only restore our competitive edge in the 21st century but it will restore the sacred bonds of trust between America and its citizens."
Australian officials have liaised with the Trump team, including with senior policy adviser Stephen Miller, to provide insights to Australia's immigration system, The Australian Financial Review in February.
Mr Miller is an immigration hardliner who previously worked for Senator for Alabama Jeff Sessions, who is now the Attorney General and helping deport illegal immigrants.
The proposed US points-based system would reward education, English-language ability, high-paying job offers, past achievements, and entrepreneurial initiative, the White House said.

Andrew Harrer

"This system is similar to the merit-based immigration systems used by Canada and Australia," the White House said.
Canberra's targeted immigration rules and points system grants visas to skilled workers on their likely contribution to society based on factors such as age, education and work experience.
In contrast, current US residency rules are skewed towards family reunions.
Mr Trump's adviser, Mr Miller, clashed with a reporter on Wednesday over the policy.

CNN's Jim Acosta said his father immigrated from Cuba before the Cuban Missile Crisis and questioned whether the White House's policy is in keeping with American tradition.
"You are sort of bringing a 'press 1 for English' philosophy here to immigration and that's never been what the United States has been about," Mr Acosta said.
"Are we just going to bring in people from Great Britain and Australia?"
In a heated exchange, Mr Miller hit back during the White House press briefing.

"I can honestly say I am shocked at your statement that you think only people from Great Britain and Australia would know English. It reveals your cosmopolitan bias to a shocking degree - this is an amazing moment," he said.
The proposed reform builds on Mr Trump's "America First" policies and will please his supporters, who are worried about immigrants stealing their jobs or bidding down wages.
However, immigration experts criticised the proposal and said President Trump and Republicans were misleading about the parallels to Australia.
Alex Nowrasteh, an immigration policy analyst at the libertarian Cato Institute, said the bill would not such as family reunification and a diversity, "while creating a points-based system for employment-based green cards that does not increase the numerical cap".

"The immigration systems in Canada and Australia do emphasise skilled immigrants over family members, but their immigration systems allow in far more immigrants, as a percentage of the population in both countries, than the United States," he  on the Washington think tank's website.
Some Republicans voiced misgivings.
Republican Senator for South Carolina, Lindsey Graham, said he supported merit-based immigration to attract the "best and brightest", but the cuts to legal immigration would hurt agriculture and tourism in his state which relies on immigrant labour.
The blueprint proposes limiting permanent resident status for refugees to 50,000 a year.
In his first presidential speech to a joint sitting of Congress in February, Mr Trump said: "Nations around the world - like Canada, Australia and many others - have a merit-based immigration system.
"It is a basic principle that those seeking to enter a country ought to be able to support themselves financially."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>America-first</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Perdue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alabama Jeff Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Attorney-General</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ANDREW HARRER</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican Senators</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Nowrasteh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cato Institute</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Great Britain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Donald Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republicans</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuban Missile Crisis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lindsey Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Strong Employment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Acosta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Carolina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Miller</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reforming American Immigration</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump's Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English-language</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Republican-drafted</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CNN's Jim Acosta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Trump</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senators Tom Cotton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
