<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416780904249689</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/donald-trump-weaker-on-world-stage-after-signing-russia-bill/8769446</url>
  <title>Donald Trump is weaker on world stage after signing Russia sanctions</title>
  <content>
When it comes to Russia, Donald Trump can't catch a break.

Key points:

The bill weakens Mr Trump's ability to control foreign policy without Congress approval.
But refusing to sign could have caused an embarrassing showdown with members of his own party.
Mr Trump says he signed the bill for the sake of "national unity" but he is clearly not happy.

Today he  designed to punish the Russian Government over interference in the 2016 presidential election and for its annexation of Ukraine's Crimea.
The bill also targets Iran and North Korea.
The legislation was passed nearly unanimously by Congress last week.
The bill erases Mr Trump's ability to ease sanctions without Congressional approval, weakening his ability to control foreign policy.
By signing it his campaign pledge to strengthen ties with Moscow has been obliterated for now - Russia's Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev says now hope of improved relations with the Trump administration are finished.

Mr Medvedev went further - saying the sanctions show the Trump administration was "utterly powerless" and that they amounted to a "full-scale trade war".
Moscow says it may impose countermeasures on the US in retaliation.
But refusing to sign would also have had negative ramifications for the President.
If he did veto the bill Congress was likely to successfully override him, causing an embarrassing showdown with members of his own party.
Mr Trump's campaign is also still being investigated for possible collusion with Russia to win the election and any refusal to sign could have been seen as an indication he was trying to curry favour with the Kremlin.
Mr Trump says he signed the bill for the sake of "national unity", but he is clearly not happy.
Quietly signed into law

The legislation sat on his desk for nearly a week after it was approved by Congress.
He often revels in the signing of a new bill by inviting the press into the Oval Office and surrounding himself with administration officials there to applaud the moment.
This was behind closed doors - no cameras, no journalists.
Afterwards the White House sent out two written statements from Mr Trump.
In them he declared parts of the bill "clearly unconstitutional" and said that while he favours tough measures to punish and deter "aggressive and destabilising behaviour by Iran, North Korea and Russia, this legislation is significantly flawed".
The President prides himself on being a superior deal maker - his primary criticism was that the bill "encroaches on the executive branch's ability to negotiate" by forcing any easing of sanctions to be approved by Congress.
That was followed by a jab at his own party's ability to negotiate sanctions, saying "Congress could not even negotiate a healthcare bill after seven years of talking".
During a tour of Baltic countries neighbouring Russia, US Vice President Mike Pence declared the signing of the bill would show that the President and Congress are "speaking with a unified voice".
In reality - when it comes to Russia - there is much that they still disagree on.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moscow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ukraine's Crimea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia's Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oval Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iran</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donald Trump</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Trump</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Medvedev</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Russia</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kremlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
