<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416355702479665</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/the-shining-legacy-for-coast-families-struggling-w/3208165/</url>
  <title>The shining legacy for Coast families struggling with loss</title>
  <content>
LOSING a loved one can be hard, but the prospect of raising a family alone compounds the heartache.
It's a situation Little Mountain resident Judy O'Connor is all too familiar with after her husband, James, died at the age of 39 in 2004.
James was an Australian Defence Force Captain.
While mourning the loss, Judy was faced with the challenge of raising a young family of four.
At the time, her son James was only two, and daughters Shannon, Maddy, and Alex were six, eight, and 15 respectively.
Living in Bundaberg, Judy was also disconnected from friends and family.
But, a shining beacon of hope in all the darkness was shone in the form of Legacy.
"Legacy took us on and invited us to different things and included us in Christ- mas lunches and made a fuss out of us and made us feel quite special," Judy said.
"There's not a lot of things that Legacy need to do for me because I'm an independ- ent adult so it's really more about how Legacy has supported my kids."
During the past 13 years, Legacy has organised, among many things, for her children to go on funded youth camps.
"It gives the kids something to look forward to and it gives them some time out with no pressures or expectations on them and from that point of view it just gives them a break," Judy said.
Legacy has even funded trips for some of her child- ren to attend the Canberra Anzac Day services.
They also helped send youngest daughter Shannon to Pozieres in France for important Anzac commem- oration events.
Judy said Legacy had proved vital in the home environment too. She said Legatees once helped watch her kids during a work commitment and even helped her daughter complete hours in the car for her learner's licence.
Since she moved to the Sunshine Coast last year, Judy said the organisation had helped the family adapt to the new area and gain new social contacts.
"They have really made a positive influence on our lives and been a significant part of our lives with the support processes," she said.
Legacy community services manager Christina Davidson said, regardless of which war a spouse served in, Legacy provided the same stability, guidance and assistance that a partner would normally provide to his or her family.
To help Legacy support Sunshine Coast families donate or buy a badge during Legacy Week.
For more information visit legacybrisbane.com.au
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
IT was heart-breaking, challenging and life-changing.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bundaberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anzac</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christina Davidson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legatees</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pozieres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Defence Force Captain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maddy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Legacy Week</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Anzac Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy O'Connor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christ</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judy</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Little Mountain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
