<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416566155880728</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4828456/trip-of-a-lifetime-for-defending-premiers/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Corrimal Cougars to feature on the international league stage</title>
  <content>
THE Corrimal Cougars will feature on the global rugby league stage when their Illawarra league-leading women's side makes the trip to Vancouver to face the Canadian women's team in October.

CANADA BOUND: The Corrimal Cougars will head to Vancouver in October to take on the Canada Ravens as they prepare for the end-of-season World Cup. Picture: Facebook
In a stunning coup for the women's game, the Illawarra's reigning premiers will play a vital role in Canada's preparations for the end-of-season World Cup in Australia.
The trip came about after four scheduled fixtures fell through, leaving Canada facing the prospect of heading into the World Cup without a full fixture under their belt.
Enter the Cougars, who've booked their ticket north for what will be a groundbreaking clash for both the Illawarra and the Canadian Rugby League Association. 
"The Corrimal Cougars have been a lifesaver to the Canada Ravens World Cup campaign," CRLA manager Paul O'Keefe told The Mercury.

"We had touring teams lined up to come here and give us a great preparation for the World Cup but during the last six months each team has pulled out for various reasons so the CRLA were desperate to find some experienced competition.
"Women's rugby league is a new sport in Canada and most of these players are playing games for the first time. Without this tour happening [coach] Mike Castle and myself were talking daily on how we could make this all work.

"Tammy Fletcher and the girls from Corrimal have been fantastic to work with and have saved Mike and myself many sleepless nights."
The ambitious plan came about through Corrimal hooker Fletcher's connections with Luke Srama and his international recruiting agency Srama Rugby League Recruitment.

"It was just an amazing opportunity that came up and we've made it a reality," Fletcher said.

"I'm good friends with Luke Srama through the Philippines National Rugby League and he spoke to me about it and I just thought 'wow, how awesome would that be'.

"Canada had four teams games with four different teams fall through so I spoke to Paul O'Keefe and he said they'd love for us to come over and I just thought it would be the trip of a lifetime."
Helensburgh and Jamberoo have both toured Canada in recent times, but the Cougars clash with an national side will be the first of its kind for an Illawarra club.

"To have a little club side from the Illawarra on international stage playing against a national side in a World Cup year is just massive for women's rugby league," Fletcher

"The chance to play on the international stage doesn't come along every day. You'd normally have to play at the very highest rep level to have that experience,

"To get to do it with the girls you've spent three-four years with, three-four days a week... they're your best friends, so to have this chance is a bit surreal."

"Since the Illawarra league started the women's game has just gone in a thousand different directions and it's been amazing to see."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRLA</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fletcher</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Helensburgh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Corrimal Cougars</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CANADA BOUND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cougars</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada Ravens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike Castle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canada Ravens World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canadian Rugby League Association</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul O'Keefe</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Srama Rugby League Recruitment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamberoo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luke Srama</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippines National Rugby League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vancouver</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tammy Fletcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
