<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416132364175513</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:08</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/cricket/debate-over-minor-details-holding-up-peace-in-cricket-pay-war/news-story/65b3409265e4e81abfdc279882106c37</url>
  <title>Last draft of pay deal gets final finesse</title>
  <content>
TEAMS of lawyers and accountants endured a painstaking exchange of information all day Wednesday as the Australian Cricketers Associaton continued to finesse the final draft of cricket's peacemaking pay deal.
Clauses within the near-finished Memorandum of Understanding were still being adjusted but expectations remain strong an agreement between Cricket Australia and the ACA is imminent.
Bookings had been made for a Wednesday announcement, but they were cancelled as ACA officials continued to seek clarification on issues of importance to the union.
Time pressures are mounting with Australia's Test squad expected to assemble in Darwin next Thursday for a training camp ahead of two matches in Bangladesh.
In a positive sign that tour will go ahead Test batsman Peter Handscomb has returned from a county cricket stint in the UK after weighing an option to stay when the tour was in doubt.

While CA threatened to take the matter to independent arbitration if there was no agreement this week, it's understood sufficient ground has been made to avoid the need for the third umpire.
More delays however could see that option raised again.
Despite being in various locations around Australia and the world, the ACA executive is on standby to endorse the final document when things considered "important" to the union are addressed appropriately.
Reports the executive had already given the green light to the agreement on Tuesday were denied as the final draft continued to be tweaked

over the course of the next five years.
That player payment pool, an increase of nearly $120 million on the last pay deal, will also be shared by around 120 female players for the first time.
The final value of player payments will equal up to 30 per cent of cricket revenue, with significant changes expected around where that money will come from, with junior cricket sponsorships one element to be excluded.

Cricket: Former Australia coach John Buchanan talks to Fox Sports News about the closing days of the pay dispute.

'It's taken way too long'
Much of the early angst over CA's wish to end the 20-year-old revenue sharing agreement centred around players capacity to enjoy "uncapped" raises.
Domestic players alone enjoyed a 53 per cent rise in wages over the course of the previous five-year agreement as a result of revenues coming in well above CA forecasts.
In its original pitch to the players in March, CA offered immediate salary increases for female players to as much as $179,000 a year, and the average international player's income would rise to $1.45 million by 2021/22.
The final version of the new deal is expected to include a share of revenue above forecast (which at this stage is $1.86 billion) for all players, male and female, international and domestic, plus significant allocation of money to grassroots cricket.
Studies undertaken by CA have revealed around $237 million is required to address grassroots cricket for issues ranging from improving facilities to employing up to 120 more development staff.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Buchanan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Handscomb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Memorandum of Understanding</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Former Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bangladesh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia's Test</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cricket Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Cricketers Associaton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
