<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416780904249677</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/sport/afl/adelaide-crows-coach-don-pyke-prepares-to-recall-three-big-names-for-showdown-43-against-port-adelaide/news-story/3bf7d77ad4e222604ef68b14128764e2</url>
  <title>Pyke confident on major gains at Crows selection</title>
  <content>
CROWS coach Don Pyke started Adelaide's major training session for Showdown 43 on Thursday morning expecting three big names - Eddie Betts, Jake Lever and Brad Crouch - to pass their last fitness tests.
And if this holds up, Pyke and his match committee will be locked in a challenging selection meeting on Thursday afternoon to adjust the Crows line-up to maintain dominance on Port Adelaide with a fifth successive derby win at Adelaide Oval on Sunday evening.
Pyke is extremely confident specialist forward Betts (appendix), midfielder Crouch (fractured cheekbone) and defender Lever (knee-hamstring) will have their names back on the selection board when Adelaide names its 25-man squad for the Showdown on Thursday evening.
"The signs are positive on all three of the guys, Lever, Crouch and Betts," Pyke said.
"We will get through training (Thursday morning) and assess them from there."
Betts is understood to have consulted his surgeon on Wednesday.
"It is going to be about how he clinically presents now and how he is able to go in terms of training," Pyke said of the Showdown specialist who has tormented Port Adelaide as a difficult match-up in attack.
"Lever is fine. He should be fine."

Adelaide Crows star Eddie Betts speaks to media outside hospital, saying he's on the improve and looking forward to getting back to footy. Courtesy: Channel Seven News Adelaide

Seven News: Adelaide Crows star Eddie Betts speaks outside hospital
Port Adelaide coach Ken Hinkley - who has no major injury concerns - joked his worry is "all three play".
Hinkley reaffirmed All-Australian Chad Wingard (left ankle) is unavailable. However, he will need to check the progress of defender Matthew Broadbent who has been troubled by an ankle injury for more than a month.
"Broadbent is a bit scratchy still at the moment coming off that ankle, so we will wait to see what that looks like," Hinkley said. "We're pretty healthy."

AFL: Port Adelaide midfielder Chad Wingard has opened up about his calf rehab and posted a video of his exercises.

Wingard opens up about rehab
Pyke maintained Adelaide's deadpan approach to answering Crows fans' growing concern with the attention uncontracted pair Jake Lever and Mitch McGovern are drawing from rival AFL clubs in Melbourne and WA respectively.
"I really don't want to talk about the contract stuff - we have a massive game this Sunday," said Pyke as reports continue of Lever visiting Melbourne Football Club officials and players recently.
"My focus is on that."
Asked if he had any reassuring response to the Crows fans who are pushing for a club statement on the Lever-McGovern impasse, Pyke said: "As I said, I'm not in a position where I want to talk about it today. That will take its due course.
"Again, I can't control (the reports on Lever and McGovern). What we control is what we can produce against Port Adelaide on Sunday.
"That is basically our focus now. We have a big game Sunday leading into a final series and we have a big couple of months coming up and that is where my focus is."
michelangelo.rucci@news.com.au
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chad Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ken Hinkley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Betts</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lever-McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyke</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide Crows</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Betts</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>All-Australian Chad Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.25</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crouch</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hinkley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wingard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Crouch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Pyke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel Seven News Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broadbent</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
