<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416742249543237</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/brand/sophisticated-traveller/ayres-rock-resort-rolls-out-the-red-carpet-for-business-and-leisure-travellers-20170716-gxci5s</url>
  <title>Want to see Uluru but don't like discomfort? Try this.</title>
  <content>
This is a special feature in association with Ayers Rock Resort.
A room in the desert

About 20 minutes' drive from the rock, you'll find the village and , which comprises three stylish hotels: the five-star Sails in the Desert, Desert Gardens Hotel (4.5 stars) and Emu Walk Apartments (four stars). Over the past five years, all three properties have undergone upgrades worth a combined $70 million. The hotels are located within walking distance of one another along the ring road, clustered around the Resort Town Square, with boutiques to browse, cafes and a cluster of art galleries. A free shuttle runs between the hotels every 20 minutes or so, making it easy to sample different restaurants. All three properties offer chic design and extreme comfort - including air conditioning and heating - in which to kick back after a morning spent cycling, jogging or walking around the rock. For visitors who don't want to take their eyes off Uluru, book one of Desert Gardens' 24 Deluxe Rock View Rooms. Of the three hotels, these rooms offer the best views of Uluru, and each has a verandah on which to enjoy room service and a glass of something chilled. Rates based on minimum two-night stay until November 15: Sails in the Desert from $500 per room a night; Desert Gardens Hotel from $400; Emu Walk Apartments from $450.
Red Ochre spa delight

Supplied

Call it a hint of Paris in Uluru. Situated in a garden nook at Sails in the Desert, the  channels the energy of the central desert to create a sanctuary of pampering using Payot French beauty products. The spa offers all the usual fare - from hot stones to pedis, but go for a Sacred Journey treatment: specifically, the Desert Awakening, starting with a foot soak, followed by a full body exfoliation, body moisturising treatment and rounded off with a mini facial and eye reviver. Book ahead as the spa can get busy. Phone (08) 8957 7036.

Just the business

You have to admit, "come have your annual team-building exercise in the spiritual heart of Australia" is a handy market differentiator. Since it opened as a conference centre in 2012,  has bagged a swag of awards. The main ballroom seats up to 420 people, while the second takes 300. Go on, let the light in on your next corporate pow wow. Packages are available to inject some fun and awe, such as Breakfast at Uluru and sunset at Kata Tjuta. Delegates stay a walk away at Sails in the Desert, Desert Gardens Hotel, or Emu Walk Apartments.
Timeless art

Priced at $145,000, No. 74 of the 155 works in the Naata Nungurrayi Collection hangs in the refurbished Mangata restaurant at Desert Gardens Hotel. The paintings are based on representations of petroglyphs made by the first people of the Central Desert. Nungurrayi is regarded as one of Australia's most collectable artists.

Supplied

Bush bounty

Croc dogs, herb-crusted steak, smoked kangaroo, gulgul beurre noisette - bush tucker has come a long way since the days of the witchetty grub stereotype. Discover more through the  program. Billed as bringing "ancient flavours into modern cuisine", all 10 restaurants within Ayers Rock Resort hotels now include native bush ingredients on their menus. To amp up the wow factor, book a special outdoor indigenous dining experience, such as Night at Field of Light, Sounds of Silence or Tali Wiru. Free daily Bush Food Experience talks and a complimentary crash course in making wattleseed shortbread complete the culinary smorgasboard on offer.

Louie Douvis

Supplied

Adam Bruzzone

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desert Gardens' 24 Deluxe Rock View Rooms</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desert Awakening</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Red Ochre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uluru</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desert Gardens Hotel</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emu Walk Apartments</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sacred Journey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam Bruzzone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nungurrayi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Desert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayers Rock Resort</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Field of Light</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mangata</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Naata Nungurrayi Collection</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Payot French</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Resort Town Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bush Food Experience</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Desert Gardens Hotel (4.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kata Tjuta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tali Wiru</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bush</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
