<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416789494184537</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-03/i-cant-control-that-pyke-quiet-on-indemand-pair</url>
  <title>'I can't control that': Pyke quiet on in-demand pair</title>
  <content>
Mitch McGovern could be tempted to return to his home state of Western Australia

ADELAIDE coach Don Pyke has refused to discuss the futures of in-demand pair Jake Lever and Mitch McGovern ahead of Showdown 43 with Port Adelaide on Sunday. 

, while the talented defender has also attracted interest from Collingwood and the Western Bulldogs. 

Meanwhile, McGovern's stocks rose after he took a sensational contested mark and .

McGovern has been linked with a move back to WA with Fremantle, while also coming to the attention of Victorian clubs.

Pyke didn't provide any insight into the latest reports.

"I don't really want to talk about the contract stuff," Pyke said. 

"We've got a massive game this Sunday. 

"My focus is on that.

"As I said, I'm in a position that I don't want to talk about it today. 

"That will take its due course." 

Crows captain Taylor Walker said on Wednesday he hoped the club's culture would play a role in Lever deciding to re-sign with the Crows.

Pyke said he wasn't frustrated with the news of Lever's on-going contract discussions taking the spotlight away from the Showdown. 

"I can't control that," Pyke said.

"What we control is what we can produce against Port on Sunday and that's basically our focus now.

"We've got a big game this week leading into a finals series and we've got a big couple of months coming up, that's where my focus is at."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROWS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Port Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Taylor Walker</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pyke</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Bulldogs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch McGovern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Lever</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Collingwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGovern</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Pyke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Showdown 43</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
