<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416140954110409</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Football League</source>
  <url>http://www.afl.com.au/news/2017-08-03/blues-will-only-trade-top-pick-for-elite-youth</url>
  <title>Blues will only trade top pick for 'elite youth'</title>
  <content>
Carlton CEO Steven Trigg says the club's first-round draft pick this year will only be traded for 'elite youth'

CARLTON will only trade its 2017 first-round draft pick for an elite youngster, but the Blues will separately target mature midfielders who can reduce their heavy reliance on Marc Murphy and Bryce Gibbs, CEO Steven Trigg says.  

If the Blues finish the season in their current ladder position, 17th, they will take pick No.2 into November's NAB AFL Draft.   

Under list manager Stephen Silvagni, Carlton has invested heavily in the draft over the past two years, taking first-round picks Jacob Weitering, Harry McKay, Charlie Curnow and Sam Petrevski-Seton, along with promising prospects such as Jack Silvagni, David Cuningham, Zac Fisher, Harrison Macreadie and Cameron Polson.

Trigg told AFL.com.au Carlton would again be a big player at this year's draft, with its first pick off limits save for exceptional circumstances. Although Trigg didn't mention emerging GWS star Josh Kelly, the Blues are one of the 22-year-old midfielder's keenest suitors and would presumably, for example, be prepared to offer pick No.2 as part of a trade for him.

But Trigg said the second half of 2017 had shown Carlton had to balance its pursuit of gilt-edged youth with more readymade recruits, particularly in the midfield. 

"We do need to go to the draft again but we do need at the same time to find just a bit more maturity when we're tested for depth, particularly in the midfield at the moment - and that's the balancing act we've got to get right in this upcoming draft and exchange period," Trigg said. 

"If the season stopped today and we have pick No.2 I can't see too many circumstances under which we would move that, unless it was for absolutely elite youth.

"Thereafter, we're contemplating getting that balance right."

After winning five of their first 12 matches this year, the Blues have dropped their past six games. In that losing stretch, the club's injury list has continued to grow, with Patrick Cripps (fractured fibula), Ed Curnow (bruised larynx), Sam Rowe (knee), Andrew Phillips (foot), Cameron Polson (shoulder) and Patrick Kerr (hip) all ruled out for the rest of the season. 

Carlton has been without experienced midfielders Cripps and Curnow over the past three rounds and their absence has been keenly felt. 

"At the moment with a dozen or so injuries we're being tested depth-wise, particularly in the midfield," Trigg said.

"We've got a young group that is challenged by the week-to-week grind and it's only going to be better for it, but that just doesn't quite manifest on the scoreboard.

"Right at the moment with Cripps and Ed Curnow out, our two experienced midfielders have had to carry a really, really heavy load. We just have to find some more support for them with mature talent in the exchange period."

Patrick Cripps' absence has been keenly felt in the past few weeks. Picture: AFL Photos

The Blues have won five games this season and face a tough task to match last year's return of seven wins in coach Brendon Bolton's first year in charge, with their final four games against finals contenders Essendon, West Coast at Domain Stadium, Hawthorn and Sydney at the SCG.

Trigg said the Blues had expected there could be "an element of vulnerability from time to time on the scoreboard" in 2017 after the club went from being the 10th oldest team on average age in 2016 to the third youngest, and from 12th to 17th in average games played.

The Carlton CEO, however, is in no doubt the club is on the right on-field track under Bolton.

"We're being challenged on the scoreboard at the moment, but in just about every other way our growth is measurable and palpable," he said. 

"There are plenty of indicators of that: six first-gamers this year and five Rising Star nominations (Caleb Marchbank, Petrevski-Seton, Charlie Curnow, Cuningham and Silvagni), you know the story.

"We'd all love to have a few more wins, but we know we're progressing. We remain really confident on where we're going."

Sam Petrevski-Seton has been a shining light for the Blues in his first year. Picture: AFL Photos

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Polson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Petrevski-Seton</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Rowe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caleb Marchbank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triggs</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harrison Macreadie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harry McKay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryce Gibbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack Silvagni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rising Star</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November's NAB AFL Draft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Cripps</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Kerr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlie Curnow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Silvagni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Steven Trigg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Photos</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed Curnow</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SCG</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Essendon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendon Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton CEO Steven Trigg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curnow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jacob Weitering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cuningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Domain Stadium</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zac Fisher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marc Murphy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GWS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cripps</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silvagni</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Cuningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josh Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
