<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416750839477945</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:32</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>http://www.businessinsider.com.au/chris-christie-cubs-fan-nachos-2017-8</url>
  <title>Chris Christie comments on tense interaction with Cubs fan: 'I didn't dump the nachos on him'</title>
  <content>
Chris Christie has been surprisingly involved in the sporting world in recent weeks.

The New Jersey governor was  at a Mets game earlier in July, and just days before that he couldn't avoid  while guest-hosting a sports radio show.

Most recently, Christie made headlines after he was  who heckled him at a game while holding a container of stadium nachos. The fan, Brad Joseph,  in a recent Facebook post, where he said he did not regret calling Christie a hypocrite.

Now, according to , Christie has given his public response to the whole story while speaking at an unrelated event in Trenton. Christie downplayed the encounter and promised that he would not stop attending baseball games no matter how many times he got heckled.

"I didn't dump the nachos on him or anything, which was an option," Christie said. "No, I'm not swearing off baseball games in any way."

Christie went on to add that he's used to the public accostings, but there's only so much he's willing to stand. "I will take a certain amount of abuse," Christie said. "You're a public official you have to. But usually it's one. You get one shot to call me a name or curse me out."

Christie's next sporting appearance is expected to be at the NFL Hall of Fame induction ceremony this weekend.

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brad Joseph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL Hall of Fame</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TRENTON</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Jersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christie</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Christie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
