<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416737954575753</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4830271/childrens-shoes-found-to-contain-cancer-causing-chemical/?cs=2452</url>
  <title>Children's shoes found to contain cancer-causing chemical</title>
  <content>
The ACCC has issued an urgent recall of a navy brogue-style shoe sold by UK company Next UK to Australian consumers over a six-month period.
The lining of the shoe, which featured in the Younger Boys section of the website, has been found to contain carcinogenic benzidine, a chemical that could cause cancer after prolonged contact with skin.
Next UK published a recall notice late in June, describing the issue as a "potential problem with the lining... which contains a quantity of restricted substance."
The company did not specify the substance, nor the risks to children it posed, however Australian authorities uncovered the presence of cancer-causing benzidine.
"Unfortunately, it's come to light that there's a potential problem with the lining of the above style which contains a quantity of restricted substance which exceeds Next's specification," the Next UK notice reads.
"As the shoes don't meet our strict, technical specifications, we've taken the decision of recalling them, and are requesting that you return them to us for a full refund.
"We're very sorry for any disappointment and inconvenience caused, but we hope you'll understand that customer safety is our highest priority." 
The following information has been published on the ACCC website and consumers should act quickly to ensure children do not wear the shoes.
Product description

964786 (UB/489) Navy Strap Brogue Shoe
What are the defects?

The lining contains a quantity of benzidine which could have carcinogenic properties if in prolonged contact with the skin.
What are the hazards?

Expert authorities classify benzidine as a carcinogen and recommend that exposure be limited.
What should consumers do?

Consumers should stop using the product immediately, and contact Ezibuy on 1800 148 148 to arrange return packaging and a full refund.

Supplier - Next
Traders who sold this product - Next UK
Where the product was sold - Nationally, internationally, online
Dates available for sale - 19 December 2016 - 29 June 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UK</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Next UK</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Younger Boys</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2016 - 29 June 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ezibuy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Navy Strap Brogue Shoe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UB/489</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
