<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416909753271213</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/meningococcal-case-in-adelaide-childcare-centre/8769788</url>
  <title>Meningococcal warning from childcare centre and school 'alarmist', SA Health says</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

A childcare centre and a school in Adelaide have "sent out alarmist and inaccurate information" about meningococcal after a two-year-old girl was admitted to hospital with the disease, SA Health has said.
SA Health said nine people who had direct contact with the child had received clearance antibiotics.
"SA Health is aware that a childcare centre where the child attended, as well as a local school, sent out alarmist and inaccurate information," the health authority said.
Chief medical officer Professor Paddy Phillips said people had been incorrectly advised to see their GPs.
"We're a little bit concerned that the childcare centre didn't contact us first before they sent out information, and similarly a local school," he said.
"There was no increased risk from this child to the kids at the childcare centre, and absolutely no increased risk to the members of the public or the kids at the local school.

Symptoms of meningococcal
Meningitis (inflammation of brain and spinal cord membranes)

Fever
Headache
Neck pain or stiffness
Pain from lights
Drowsiness or confusion
Septicaemia (blood infection)

Fever
Muscle aches
Vomiting
Rash (a red rash which does not fade when pressed and can become dark purple)
Other symptoms

Joint pain and swelling
Lung infection with fever, cough, chest pain and difficulty breathing
Severe throat infection with pain, difficulty swallowing, and drooling
Source:

"It did cause alarm. There were a number of people who presented to one of our hospital's ED [Emergency Department].
"Also we had a number of calls from general practices."
SA Health said it wanted to reassure the community anyone who required antibiotics had been contacted.
"As the disease is only spread by close or lengthy contact, there is no increased public health risk," a statement said.
There have been 21 cases of the disease reported in South Australia this year, compared to 13 at the same time last year.
The strain of the child's illness has not been determined.
"I understand she's doing well," Professor Phillips said.
"She's under really good care."
Thirteen of the cases this year have been the B strain, five have been the W strain and two have been the Y strain.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Emergency Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Paddy Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Phillips</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>W</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SA Health</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
