<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416914048238696</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/obituaries/judith-jones-editor-discovered-french-chef-julia-child-and-anne-frank-20170802-gxo7tq.html</url>
  <title>Judith Jones, editor discovered French chef Julia Child and Anne Frank</title>
  <content>
Judith Jones, the editor who discovered Julia Child and advanced a generation of culinary writers that revolutionised cooking and tastes in American homes, and who for a half-century edited John Updike, Anne Tyler, John Hersey and other literary lions, died on Wednesday at her summer home in Walden, Vermont. She was 93.
The cause was complications of Alzheimer's disease, her stepdaughter Bronwyn Dunne said.Photo: Chester Higgins Jr/The New York Times
Authors and publishing colleagues called Jones an extraordinary editor - imaginative, versatile, fascinated with stories, curious about people and places, a deft wordsmith and above all insatiable for the pleasures of French cooking. She talked about it, wrote about it and practiced its arts in her kitchens in Manhattan and rural Vermont.
She modestly ascribed her success to being in the right place at the right time. Certainly that was true in 1950, when as a young editorial assistant at Doubleday in Paris she rescued the diary of Anne Frank from a pile of rejects and persuaded her superiors to publish it in the United States - a stroke of fortune that gave the English-speaking world the intimate portrait of a forgotten girl, the child everyone had lost in World War ll.
And Jones was again in the right place at the right time a decade later when a shopworn, 800-page manuscript by three unknown women with no literary credentials landed on her desk at the Alfred A. Knopf publishing house in New York. The book, too long and with the uninspired title French Recipes for American Cooks, had been rejected by several other publishers.
Jones, who knew a great deal about French cooking from her years in Paris, began reading the manuscript and was so enthralled, she could not put it down. She took it home and tried some of the recipes, which proved to be magnificent. It was a lucid, approachable cookbook that took the mystery out of coq au vin and boeuf bourguignon and hundreds of dishes long thought to be too daunting for the American cook.

"Here was the cookbook I had been dreaming of - one that took you by the hand and explained the whys and wherefores of every step of a recipe," Jones recalled in a New York Times article in 2004.
The book, Mastering the Art of French Cooking, by Child and two French colleagues, Simone Beck and Louisette Bertholle, was not a blockbuster best seller when it was published in 1961. That did not happen until 48 years later, when in 2009 the book, often revised but still in print, got a lift from a new movie, Julie & Julia.Julie & JuliaMastering the Art of French Cooking
But the book was so popular over decades that it warranted scores of reprintings and a second volume in 1970, and it eventually sold more than a million copies.
For Jones, who had previously edited translations of the French philosophers Albert Camus and Jean-Paul Sartre, the Child book opened a new career path, editing culinary writers: James Beard and Marion Cunningham on American fare, Madhur Jaffrey (Indian food), Claudia Roden (Middle Eastern), Edna Lewis (Southern), Lidia Bastianich and Marcella Hazan (Italian), and many others.
Jones and her husband, Evan, an American food writer she met in Paris in 1948, wrote three books together, two of them on breads and one on New England cooking. They also collaborated in the kitchen on dinners for friends at their homes on Manhattan's Upper East Side and at Bryn Teg Farm, in Walden Township in northern Vermont.
After her husband died in 1996, Jones began cooking for herself and wrote a book about it, The Pleasures of Cooking for One (2009). It was a blend of kitchen advice and encouragement for people who live alone in their final years.
Judith Bailey was born in New York City on March 10, 1924, to Charles Bailey, a lawyer, and the former Phyllis Hedley. Judith and her sister, Susan, grew up in Manhattan in a prosperous but frugal household where garlic was shunned as vulgar. The food shopping was done by telephone and the cooking by a nanny. Evening meals were English-style meat and boiled potatoes. Sometimes, on Saturdays, Judith's father took her to a French restaurant.
Judith attended the Brearley School and Bennington College, graduating in 1945 with a degree in English. After three years as an editorial assistant with Doubleday in New York, she moved to Paris. She and her future husband, sharing rooms and a love of French cuisine, scoured the food stalls and markets and turned their apartment into what she called a speakeasy restaurant, making a meagre living with meals prepared together.
To make ends meet, she took a job in Doubleday's Paris office, reading manuscripts and advance copies of books in French in search of material for publication. The Diary of Anne Frank had already been published in Dutch and German, but not in English. Attracted by the girl's picture on the cover of the French edition, which had been consigned to the trash, she began reading. Her boss found her in tears late in the day.
 
"We have to send this book to New York," she said. "It's wonderful." In 1952, Doubleday published Anne Frank: The Diary of a Young Girl, to wide approbation.
Jones, who joined Knopf in New York in 1957, wrote for Vogue, Saveur and Gourmet magazines. She won many honours, including the James Beard Lifetime Achievement Award in 2006, and retired in 2013.
"At the table, one never grows old," she explained to a discussion group at a bookstore in Washington, quoting an old Italian saying. "Isn't that enough reason to come home at the end of the day, roll up one's sleeves, fire up the stove and start smashing the garlic?"
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan's Upper East Side</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jean-Paul Sartre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English-speaking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judith Jones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Tyler</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alzheimer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judith</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alfred A. Knopf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Updike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Judith Bailey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Beard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saveur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brearley School</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World War</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jones</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pleasures of Cooking</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charles Bailey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diary of Anne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claudia Roden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lidia Bastianich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edna Lewis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia.Julie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Beard Lifetime Achievement Award</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>French Recipes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Madhur Jaffrey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwyn Dunne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anne Frank</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia Child</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walden Township</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bennington College</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New England</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Young Girl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone Beck</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Knopf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manhattan</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One (2009</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doubleday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marion Cunningham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>English-style</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Camus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dutch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louisette Bertholle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frank</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Susan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vermont</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Hersey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Doubleday's Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcella Hazan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryn Teg Farm</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phyllis Hedley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>American Cooks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Art of French</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester Higgins Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JuliaMastering</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
