<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416823853923529</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/03/09/14/venezuelan-president-makes-us-dictator-list-over-civil-unrest-and-claims-of-voter-fraud</url>
  <title>Venezuelan president makes US 'dictator' list over civil unrest and claims of voter fraud</title>
  <content>
Venezuelan president Nicolas Maduro has joined the ranks of Robert Mugabe, Kim Jong-un and Bashar al-Assad after the US added him to its "exclusive dictator" sanction list.

The US branded Maduro on a par with the Zimbabwe, Syria and North Korea leaders after  following Sunday's controversial .

This morning the European Union purported similar restrictions might also be imposed on Venezuela after it announced its refusal to recognise the nation's new radical assembly, saying it could undermine the country's institutions.

EU foreign policy chief Federica Mogherini says the election of the assembly amid violence over the weekend "has durably worsened the crisis in Venezuela".

In the past four months more than 120 people have bene killed including teenagers and a soldier during violent protests.

Opposition activist and a candidate Jose Felix Pineda was shot and killed in his home last weekend and opposition leaders Leopoldo Lopez and Antonio Ledezma  by secret state police and locked in a military prison.

Mogherini said there are doubts about whether the body can represent all parts of Venezuelan society.

Related Articles

Mogherini added the EU and its member countries stand ready to "gradually step up their response in case democratic principles are further undermined".

The president of Venezuela's electoral council, Tibisay Lucena, has slammed accusations by a voter technology firm that the results of the election were tampered with.

The CEO of the voting technology company Smartmatic said the results from the election were void because there was clear evidence of manipulation.

Antonio Mugica told reporters in London on Wednesday there was a discrepancy of one million votes between the turnout figures announced by the government and those recorded by his systems.

"It is therefore with the deepest regret that we have to report that the turnout figures on Sunday, 30 July, for the Constituent Assembly in Venezuela were tampered with," Mugica said.

Smartmatic was a company created by Venezuelans that provided electronic voting machines used during the administration of the late President Hugo Chavez.

Lucena called the CEO's comments "irresponsible and promised said legal actions could be taken against Smartmatic".

The president of Venezuela's opposition-controlled National Assembly, Julio Borges, says the legislature will call for an investigation into the voter fraud claims.

Borges says findings disclosed by Smartmatic provide "complete confirmation" of what opposition leaders and independent analysts had suspected.

The National Electoral Council reported that more than eight million Venezuelans cast ballots for delegates to a government-backed, all-powerful assembly with powers to rewrite the constitution and override any other branch of government.

Opposition leaders questioned that figure and at least one exit poll suggested the turnout was less than half that amount.

US Vice President Mike Pence has urged condemnation of the regime of Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro for the arrest of two top opposition leaders.

Pence said in Montenegro that the US will "hold Maduro personally responsible for the health and safety" of Venezuelan opposition leaders Leopoldo Lopez and Antonio Ledezma.

The two had been under house arrest but security force officers hustled them off to a military prison before dawn on Tuesday.

Pence says that "in recent days we've seen completion of Venezuela's collapse into dictatorship".

"The United States calls all who cherish freedom to condemn the Maduro regime for its abuse of power and its abuse of its own people. Venezuela deserves democracy."
With AP
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>EU</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Ledezma</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Borges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuela</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bashar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julio Borges</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Korea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federica Mogherini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United States</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Felix Pineda</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Jong-un</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Montenegro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Electoral Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constituent Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Mugabe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tibisay Lucena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mogherini</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maduro</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Assembly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>European Union</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Syria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Antonio Mugica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Vice President Mike Pence</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Smartmatic</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>President Hugo Chavez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mugica</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zimbabwe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Venezuelan</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leopoldo Lopez</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
