<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416871098564665</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:00</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/great-white-shark-bites-underwater-camera/8769580</url>
  <title>Great white shark chomps on underwater video camera</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

Ever wondered what the inside of a great white shark's mouth looks like as it bites down on its prey?
Underwater footage captured by a scientist in the US gives us an idea.
Greg Skomal from the Massachusetts Marine and Fisheries Division was tagging great whites with a crew from the Atlantic White Shark Conservancy off Cape Cod when a female shark swam up to his GoPro.
The video, posted on the agency's Facebook page, shows the 3.6-metre shark opening its mouth and taking a bite.
Mr Skomal said he has put a camera in front of hundreds of sharks during his career, but this was "new behaviour".
"I had the camera on a pole in the water and the shark was swimming and I'm thinking, 'I'll get a great view of the face of the shark and that will help us identify it'," he told New England Cable News.
"It kept coming and then opened its mouth and bit it."
Mr Skomal believes it was an "unusual" exploratory bite - the shark was trying to work out what the camera was.
If it had been a predatory action, he said the shark would easily could have destroyed the camera.
Mr Skomal said the shark was not among the 110 animals already tagged by his team for research.
Scientists will now review the video to look at the shark's markings and determine if it is new to the area, or one of the 300 sharks his team has named and keeps records of.
ABC/AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Skomal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cape Cod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Skomal</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New England Cable News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Atlantic White Shark Conservancy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fisheries Division</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC/AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Massachusetts Marine</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GoPro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
