<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416828148890888</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/sport/athletics/australians-riley-day-ella-connolly-take-on-the-world-at-athletics-championships-20170802-gxo79u.html</url>
  <title>From Queensland to London: Aussie teens take on the world</title>
  <content>
Riley Day and Ella Connolly have been in lockstep since they were racing one another in grade five.
That was when they became best friends. Both are now 17 and both still at school. At least they would be at school, were it not for the fact they are in London at the world athletics championships.

Up Next

Teen opens emergency plane exit and jumps

01:07

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Bolt: 'I'm happy to retire now'

The champion sprinter hangs up his running shoes in less than two weeks and says he's ready to enjoy life a bit more.

The two teenagers were late call-ups to the Australian team. School can wait.
Connolly was in the Bahamas when she learned she was picked for the women's 400m relay team. She had just won a mixed relay - of course with Day running one leg - at the Commonwealth Youth Games held in the Caribbean and was preparing to go home.Photo: Supplied
Day, who rose to prominence at this year's Nitro series when she ran against Usain Bolt in Melbourne waved Ella off and wished her speed - if not God's then at least her own - before boarding a plane and heading in the other direction, flying home to Beaudesert near the Tambourine Mountains in Queensland.
"I was at work when mum came in and said I have some good news. I said 'what?' They want you to go to London. I didn't say anything for like 10 minutes, I couldn't believe it," Day said.

"I wouldn't pass up an opportunity like this. It is amazing, especially at 17.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"There were a few pros and cons but the pros outweighed the cons - it's the world championships - I was definitely going to come no matter what. Even if everyone said no I was like 'sorry, see ya'."Photo: Supplied
Connolly interrupted: "I would have made you come".
The pair also can't believe they are here together. Day and Connolly are best friends. They met when they were 11, competing at the National Primary School Championships in Bendigo in 2010.
They only see one another a few times a year because of where they live - Connolly is from Burpengary, north of Brisbane - but instantly pick up where they left off when they meet.
"Being here is amazing ... (but) to have your best friend here, you can't ask more than that," Connolly said.
For Day it is another life goal ticked off. The first one came when she competed at Nitro and was featured on the TV.
"Coming from a small town, The Beaudesert Times was the only publicity I got, so to then being on the news it was one of my life goals to be on the news, no sorry to be on TV. So I ticked that off. Nitro was really good," she said, laughing at herself.
"I still can't believe that I am here."
Nitro elevated her profile after she ran well but she also learned from watching Usain Bolt up close. The Jamaican team is in the same hotel as the Australians in London and Day has seen Bolt in the foyer and restaurant but hasn't spoken to him again yet. She is a bit worried he might have taken some of her trash talking of him in Melbourne to heart. It is doubtful he did.
"Nitro helped me learn not to take things as seriously. Before Nitro I used to get extremely nervous before (racing). After that I learned to calm down a little bit. I tried not to get too worked up in the Bahamas and that worked OK.
"Usain told me, well he didn't ell me but the vibe from him was not to take things so seriously, just have fun with it, do your best and that is all you can hope for and a PB is a bonus."
Everything feels like a bonus now. Plainly the expectations on both are about growth and learning more than performance. That in itself eases the pressure.
"I am only 17, I will just go there and run as fast as I can, I don't know the competition. I don't know my heat or anything, I just want to go there and I will just be running all guns blazing."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Usain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caribbean</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nitro I</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ella Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Connolly</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Riley Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bahamas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bendigo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Primary School Championships</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaudesert Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tambourine Mountains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jamaican</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beaudesert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bolt</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>God</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burpengary</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Youth Games</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
