<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416823853923489</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/inner-south/investor-wins-keys-to-aspendale-home-they-first-saw-that-day/news-story/2ab6f6b2221e774af64f242030a3492b</url>
  <title>Investor wins keys to Aspendale home they first saw that day - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
sold for $1.125 million at auction on July 29.

AN INVESTOR has splashed seven figures on an Aspendale property that they saw for the first time on auction day.
Barry Plant Mordialloc agent Nick Blow said the property at had attracted good interest, with 46 different groups inspecting it in the lead up to its July 29 auction.
Except for the buyer.
"The buyer rolled up on the day - they hadn't been through the property," Mr Blow said.
They won out against four other prospective buyers as the home went under the hammer, he added.
"We had five bidders, and it was a competitive auction," he said.
Mr Blow said the contest pushed bidding well beyond the property's $1.05 million reserve, and it sold for $1.125 million.
He said the buyer, an investor from outside of the area, beat a home builder, a potential owner-occupier, and another investor to the keys.
"It was a real mixed bag," Mr Blow said.
He said the result for the property was a more than $300,000 improvement on its last sale price from less than two years ago, something that was testament to strong price growth in the area.
"The market in Aspendale has really moved in that time," he said.

The property is two blocks from the bay and features a large yard.

Mr Blow said the unrenovated four-bedroom home on 621sq m is two blocks from the bay, and this location had appealed foremost to buyers.
"Its so close to the shops, beach, and train station," he said.
Mr Blow said properties in need of some TLC were selling especially well in the region.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TLC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASPENDALE</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Blow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Blow</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry Plant Mordialloc</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
