<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416312752805844</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-03/does-scathing-report-on-ord-irrigation-scheme-add-up/8759732</url>
  <title>Does scathing report on Ord Irrigation Scheme add up?</title>
  <content>
A Broome-based environmental group paid a Canberra-based think tank to research the economics of the Kimberley's Ord Irrigation Scheme, and the results have left the community of Kununurra feeling undervalued and frustrated. ABC Rural's Matt Brann takes a look at the Australia Institute's report, the motives behind its commissioning, and whether it holds any water.
Kununurra not valued in report

Called Dam the Expense, the  claimed more than $1.5 billion of taxpayer money had been spent on the irrigation scheme since 1959 for little return, and that only 260 people were employed by agriculture in the region.

Ord Irrigation Scheme fact box

Ord Irrigation Scheme history:

Town of Kununurra gazetted in 1961 as construction begins on the Ord Irrigation Scheme
Ord River Diversion Dam completed in 1963 and officially opened by prime minister Robert Menzies
Ord River Dam (Lake Argyle) officially opened in 1972
Argyle Diamond mine commissioned in 1985, pumping water from the southern end of Argyle
Ord Hydro Scheme opened in 1996, supplying electricity to Kununurra, Wyndham and the Argyle Diamond mine
Kimberley Agricultural Investment (KAI) named as preferred developer of Ord Stage 2 in 2012

The report did not put a value on other benefits such as local tourism, , hydro electricity and the entire town of Kununurra - all of which would not exist if the Ord River had never been dammed.
Speaking to ABC Rural, the report's author Rod Campbell agreed those benefits "should be considered", but when asked why his report did not consider them, replied "because nobody else has".
"Our study is largely a compilation of other studies and none of those things have been highlighted before," he said.
"I'm surprised the WA auditor general didn't look into some of those impacts, because things like that should be considered in an economic assessment of an investment."
Despite not assessing all of the benefits of the Ord scheme, Mr Campbell denied the oversight damaged the credibility of the report's conclusions.
"When the data is not there and not made available ... it would be great to have a lot more detailed information, but this [the report's conclusion] is not a new conclusion," he said.

"Economists have been concerned about the Ord as an investment since it was first proposed."

Report strikes a nerve with locals

The town of Kununurra has become used to reports and southern media taking swipes at the region, but a quick look at the local community Facebook page shows the latest report has struck a nerve.
"This scheme is the lifeblood of our town," wrote local electrician Neil Portas.
"The [Australia] Institute found that there was currently 260 agricultural jobs created, [but] I wonder if this includes the transport drivers that transport the goods in and out, or the port operators.
"Or the local businesses that maintain the machinery, or the people that supply the local produce to the local hotels to feed the tourists who are here to look at the beautiful water in the lake?
"I wonder how much they paid for this inquiry?"

The Ord River is a site for community events, including the annual Kimberley Moon Experience concert.

The Ord River is a site for community events, including the annual Kimberley Moon Experience concert.

Supplied: Ben Broadwith

How much did Environs Kimberley pay and why?

The Australia Institute said the Ord report was assisted by the Broome-based Environs Kimberley "through financial support and local knowledge of the Kimberley region".
Neither Mr Campbell or Environs Kimberley director Martin Pritchard would disclose how much money was paid for the report.
Mr Pritchard said the money paid to the Australia Institute was irrelevant.
"What I would say is that in terms of what the report has shown, the cost of it [the report] is not really relative to the view of what's been happening in Kununurra," he said.
"We've got this massive push for agriculture across northern Australia through things such as .

"And if there's going to be a push for development in northern Australia, we think most people in the community would like to see what the costs and benefits are."

Mr Pritchard said the purpose of the report was to look at agriculture and not "side benefits" of the Ord Scheme.
"The main purpose of the dam was to create agricultural areas, and if we're going to look at it in terms of public investment, then let's have a proper look at it and see what it has actually produced," he said.
"We've done the research, people can have a look at it, [and] if they want to knock it that's fine, but the numbers speak for themselves."

Environs Kimberley's Martin Pritchard says people are interested in the costs and benefits of the scheme.

Environs Kimberley's Martin Pritchard says people are interested in the costs and benefits of the scheme.

Supplied: Ben Broadwith

Report has a paucity of detail, economist says

Agricultural economist Francis Bright, who has worked in northern Australia for 15 years, said the report by the Australia Institute was easy to read but lacked detail.
"It's picked out various facts without looking at all of the facts that are available," he said.
"I'm a bit disappointed that there's been no efforts made to obtain the value of production out of the Ord since the early 1990s, which is information that is freely available and in the public domain through the local Department of Agriculture.

"In terms of primary data sources, I can't see any acknowledgment or recognition of people they actually spoke to in the East Kimberley.

"Where is the ABARES data? Where is the Department of Agriculture's data on the production which has come from the Ord?"
Mr Bright said the report's headline figure of $2 billion spent on the Ord, of which more than $1.5 billion was public money, was intriguing, given the figures were the result of converting all investments into 2016 dollars.
"You can do it, but over that sort of timeframe there are problems," he said.
"Using a cost benefit framework to compound stuff from the early 1960s into 2016 dollars, that's a really long timeframe, cost benefit analyses normally have a timeframe of 10 to 20 years.
"And the other omission in this report is, what was their compounding rate? What were they multiplying by to get to 2016 dollars? And is that reasonable?
"I'd be very careful at looking at this sort of report."
Mr Campbell told ABC Rural the organisation did not speak to anyone from Kununurra during the research period.
One source it did rely on was a , which in 2013 was commissioned by the Wilderness Society to research the economics of the Ord.
Called 'Rivers, rivers, everywhere', the report estimated that about $1.45 billion had been spent on the Ord Irrigation Scheme for a return of 17 cents for every dollar spent - a conclusion repeated by the Australia Institute's report released on Friday.
Both reports made assumptions on the value of the Ord's irrigated agriculture during 1992 to 2012.

Environmental groups have been citing the Australia Institute's report to promote concerns about the Ord expansion project.

Environmental groups have been citing the Australia Institute's report to promote concerns about the Ord expansion project.

Supplied: Facebook

Environment groups using report to argue against expansion

Environs Kimberley and the Wilderness Society have voiced concerns about the current Ord expansion on their respective Facebook pages, using the Australia Institute's report to question why more money should be spent on the "failing Ord River Scheme".
The company at the heart of the expansion plan is Kimberley Agricultural Investment (KAI), which has made no secret of its desire to spend upwards of $700 million to
It has recently applied to develop just over 3,000 hectares of freehold land on
Environs Kimberley describes the application as a "massive land clearing proposal" adjacent to a Ramsar-listed wetland.
"When we first saw the application by KAI we were really shocked," Mr Pritchard said.
"We actually met with the Department of Environment Regulation and basically it was the largest land clearing application that had come before them in a very long time.
"We're just concerned and any assessment of this area needs to be done thoroughly."
The Wilderness Society on its Facebook page said it had written to the state EPA "telling them to assess this at the highest possible level".
Private company willing to invest in Ord's future

While most people in Kununurra would agree the scheme has received plenty of government funding, it has now attracted a private company, KAI, that is willing to spend millions of dollars developing land and building processing facilities that would lead to significant job creation.
The Australia Institute's report relies heavily on a cost-benefit analysis carried out in 1993 by Hassall and Associates, which goes on to endorse the Ord's expansion.
That report, called The Ord River Irrigation Project Past, Present and Future, found the Ord project from 1959 to 1991 had resulted in a net loss to the nation of $497 million (in 1990/91 dollars) - a value the Australia Institute converted to more than $900 million in "2016 dollars".
However, the Australia Institute did not add Hassall and Associates' other conclusion, which was from 1988, that the total annual benefits of the Ord scheme had consistently exceeded annual costs and that "if the Ord project is to ultimately provide a net positive return to the nation, the release and development of additional land for irrigated agricultural production must be facilitated".
"Indeed, it is a remarkable achievement that annual total-project benefit generated from just 12,000 hectares of land now exceed the annual costs of a project designed to irrigate 70,000 hectares," the report read.
Back at the Kununurra community Facebook page, local business owner Chris Magnay provides his conclusion of the Australia Institute's report, writing, "I think report is a very generous word. Have a read and decide for yourself."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Broadwith</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord Stage 2</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord River Diversion Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broome-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Environment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wyndham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord River Irrigation Project Past</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Magnay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Town of Kununurra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KAI</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Rural's Matt Brann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley Agricultural Investment</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley's Ord Irrigation Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Environs Kimberley</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Rural</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pritchard</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hassall</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Portas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Martin Pritchard</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABARES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Menzies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Campbell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley's Martin Pritchard</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Campbell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord River Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wilderness Society</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord Irrigation Scheme</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberley Moon Experience</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Argyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kununurra</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Argyle Diamond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>East Kimberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord Hydro Scheme</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Institute</name>
    <count>12</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Does</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramsar-listed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Agriculture</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord River</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Broome-based Environs Kimberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ord River Dam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Francis Bright</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
