<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416398652153385</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/sport/the-quarterback-the-brownlow-medal-needs-tweaking-not-transforming/news-story/dbbeaadf63dae23c26c1d46a43b508e6</url>
  <title>The tweaks the Brownlow needs</title>
  <content>
THE Brownlow Medal needs a makeover, not a facelift.
The rules of eligibility simply don't reflect the modern game.
But first, some context.
The match review panel got it right when it handed Patrick Dangerfield a two-match ban, reduced to one with an early guilty plea.
It was classified as careless conduct with medium impact to the head.
Forget the science behind the one or two motion tackle or the duty of care. Dangerfield put Carlton ruckman Matthew Kreuzer at serious risk by pinning his arms and driving him head first into the the turf. Kreuzer failed a concussion test and took no further part in the game.
Brownlow bombshell

Now if you dispute that, swap the jumpers. What if Kreuzer had committed the same tackle on Dangerfield, ruling the Cat out for the remainder of the game? As good as Kreuzer's season has been, there is probably no Brownlow at stake and so no argument.
Geelong also got it right when they chose not to challenge and risk a two-match suspension.
And Dangerfield handled the drama like the consummate professional he is, putting the team and their pursuit of a premiership ahead of his own interests.
Yes, it is disappointing he can't win the Brownlow, but as the rules stand it's a just decision.
It seems every year there is controversy over a MRP decision that rules a player ineligible for the Brownlow.
I was once a proponent of taking the "fairest" out of the equation and there is still merit in that argument because the suspended player is punished anyway by missing matches he can't poll votes in.
But I have tempered that opinion.
The Brownlow Medal is unique because it takes in the fairest component and is also judged purely by the umpires.
Take that away and it's really no different to the AFL Players' Association's Most Valuable Player award, better known as the Leigh Matthews Trophy.
In that award, the players hand out 3,2,1 votes for the best player in the competition (they can't vote for a teammate). Suspension doesn't come into it.
The Brownlow needs tweaking not transforming.
As the AFL enforces a duty of care on the competition and tries to attract a new generation of kids and parents to the game wave, the head is sacrosanct. Players are now suspended for incidents that wouldn't have warranted a column centimetre in a newspaper or a single mention on a digital media platform in the past.
Tummy taps cop a week too.
That's not necessarily a bad thing, as the game needs those numbers coming up from beneath.
But the landscape has changed and the AFL needs to move with that transformation.
Sam Mitchell's retirement press conference

It would make more sense to have a tipping point for ineligibility.
A two-week suspension handed out by the MRP is at the lighter end of transgressions - watered down to one with an early guilty plea - so those players should still be eligible for the Brownlow. Three matches or more from the MRP or the AFL Tribunal would rule a player ineligible.
As for Dangerfield, he clearly cares more about winning a flag than he does about being awarded a second Brownlow right now. His teammates know it now by his actions and that may well galvanise the group. There odds are he'll win one or two more anyway.
In any case, he's been suffering from a sore foot and the break in the lead-up to September might just be perfect timing.
Heaven help the Cats' finals opponents if he returns even better.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MRP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brownlow Medal</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kreuzer</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leigh Matthews Trophy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patrick Dangerfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Players' Association's Most Valuable Player</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Kreuzer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geelong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dangerfield</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AFL Tribunal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
