<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416866803597273</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:59</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/sport/football/neymar-to-psg-how-much-will-he-earn-financial-fair-play-barcelona-uefa-appeal/news-story/54e6861df8545d8a04ae761fdeef382c</url>
  <title>'Financial Doping': Dark side of Neymar's $747m deal</title>
  <content>
THE numbers are dizzying, even in football's crazy world of exorbitant fees.
. That's $67m a year before tax, or $44.49m after tax.
He eclipses the latest deals signed by Cristiano Ronaldo and Lionel Messi, as well as the absurd money earned by Carlos Tevez in China.
, who will have to stump up $328.7m to Barcelona to execute the Brazilian's release clause.
United boss Jose Mourinho weighed in on the mind boggling fee, saying Neymar's worth is only relative to the other inflated payments going around the market.
"When we paid that amount for Paul [Pogba] I said that he was not expensive," said Mourinho. "Expensive are the ones that get into a certain level without a certain quality. I think with Neymar it is going to happen the same [as Pogba]. I don't think he's expensive for £200 million. I think he's expensive for the fact that you are going to have more players of £100 million and more players of £80 million and more players of £60 million.
"I think that's the problem because Neymar is one of the best players in the world. Commercially he's very strong and for sure Paris Saint-Germain thought about it. So I don't think the problem is Neymar, it's the consequences after Neymar."

To put that into perspective, PSG will spend more on Neymar's transfer fee than 13 Premier League clubs' total squad's transfer fees (except Tottenham, Everton, Liverpool, Arsenal, Chelsea, Manchester United and Manchester City -see index at foot of the article).

Football: Lionel Messi has paid tribute to departing teammate Neymar.

Messi's tribute to Neymar
The big question now is: how on earth does Paris Saint-Germain conform to Financial Fair Play regulations, where clubs are not permitted to make losses in excess of €5 million over three years (with owners allowed to spend €30m of their own money above and beyond as well).

Football: Neymar has agreed to a five-year contract with French club PSG.

Neymar agrees to PSG deal
At a time UEFA is supposed to curb clubs spending beyond their income, according to The Telegraph, Neymar's deal could cost almost one quarter of the club's annual revenue.
By enforcing Neymar's release clause, Barcelona will command the entire $328.7m to be paid up front and in full by PSG, as opposed to allowing it to be paid in instalments like a normal transfer fee.
The release clause was set at an astronomical mark to prevent a club like PSG muscling in, so its execution has prompted demands for UEFA, European football's governing body, to look into how the deal is being financed, with particular attention being paid to PSG's owners, the Qatari Sports Investments group.
There are concerns about reports that he is being paid separately to become an ambassador for the 2022 World Cup finals in Qatar for $448m, which could be construed as a payment to try and sneak around the FFP regulation.
There are also reports that the Qatari state might pay Neymar's release clause - thus, PSG would not have paid the transfer fee. Heck, if Neymar's earning that coin to be an ambassador, he can even pay the release clause himself!
Any deal with sponsors related to club owners should spark the ire of FFP regulators, with the deal susceptible to be deemed as a way to disguise payments from club owners, or as another mechanism to inflate, artificially, the club's coffers.
La Liga president Javier Tebas has brought these suspicions to the fore, declaring PSG guilty of "financial doping".
"Basically, LaLiga will denounce the unfairness of competing against state-backed clubs; the teams that receive economic investment from countries that gift players to their fans at the cost of taking them from other clubs.
"In terms of PSG, it is a clear case of 'financial doping', with the club and the state. PSG's accounts show that they have a larger commercial income than Real Madrid and Manchester United, which is to say that the value of their brand is greater than those clubs. Well, that is impossible."
He continued: "If UEFA don't react, we will present the claim immediately. We haven't done it yet because we thought that UEFA were going to take measures to ensure that Financial Fair Play (FFP) is respected, and this 'financial doping' is avoided.
"I am surprised that the individual responsible for FFP, Andrea Traverso, vouches for the checks that PSG's losses do not exceed €30m over the course of three years. Traverso knows that checking that data is not the problem.
"The problems are whether PSG have inflated their income, and checks in to the origins and economic bulk of their sponsors. If they [the sponsors] come from Qatar and they are difficult to explain, then we have a clear case of 'financial doping'."
PSG could also try and circumvent it by back-ending Neymar's deal, to allow them to sell some of their pricier stars in the meantime.
But by then, will UEFA have the gumption to investigate, and inflict some of its potential punishments, including fines, or restricted squad sizes in the Champions League?
Even Liverpool boss Jurgen Klopp, who continues to swat away speculation linking Philippe Coutinho to Barcelona as Neymar's replacement, weighed in overnight.
"There are clubs that can pay fees like that - Man City and PSG. Everyone knows that.
"I thought Fair Play was made so that situations like that can't happen.
"That's more of a suggestion than a real rule. I don't understand that. I don't know how it happens.
"That's not the next step I hope.
"I think and hope it will stay an exception but we don't know."
Neymar's wealth is even more staggering given his off-field endorsements with the likes of Nike, Gillette, Panasonic and Beats by Dre, which net him over $28m a year outside of his football exploits.
What PSG paid for Neymar: £198m.
What Premier League clubs paid for their squad's transfer fees (source The Mirror)
Brighton: £25,605,000
Huddersfield: £52,420,000
Burnley: £68,950,000
West Brom: £70,750,000
Swansea: £83,650,000
Bournemouth: £90,250,000
Stoke: £96,950,000
Watford: £97,600,000
Crystal Palace: £139,735,000
Newcastle: £144,300,000Leicester: £144,400,000
Southampton: £149,550,000
West Ham: £150,950,000
Tottenham: £207,900,000
Everton: £226,150,000
Liverpool: £331,100,000
Arsenal: £379,650,000
Chelsea: £468,300,000
Man United: £593,000,000
Man City: £727,500,000
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnley: £68,950,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea: £468,300,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Madrid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nike</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsenal: £379,650,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javier Tebas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watford: £97,600,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arsenal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huddersfield: £52,420,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Ham: £150,950,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cristiano Ronaldo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Man City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool: £331,100,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Brom: £70,750,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Swansea: £83,650,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carlos Tevez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Premier League</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Fair Play</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chelsea</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tottenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Liga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>United: £593,000,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pogba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fair Play</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tottenham: £207,900,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LaLiga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liverpool</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>15</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stoke: £96,950,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everton: £226,150,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle: £144,300,000Leicester: £144,400,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crystal Palace: £139,735,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>City: £727,500,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Philippe Coutinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telegraph</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Panasonic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Everton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brighton: £25,605,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Messi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar's $747</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jurgen Klopp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatari Sports Investment</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bournemouth: £90,250,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southampton: £149,550,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrea Traverso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Traverso</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>18</count>
    <score>15</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gillette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
