<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416140954110339</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/finance/business/retail/i-need-a-new-team-gumtree-advertisement-offers-friendship-services-in-viral-marketing-post/news-story/ad67483399d65b8940f0827f4f64e82d</url>
  <title>'I need a new team': Gumtree advertisement offers friendship services in viral marketing post</title>
  <content>
A Perth man posting under the pseudonym James Dorman has offered his friendship online. Picture: Gumtree.

Share

WHETHER it's biting satire or marketing genius - one Gumtree post has cut to the heart of a major issue in our smartphone-addled lives.
A Perth man posting under the pseudonym James Dorsman has offering his "amazing friendship" after realising he was sick and tired of having the same old conversations with his mates.
At least that's what the post would have you believe were it not for cryptic references to  - a card game currently fundraising on Kickstarter that bills itself as building "life-changing conversations".
In the post, the 31-year-old self-described "good all 'round bloke" said he needs "new friends" as "I can't stand my current ones".
"James" promises he won't "check my phone while talking to you ... I can go out and enjoy myself without needing 24 shots of tequila or alcohol through IV. I actually read books".

Sounds like a pretty ideal friend. Picture: Gumtree.Source:Supplied
The married man said he decided he needed a new crew after realising all he talked about with mates was "d*cks", "MasterChef", "Trump," "their 50th start-up idea that they won't even start".
He claims he doesn't want to waste his thirties getting drunk and sharing pictures on Whatsapp.
"I need a new team," he writes. "I need friends that are kinda like me."
"So I am offering my services of ... being a good bloke ... someone who likes to read, learn, and can have educated discussions."

While the lament on phone-addicted friends and drunken conversations might ring true for many, the advertisement is not all it seems.
The brains behind card game Jouska, Jasky Singh, said he "strongly suspects" the post is the work of his business partner, Chris Patton, who has nailed the "vision" in a tongue in cheek way.
"I think it would be my business partner, he's probably clever enough to pull this off," he joked after news.com.au bought the ad to his attention.

Jasky Singh and his wife Aesha are behind a card game called Jouska currently raising money on Kickstarter. Picture: Kickstarter.Source:Supplied
Mr Singh developed the game with his wife Aesha following the death of his mother three years ago, after realising that time with loved ones was not to be squandered.
"You come to the realisation that life is short so when you get those moments to spend time with people that matter, you don't want to waste those opportunities," he told news.com.au
"Having those deep conversations are more enjoyable."
Jouska is defined online as a "hypothetical conversation that you compulsively play out in your head". The game version is made up of a series of cards to evoke emotionally confronting scenarios with questions like "What would you want to hear at your eulogy?" and "What would you do if you found a friend's phone unlocked?".
Mr Singh said ever scenario has been "thoroughly tested" and "hopefully it gets people to connect a little bit more."
It's already raised more than secured $2800 of their $14995 goal with 21 days to go.
Gumtree and "James Dorsman" have been contacted for comment.
Jouska is expected to begin shipping in October 2017

Perth entrepreneur Jasky Singh. Picture: Facebook.Source:Supplied
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>IV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Singh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumtree</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gumtree.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jasky Singh</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterchef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jouska</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WhatsApp</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trump</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Dorsman</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Patton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kickstarter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>James Dorman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aesha</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kickstarter.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
