<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416780904249736</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/business/banking-and-finance/suncorp-raises-dividend-confident-in-outlook-20170802-gxo7yb.html</url>
  <title>Suncorp raises dividend, confident in outlook</title>
  <content>
Suncorp has lifted dividends paid over the full year by 7 per cent and said it would maintain a high payout ratio in 2018, a sign of confidence as the company benefits from rising insurance prices.
The financial services conglomerate on Thursday notched up a full-year cash profit of $1.075 billion, an increase of 3.6 per cent on last year, helped by a strong performance in its insurance arm.

Up Next

ASX winners and losers - a snapshot

00:43

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Can earnings shake life back into the ASX 200?

What to expect this week as the corporate reporting calendar starts. This video was produced in commercial partnership between Fairfax Media and IG Markets.

With insurance prices rising and claim costs contained by low inflation, insurance profits surged 30 per cent to $723 million.
Although banking and wealth earnings were more subdued, Suncorp lifted the final dividend by 2¢ to 40¢ a share. The increase takes dividends paid over the full year to 73¢ a share, up 7 per cent on last year.Photo: Nick Moir
The group's dividend payout ratio was pushed to 81.9 per cent - slightly above its target range, which it said "reflects the board's confidence in the outlook for the group". 
"The final dividend reflects momentum in growth driven by Suncorp's refined strategy and focus on the customer, as well as evidence of a hardening insurance market," chairman Ziggy Switkowski said.

"The group remains well capitalised and has a diversified earnings base that continues to provide a strong foundation to create value for our customers, shareholders, employees and communities." 

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

In its outlook, Suncorp said it planned to lift the dividend payout ratio above its 60 to 80 per cent target range in the coming 2018 financial year, in order to offset the impact of extra investment spending.
It also pointed to "improving" net profit and a commitment to return surplus capital to shareholders.
Suncorp is the owner of major insurance brands including AAMI, GIO, Bingle and APIA, and the results showed 3.9 per cent growth in gross written premium.
It also released $301 million in reserves that had been set aside old claims, an amount it said was "well above long-term expectations" and a reflection of very low inflation. Its rival Insurance Australia Group benefited from a similar dynamic, l.
Its outlook said "positive price momentum" was expected to continue in 2018 in its consumer insurance business - a sign customers can expect premium increases.
The final dividend reflects momentum in growth driven by Suncorp's refined strategy and focus on the customer, as well as evidence of a hardening insurance market.
Chairman Ziggy Switkowski

Suncorp's banking and wealth profits fell to $400 million, down from $418 million last year, as lenders face slower credit growth and Suncorp invested in a technology revamp of its banking systems. 
Lending growth slowed to 1.9 per cent over the year, down from 4.55 per cent a year ago, after regulators put the brakes on the mortgage market. Its net interest margin - what it charges for loans compared with its cost of funds - narrowed slightly to 1.83 per cent.
Chief executive Michael Cameron said in the year it had turned around outflows in customer numbers, with the overall number of customers now growing. 
"Broadening and deepening relationships with our customers will unlock significant future value for shareholders," he said.
It will invest an extra $100 million in its goal of developing a "marketplace" for financial services, an overhaul of its online presence, physical stores and brokers.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ziggy Switkowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman Ziggy Switkowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Suncorp</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>9</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IG Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cameron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insurance Australia Group</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.33</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bingle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Moir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX 200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAMI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
