<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416965587847017</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/proximity-privacy-and-style/3208232/</url>
  <title>Proximity, privacy and style</title>
  <content>
POSITIONED on the curve of the river bank, this truly remarkable site offers one of the most serene and private outlooks on Noosa Sound while being a short stroll from Noosa's exclusive dining precinct and protected beaches.
If you are looking for a home that offers supreme privacy and is built to the highest standard then do not hesitate.
Great homes all have something in common. They start with a truly remarkable site and they are enhanced by inspired design.
Designed and built by one of Australia's most decorated and accomplished designers, Di Henshall, it is abundantly clear that she is acutely aware of the environment of the site and all aspects of this remarkable position have been leveraged.
Immediately as you enter the property the phenomenal design and impeccable detail is realised. Starting with the feature lighting and ponds that continue throughout the house, to the strategically positioned windows that give the entire house a feeling of transparency and consistent light.
The unique architectural attributes are further instilled by the dramatic staircase and juliet balcony below an eight-metre void with glass ceiling.
Privacy is paramount in this property, offering views across Noosa River all the way to Mt Cooroy without the hint of a neighbour from the entertaining areas.
Entertaining is at the forefront of the design as highlighted by the billiard room with full bar including sink, dishwasher, three temperature controlled fridges and a gas strut window opening onto the rear deck.
The western aspect ensures the well-integrated pool is consistently basking in the afternoon sun. Clever roof lines, electric Vergolas and awnings as well as motorised blinds ensure the sun is kept off the house in the hotter summer months.
When winter rolls around simply switch on the heated flooring, warming the kitchen and dining area as well as the external sunset lounge.
Five full-size bedrooms all with ensuites ensure you and your guests have ample accommodation, while in the master you have the ultimate feeling of grandeur and luxury with a floor-to-ceiling window next to the retreat, two walk-in robes and an ensuite with one of the most enviable views.
NOOSA SOUND
35 Dolphin Cres
5 Bed, 5 Bath, 2 Car, Pool
Features: Designer waterfront house with pool, entertaining wing. Impeccable attention to detail including award-winning kitchen with heated flooring
Price: Price guide $3,800,000
Agent: Adrian Reed and Darren Neal at Dowling Neylan Real Estate
Contact: 0409 446 955, 0401 212 505
Inspection: Saturday 11-11.30am
A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bed, 5 Bath, 2 Car</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Di Henshall</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dolphin Cres</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adrian Reed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mt Cooroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vergolas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darren Neal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dowling Neylan Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa Sound</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
