<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417081551965601</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:49</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/south-east/amazon-confirms-huge-fulfilment-centre-to-open-in-dandenong-south/news-story/7d300b6fb716549aa846a810251c93f0</url>
  <title>Amazon confirms it's Dandenong-bound</title>
  <content>
AMAZON has today confirmed it will open its first Australian distribution centre in Dandenong South, bringing hundreds of jobs to the region.
Leader recently reported the online retail giant had been advertising management positions based in Dandenong South and the retail giant now say they will begin recruiting pickers, packers, systems technicians, and HR specialists immediately.

The new 24,000 sqm "fulfilment centre" will be located in the Pellicano's M2 Industry Park in Dandenong South, providing easy access to the South Gippsland Highway, Monash Highway and EastLink.
Amazon's director of operations for Australia Robert Bruce said the company was thrilled to be creating jobs in Dandenong South and said thousands more roles would be brought to Australia as the company expands.

"Over time, we will bring thousands of new jobs to Australia and millions of dollars of investment as well as opening up the opportunity for thousands of Australian businesses to sell at home and abroad through Amazon Marketplace," Mr Bruce said.
"This new fulfilment centre will stock hundreds of thousands of products which will be available for delivery to customers across Australia when we launch our retail offering.
"We will be focusing on offering our Australian customers low prices on a great selection of products and can't wait to get started."
Dandenong state Labor MP Gabrielle Williams said the development further cemented Dandenong South as a key place to do business.
People interested in applying for jobs at Amazon should visit
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pellicano's M2 Industry Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Robert Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monash Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong-bound</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>EastLink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Gippsland Highway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong South</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labor MP Gabrielle Williams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
