<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416961292879705</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:21</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-surfers-claim-top-honours-at-australian-surf/3208234/</url>
  <title>Coast surfers claim top honours at Australian Surf Festival</title>
  <content>
SURFING: Sunshine Coast surfing talent was among several  newly crowned national champions following the Australian Surf Festival.
Mooloolah Valley's Les Aberley and Noosaville's David Cousins dominated the four-foot waves at Duranbah Beach in New South Wales yesterday to be awarded Australian Surfmasters Champions.
Aberley surfed well in the Over-55 Men's class to score 14.75 in the final while Cousins hit the surf in the Over-60 Men's division and put in a score of 15.15 for the win.
The duo weren't the only Coast surfers in the festival's finals, with Coolum's Jye Gofton claiming a third placing in the Over-40 Men's with a score of 12.80 and fellow Coolum surfer Paul Wayland making an impression with a score of 13.25 to claim third in the Over-45 Men's division.
-On the international stage, Sunshine Coast surfer Keely Andrew has been knocked out of the Championship Tour's Vans US Open of Surfing at Huntington Beach in California.
Andrew was defeated by Sally Fitzgibbons in round one, heat four of the event and was eliminated by Silvana Lima in round two, heat one.
A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>New South Wales</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Championship Tour's Vans US Open of Surfing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Wayland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Silvana Lima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Surfmasters Champions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duranbah Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mooloolah Valley's Les Aberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coolum's Jye Gofton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Fitzgibbons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Surf Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aberley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosaville's David Cousins</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Keely Andrew</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
