<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417004242553193</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/national/2017/08/03/10/02/triple-j-hottest-100</url>
  <title>Triple J reviews Hottest 100 countdown Australia Day date</title>
  <content>
Triple J is reviewing the date of its Hottest 100 countdown after growing national debate about holding the iconic event on Australia Day.
Triple J - which is part of the ABC - is asking its audience to share their thoughts on holding the countdown on January 26.
"You'll see it's not a yes or no survey - we've included a mix of closed and open-ended questions to encourage your considered responses. We want to hear the thoughts around your opinion, as well as how you personally relate to the Hottest 100," a explaining the process said.
"Your comments will be used by Triple J to help shape our decision, alongside the perspectives and learnings from other stakeholders we have spoken to. The outcome will be announced in the coming months."
Triple J kept its annual Hottest 100 on Australia Day this year, with a post at the time acknowledging discussions around the date.
"Triple J is heavily involved in the growing dialogue around Indigenous recognition and perspectives on 26 January. This is really important to us," it said.
"We will continue to talk to Indigenous communities, artists and our audience about the date for the Hottest 100 in future years. In short: it's under review.

Related Articles

"We want the Hottest 100 to be an inclusive and respectful event for all Australians, including all the incredible Indigenous artists making great Australian music, and the listeners from all cultural backgrounds who love it."
The survey asks users a variety of questions starting with how often they listen to Triple J, moving through to their relationship with the Hottest 100 and if they view it as being an essential part of Australia Day celebrations and ending with questions around the values of Triple J.
Questions around hosting the annual countdown on January 26 come as increasing pressure is placed around the suitability of the date as a celebration for the birth of Australia as a nation.
Indigenous groups argue the date is tarred with bloodshed, and is a date of mourning for their people.
Last year the mayor of Fremantle in Western Australia decided to shift the city's Australia Day fireworks away from January 26 out of respect to indigenous people, with the celebrations to occur on the weekend instead.
"It's come as an attack on Australia Day when it's not really that," he .
Last year saw proposed alternative dates start to gain attention in the media and amongst the public, with comedian and Axis of Awesome frontwoman Jordan Raskopoulos proposing Australia celebrate the nation as a whole on May 8.
Triple J said its decision on a potential date change "will be announced in the coming months".
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Axis of Awesome</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hottest 100</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 26</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Triple J</name>
    <count>9</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Day</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fremantle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jordan Raskopoulos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Indigenous</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
