<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416527501174527</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/missing-girl-morayfield/3208176/</url>
  <title>16-year-old girl missing from Morayfield</title>
  <content>
Police are appealing for public assistance to help locate a girl missing form Morayfield.

The 16-year-old was last seen at a home on Petersen Road in the afternoon of July 23.

She had remained in contact with family up until July 28, but they have not heard from her since.

Police and family are concerned for her welfare due to her age.

She is described as Caucasian in appearance, around 171 centimetres tall with long brown hair and blue eyes.

Anyone who may have seen her is urged to contact police.

If you have information for police, contact Policelink on 131 444 or provide information using the online form 24hrs per day.
You can report information about crime anonymously to Crime Stoppers, a registered charity and community volunteer organisation, by calling 1800 333 000 or via crimestoppersqld.com.au 24hrs per day.
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
Grant Kenny asks council to ditch Maroochy River rock wall concept
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Petersen Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Policelink</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morayfield</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochy River</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crime Stoppers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caucasians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grant Kenny</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
