<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417038602291997</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/mental-health-problems-facing-young-people/8759454</url>
  <title>Mark is 11. He likes Minecraft and Lego. He also wants to kill himself</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

Related Story:

This is 11-year-old Mark, who in many ways, is just like most other boys his age.
He likes to go the local park, play Minecraft on his computer, build things with Lego and play for his junior cricket club.
But at times Mark also wants to kill himself.

If you or someone you know needs help, call:

His mother, Louise, said her son became a different child after his father took his own life when Mark was just three.
He also lost his mother for a time as she struggled with the immense grief that came with losing her husband.
Now Louise is another relationship, is putting her life back together and Mark is receiving counselling.
His case is considered urgent, but at his age there are not many places to treat a child with Mark's problems.
He is currently in the hands of Western Australia's Child and Adolescent Mental Health Service (CAMHS), but that expires when he turns 12 in September.
Youth mental health a 'potential epidemic'

Enter  -an independent, West Australian not-for-profit organisation working to stop youth suicide.
Youth Focus works with people aged between 12 and 25 to help them overcome issues associated with depression, anxiety, self-harm and suicidal thoughts through free, unlimited and professional face-to-face counselling.
But Youth Focus needs corporate funds and donations to do its job.
Chief executive officer Fiona Kalaf said the organisation had identified more than 82,000 young West Australians who could benefit from its help.
She did not like the expression "epidemic", but she said the term was hard to avoid.
"Yes, potentially there is a bit of an epidemic," she said.
"What we do know is statistically 48 per cent of all Australians will experience some form of mental illness in the course of their life. That's more common than breaking a limb."
Ellie O'Grady, 23, is a university student who has been involved with Youth Focus for years.
Her family raises funds for the organisation, while she is a member of a reference group.

She has long suffered from anxiety and has taken to helping her friends with similar issues.
"Being involved with Youth Focus has made me more open to talking about it and, yes, there is still a stigma about mental health which stops a lot of young people from asking for help," she said.
Youth depression is on the rise: Headspace CEO

The Federal Government also offers a fully-funded service for 12 to 25-year-olds to help tackle mental health issues in Australia's youth via the .
It announced additional Headspace centres across the country in its May budget.
Two new ones have opened in WA, one in Mandurah and the other in the Pilbara, which is more of an outreach centre for those living in remote areas.

Headspace acting chief executive officer Matthew Posar said youth depression was on the rise.
"It does appear to be increasing anecdotally. I think that's why the Government continues to invest in services like Headspace to meet that demand particularly among young people," he said.
Fiona Kalaf said young people wanting to use the free services provided by Youth Focus would normally have to wait.
"It depends on where they are physically located but it is typically about two weeks," she said.
Ms Kalaf said it was unacceptable that Australian children as young as 10 were taking their own lives and some as young as eight were attempting to take their own lives.
She said the organisation currently had the funding needed to maintain its services, but Mark's mother Louise said she was scared this may change in the future.
"I can't afford psychiatric care for Mark and I'm scared that without outside intervention, he may unwittingly fatally hurt himself while trying to self-harm."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>WA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lego</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Posar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mandurah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia's Child</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ellie O'Grady, 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Kalaf</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CAMHS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fiona Kalaf</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minecraft</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louise</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adolescent Mental Health Service</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Youth Focus</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>September</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
