<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417047192226748</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/queensland/cops-called-over-camp-ground-squatters/news-story/5115934e8165fcf32bc051085211903a</url>
  <title>Cops called over camp ground</title>
  <content>
CLAIMS of squatters at a popular southeast Queensland camp ground have been referred to police, following allegations of alcohol distilling and complaints the activity is hurting the region™s tourism.

about 40 people living at Inskip Point, near Rainbow Beach, illegally, including one who was producing and selling alcohol, reports.

It was affecting the whole community, she said, particularly with fears the distillery could explode and injure people.

"People are feeling uncomfortable. I refuse to take my children now. The smell out there is putrid."

The alleged squatters' presence was also hurting the region's tourism, she said.

"(Tourists) are not going to come back. It's the whole community that loses out."

A Queensland Parks and Wildlife spokeswoman said QPWS had visited the site on July 26 after receiving a complaint.

"QPWS has no evidence of illegal activity but has followed up with Queensland Police," she said.

"Camps are only allowed to remain in place for 30 days at Inskip Peninsula Recreation Area."

She said QPWS was aware some people overstay.

"Rangers monitor the area and ask campers to move on as necessary under the relevant legislation."

Like this:

Like Loading...

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inskip Peninsula Recreation Area</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QPWS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Parks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rainbow Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inskip Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
