<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417042897259333</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://afr.com/brand/rear-window/the-realpolitik-behind-the-governments-30-million-foxtel-payment-20170724-gxha7p</url>
  <title>After the controversy comes the paperwork</title>
  <content>
Almost three months after the announcement of a $30 million payment over four years to Foxtel for the broadcasting of little seen women's sports, the federal communications department has yet to finalise the terms and conditions on which the funding will be provided to the subscription TV operator.
Though Rear Window is told the formal funding arrangement, which will include performance targets, is coming along. Which'll is news we don't doubt will be treated with eager anticipation from the many parties who want to get their hand on the details - the payment, announced in the budget, has been nothing if not controversial. 
That's particularly the case at the ABC, which has in recent years been forced to dramatically curtail its womens sport coverage since large funding cuts passed down by then-comms minister Malcolm Turnbull in 2014. Giving the ABC more funding for women's sport was a Labor policy at the last election, but alas, that idea's gone to benefit Foxtel, and more specifically, to Fox Sports, which is wholly owned by News Corp. Some of those party to media reform talks say the $30 million sweetener wasn't a part of most the formal discussions, and believe Turnbull himself may have played a role in negotiating the last-minute Foxtel package - perhaps directly in discussions with Rupert Murdoch in New York in May. Which explains why the department is only now getting around to the paperwork - FOIs filed by the ABC on the deal have so far turned up zip.
Within both commercial media and government circles, the payment is universally understood as Foxtel's compensation for the revenue losses besetting the industry as a result of the government's curtailment of gambling ads during live sports broadcasts. The free-to-air operators, naturally, got a licence fee cut, pumping millions directly into their bottom lines. But Foxtel doesn't pay a licence fee, and so something else had to be found. 

For the government, it's the cost of keeping the media united on the media reform front. Foxtel, owned by News Corp and Telstra, doesn't benefit from a licence fee waiver. The government is keen to pass a package, but has demanded some measure of unity and leadership from the media industry to do so - it doesn't want to find itself arguing with specific parts of the sector over who benefits the most. Hence News Corp's Michael Miller telling everyone - well, the domestic commercial media operators at least - to play nice at the Melbourne Press Club last week. The realpolitik of media reform may be messy and bewildering to outsiders, but it may help get the much-delayed package over the line. Particularly when you've got to keep the media operators onside while crimping their revenues to get Nick Xenophon's support of the total deal. 

We should say, comms minister Mitch Fifield has in parliament been trying to justify the payment by pointing to research by the Australian Sports Commission which found that 70 per cent of all women's sport on television is currently provided by Foxtel, and more specifically Fox Sports. We wonder that's a point being hammered home by Fox Sports CEO Patrick Delany, who we're told has been quietly telling MPs about all the women's sports coverage in jeopardy if the payment doesn't go through. Alas, he didn't return our emails. 
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rear Window</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Xenophon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fox Sports CEO Patrick Delany</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rupert Murdoch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne Press Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Sports Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp's Michael Miller</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mitch Fifield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
