<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417051487194168</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/good-wife-spin-courting-all-new-dramas/3208222/</url>
  <title>The Good Wife spin-off courting all new dramas</title>
  <content>
WHILE her real-life partner battles White Walkers on Game of Thrones, Rose Leslie is taking up the good fight in the courtroom.
The Downton Abbey and Game of Thrones star, famous for her line 'You know nothing Jon Snow', joins the returning cast of The Good Wife in the new spin-off The Good Fight.
Picking up one year after the events of the final episode of The Good Wife, a financial scam has destroyed the reputation of young lawyer Maia Rindell (Rose), while simultaneously wiping out her mentor and godmother Diane Lockhart's (Christine Baranski) savings.
Forced out of Lockhart & Lee, they join Lucca Quinn (Cush Jumbo) at one of Chicago's leading law firms specialising in representing police brutality cases.

"I was aware, certainly, of The Good Wife," Rose tells The Guide.

"It had been on for seven years. I came quite late to the party, but girlfriends of mine had been speaking about it for a while. I was really excited (about The Good Fight), mainly because it meant I could work with Christine, and because it's a very familiar universe where we get to create new characters."
In the show's first episode, which premiered last night, Maia is navigating her first day as a lawyer at Christine's law firm when her father is arrested.
As the news of his investment fund's crash and alleged fraud hits the news, it turns Maia's world upside down.

"When we first meet her she's fighting to stay sane," Rose says.
"The name Rindell used to bring with it so much respect and clout; it's all she's ever known. Then to have this enormous turnaround and for it to be tarnished and disgraced is such a mortifying experience.
"That jarring reality of suddenly you wake up and your world is no longer what you've known for 26 years was one thing that piqued my interest when I read the pilot. It's a fantastic premise."
Both she and Diane must forge new futures for themselves if they are going to weather the storm.
 

"Maia has to dig deeper than she ever has within herself, and the passion she has for the law is possibly the last resort she has to hold her head up high," she says.
"There's a strong desire to carve her own way in the world... and a determination in this young woman that I was very much drawn to.
"There's a resilience within her that builds up by the end of the first season.
"I had always wanted to work with the Kings (writers Robert and Michelle King). They are incredible at writing court dramas and they write so vividly. They make sure their characters are flawed and imperfect."

The Good Fight continues Wednesdays at 9.30pm on SBS and is also available to stream on SBS On Demand.
 

A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine Baranski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lockhart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diane Lockhart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GOOD FIGHT</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose Leslie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS On Demand</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Downton Abbey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rindell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucca Quinn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cush Jumbo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Good Wife</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chicago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Snow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Diane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelle King</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Walkers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maia Rindell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
