<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416347112544889</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:58</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/sport/american-sports/college-basketballers-night-goes-from-bad-to-worse-to-knocked-out-on-a-jail-cell-floor/news-story/f8bbba2eb77dab5dbbe82353aec3b0f5</url>
  <title>College basketballer's night goes from bad, to worse to knocked out on a jail cell floor</title>
  <content>
College basketballer Sam Miller had a really, really, bad night.

Thomas LipeNY Post

Share

A COLLEGE basketball player started a jail fight that left him with a bloody nose and a bruised forehead on a night that got worse and worse.
Sam Miller, a rising junior forward for Dayton men's basketball team, is facing charges of disorderly conduct, underage drinking and assault after an arrest Sunday in Beavercreek, Ohio, in the early hours over what began as an assault claim.
According to a police report obtained by Dayton Daily News, one of the bartenders at Caddy's Tap House said the 20-year-old Miller turned violent when he was told he could not be served more alcohol. Miller allegedly responded by knocking glassware off the bar's counter and pushing the bartender who refused to serve him.

When Beavercreek police arrived on the scene, officers reported that Miller's speech was slurred to the point that he was difficult to understand. The 6-foot-9, 244-pound Miller allegedly acted aggressively toward officers by screaming profanities and resisting attempts to place him in the back of a squad car - which Miller allegedly kicked.
After being transported to Greene County Jail in Xenia, Miller, who was issued a court summons for disorderly conduct and underage consumption of alcohol, continued to be combative.
Miller urinated on the floor of his holding cell before picking a fight with John Watkins Jr., who was being held in the cell after being arrested on an OVI charge.
Security-camera footage shows the student standing shirtless with his pants at his ankles as he gets in Watkins' face. Miller then swings at Watkins.
Watkins jumped to his feet and landed shots to Miller's face, including one that caused the basketball player's knees to buckle.
Miller was sent to Greene Memorial Hospital with a bloody nose and a bump on his forehead.

Dayton has not commented, citing privacy laws. Miller averaged 4.5 points and 2.3 rebounds in 12.2 minutes per game last season.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Watkins Jr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Miller</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OVI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greene County Jail</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Security-camera</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OHIO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beavercreek</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DAYTON</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dayton Daily News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caddy's Tap House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas LipeNY Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Miller</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Watkins</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Xenia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greene Memorial Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
