<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417047192226820</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/soccer/aleague-clubs-allege-ffa-proposes-to-cut-marquee-player-fund-20170802-gxo27l.html</url>
  <title>FFA set to cut A-League marquee player fund - after just one year</title>
  <content>
A major fund set aside for bringing high-profile players to the A-League will be scrapped a year after it came into effect, with Football Federation Australia set to drop its marquee fund before the start of the season.
Fairfax Media understands $3 million set aside by FFA to assist clubs purchasing big-name stars is on the chopping block and is set to be redirected to the clubs, but only conditionally for marketing purposes.Photo: Paul Jeffers
As part of the clubs' ongoing pay dispute with FFA, the governing body has all but confirmed its intention to scrap the fund that was hoped to rejuvenate the enthusiasm of clubs signing marquees such as Alessandro Del Piero, Shinji Ono and Tim Cahill. In a letter from the clubs unanimously rejecting the organisation's latest pay offer, it is alleged the FFA proposed to provide each of the 10 clubs a conditional increase of $300,000 for marketing of the league, with the funds to be distributed after the approval of Whitlam Square.
"The inclusion of the $300,000 marketing grant in the proposed 17/18 distribution is the result of the FFA administration extricating itself from the centralised marquee proposition that it sold in the broadcast deal, against the advice of the clubs and in the face of the obvious realities of the global transfer/player market," the letter from the club chairman read.
FFA announced the introduction of a $1 million marquee fund at the start of last season and contributed more than $500,000 towards Melbourne City's signing of Cahill. As part of the new $58 million per annum broadcast deal that comes into effect this season, FFA reached an agreement with Fox Sports for an additional $2 million specifically to help Australian clubs compete with Chinese, American and Middle Eastern clubs for the signatures of famous stars.
"We have had great success by making an investment into a few funds this season. Exhibit A is [Cahill] and we're adding $2 million dollars to the fund," Gallop said at the announcement in December.

Fairfax Media sought comment from FFA.
The A-League clubs are set to begin legal proceedings against FFA in seven days to gain access to the organisation's financial books, after announcing their final refusal to accept their share of revenue. The 10 club chairmen issued a detailed letter to FFA explaining why they are refusing to accept the $3.55 million annual grant as part of the competition's revenue. The clubs are complaining they covered a gap of more than $18 million in player wages last year after spending heavily on marquee players in a year when FFA was negotiating a new broadcast deal.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

The clubs claimed FFA's estimates of the A-League generating $70 million per annum presents a conservative figure and are frustrated that by those calculations, they are only receiving a 50 per cent share.
In the letter, the clubs urged FFA to return to the negotiating table to discuss a new pay model for their share of the A-League revenue. Talks between the two parties broke down as a result of the legal threat from the clubs to access FFA's books. Chairman Steven Lowy said the board would not proceed with planned talks for a new A-League operating model as a result.
"The issue requires dialogue and we urge the FFA board and administration to engage in a meaningful way to bring about resolution in the face of the compelling financial evidence of the unsustainability of the FFA board and administration's current approach," the letter said.
It's understood clubs have also requested FFA provides them with the windfall from the A-League finals series.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Football Federation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cahill</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gallop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shinji Ono</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ALESSANDRO DEL PIERO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Eastern</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Cahill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Jeffers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MELBOURNE City</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Whitlam Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chairman Steven Lowy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FOX SPORTS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FFA</name>
    <count>17</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chinese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
