<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416952702944981</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/there-is-a-renewed-push-to-sell-the-hamilton-home-of-once-notorious-businessman-christopher-skase/news-story/12e543394971d760f3a6528827cfbeaf</url>
  <title>There is a renewed push to sell the Hamilton home of once notorious businessman Christopher Skase - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
36 Dickson Tce, Hamilton

IT'S list of features is extraordinary, not least of which, that is was built by one of Australia's most notorious businessmen, but that still hasn't been enough to find a buyer yet for the Hamilton home once owned by Christopher Skase.
The house, known as Bromley, at Dickson Tce, has now been listed with its third agency since July 2016.
It is now owned by Dr Soo Hian Beh. It was bought in 2001 for $6.5 million.

Dr Beh is selling her opulent family home in Hamilton. Picture: Claudia Baxter

Dr Beh's estranged husband, Sir Yii Ann Hii, is being pursued by the Australian Taxation Office which accused him of paying no tax between 2001 and 2009.
He claimed he was not a resident at the time.

The opulent home on Dickson Tce in Hamilton is up for sale. Picture: Claudia Baxter

The nine-bedroom home was most recently listed for rent on realestate.com.au with an asking rent of $12,800 a week.
It is now listed for sale through Stephen Weber of Queensland Sotheby's International Realty through an expressions of interest campaign.

36 Dickson Tce, Hamilton

His listing describes the home as a "lavish portrayal of an extraordinary era in Australian history''.
The 2759sq m estate is on Hamilton Hill. It has nine bedrooms and nine bathrooms.

36 Dickson Tce, Hamilton

It has a medieval circular staircase and an internal bell tower, the boundary fence of the home is made from one metre thick concrete and reinforced steel.
Skase also famously had bullet proof glass installed in parts of the home.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Beh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5.2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamilton Hill</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sotheby's International Realty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bromley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Weber of Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Taxation Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Soo Hian Beh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Skase</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2016</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Claudia Baxter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sir Yii Ann Hii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Skase</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dickson Tce</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
