<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416145249077773</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/global-warming-progression-cannot-be-denied/3207838/</url>
  <title>Global warming progression cannot be denied</title>
  <content>
THERE is one undeniable fact associated with climate disruption.
Doubters or deniers of climate disruption are universally politically conservative.
This seems to be true mainly in Australia and the USA, however.
In most other nations of the world, climate change, as a result of global warming, is understood and accepted bipartisanly.
The simple explanation, here, is that conservative voters embrace small government, low taxes, private ownership and free enterprise.
If one holds these values dear, it's hard to believe in global warming because the solution, at this late time, requires government action, carbon taxes and involvement.
Private industry, as many separate entities, does not seem capable of responding to such an enormous challenge.
There may be much more to this, though, as everywhere else in the world both conservative and progressive parties are working together to realise a carbon-neutral society.
Mr Buick (Daily, July 28) got one thing correct in his remarkable anti-green rant.
Global warming predictions are debunked monthly.
It seems the IPCC, that UN body initiated by Margaret Thatcher to monitor climate disruption and predict some of its consequences, has underestimated almost all of the increases in temperature.
Global warming is progressing much faster than predicted.
Stopping the Adani coal mine would be a great way for Labor to start making sense.
STEVE HALL
Cooroy
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
IT was heart-breaking, challenging and life-changing.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>UN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>STEVE HALL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Margaret Thatcher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 28</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>USA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IPCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Buick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cooroy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
