<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417167451312732</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4813905/berner-street-beauty-on-the-market/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Berner Street beauty on the market</title>
  <content>
Berner Street beauty on the market

exit

CUSTOM built in late 2011 to early 2012, this Hamptons-inspired home is located in Berner Street, Merewether - where the beach, coastline walks, parklands, bars and eateries are all just a part of everyday life.
The vendors Mark and Julia van Huisstede, who have four children between them, are simply downsizing with intentions of staying in the area.

"The fact is I have my oldest travelling the world and my youngest two are happy to share a room.
"We just don't need what is basically a six-bedroom house anymore. Though we'll probably build something similar again, just not as big."
The five bedroom, four-bathroom home with separate office is being listed through Robinson for $2.98 million and has been designed to maximise the usage of every inch of the 462 square-metre block.

Mr van Huisstede was involved in the design process from the beginning and the result is a luxurious and contemporary home with an abundance of storage and apparent attention to detail.
"It's a three-storey house but you don't realise it's three stories until you're in the home," Mr van Huisstede said.
"The office downstairs is perfect for a professional, you don't have to have people entering the home. The sub-floor would make an ideal wine cellar, it's huge and basically a concrete bunker."
The saltwater pool is flanked by a versatile layout where family functionality, relaxation and entertainment are the focus according to Michael Flook from Robinson Newcastle. The impressive design coupled with its location 300 metres from the beach has meant that there's already been solid interest in the property.

CUSTOM DESIGN: The attention to detail is apprent in this Berner Street, Merewether home being sold for $2.98 million.
"If you start at the beach, properties at Bar Beach Avenue are selling for $4.5 million and upwards," he said.

"This place is a couple of blocks back from the beach, a short walk to the ocean and would probably cost a million to build [the house].
"If you're buying a block like this, it would probably cost 2.5 million. This property allows you to get in the market for $3 million. So the value is there."
If the number of bedrooms and bathrooms weren't enough to convince you of the ample space and ease of living incorporated into this home, the alfresco entertaining area overlooking the pool, multiple living areas and self-contained office area, ideal for professionals, may do the trick.

"The top end of the market is very strong," Mr Flook said. "We've already had people returning for a second look."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Merewether</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinson Newcastle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huisstede</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bar Beach Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Berner Street</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hamptons-inspired</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Flook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Flook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CUSTOM DESIGN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robinson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
