<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417085846932979</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/lifestyle/fashion/people/blake-lively-and-rachel-bilson-were-photographed-in-50-jeans-now-we-all-want-a-pair/news-story/bfe12b87ec82e0bf368a20208d2afd51</url>
  <title>Blake Lively and Rachel Bilson were photographed in $50 jeans, now we all want a pair</title>
  <content>
Blake Lively is considered one of the most stylish women in the world. So when she wears a $50 pair of jeans, we want to know where she got them. Immediately. Picture: Instagram

Share

EVERYBODY loves a good buy.
Just ask the people who.
So it comes as no surprise that people are clamouring to get their pair on the latest celeb-endorsed fashion bargain.
Blake Lively and Rachel Bilson have both been photographed wearing a pair of jeans that cost just $US39.99 ($50).
Lively was spotted in Long Island, New York over the weekend looking as classic as ever in a white button-down blouse, black heeled sandals and the aforementioned dark wash skinny jeans.

A post shared by Blake Lively Fanpage (@ohmyblakelively) on

A day later, Rachel Bilson was seen walking in Beverly Hills in the same jeans, but in a more laid-back light wash that she paired with a grey tee and brown peep-toe sandals.

on

The jeans are . These mid-rise super skinny jeans come in three different washes and are made of a soft stretchy knit material that looks like denim but is supposed to be way more comfortable.
Apparently they have "special 360-degree stretch technology" (!) developed by cult denim designer Adriano Goldschmied.

The jeans, as they appear on Old Navy's website.Source:Supplied
If you haven't come across the label yet, Old Navy is an American brand that is owned by Gap. Hence their strong denim game.

The jeans, as they appear on Old Navy's website.Source:Supplied
And the good news? Unlike so many US fashion sites, they actually ship to Australia.
Hear that? That's the sound of credit cards being whipped out of wallets everywhere.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adriano Goldschmied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Lively</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Old Navy</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Blake Lively Fanpage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BEVERLY HILLS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Long Island</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rachel Bilson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US39.99 ($50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
