<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417176041247516</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/leader/inner-south/bentleigh-retiree-wins-5m-division-one-oz-lotto-prize/news-story/1dd3f510f172c5ab649870b5831fdcd7</url>
  <title>Retiree scoops $5 million lotto pool</title>
  <content>
A BENTLEIGH retiree has won the huge $5 million division one prize in Tuesday night's Oz Lotto draw.
But incomplete contact details on his Tatts card could have cost the winner his riches.
Luckily the man discovered his Oz Lotto windfall yesterday while routinely checking his tickets.
"I had absolutely no idea I'd won," he said.
"It still hasn't sunk in yet. I'm not jumping up and down like a cat on a hot tin roof, but I'm sure I will be.
"Before this, my biggest ever lotto win was a division four prize in Oz Lotto. Oz Lotto seems to be a good game for me."
The regular lottery player said his win had come at a great time as he had been forced to retire early because of ill health.
The lucky winner will use his new found wealth to fulfil his travelling dreams, buy a house and help out his family, he said.
He was the only division one winner in Australia for Oz Lotto draw 1224 on Tuesday 1 August 2017.
His winning 36-game QuickPick entry was purchased at Patterson Road Lotto, News & Post in Bentleigh.
Store owner Melissa Pham and her husband Daniel Nguyen only took ownership of the outlet about two months ago and were thrilled to have already sold their first division one winning entry.
"It's so exciting," Ms Pham said.
"Hopefully it's the start of many more big wins for our customers."
The winning numbers in Oz Lotto draw 1224 on Tuesday 1 August 2017 were 9, 16, 41, 13, 37, 43 and 3, while the supplementary numbers were 11 and 26.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Pham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melissa Pham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QuickPick</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Nguyen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday 1 August 2017</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bentleigh</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patterson Road Lotto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oz Lotto</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
