<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416828148890868</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/rural/2017-08-03/online-farmers-market-gets-ready-to-launch/8769578</url>
  <title>Online farmers' markets: Veggies on the smartphone</title>
  <content>
Farmers' markets are going online, with a new digital start-up tapping into the increasingly popular paddock-to-plate movement by offering fresh produce with a touch of the smartphone.
Customers will be able to buy fresh veggies in the same way they shop on eBay or Amazon.
Called Megafresh, the online marketplace for producers is the brainchild of Melbourne-based Alex Stefan.
Mr Stefan wants to provide a connection between consumers and farmers.
"I do feel that farmers and manufacturers have been mistreated by the large corporates," he said.
"I want to help farmers and manufacturers access consumers directly. I don't think it's necessary for them to have to use retailers.''
Testing for freshness

Megafresh will be one of the first places in Australia to use new technology to test fresh produce

Megafresh will be one of the first places in Australia to use new technology to test fresh produce

Supplied: Megafresh

Mr Stefan said many consumers would not buy fresh produce online because they could not see and feel the quality.
But Megafresh has invested in new technology that tests the produce so that consumers know what they're buying.

"We're providing a testing service where all fresh produce is tested and the results are available on the listing."

The technology, developed in Israel, uses beams of light to measure sugar levels and nutrients.
Mr Stefan said he believed Megafresh would be one of the first places to use the technology in Australia.
"The test will show the aroma intensity, the flavour intensity, the nutritional profile and the level of ripeness.
"That's something you can't even get from any other supermarket."
Farmers get on board

Megafresh wants to provide a connection between producers and consumers.

Megafresh wants to provide a connection between producers and consumers.

ABC Rural: Jennifer Nichols

Apple producer Kevin Sanders, from the Yarra valley in Victoria, is happy to act as a guinea pig for the start-up.
"I think this is going back to one of the things that the public used to have, they used to know their grower on a fairly regular basis,'' Mr Sanders said.
"They feel much more comfortable with where they buy if they can understand who the grower is and they can talk to their grower on a regular basis through social media.''
Mr Sanders said the instant feedback on quality and communication with customers would help him expand his business.
"It might enable opportunities to grow different varieties that are not very mainstream or introduce people to different varieties," he said.

"You need the constant communication from your customers about what's good about your variety and what's bad about it."

Mr Stefan will need about 200 producers to make the project viable.
"It's early days so we're currently in the process of signing up farmers and sellers," he said.
"The sooner we can do that the sooner the platform will make money for famers and become a popular destination on the internet."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kevin Sanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Israel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>eBay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne-based Alex Stefan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Rural</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jennifer Nichols</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stefan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Megafresh</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Sanders</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apple</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
