<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416780904249697</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/nsw-act/operation-credo-icac-finds-dpp-should-investigate-laying-charges-against-eddie-obeid-tony-kelly-and-joe-tripod/news-story/b7f8173777bd29c12ab4890af1ac8223</url>
  <title>Operation Credo: ICAC finds DPP should investigate laying charges against Eddie Obeid, Tony Kelly and Joe Tripod</title>
  <content>
Disgraced former MP Eddie Obied faces further scrutiny following today's ICAC findings.

Andrew Clennell

Share

ICAC has found that the DPP should investigate laying charges against former ministers Eddie Obeid, Tony Kelly and Joe Tripodi and former Labor staffer Laurie Brown in relation to the Australian Water Holdings affair.
But despite fears that federal minister Arthur Sinodinos may be criticised for being a poor witness during the inquiry into Australian Water Holdings' boss Nick Di Girolamo's dealings with Labor and Liberal parties, he has escaped criticism.
In fact, no Liberal figures and Mr Di Girolamo himself have not had any findings made against them.

ICAC has found that the DPP should investigate laying charges against disgraced former MP Eddie Obeid.Source:Supplied
Despite resigning as premier after misleading the Commission over the gift of an undisclosed $3,000 bottle of Grange from Mr Di Girolamo at the time he was lobbying the government for a $1 billion contract, the Commission has cleared former premier Barry O'Farrell.
It says: "When he gave evidence on 16 April 2014, Mr O'Farrell had no recollection of receiving the wine.
"The Commission is satisfied that there was no intention on Mr O'Farrell's part to mislead the Commission on either occasion that he gave evidence."
"Mr O'Farrell gave further evidence, which other evidence bears out and the Commission accepts, that he never acceded to any request from Mr Di Girolamo or anyone else to give AWH special assistance.
"Mr O'Farrell announced his intention to resign as premier and minister for western Sydney. He formally resigned on 17 April 2014 as NSW Liberal Party leader.
"In advising his colleagues of his decision to resign, he noted that he had no recollection of receiving a bottle of wine from Mr Di Girolamo and had given an honest recollection of events in his evidence to the Commission on 15 April 2014.

"He went on to note that "[a]s someone who respects the role of the ICAC and the importance of transparency and accountability, I accept the consequences of what I can only describe as a massive failure of memory".

ICAC cleared former premier Barry O'Farrell over the gift of an undisclosed $3,000 bottle of GrangeSource:Supplied
During Operation Credo, the -commission heard evidence that -Australian Water Holdings used Sydney Water contract money to deliver water infrastructure in northwest Sydney on $10,000 on a football corporate box, hired limousines, spent tens of thousands in Liberal Party donations and that tens of thousands were allegedly paid to a political slush fund.
The commission announced at the inquiry's outset that it was to consider whether there was enough evidence to make corruption findings against Mr Di Girolamo, Labor powerbroker Eddie
Obeid and former ministers Joe Tripodi and Tony Kelly over their alleged roles in the creation of a cabinet minute -recommending AWH receive a -$1 billion public-private partnership.
The commission also explored whether the Obeid family had a secret financial interest in AWH.
ICAC found that consideration be given to obtaining the advice of the DPP with respect to the prosecution of Edward Obeid Sr, Mr Kelly, Mr Brown and Mr Tripodi for common law criminal offences of misconduct in public office," the ICAC report Operation Credo says," a statement from ICAC says.
In a statement, ICAC said: The NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption (ICAC) has found that former NSW minister for infrastructure Anthony Kelly and former members of Parliament, Edward Obeid Sr and Joseph Tripodi, engaged in serious corrupt conduct in relation to their actions concerning a public-private partnership (PPP) proposal by Australian Water Holdings (AWH) Pty Ltd which, had it proceeded, could have resulted in substantial financial rewards for that company and the Obeid family.
"The Commission's report on Operation Credo, Investigation into dealings between Australian Water Holdings Pty Ltd and Sydney Water Corporation and related matters, was released today. It notes that Edward Obeid Sr's son, Edward Obeid Jr, was working for an AWH-related company, Australian Water, from at least about July 2007. By that time, Edward Obeid Sr was aware that his son was involved with AWH, and by November 2007 he knew that AWH wanted to proceed with a PPP proposal for the purchase, supply and operation of water infrastructure in the North West Growth Centre in northwestern Sydney.

Senator Arthur Sinodinos escaped criticism in this morning's ICAC findings.Source:News Corp Australia
"He knew that Edward Obeid Jr was interested in acquiring shares in AWH and that by July 2008 there was interest in an Obeid family entity acquiring shares in that company. If approved, the AWH PPP proposal meant any such investment would be extremely profitable for the Obeid family. The Commission is satisfied that Edward Obeid Sr used his position as a member of Parliament to promote AWH's interests to a number of ministers and premiers at a time when he knew that his family or a family entity could benefit if they acquired shares in the company and the PPP proposal proceeded.
"The Commission finds that Mr Kelly's former chief of staff, Gilbert (Laurie) Brown, engaged in serious corrupt conduct through his involvement in preparing a cabinet minute in 2010 to the Cabinet Standing Committee on the Budget (the Budget Committee of Cabinet), with the intention of improperly favouring Edward Obeid Sr by enabling AWH to proceed to direct negotiation with the NSW Government concerning the PPP proposal.
"An initial draft Cabinet minute, prepared by Department of Premier and Cabinet associate director of investment and economic development Brian McGlynn, recommended that the AWH PPP proposal be rejected on several grounds including that it would not provide value for money for the state, Sydney Water Corporation (SWC) or the community. The proposal would also not transfer sufficient risk to AWH, and there was no prospect that the PPP would lead to an acceptable outcome for the NSW Government.

Nick Di GirolamoSource:News Corp Australia

Joe TripodiSource:News Corp Australia
"The McGlynn draft Cabinet minute was sent to Mr Brown at Mr Kelly's office. As minister for infrastructure, Mr Kelly was responsible for submitting any Cabinet minute on the AWH PPP to the Budget Committee of Cabinet.
"The Commission finds that Mr Brown, a long-time friend of Edward Obeid Sr's, subsequently helped draft a new minute that was instead favourable towards the AWH PPP proposal proceeding. He helped draft this minute with material he obtained, in large part, from Mr Tripodi, knowing that the new minute substantially misrepresented the truth and was highly deceptive. The Commission finds that Mr Brown undertook this course of action, because he believed it was what Edward Obeid Sr wanted.
"The Commission finds that Mr Kelly engaged in serious corrupt conduct when he misused his office as a minister of the Crown by arranging for the preparation and submission of the minute to the Cabinet Standing Committee on the Budget, with the intention of improperly favouring Edward Obeid Sr. Mr Tripodi engaged in serious corrupt conduct when he misused his position as a member of Parliament to prepare a draft Cabinet minute with the intention that it would be used by Mr Brown and Mr Kelly as the basis for the minute that would be submitted by Mr Kelly to the committee.
"All of these actions were undertaken with the intention of improperly favouring Edward Obeid Sr by enabling AWH to proceed to direct negotiation with the NSW Government concerning its PPP proposal for the North West Growth Centre.
"The Commission is of the opinion that consideration should be given to obtaining the advice of the Director of Public Prosecutions with respect to the prosecution of Edward Obeid Sr, Mr Kelly, Mr Brown and Mr Tripodi for common law criminal offences of misconduct in public office.
"Operation Credo also investigated allegations in relation to approaches made to the NSW Liberal Party by AWH in relation to its PPP proposal. The ICAC makes no findings against any individual in relation to that part of the investigation.
"The Commission also investigated whether persons having an interest in AWH obtained a financial benefit by inflating charges made to SWC. No findings of corrupt conduct were made in relation to that matter."
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Sinodinos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Water Holdings</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grange</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Crown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGlynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Di Girolamo</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Arthur Sinodinos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North West Growth Centre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joseph Tripodi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GrangeSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operation Credo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Water</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anthony Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obeid</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>November 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tripodi</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-16</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney Water Corporation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Eddie Obeid.Source</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWH PPP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Premier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Water</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr O'Farrell</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Di GirolamoSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPP</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Di Girolamo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SWC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Kelly</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe TripodiSource</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Brown</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brian McGlynn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Independent Commission Against Corruption</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Water Holdings Pty Ltd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Kelly</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Budget Committee of Cabinet</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barry O'Farrell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2007</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 2008</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWH-related</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Liberal Party</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DPP</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP Eddie Obied</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eddie Obeid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAC</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tripodi</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward Obeid Sr</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Edward Obeid Jr</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cabinet Standing Committee</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWH</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew Clennell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April 2014</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tripod</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
