<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417133091573913</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:01</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Courier Mail</source>
  <url>http://www.couriermail.com.au/real-estate/queensland/complex-lending-policies-have-helped-drive-the-demand-for-fixed-rate-home-loans-to-new-highs/news-story/bf28a8aa63df2a6b338defe9a802ad9b</url>
  <title>Complex lending policies have helped drive the demand for fixed rate home loans to new highs - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
Increasingly complex lending rules are driving borrowers to fix rate home loans, according to one major mortgage broker.

DATA from one of the nation's largest mortgage brokers, Mortgage Choice, revealed fixed rate home loan demand reached a three-year high in July, accounting for 29.63 per cent of all loans written.
"This is the highest level of demand we have seen for fixed rate home loans since December 2013, when fixed-rate home loans accounted for 33.06 per cent of all loans written," said John Flavell, CEO of Mortgage Choice.
Mr Flavell said the surge in fixed-rate popularity wasn't a surprise, as many Australian lenders had recently introduced policy and pricing changes.
"These changes have helped make the mortgage market more complex than ever before.
"Subsequently, borrowers wanting certainty and security over their repayments for a set period of time are increasingly turning to a fixed-rate mortgage."
Across the states, Queensland had the third highest proportion of fixed rate borrowers at 28.08 per cent of all loans written.
Western Australia had the highest proportion of fixed rate borrowers at 35.77 per cent.
Mr Flavell said competition for borrowers had stepped up.
"A few of Australia's lenders have lowered the interest rates charged on some of their fixed rate products, with some trimming up to 10 basis points from their four and five year rates," he said.
"As a result, many of the fixed rate home loans now on offer are very competitively priced."
Despite the rise, Mr Flavell said variable rate home loans remained the most popular product across Australia, making up 40.71 per cent of all loans written.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO of Mortgage</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DATA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Flavell</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2013</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Flavell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
