<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417176041247544</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/west-beaches/new-artisan-on-partridge-event-planned-for-glenelg-as-part-of-the-sala-festival/news-story/d754224b79abb50f52d4b538417d3aa7</url>
  <title>Arts festival comes to historic Bay home</title>
  <content>
PARTRIDGE House will be awash with colour this month when it hosts a new two-day arts event as part of the SALA Festival.
Artisan on Partridge, on August 12-13, will feature an art exhibition and classes over both days, and a market on the Sunday.
There will also be a range of live music acts, including Porch Sessions bands, and food trucks to feed the locals.
Arts and cultural coordinator Jenni Reynolds says about 3000 people are expected on the Sunday, which will be the event's busiest day.
"If it works and it's really successful, we'd love to grow it," she says.
There will be about 20 stallholders, selling items from jewellery to ceramics, textiles and iron works.
Classes in art styles such as mandala drawings and lino printing would help locals get involved.
"It's creating opportunities for people to come and have a go, and not just look at the art but be a part of it," Ms Reynolds says.
Denise Hojdyssek, of Glenelg South, will launch her new textiles label Deer Henri.
"The artworks I create are influenced a lot by my love of Scandinavian design and mid-century design and architecture," she says.
"I grew up in Sydney and used to go to the Paddington Markets, and love going to markets, and thought, 'What a great opportunity to be part of that and launch the label'."
Hallett Cove artist Rosana Cohen, hoped it would be a good opportunity to show off her ceramic work. "We're really hoping to have a fun day," she says.
The South Australia Living Artists Festival is Australia's biggest community-based art event.
Artisan on Partridge is at 38 Partridge St, Glenelg, on August 12-13, from 11am-4pm.
Bookings are required for some classes.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rosana Cohen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Australia Living Artists Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenni Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Partridge St</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hallett Cove</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paddington Markets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Reynolds</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SALA Festival</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scandinavian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Partridge</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PARTRIDGE House</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Porch Sessions</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Deer Henri</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denise Hojdyssek, of Glenelg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Glenelg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
