<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417223285888328</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/a-police-officer-was-allegedly-bitten-on-the-hand-during-an-arrest-of-two-men-in-the-cairns-cbd/news-story/e89b52acf1a06d7a4c3dd8df34a7a401</url>
  <title>Officer bitten in CBD arrest</title>
  <content>
A CAIRNS man has been charged with serious assault after he allegedly bit a police officer on the hand during the arrest of two men in the Cairns CBD.
Police were called to a disturbance at the corner of Esplanade and Shields Street in the Cairns CBD yesterday afternoon after it was reported a man was yelling and abusing people in the area.
Police arrested the man and were forced to restrain him after a struggle.
The second man was wanted in relation to other matters and allegedly struck out at the officers, biting a male officer and causing an open wound.
After police restrained the man it was alleged he then spat on the injured officer.
A 34-year-old Yarrabah man was charged with committing a public nuisance offence and
obstructing police and is due to appear in the Cairns Magistrates Court on August 30.
A 42-year-old Cairns man was charged with serious assault of a police officer causing bodily harm. He is due to reappear in the Cairns Magistrates Court on September 20.
The officer attended the Cairns Hospital for treatment and will also undergo disease
testing procedures.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shields Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns' CBD</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Yarrabah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SEPTEMBER 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUGUST 30</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns Magistrates Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBD</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
