<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417085846932972</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/breaking-news/police-powers-keeping-dv-victims-safe-mp/news-story/3275bf30e4209a213cb8840d7cbe4d2d</url>
  <title>Police powers keeping DV victims safe: MP</title>
  <content>
Protection orders for domestic violence victims have almost tripled since Queensland police were granted the power to issue them on-the-spot, the state government says.
New legislation allows police to issue immediate protection orders for victims of domestic violence.
Prevention of Domestic and Family Violence Minister Shannon Fentiman says since the legislation came into effect in May, the number of orders issued by police has almost tripled.
Of the more than 1970 notices issued in the last financial year, Ms Fentiman says 1185 were issued in the first month of the new legislation taking effect.
"The wonderful thing is we have absolutely streamlined these orders so there is less paperwork, that immediate order can be given and police can get on with their job of holding perpetrators to account and also protecting victims and their children," she said on Thursday.
Ms Fentiman says the police powers are just one of the measures being taken by the Palaszczuk government to tackle domestic and family violence.
A specialist domestic violence court on the Gold Coast has been expanded with additional resources and Ms Fentiman says a trial to have GPS trackers fitted to alleged offenders is in the pipeline.
"The increase in reporting of domestic violence incidents and breaches in DVOs is a good thing because it's out in the open and we can tackle it," she said.
Gold Coast-based Detective Inspector Marc Hogan says the legislation has turned police protection orders from a time-consuming and rarely used tool into an effective measure for officers.
"The take up has been very strong and very positive and certainly it's matter where we can provide a level of safety very early in the piece, and then later follow up with services," Det Insp Hogan said.
National domestic violence helpline: 1800 737 732 or 1800RESPECT. In an emergency call triple-zero.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>DV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DVOs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast-based Detective Inspector Marc Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Palaszczuk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Det Insp Hogan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fentiman</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Family Violence Minister Shannon Fentiman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prevention of Domestic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GPS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gold Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
