<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416355702479614</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:00</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/news/northern-territory/hidden-valley-crash-causes-serious-injuries-for-western-australian-man/news-story/87cf4462194c1f82519226426b405ccf</url>
  <title>Man loses part of leg in Valley crash</title>
  <content>
A WEST Australian man has lost the bottom half of his leg after a motorcycle crash at Hidden Valley Motorsports Complex on Tuesday.
The injury was believed to have occurred after the 50-year-old's bike, and the bike of a 47-year-old woman, collided at 10.50am.
The riders were participating in the Top End Road Racing Association's TERRA Territory Challenge.
St John Ambulance operations manager Craig Garraway said the man sustained serious leg injuries after the motorbikes collided. Mr Garraway said they were already at Hidden Valley for a different incident with another 50-year-old - which was not motorcycle related. He said the man was taken to hospital in a private car with an off duty paramedic.
St John Ambulance transferred the man with serious leg injuries and the woman, who had pain to her right shoulder and ribs. Motorcycle Australia NT president Gary Lambert said the riders were completing unofficial practise where they are able to ride the track to get a feel for the course. He said it was still supervised.
He said organisers closed the track as soon as the accident occurred. "While people were stabilised and ambulances were in attendance the track was closed for a couple of hours," he said.
The TERRA Territory Challenge has run for the past 25 years and involves motorcyclists racing around the track.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hidden Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Garraway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St John Ambulance</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Top End Road Racing Association's TERRA Territory Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Garraway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gary Lambert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TERRA Territory Challenge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hidden Valley Motorsports Complex</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
