<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417253350659853</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/popular-arctic-dog-breeds-abandoned-and-need-rehoming/8769488</url>
  <title>Arctic dog breeds growing in demand through popular culture, then abandoned</title>
  <content>
With arctic dog breeds gaining popularity through Games of Thrones and the movie Snow Dogs, many people are finding their new pets are more difficult to manage than they first realised, and abandon them.
But according to Janelle Wyatt, dogs really are the best people.
Specifically, Alaskan Malamutes and Siberian Huskies.
You would have to really love the breeds to take care of over 70 of them at the one time.
From a secluded rural property near the central coast of NSW she runs the High Tails Lodge. It is here where she and a small team of fellow animal lovers take care of rescue dogs for the not-for-profit  (AMRAA).
"They're just a special breed in their own," explains Mrs Wyatt.
"I live my life for them."
After leaving her corporate job of over 20 years, Mrs Wyatt was happy to dedicate her life to looking after these abandoned arctic breeds, describing herself as "the crazy arctic lady".
"Until you own one, you don't understand."
When her first Malamute died many years ago, she found another dog online who needed to be rehomed, instead of going to a breeder. This is where she met the founder of AMRAA and knew it was an organisation she wanted to be a part of.

Most the dogs the charity is trying to rehome come from the pounds, but they have also taken on dogs from people who privately surrender them.

"There's too many people breeding them out there and selling them off to get the money. And then people watch 'Snow Dogs' and think it would be awesome to get that [breed of] dog," Mrs Wyatt says.
"They don't realise they need a lot of activity, they moult a lot, and they're high maintenance. Unless you put the training into them, they can actually get a little bit out of control as well."
Having many dogs to rehome doesn't mean she is willing to give the dogs to whoever wants to take them.
"If someone wants to adopt, we're very, very fussy," Mrs Wyatt says.
"If someone turns up and asks for a dog, I'll ask them what their lifestyle is like, if they've got kids and all that sort of thing. And then we will choose the right one for them.
"Because they need to go to their forever home from here."
On the lookout for 500 Heroes

Tallying up the price of food, water, vet bills and wages, it costs around $2500 a week to look after her growing brood of temporary fur babies.
"Flea and tick costs around $300 a month, worming is probably $300 a month. It's crazy."
On August 5 Mrs Wyatt will be representing AMRAA at the Sydney , and is on the hunt for  to donate $5 a week to help in the cost of looking after the dogs.

"Hopefully we'll meet some people down there who have got arctics and want to donate.
"As it is at the moment it's not sustainable, because we're constantly getting money out of our own pockets and you get to the stage where you'll go broke."
The exorbitant price for taking care of the dogs don't cause Mrs Wyatt any stress though, because she knows it's worth the cost.
"The only stressful part of this job is seeing the conditions of some of the dogs when they come in," Mrs Wyatt says.

For more stories like this, join the Australia Plus community on , or follow us on  and .

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5 Mrs Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia Plus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snow Dogs</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Tails Lodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arctic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Game of Thrones</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Wyatt</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Janelle Wyatt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malamutes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AMRAA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siberian Huskies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alaskan Malamutes</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
