<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416909753271221</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Newcastle Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.theherald.com.au/story/4819710/survivor-severs-ties/?cs=305</url>
  <title>Survivor severs ties</title>
  <content>
Moving on: Steph has started a new chapter after escaping abuse. She encouraged survivors to ask for help and join the workshop. "You've got nothing to lose and everything to gain." Picture: Simone De Peak

STEPH* doesn't consider her mother, father or any other relatives as her family.
After being sexually, emotionally and verbally abused at their hands, she has changed her name and phone number, moved cities and started a new life filled with people who for the first time, she feels she can trust. "They're just people from my past," Steph said, referring to her estranged parents.

"I needed to sever all ties with them or I would not be here. I've grown and changed so much in the past 10 years and have started to let new people into my life.
- Steph, domestic violence survivor
"For a very long time I had closed myself off to that - I had not let anyone in because I was so scared of being hurt again."
Steph points to her participation in Hunter charity Got Your Back Sista's Rise and Thrive workshop as crucial to her transformation.

She signed up earlier this year for sessions in mindfulness, improving self esteem and financial literacy and was partnered with a mentor, who became a confidante and helped her secure part time work.
"I have really struggled over the past 10 years with my depression and I still have bad days," she said.

"But I have people in my life now that I can rely on or turn to in order to try and get through it."
Steph was only a child when her father started sexually abusing her, shortly after her parents separated.
"I was paralysed with fear," she said. "He would say that there is no point in telling anyone because no-one would believe me. I told my mother a fair while after it started and she could not believe he would do anything like that and so she dismissed it."
Steph's attempts to avoid her father were futile.
Her mother would take her to his house for babysitting and court-enforced fortnightly visitation.
The abuse continued for about three years, until she started high school and refused to see him.
"When it was over, I tried to bury it inside and get on with my life," she said.

"It was heartbreaking and an experience I would never want to put anyone through."
Her father later confessed to police and was charged and sentenced to jail.
But even after his assaults stopped, the put-downs from her mother had just begun. "I felt more alone than I ever had before," she said.
"It was like I was not the same as my family, that I had no-one in my life. I was the first one to blame whenever anything went wrong.
"I was isolated, pushed out of the family and left out of anything like holidays. I hate Christmas and birthdays because things like that were not really celebrated when it came to me. I was the black sheep of the family - the problem child."
Steph had always been creatively minded and tried to focus on her dream of a career in design. "I tried to talk to myself and tell myself I was stronger than I thought and I can get through this."
When the opportunity arose to study in another town, she couldn't leave fast enough. Apart from a few vile phone calls and text messages, she has not had any contact with her family since. "I'd just had enough of being treated like crap by the people who were supposed to love me - I needed a way out and did everything in my power to try and get that," she said. "I was so relieved to be out of the situation - it was just so freeing to get away from them and finally be able to try and work through some of the trauma.
"That really started the process for me of trying to sort through some of the stuff that happened."
Steph underwent counselling, started medication for her depression, began freelance work and met people who "wanted to build me up, instead of bring me down". A friend suggested she try the Rise and Thrive workshop, which is open to domestic violence survivors and aims to help equip them with skills to begin the next phase of their life. She describes it as "one of the best decisions I've ever made". "It encouraged me to look at things from a different point of view," she said. "I just sat back and took it all in - I had never been to something like that before. I didn't want to tell my story to a group of strangers, but it was really comforting and a relief to know everyone in that room had a similar background to what I had."

Steph approached the team afterwards and asked for assistance with her finances. "I wanted to move forward and change the situation I was in," she said. "I wanted to be proactive - if I didn't do anything, no-one else would do it for me."
She is now using her qualifications to pursue her passion and has also set up her own food business.
"It makes me feel like I'm worth something to someone and helps with my self esteem - I feel like I'm contributing to the community and they do want my skills."
Steph said she would never have expected 10 years ago her life would improve so dramatically. Her advice for her younger self is simple. "This is just a chapter in your life - you will get through it," she said. "It's just a season with something that should not have happened, but it did. Surround yourself with people who are going to help you through it. You can't do it own your own. Ask, because people do want to help."

* Names have been changed. Got Your Back Sista has invited the community to show opposition to domestic violence by wearing "Say no" shirts and marching onto the field during the Newcastle Knights August 5 game against the New Zealand Warriors. Participants needs to be ticketholders, make a $20 donation that includes the tshirt and register at mycause.com.au/events/gybsknights

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steph</name>
    <count>11</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Warriors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hunter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Got Your Back Sista's Rise</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Newcastle Knights August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Back Sista</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simone De Peak</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
