<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417171746280170</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:10</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>News.com.au</source>
  <url>http://www.news.com.au/national/victoria/don-bosco-catholic-primary-school-has-banned-girls-and-boys-playing-together-at-breaks/news-story/ea22abac54216a36691c4dec66727e7e</url>
  <title>Don Bosco Catholic Primary School has banned girls and boys playing together at breaks</title>
  <content>
A co-ed catholic primary school in Narre Warren has introduced a "no socialising" rule between the students of the opposite sex. Picture: iStock

Genevieve Alison

Share

A CO-ED Catholic primary school in the city's southeast has come under fire from parents after introducing a "no socialising" rule between the students of the opposite sex.
Don Bosco Catholic Primary School in Narre Warren announced the strict new rules - banning students from year five and six gathering in co-ed groups in the playground - in an emergency school assembly yesterday.
The move by the school has angered parents who have labelled it "sexist".
One concerned parent said he only found out about the rule through his 11-year-old son and had no communication from the school.
"He told us that the senior school students weren't allowed to gather in groups with the other gender at recess or lunchtime anymore," the parent told Neil Mitchell on 3AW.
The rule is understood to have been introduced as a result of some senior students breaking "school guidelines".
"They shouldn't all be tarred with the same brush," the parent said.
The parent, who wished not to be named, said angry parents had "heated conversations" with the school principal about the new restrictions.
The school has been contacted for comment.

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>AW</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>iStock</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CO-ED Catholic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genevieve Alison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Narre Warren</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bosco Catholic Primary School</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neil Mitchell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
