<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417176041247489</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:11</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/a-250000-anonymous-donation-has-saved-victorias-castlemaine-art-museum-from-closure-2017-8</url>
  <title>A $250,000 anonymous donation has saved Victoria's Castlemaine Art Museum from closure</title>
  <content>
A last-minute $250,000 donation from an anonymous Victorian couple has saved the 104-year-old Castlemaine Art Museum from closure next week.

The 1931 art deco building in Victoria's goldfields region, which houses works by Australian artists such as Arthur Streeton, and is currently displaying Patricia Piccinini's "Graham", the sculpture commissioned by the Transport Accident Commission, announced last month that it would close on August 11 until March 2019, due to "a range of financial and operational challenges", sent shockwaves through the arts community.

Earlier this year, the museum lost a long-term financial supporter and a 2015 report noted that the gallery's financial performance had been "precarious for many years".

Artist Ben Quilty called the pending closure "another kick in the guts" to the sector. Last year CAM hosted his exhibition of portraits of war veterans from Afghanistan.

Today auction house Sotheby's Australia announced it helped facilitate an anonymous donation to keep the museum open.

The $250,000 over two years will help pay operating costs and also make entry to the museum free.

Sotheby's chairman Geoffrey Smith said he hoped the donation would inspire others to support the institution.

"We look forward to Castlemaine Art Museum regaining its rightful position as a pre-eminent local, state and national cultural destination and will provide the board with our full support," he said.

Sotheby's issued a statement on behalf of the benefactor that said they are "delighted" to offer the support.

"We are a couple from Central Victoria with family links in the district and have been frequent visitors to both the town and the Museum," the statement says.

"Our initial donation of $250,000 over two years will be supplemented by further donations to support exhibitions during this time. Our commitment of financial support beyond 2019 will depend on the level of support and engagement from the community as a whole and Mount Alexander Shire Council in particular.

"We believe this is a great opportunity to grow the Museum, raise its national profile and make it a 'must visit' destination."

NOW WATCH: Executive Life videos

Business Insider Emails & Alerts

Site highlights each day to your inbox.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Castlemaine Art Museum</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Afghanistan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria's Castlemaine Art Museum</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sotheby's Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ben Quilty</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March 2019</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Graham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Patricia Piccinini</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Accident Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Geoffrey Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Arthur Streeton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sotheby</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Executive Life</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insider Emails</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Alexander Shire Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 11</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Central Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
