<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417223285888360</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/sport/act-sport/chubby-checkers-daughter-mistie-bass-signs-with-canberra-capitals-for-wnbl-20170802-gxo9d1.html</url>
  <title>Caps doing the twist after Mistie Bass, daughter of Chubby Checker, completes roster</title>
  <content>
She's the daughter of rock and roll icon Chubby Checker and the wife of former NFL quarterback Shane Boyd, and now Mistie Bass is the newest member of the Canberra Capitals.
The Capitals filled the final spot on their roster for the 2017-18 WNBL season with the WNBA title winner as they look to end a long finals drought.
Bass gave birth to her son Braven in June and will be doing The Twist - the dance move made famous by her father - if she can help the Capitals back to title contention.
And , she's just about the best person in the world at the dance - right behind her dad.
"I've always wanted to play in Australia," Bass said.
"Many WNBA players speak highly of the league and its competitiveness. I am excited to play for the Capitals this season and help the team be as successful as possible.

"Motherhood is certainly an adjustment; there are long nights and not much sleep. I absolutely love being a mother though, it has given me a new outlook on life and a fresh perspective on how to approach basketball.
"I love the physical element of basketball so my personal goal is to get back to dominating consistently."

Bass won a WNBA championship with the Phoenix Mercury in 2014 and Capitals coach Paul Goriss says she will bring some much-needed experience to a young group.

"There are some terrific big players in the league this year and we needed someone with that veteran experience to go alongside  and ," Goriss said.
"Mistie will be a great mentor to our younger players. We have great flexibility and depth at all positions which we identified as an area of improvement from last season."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shane Boyd</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mistie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NFL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Goriss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Braven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chubby Checker</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WNBA</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mistie Bass</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Goriss</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra Capitals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Phoenix Mercury</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
