<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417085846932969</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/national/unwitting-passenger-may-have-been-used-in-alleged-sydney-terror-plot-source-claims/news-story/d4aa0c7820614a8d587590c6696aefa0</url>
  <title>Plot to use unwitting passenger</title>
  <content>
AN UNWITTING passenger may have been used to smuggle a bomb on board a plane as part of the alleged terror plot disrupted in Sydney.
That's according to reports that claim a person could have been "blown up without knowing they were part of a suicide mission."
However it's believed the allegedly sophisticated plans hit a roadblock when the device turned out to be too heavy for cabin baggage.
Australian intelligence received word last week about an apparent plan to smuggle an explosive onto a flight which led to dramatic raids over the weekend.

Police have remained tight-lipped about their investigations, however they are working with Etihad Airlines who are assisting inquiries.
On Tuesday one of the four men arrested, Abdul Merhi, 50, was released without charge. Three other men remain in custody and have not been charged.
Abdul Merhi's lawyer Moustafa Kheir said his client felt he was "in a movie" when he heard of the allegations.
"It's a very serious allegation to have against you," Mr Kheir said. "It's just unfathomable that he would be associated- with anything like this."
"He just wants to go back to as normal life as possible now," Mr Kheir said.
Police have called for photo identification to be reintroduced for issuing domestic plane tickets and for all airport employees to go through security screening.
The peak body for pilots has also called for greater security. AusALPA president Captain Murray Butt backed calls for all passengers to be required to produce photographic identification as they must in the US.
"We certainly don't want to alarm the public," he said in Sydney. "But we want to make sure we're providing the best service that we can and the safest service that we can."
Police are still searching properties in Lakemba, Wiley Park, Punchbowl and Surry Hills for evidence.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi, 50</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Punchbowl</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Kheir</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Etihad Airlines</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wiley Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AusALPA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lakemba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Abdul Merhi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Captain Murray Butt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Surry Hills</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moustafa Kheir</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
