<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417223285888405</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:22</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/coast-stylist-celebrates-hair-raising-win/3208275/</url>
  <title>Coast stylist celebrates hair-raising win</title>
  <content>
SUNSHINE Coast hairdresser Teyanah Popik is celebrating this week after taking out first place in a coveted Queensland styling competition.
Ms Popik won the Avant Garde Upstyle competition at the recent Brisbane Hair and Beauty Expo.
The 21-year-old TAFE Queensland graduate was among 14 hairdressers from across the state to compete in the category, transforming model Cheyanne Hodge with what she described as a "punk grunge warrior glam" look as part of the Sunshine Pro Series.
Ms Popik graduated from TAFE Queensland's Mooloolaba Campus in May this year and has been working at Array Hair Design for the past two months, but credits her success to the encouragement she received from her teacher Sharan Doyle-Berry.
"Having Sharan as a teacher was awesome - she's so encouraging and when I told her I was thinking of entering she pushed me to go for it," Ms Popik said.
"TAFE is what opened up my creativity when I was in my apprenticeship - you had free range and weren't put in a box."
Ms Doyle-Berry was bursting with pride when she was asked about Ms Popik's win.
"Tey was and is amazing," Ms Doyle-Berry said.
"She is highly dedicated and attended college every week.
"She worked very hard in her apprenticeship and was always willing to help other students.
"I'm ecstatic for her. I had a great feeling that she would win - her preparation and knowing exactly how she would undertake the task at hair expo was well practised."
Ms Popik worked with TAFE Queensland beauty student Karlah Condon as her make-up artist to come up with the overall look for her model, and designed the costume herself.
She was then given one hour to create the intricate gravity-defying mohawk that won her the title while on stage.
"I knew I needed to create something that would be out there and would make people say 'wow'," said Ms Popik.
"I was more entering it for experience, not knowing I was going to take out first place.
"I was more or less going in it because it would be good for my career and it would give me more experience.
"I wasn't sure I was good enough to compete, but it just shows you what you're capable of doing."
More than 6000 people attended throughout the duration of the expo, providing competitors with a unique opportunity to showcase their work and gain exposure to industry experts.
As the Brisbane Hair and Beauty Expo was her first expo and on-stage competition, Ms Popik said no one was more surprised by her win than she was.
"I was shocked - I just kept looking around thinking that these other upstyles were amazing," she said.
"I was just happy to be there for the experience so when they called my name I was like 'wow'.
"I think it was more the self-satisfaction of knowing that I am good enough and that I created the whole look."
The win is a huge achievement for the young hairdresser, and signals the beginning of what is sure to be a long and illustrious career.
For information on TAFE Queensland's hairdressing courses visit tafeeastcoast.qld.edu.au.
A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
NAMBOUR residents have donated around 2000 knitted items.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Karlah Condon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cheyanne Hodge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Pro Series</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Popik</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>5.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Doyle-Berry</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE Queensland's Mooloolaba Campus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE Queensland</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Hair</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>TAFE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Avant Garde Upstyle</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Array Hair Design</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sharan Doyle-Berry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Beauty Expo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Teyanah Popik</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
