<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417167451312748</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/03/09/13/florida-man-disarms-beach-gunman-with-umbrella</url>
  <title>Hero disarms Florida beach gunman with umbrella</title>
  <content>
A beachgoer in Florida whacked a man with an umbrella after he pulled a gun on the sands over an argument about a toy octopus.
Monday's fight on Fort Walton Beach was sparked over a dispute about a $2 inflatable octopus and quickly escalated to the man drawing his pistol, reports the
Video shows how have-a-go hero Wes Woodin grabbed the nearest weapon - a giant beach umbrella - and knocked the man out. He then confiscated the gun.
Woodin told WKRG how he became alarmed at the man's behaviour on the beach.
"I saw him punch one of the guys in the face and knock him down while he had a gun out," Woodin said
Witness Kimberly Gutierrez and her sister filmed the brave intervention.
"The umbrella dude came and just whacked him upside the gun because he had the gun out," she said.

Related Articles

Deputies from the Okaloosa County Sheriff's Office attended the incident but neither Woodin or the man he struck pressed charges, WKRG reported.
In an amusing conclusion, Woodin posted on Facebook: "This is what happens when you bring an umbrella to a gun fight".
 
(C)   Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Florida</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimberly Gutierrez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Okaloosa County Sheriff's Office</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wes Woodin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WKRG</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Woodin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nine Digital Pty Ltd 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fort Walton Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1.7</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
