<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417343544974497</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/news/2017/08/03/malcolm-roberts-citizenship-documents/</url>
  <title>Malcolm Roberts to release citizenship documents, Hanson says</title>
  <content>
Queensland Senator Malcolm Roberts will next week table documents he says prove he was not a British citizen at the time of last year's election, One Nation leader Pauline Hanson says.
Senator Hanson said the fact the paperwork hadn't been publicly released did not mean there was a problem with it, rather, the matter was just being dealt with through the right channels.
"It will be put before the Senate next week," she told ABC Radio on Thursday.
"Those papers will be tabled."
Senator Hanson said it would be up to the upper house to decide if the matter needs to go to the High Court.
"We have no problems about that," she said.
"I was the one who said Rod Cullerton should go to the High Court because I thought he did the wrong thing.
"I have given Malcolm Roberts my full support.
"He has not done anything illegal here; he was in compliance with the Constitution."Photo: AAP
Senator Hanson said QCs had confirmed the Queensland senator had "no problems whatsoever", but it was for the Senate, not the public, to decide.
"I'm not going to be pushed into a corner by people from the media who feel it's their right," she said.
"It will go through the right channels and I have nothing to hide from the people."
Senator Roberts has faced questions about his eligibility to run for parliament in the 2016 election.
He insists he sought to renounce his British citizenship before nominating, but did not receive a written reply until six months after he was elected.
- AAP
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>QCs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland Senator Malcolm Roberts</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Constitution</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC Radio</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Roberts</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>High Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Queensland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rod Cullerton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
