<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416737954575733</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/minneapolis-school-gas-explosion/8769610</url>
  <title>Minneapolis school explosion: One dead, one missing after building collapses in gas blast</title>
  <content>
Related Story:

One person is dead and another is missing after a natural gas explosion demolished part of a private school in Minneapolis.

Key points:

Seven people hospitalised, three with critical injuries
Contractors were working on the site at time of explosion
School serves students from pre-kinder to year 12

The body was found in the rubble of a building that partially collapsed during the explosion at the Minnehaha Academy, Minneapolis fire chief John Fruetel said at a news conference.
Both individuals worked at the school, according to the Minneapolis Fire Department. No other details were immediately released.
The school had released a statement earlier in the day saying all of its summer program students and staff were "accounted for and safe".
The school didn't immediately return a message seeking comment following Mr Fruetel's news conference.
The Christian school serves students from pre-kindergarten through to year 12.
Contractors were doing work on the building at the time of the blast, which investigators determined was caused by a gas explosion, according to assistant fire chief Bryan Tyner.
The Star Tribune reported that city records showed Master Mechanical was issued a permit on June 7 for "gas piping and hooking up meter" at the school's address.
Seven adults were hospitalised, including three with critical injuries. They included head injuries and broken bones, according to the hospital's chief of emergency medicine.
'We just started digging'

Aerial video footage of the school's campus showed part of a building crumbled, windows in other areas blown out and shattered, and bricks and other debris scattered about.
Mr Tyner said three people were rescued from the roof of the building shortly after the explosion.
Paul Meskan, who lives across the street from the school, said he ran over to the school to help pull a man from the rubble.
"We just started digging," Mr Meskan said.
"Gas was going. Fire was going. And it's like, 'we're not going back until we get this guy out of here'. And [we] got him out, and they got him on a stretcher."
Governor Mark Dayton released a statement saying his office was in contact with city officials and the state "will provide any and all resources necessary" to help first responders and ensure everyone is safe.
AP

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minnehaha Academy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Fruetel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bryan Tyner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Star Tribune</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minneapolis Fire Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINNEAPOLIS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Meskan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Meskan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Tyner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fruetel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Governor Mark Dayton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Master Mechanical</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
