<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417343544974480</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/messenger/south/notorious-morphett-vale-intersection-to-get-500000-safety-fix/news-story/d0d5afa03d8d7e9f70216ce7593ec7a3</url>
  <title>Intersection to get $500,000 safety fix</title>
  <content>
THE intersection of Main South and Hillier roads at Morphett Vale is being redesigned to make it less hazardous.
In a $536,000 State Government upgrade, access from Main South Rd to Hillier Rd will change.
The existing road will be blocked and replaced with a left-turning lane slightly further north.
The right-turning lane from Hillier Rd to Main South Rd is to be realigned, with an increased curve - to allow the new left-turning lane.
A reversing bay will be installed within the blocked-off section of Hillier Rd to ease access for traffic entering and leaving properties.
New street lights and a bike lane will also be installed along Main South Rd.
A Transport Department spokesman said the improvements would help reduce the risk of rear-end and right-turn crashes.
He warned drivers to be cautious of road restrictions throughout construction.
"While the department will make every effort to minimise impacts to road users, it will be necessary for lane and speed restrictions to apply during construction," the spokesman said.
"Access to properties will be maintained throughout the works."
Construction is expected to start in the next few months. Posts already mark the site.
The spokesman said the project should be finished by the end of the year.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillier</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main South Rd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Transport Department</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hillier Rd</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morphett Vale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>State Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Main South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
