<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416785199217121</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/real-estate/victoria/east/custom-built-home-attracts-seven-figures-in-preauction-deal/news-story/cf78dadda9f1b1538e2e761a0dc74a09</url>
  <title>Custom built home attracts seven figures in pre-auction deal - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
sold ahead of auction for a seven-figure price.

A CROYDON North property has sold ahead of its auction for more than $1 million, after a buyer couldn't wait for it to go under the hammer.
McGrath Croydon principal Paul Fenech said the home at had been scheduled for a July 29 auction.
He said a keen buyer emerged from among the others, however, and made an early offer that secured the home.
"It sold a few days before," Mr Fenech said.
The property sold for an undisclosed, seven-figure sum, he added.
The four-bedroom house on an 8100sq m block was custom built by boutique building company Genjusho.
It has a treetop outlook, decked areas, and a north-facing living area with vast expanses of glass.

The north-facing living area captures natural light and a treed outlook.

Mr Fenech said the buyer, from near the Mornington Peninsula, will move to the property.
"They loved the land, and the openness and natural light the house offered," he said.
Mr Fenech said the sale had demonstrated there was demand for custom-built homes in the area, and that this coupled with the large land size had been a winning combination.
"Anything a bit different always attracts a lot of attention," he said.
"And anything that has plenty of land is well sought after."
SEE SUBURB PROFILE:
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Fenech</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mornington Peninsula</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SUBURB PROFILE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Fenech</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CROYDON North</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath Croydon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Genjusho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
