<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417257645627280</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/entertainment/tv-and-radio/i-was-the-most-famous-person-in-the-room-marco-pierre-white-on-hells-kitchen-20170731-gxm34j.html</url>
  <title>'I was the most famous person in the room': Marco Pierre White on Hell's Kitchen</title>
  <content>
I wouldn't have cut it in a professional kitchen. Burly dudes in whites spitting "Donkey!" in my face because I over-browned the butter sauce. I'd crumble like halva.
I know this because I was just chewed out by Marco Pierre White, the enfant terrible of London's '90s food revolution, the menacing chef whose frenzied glare in White Heat unleashed the enduring image of the tortured galley artiste driven by demons towards culinary perfection.

Up Next
The Bacherlor 2017:
The first kiss

02:18

More Entertainment News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Entertainment news highlights

Thor and Stranger Things release trailers at Comic Con, Sam Newman keeps quiet, Delta gets pulled and Rhys Nicholson gets cut off.

White, 55 - whose reign at Harveys and Restaurant Marco Pierre White ended with the ultimate act of professional dissidence, when he handed back his hard-won three Michelin stars ("I was being judged by people who had less knowledge than me - so what are three stars worth?" he offers) - has become better known to local TV audiences as the surprisingly sweet "Marco" on MasterChef, a guest mentor who, with a nurturing line, could break the most heavily tattooed bloke into tears about his nonna's raviolo.
He's now switched networks, leading Hell's Kitchen, Seven's latest foray into reality cooking - a move that tabloid whispers levelled at clashes with the MasterChef team, and a very public falling out with host Matt Preston who offhandedly quipped about White's son's drug problems during a recent radio appearance ("I will never forgive that man," White reportedly responded at the time).
As is my journalistic burden, I broached the subject with a nervous glint. The saucepan boiled over.
"There were no personality clashes. And if you want me to give you some clarification on that, I'll have some clarification on it," White boomed.

"Well, there were reports of a feud with Matt Pre-"

You will now receive updates from

Entertainment Newsletter

Entertainment Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

"I have no feud with Matt Preston. And if you'd done your homework correctly, you'd realise that I was brought into a situation, I didn't create a situation ... Therefore I think it's pointless going down this road, sir. Any more questions?"
Eyes glowered, he shuffled to leave, minutes into our scheduled chat. I won him back with a shameless story about my infant son's eating habits and a vague summary of Michael Steinberger's Au Revoir To All That ("One of my favourite ever books," says White). Hey, you use what you can.
With his cuddly spell on MasterChef in the distance ("Never watched that show. Not interested," he says), Marco, the intimidating myth, is back. And this time, his ire is aimed at celebrities. Well, "celebrities".
Hell's Kitchen, all ominous mood music and shots of a silhouetted Marco dragging his eight-inch chef's blade across kitchen benchtops, finds White entering service with the likes of failed Bachelorette Sam Frost , Pettifleur from Real Housewives, one of the quizmasters from The Chase, and Pippa from Home and Away (Debra Lawrance).
"Didn't recognise one of them, not one," White deadpans. "As far as I was concerned, I was the most famous person in the room."Hell's Kitchen
He says he returned to the show, a concept created by his protege Gordon Ramsay, which he originally hosted in Britain for two seasons in the late 2000s, because it's the "most natural environment for me to operate in".
"That's the world I grew up in, a kitchen," he says. "I'm not a TV presenter, I'm a cook. It'd be like asking me to do a gardening show. I wouldn't be very good at it.
"But those doors open," he thunderously claps his hands, "service begins, the producers have no say in what happens - they just have to film it and watch it unravel."
Despite the demands of reality television - and Seven's brand at that, which tends to flourish on concocted drama - White denies he's playing up his strong-arm persona for entertainment value.
"I'm not trying to ridicule people or belittle people. It's not my job to bring drama. Drama unravels because of the pressure. When you've got 90 covers and just four chefs and me, you don't need to create drama.
"I'm just a ringmaster, a Pied Piper, a bingo caller," he says, deflecting his headline act. "The celebrities are the stars, and I'm there to help them succeed. I have to dissolve all those things that intimidate them: covers, stoves, the kitchen, Marco ... It's all created in their minds. What they've got to do is follow me and learn quick. It's survival of the fittest."
His approach, though terse, is proven: Ramsay, Mario Batali​ and local heroes Curtis Stone and Shannon Bennett are among those who've flourished under his tutelage. On Hell's Kitchen, it commands a begrudging respect.
"Just gotta be firm, and drive them," he says. "Whip them. That's metaphorically speaking. You say, 'Do you want me to drive you, to push you, to bring out the best in you?' They say, 'Yes, Marco.' That's it."
Hell's Kitchen premieres on Seven on Sunday, August 6, at 7pm.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comic Con</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Steinberger's Au Revoir To All That</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Pre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White Heat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Debra Lawrance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stranger Things</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Curtis Stone</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pippa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gordon Ramsay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London's '90</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Delta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michelin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harvey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterchef</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pettifleur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bachelorette Sam Frost</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam Newman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Real Housewives</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>White, 55</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marcos</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bacherlor 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Restaurant Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mario Batali</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shannon Bennett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 6</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hell's Kitchen</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ramsay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pied Piper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matt Preston</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rhys Nicholson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Entertainment News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Marco Pierre White</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
