<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417352134909217</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:52</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/ingebrigtsen-signs-on-for-another-year-at-falcons/3208302/</url>
  <title>Ingebrigtsen signs on for another year at Falcons</title>
  <content>
RUGBY LEAGUE: Craig Ingebrigtsen will coach the Sunshine Coast for at least another year after signing a contract extension.
In a boost to the club, 'Trigger' will remain at Bokarina until the end of 2018.
"I'm really enjoying my time here at the Falcons and am very happy to have extended my contract for a further 12 months," he said in a club press release.
"We're in a strong position on the ladder and as a club and I'm looking forward to continuing to help the club move forward both on and off the field.
"We have a great junior rugby league nursery here on the Sunshine Coast and we need to continue to develop those young players into future Falcons and provide them with a pathway to the NRL through the Falcons Football Club."
Ingebrigtsen initially joined the club at the end of 2015 on a two-year deal.
In his first season, he helped the Falcons emerge as a force on the state league stage, taking the side to the preliminary final.
It was the club's first taste of finals football in six years.
He's got this year's outfit in second place on the Intrust Super Cup ladder with finals approaching and the team is favoured by bookmakers to win the competition.
"Trigger has been outstanding since his appointment," club CEO Chris Flannery said.
"To take a team from 12th to a preliminary final in the space of 12 months is a massive achievement and shows the class and professionalism of his coaching, leadership and man management skills.
"We have big plans for our club's future and having a quality head coach is paramount to our future development and success" Flannery added.
A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
NAMBOUR residents have donated around 2000 knitted items.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Ingebrigtsen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO Chris Flannery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NRL</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falcons Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ingebrigtsen</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Intrust Super Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bokarina</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flannery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Falcons</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RUGBY LEAGUE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
