<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417296300333569</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4830805/crucial-showdown-for-group-seven-rivals-gerringong-kiama/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Crucial showdown for Group Seven rivals Gerringong, Kiama</title>
  <content>
Showdown: Gerringong Lions' captain Rixon Russell and Kiama Knights' captain Kieran Poole prepare for their teams clash on August 5.

Reigning premiers, Gerringong take on Kiama Knights in a crucial battle for finals sports at Michael Cronin Oval on Saturday.
Radio 2GBs Ray Hadley, 'The Big Marn' Darryl Brohman, Bob Fulton, David Morrow and Mark 'Piggy' Riddell will broadcast the first grade match live from 2pm.
The annual contest started in 2012 after the 2GB team enjoyed their initial day there so much they asked if they could come back.
The following year they turned up with a cup and and the 2GB Continuous Call Team Cup has been contested each year since.
"We will be coming off a bye, which is pretty handy for us," Gerringong Lions captain Rixon Russell said.  
"We had a couple of slow weeks there with two losses on the trot. 
"The bye will hopefully freshen us up and we're getting one or two blokes back - everyone is always keen to play Kiama and I'm sure it will be a good game."
Kiama Knights captain Kieran Poole said his team would benefit from the return of injured players.
"We've got a couple of the boys coming back - we like to play fast so hopefully we're nice and mobile and we can move the ball around, it will be a good game," he said.
Since 2010, Kiama and Gerringong have also contested the Danny Morse Challenge Shield on the day.
"Danny was a favourite son of ours and we lost him a few years back," Gerringong Rugby League Football Club president Daryl Hobbs said.
"In memory of Danny, who actually played for both clubs, we thought the contest between Gerringong and Kiama was a fitting tribute."
"We've shared it around a bit between the two clubs, it's been a very good contest and everyone gets enthused about it each year."
Both teams will endeavour to raise some much needed funds on the day for local charities including a young local junior player battling illness.
"We're going to use the day to raise some funds for The Mark Hughes Foundation," Hobbs said.
"We will be selling beanies for $30, $20 goes to the foundation and $10 will go to a young junior here who has been diagnosed with a tumour on the brain, Denver Ford.
"We're going to try and help his family out with the mounting medical costs."
The charities to benefit from the day include:

Beanies For Brain Cancer - beanies will be for sale at the ground to raise funds for The Mark Hughes Foundation.
The KidzWish Foundation -  who organisers hope can get some of their young people to the game and enjoy the festivities with family and friends.
The McGrath Foundation - first grade players will be wearing pink socks to create awareness of breast cancer.

There will also be a jumping castle for the kids and a new slushy machine in the canteen, not to mention a revamped 'Steak Hut' serving plenty of delicious food.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>GB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Cronin Oval</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daryl Hobbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Piggy' Riddell</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerringong</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGrath Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rixon Russell</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>GB Continuous Call Team Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hobbs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny Morse Challenge Shield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver Ford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Radio 2GBs Ray Hadley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brain Cancer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Morrow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerringong Lions</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mark Hughes Foundation</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama Knights</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KidzWish Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Group Seven</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steak Hut</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Fulton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerringong Rugby League Football Club</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Danny</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Marn' Darryl Brohman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kieran Poole</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
