<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417090141900304</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:51</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/sport/soccer/soccers-330-million-man-neymar-set-to-move-from-barcelona-to-psg-this-week-20170802-gxo81y.html</url>
  <title>Soccer's $330 million man: Neymar set to move from Barcelona to PSG this week</title>
  <content>
Brazilian striker Neymar is expected to complete the richest transfer in soccer history this week after informing his club, Barcelona, that he wishes to join Paris Saint-Germain.
The transfer fee alone will cost the French team €222 million ($330 million), more than doubling the previous record.

Up Next

Hooper steps up as Wallabies skipper

01:13

More Sports HQ Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Neymar leaving Barca, Spanish superclub confirms

Brazilian striker Neymar has informed Barcelona he plans to leave the club. The soccer superstar is expected to sign with Paris Saint-Germain (PSG) in a world record deal worth nearly $750 million.

As well as meeting the €222 million buyout clause in the player's contract at Barcelona, PSG is prepared to pay Neymar about €30 million a year, after taxes, in salary over the next five years.
That would make Neymar worth about $554 million over five years.

Neymar's father, who also acts as his agent, is expected to earn a commission in the region of €40 million.
Some estimates have put the total cost of the deal to PSG's Qatari owners at more than half a billion US dollars, including various image rights allowances and, according to at least one report, a possible ambassadorial role for Neymar during the 2022 World Cup in Qatar.

Neymar, 25, informed Barcelona of his wish to leave after returning to Spain from a brief promotional visit to China on Tuesday.

You will now receive updates from

Sport Newsletter

Sport Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

He reported to Barcelona's training centre on the outskirts of the city on Wednesday morning, but, with the blessing of the club's coach, Ernesto Valverde, did not join in training.Photo: AP
Instead, after informing teammates of his decision to leave, he and his father met Barcelona's president, Josep Maria Bartomeu, in the club's offices.
Neymar also told Bartomeu of his desire to leave the club. According to a club statement, Neymar was reminded that Barcelona would only sanction his departure upon full payment of the buyout clause in his contract, signed last year and which runs until 2021. The meeting lasted less than 30 minutes.Photo: AP
Neymar is thought to have travelled to London with his father on Wednesday afternoon to review and sign the contract on offer from PSG.
Wagner Ribeiro, the agent who represents Neymar in Latin America, travelled to Paris this week, and he is expected to meet the player in London.Photo: Siu Wu
Neymar then will undergo a medical examination. PSG is planning to present him as its player, and the most expensive in the history of the sport, by the end of the week.
The record stands at €105 million, the fee Manchester United paid to Juventus last summer to sign midfielder Paul Pogba.
Javier Tebas, the president of La Liga, the Spanish top division, had previously intimated that the league might refuse to ratify payment of the buyout clause, citing concerns over PSG's inability to complete the deal and comply with the Financial Fair Play regulations introduced by UEFA, the sport's governing body in Europe.
Those rules dictate that any club making a €30 million loss over a three-year period is punished.
However, there is believed to be no mechanism that allows the Spanish authorities to block Neymar's move.
Barcelona's players appeared resigned to Neymar's decision, with Lionel Messi posting a tribute on Instagram.
"It was a great pleasure to share all these years with you, friend," Messi wrote. "I wish you good luck in this new stage of your life."
In Neymar and Messi's four years together at Camp Nou, Barcelona won two Spanish championships, three Copas del Rey, the 2015 Champions League and the 2015 Club World Cup.
Together with Luis Suarez - an attack the Spanish press dubbed the MSN - they formed what many regard as the best forward line in the club's history.
That Neymar has elected to break it up is, to those around him, testament to his desire to become a franchise player in his own right.
Neymar's ambition remains to win FIFA's World Player of the Year award, something he felt he could not do while he remained at Messi's service.
Barcelona's hierarchy is less impressed. Neymar turned down an approach from PSG last summer, choosing to extend his contract instead.
Barcelona has confirmed that it has withheld a loyalty bonus due to Neymar for that decision until his future is clarified.
For PSG, meanwhile, the move represents a significant coup and a considerable step toward its ambition of taking a place at European soccer's top table.
As well as the financial firepower required to lure Neymar from Barcelona, the club has also moved to make him feel as comfortable as possible.
It added Daniel Alves, a former teammate and fellow Brazilian, to its roster this summer, as well as deciding that his close friend Lucas Moura will be retained.
Manchester United manager Jose Mourinho said the fee for Neymar was "not expensive".
Mourinho believes the Brazilian striker is worth the record-breaking price tag, but he did express concern the move would inflate the value of players who were not so deserving of big transfer fees.
"When we paid that amount for Paul [Pogba], I said that it was not expensive," Mourinho said after United's 2-1 friendly victory over Sampdoria in Dublin.
"Expensive are the ones who get into a certain level without a certain quality.
"I think that Neymar is the same [as Pogba]. I don't think he is expensive.
"I think he is expensive [in] the fact that now you are going to have more players at £100 million ($166 million), you are going to have more players at £80 million and more players at £60 million.
"And I think that's the problem.
"Neymar is one of the best players in the world; commercially he is very strong and for sure Paris St Germain thought about it.
"So I think the problem is not Neymar, I think the problem is the consequences of Neymar."
The New York Times, with PA
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MSN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Copa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Siu Wu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Javier Tebas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Latin America</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Europe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>UEFA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sampdoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Juventus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ernesto Valverde</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bartomeu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messi</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Financial Fair Play</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sports HQ Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris St-Germain</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Club World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jose Mourinho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mourinho</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>La Liga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pogba</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paris Saint-Germain</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dublin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Qatar</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wagner Ribeiro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Paul Pogba</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Cup</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazilian</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wallabies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Daniel Alves</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lionel Messi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lucas Moura</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PSG's Qatari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Luis Suarez</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hooper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Manchester United</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Spanish</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barca</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Camp Nou</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar, 25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Josep Maria Bartomeu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champions League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fifa World Player of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>London.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Neymar</name>
    <count>26</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barcelona</name>
    <count>13</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
