<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417261940594604</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Channel 9 News</source>
  <url>http://www.9news.com.au/world/2017/08/03/11/19/aussie-s-widow-weeps-for-damond-family</url>
  <title>Aussie's widow weeps for Damond family</title>
  <content>
It has been six years since Katie McNicol's husband Greg McNicol, the life-loving Australian property developer, was gunned down in the front yard of a Detroit apartment complex he bought for $US35,000 and was renovating.
It has been a tough six years.
Ms McNicol nursed her broken heart by learning to live her life a day at a time.
But, the recent Minneapolis police shooting death of Justine Damond, another vibrant Aussie who met a tragic end in the US, broke her heart again.
"Justine's story has opened a wound," Ms McNicol told AAP.
"Her personality was very similar to Greg's.
"Justine brought joy to everybody around her and that's how Greg was - he was the light of the room."

Related Articles

Both believed the US to be a land of opportunity.
Mr McNicol saw great opportunities to buy properties in US and used his skills to bring them back to life.
Ms Damond moved to the US after falling in love with Minneapolis man Don Damond and they planned to marry in Hawaii this month.
Ms McNicol has been repeatedly brought to tears as she read media reports about the Damonds, noting similarities big and small, like how Ms Damond would sleep on her fiance's side of the bed when he was away on business.
"I did that," she said.
"They were deeply in love with each other and that's how Greg and I were after eight years together.
"It's another love story interrupted."
Almost 115,000 people are killed by guns in America each year.
Ms Damond was shot by Minneapolis police officer Mohamed Noor in an alley on July 15 after she called 911 fearing a woman was being raped near her home.
Mr Damond was in Las Vegas on business and had to make a horrific flight home.
Ms McNicol's nightmare came on May 7, 2011, when she was visiting her native Brazil and also had to make a horror flight back to the US.
Mr McNicol, 45, had given one the tenants of his Detroit apartment complex, 20-year-old Ayana Young, an eviction notice after she failed to pay rent.
Ms Young called her father, Freddie Young, a 63-year-old who continued his US postal job despite winning $US29 million in a lottery with 12 colleagues just months earlier.
Young drove to the complex, pulled out a gun and shot Mr McNicol near the groin, severing arteries.
He quickly bled to death.
Young was jailed for 25 to 30 years.
Ms Damond, Mr McNicol and their families join a sad and long list of Australians killed or severely injured while in the US pursuing their dreams.
2013 - Chris Lane, 22, from Melbourne and a member of an Oklahoma university baseball team, went for a jog on the residential streets of his girlfriend Sarah Harper's home town of Duncan when Chancey Luna, then 16, randomly selected him and fired a fatal bullet into his back.
2014 - Champion Australian rower and lifesaver Robert Scott, 26, suffered brain damage when he was punched on a Fresno, California residential street.
2016 - Canberra-born Kevin Reid, owner of an Aboriginal art gallery in Savannah, Georgia, was on an after dinner stroll home with American wife Kari when three thugs, one wearing a bandana across his face, shot him dead.
2016 - Kalgoorlie-based Curtin University mining students Toben Clements and Jake Rovacsek were shot, but survived, after a night out on New Orleans' Bourbon Street.
2017 - Matthew Bate, an Australian tourist in San Francisco, was killed when allegedly punched by a Californian man.
Ms McNicol believes she may have met Ms Damond as they both attended workshops run by Dr Joe Dispenza, who uses neuroscience and quantum physics to heal illness and help people live fulfilled and happy lives.
"What Don Damond is going through now is the hardest part because you feel so powerless that the one you love is not coming back," said Ms McNicol, who added that books by author Anita Moorjani also helped her grief.
"One thing I didn't like what people told me was 'Time heals all wounds'," she said.
"It's partly true, but I think you need to take it a day at a time."
(C)  AAP 2017
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McNicol, 45</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anita Moorjani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chris Lane, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fresno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Matthew Bates</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg McNicol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chancey Luna</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kari</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>July 15</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oklahoma</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ayana Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Freddie Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms McNicol</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Georgia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra-born Kevin Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>May 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$35,000</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toben Clements</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Don Damond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Champion Australian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MINNEAPOLIS</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Orleans' Bourbon Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Damond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Detroit</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aboriginal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justine</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SAVANNAH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Joe Dispenza</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Justine Damond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Las Vegas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP 2017</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Young</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mohamed Noor</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Damond</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aussie</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaii</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sarah Harper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jake Rovacsek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr McNicol</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Katie McNicol</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Scott, 26</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Duncan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AAP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kalgoorlie-based Curtin University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Damond</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US29</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Californian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
