<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417339250007143</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:49</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Australian Financial Review</source>
  <url>http://www.afr.com/business/media-and-marketing/tv/fairfax-media-signs-up-for-network-tens-financial-details-20170803-gxobkm</url>
  <title>Fairfax Media signs up for Network Ten's financial details</title>
  <content>
Fairfax Media is understood to be one of at least nine parties to sign up for the financial numbers on Network Ten, as the collapsed free-to-air broadcaster's advisors call for indicative bids by the end of August.
Sources close to the sale process of Ten said Fairfax, publisher of The Australian Financial Review, signed a non-disclosure agreement and has picked up an information memorandum (IM), a document detailing Ten's business and financials.
However, they noted they did not believe Fairfax was serious about acquiring Ten, the home of Masterchef and Gogglebox, rather it was taking the opportunity to have a look at the metropolitan broadcaster's numbers.
Fairfax declined to comment.

Louie Douvis

Others to have secured an IM include , which helped keep . New York-based hedge fund , private equity and distressed debt firm , US studio CBS, Lachlan Murdoch's Illyria and Bruce Gordon's Birketu have also picked up Ten's documents.

Releasing the IM is the first stage in the two-step auction process. Indicative bids are due in late August after receiver PPB Advisory and adviser Moelis & Co pushed back the date so bidders would have more time to get offers prepared.
Even if Fairfax were interested in buying Ten it is prevented from doing so by current media regulation. The 'two out of three' rule, which prevents one entity from owning a TV station, radio network and newspaper in the same market would prevent Fairfax from acquiring Ten.
should media ownership regulation change.
The government is trying to remove the 'two out of three' rule, which also prevents Mr Murdoch from making a bid, as well as the 'reach rule' which prevents a TV network from broadcasting to more than 75 per cent of the population, a rule which stops Mr Gordon from acquiring Ten.

 after billionaire shareholders and guarantors of a $200 million Commonwealth Bank of Australia loan .
Mr Gordon and Mr Murdoch have long pined for taking greater control of Ten - the former is the network's largest shareholder with just under 15 per cent via his investment company Birketu, while Mr Murdoch holds around 7.7 per cent through his investment vehicle Illyria. Foxtel, which is 50-50 owned by Telstra and News Corporation, of which Mr Murdoch is co-chairman, owns another 13.9 per cent of Ten.
The pair have  which hinges on the government successfully changing media ownership regulation when Parliament returns in August 8.  which is slated to give a ruling, or a statement of issues, on August 24.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Co</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IM</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corporation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr. Gordon</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Network Ten</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Financial Review</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Masterchef</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gogglebox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Murdoch's Illyria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Birketu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Murdoch</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bruce Gordon's Birketu</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moelis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Foxtel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commonwealth Bank of Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illyria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 8</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PPB Advisory</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fairfax Media</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-0.5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CBS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
