<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417261940594609</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/entertainment/music/latest-album-reviews-julia-michaels-vic-mensa-closed-circuits-fountaineer-black-cab/news-story/93ca1c8b103e8c79619cb8ea89f541e2</url>
  <title>Latest Album Reviews</title>
  <content>
Five records, analysed with intent.
NERVOUS SYSTEM
JULIA MICHAELS
(UNIVERSAL)
3.5 stars
Julia Michaels started her career as a celebrity whisperer, a songwriter helping coax out - or indeed implant - personal words in the mouths of everyone from Bieber to Britney, Selena to Chester. Now she has cut out the middle person and is writing the hits and singing them herself.
Several A-listers wanted Issues but Michaels kept it for herself, knowing it was too private and no doubt realising it was also a stone cold hit. This debut mini-album will also create instant superstar envy as Michaels opens her diary and her heart. Worst In Me is the kind of toxic relationship song that manages to put a new spin on toxic relationship songs - lines like "remember when I used to be happy for you? You could go out with your friends and I'd
be totally fine" sounding like someone raised on Alanis Morissette's self-help pop.
See also Let Me Make It Up To You's opening line "no you're not really that small, I just said
it so I hurt you". Her cut-to-the-core words are also wrapped in smart, modern pop tunes fashioned with the team Michaels usually writes with for other people. New single Uh Huh taps into the fun of early Kesha, with one of the year's best pre-choruses and you already know how special Issues is. Michaels got Hailee Steinfeld to sing about self-love in her Disney days, but for her own record Pink's lyrics are Peaches meets Prince. On Pink Michaels whispers (like the 'I mean I could but why would I want to' bit on another Michaels co-write, Selena Gomez's Hands To Myself) that there's no innuendos or metaphors in the literal, not-so-self-love love song. Michaels flies solo on Don't Wanna Think, a "drinking" song full of drunk texts, anger and, most importantly, honesty - already her trademark trait./CAMERON ADAMS
Sounds like: honest pop
In a word: direct
Here are four more what we did score:
and time to buy them, good citizens of the world:

Hit us up on twitter, ya fiends

(Mikey)

Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cameron Adams</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Album Reviews</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wanna Think</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Disney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chester</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mikey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uh-huh</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prince</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>JULIA MICHAELS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selena Gomez's Hands To Myself</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Selena</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Britney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Let Me Make It Up To You</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pink Michaels</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kesha</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hailee Steinfeld</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bieber</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alanis Morissette</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
