<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417300595300882</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.themercury.com.au/news/scales-of-justice/driver-with-kids-in-car-clocked-at-123kmh-on-icy-road-near-burnie/news-story/8fe9e20f22d9622fb64fd186d5cad662</url>
  <title>Speeding driver dicing with danger: police</title>
  <content>
A DRIVER with kids in her car has been caught speeding on an icy road on the state's North-West Coast, but police say the penalty could have been much higher.
Tasmania Police said the woman was clocked at 123km/h on the frosty Ridgley Highway - 23km/h over the limit.
Inspector Adrian Shadbolt, of Western District Road and Public Order Services, said officers were carrying out a targeted speed reduction operation this morning in response to a recent serious crash because of black ice on the road.
Insp Shadbolt said it was disappointing some motorists continued to ignore road weather warnings.

"Despite numerous and ongoing warnings from police, coupled with road weather alerts from the weather bureau relating to road conditions and black ice, RPOS detected a female motorist with her two children in the car with her travelling at 123kmh," he said.
"The road was subject to frost and ice at the time and the air temperature was -4 degrees."
"While the motorist will receive an infringement notice for speeding as a result of the detection with a penalty of three points and a monetary fine, in this circumstance, the penalty for speeding could have been much higher.

We still have a few more weeks of winter and are likely to continue with frosty mornings into spring, please take heed of warnings and alerts, reduce speed and drive to the conditions.
"The apparent lack of driver consideration of all the factors in this incident including weather and road conditions, speed and precious cargo in the vehicle is very concerning and could have ended tragically, not only for the detected driver and passengers in this instance but also other road users.
"Road weather alerts, and driving to the conditions warnings are not given lightly.
"If you think it won't happen to you, think again.
"We still have a few more weeks of winter and are likely to continue with frosty mornings into spring, please take heed of warnings and alerts, reduce speed and drive to the conditions."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Insp Shadbolt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Inspector Adrian Shadbolt, of Western</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Public Order Services</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>District Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ridgley Highway - 23</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North-West Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tasmania Police</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RPOS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
