<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417300595300916</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Northern Territory News</source>
  <url>http://www.ntnews.com.au/entertainment/rocker-to-give-crocs-wide-berth/news-story/136b39e25771fb364188e80414c84a38</url>
  <title>Rocker to give crocs wide berth</title>
  <content>
THERE will be no windsurfing for Icehouse front man Iva Davies while he's in Darwin - he came too close to a croc the first time he gave it a shot in Darwin.
Icehouse is in town headlining One Tropical Day on Sunday with Jon Stevens, Kate Ceberano, 1927 and Pseudo Echo, but it was back in 1990 while touring the Code Blue album that Davies brushed close to a crocodile. "In those days a number of the band were fanatical windsurfers and we found a beach in Darwin Harbour that hired windsurfing boards," he said.
"I was in my intermediate days so I was still falling off a lot but I was merrily going out from the shore and going past what I thought was an old tyre in the water.
"Of course, I had a sudden realisation when I was a long way off shore that it was in fact a crocodile." Davies recalled seeing a huge crocodile pulled from the Darwin Harbour on the front page of the NT News the following day, confirming his initial fears.
"I was gobsmacked that anybody would windsurf in Darwin Harbour and couldn't believe there was a hire service and scores of people on the water."
Needless to say Davies said he wanted this trip to more relaxing with the most energy expended on stage at the Darwin Amphitheatre.
"I always got very nervous before shows, and I still do - something short of absolute panic," he said. "But it's an incredible rush of adrenaline."
After a huge string of shows so far this year Davies said the band was in fine form for Sunday's performance.
"So far this year we've played 26 shows to 270,000 people so we're playing pretty well," Davies said.
"We have an awful lot of people and an extraordinary team and the production values we will be bringing to the NT will be on a scale that's not been seen there for a very long time - it's a very big show."
Davies said they would perform as many hits as possible but it wasn't possible to play them all.
"It's tricky because we always have to leave something out, which becomes incredibly difficult when you're leaving out something that's been a top 10 hit," he said. "There will inevitably be something left out that someone really desperately wanted to hear, but having said that, we get to play a whole load of songs a whole load of people really love."
One Tropical Day featuring Icehouse, Jon Stevens, Kate Ceberano, 1927 and Pseudo Echo at the Darwin Amphitheatre on Sunday from 4pm. Tickets $99-150 from ticketebo.com.au.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pseudo Echo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jon Stevens</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tropical Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NT News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Code Blue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>IceHouse</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kate Ceberano, 1927</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Amphitheatre</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>One Tropical Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Darwin Harbour</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Iva Davies</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Davies</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
