<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416742249543152</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:30</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/blogs/andrew-bolt/now-abcs-julia-baird-tells-falsehood-about-islam/news-story/0981655c7cee5333220a45f770f9e2e9</url>
  <title>NOW ABC'S JULIA BAIRD TELLS FALSEHOOD ABOUT ISLAM</title>
  <content>
The ABC's Julia Baird falsely smeared Christians as encouraging wife-beating. In contrast, she falsely clears Islam's Mohammed. Detect a pattern here?  

Research shows that the men most likely to abuse their wives are evangelical Christians who attend church sporadically.
, and .
So Baird replaced falsehood that with:
Overall the international studies indicate that intimate partner violence is just as serious a problem in Christian communities, as it is in the general community.
This, too, was false, and:
Professor Bradford Wilcox, says this is not at all what his study found: "The [ABC's] story fails the basic journalistic test of fairness by presenting an almost completely negative picture of Christian approaches to domestic abuse, one that does not square with the evidence that church-going couples, in America at least, appear to be less likely to suffer domestic violence and more likely to enjoy happy marriages."
So Baird's agenda is plain. She wants Christianity to seem a danger to women when the opposite is true.
Now contrast.

Debate around whether Islam permits wife beating is mostly concentrated on the 34th verse in chapter four of the Koran.
For centuries male scholars have argued that it gives husbands financial and or fundamental superiority over women, as well as the right to physically discipline - or "beat lightly" - their wives.
According to one translation, :
"Men are the protectors and maintainers of women, because Allah has given the one more (strength) than the other, and because they support them from their means. Therefore the righteous women are devoutly obedient, and guard in (the husband's) absence what Allah would have them guard. As to those women on whose part ye fear disloyalty and ill-conduct, admonish them (first), (next), refuse to share their beds, (and last) beat them (lightly); but if they return to obedience, seek not against them means (of annoyance): For Allah is Most High, great (above you all)."
However, in recent decades  have argued such interpretations contradict major Islamic teachings of non-violence and gender equality.
The verse should not be read literally, they say, but in context with other Koranic verses, as well as the example of the Prophet Muhammad, who - as has been well-established in hadiths, which document his words and actions - never hit his wives, and encouraged men to treat women with respect.
False. At least one hadith shows Muhammad did indeed hit his wives.
Here is some of Hadith Number 2127 from the Sahih Muslim, considered one of the most authentic collections of sayings about the Prophet, quoting here his wife, Aisha, saying what he'd done after she'd left home without permission:
I, however, preceded him and I entered (the house), and as I lay down in the bed, he (the Holy Prophet) entered the (house), and said: Why is it, O 'Aisha, that you are out of breath? I said: There is nothing. He said: Tell me or the Subtle and the Aware would inform me. I said: Messenger of Allah, may my father and mother be ransom for you, and then I told him (the whole story). He said: Was it the darkness (of your shadow) that I saw in front of me? I said: Yes. He struck me on the chest which caused me pain, and then said: Did you think that Allah and His Apostle would deal unjustly with you?
What's more the Koran is the word of Muhammad, who indeed instructed men to "beat" his wives. And - again, counter to the impression Baird gives.
Her agenda is again clear. She wants Islam to seem safe for women when the opposite is true.
What on earth is the ABC doing?
(Via .)
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koranic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sahih Muslim</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prophet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Messenger of Allah</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prophet Muhammad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islamic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam's Mohammed</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC's Julia Baird</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allah</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Koran</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Professor Bradford Wilcox</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christianity</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hadith Number 2127</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC'S JULIA BAIRD TELLS FALSEHOOD ABOUT ISLAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Aisha</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Muhammad</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Apostles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>O</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Islam</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Holy Prophet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baird</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
