<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416652055228069</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>23:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Perth Now</source>
  <url>http://www.perthnow.com.au/news/western-australia/fatal-dog-attack-victim-sue-lopicich-loved-all-dogs-at-her-perth-kennel/news-story/adc9ce7bbcd1bb71254151dd79dc3824</url>
  <title>'Dog crazy' mum who cared for all types</title>
  <content>
SUE Lopicich loved her dogs - according to her neighbours, even the aggressive ones.

Many were her pets, others short-term guests on their way to a permanent home. Some were other people's pets boarded while their owners were away.
Whatever their story, Ms Lopicich treated them with the same love and affection.
In a Facebook post on Mother's Day, Ms Lopicich's daughter Courtney wrote that her mum was a little "dog crazy", but that her family loved her for it.
Last month, rescue group Dogs Behind Bars praised Ms Lopicich on Instagram for her help caring for dogs they could eventually place in a home.
"Without Sue offering to help, we would be unable to save so many dogs," the post said.
"We wanted to thank her for all the hours of cooking, cleaning and cuddling she puts in for these unwanted pups while they are searching for their forever home."
Ms Lopicich was so passionate that, according to one neighbour, she often took in dogs unsuitable for rescue. Reviews of her kennels on Facebook painted a similar picture of her love and care for the animals.
"I would highly recommend Barko's for your fur babies holiday," Nicole Ferrel posted last year.
"Sue is extremely caring and knowledgeable. She ensures that all dogs get plenty of outside play each day. On cold nights she wraps them in blankets to keep them warm."
Another customer, Anna Bella, posted: "Care is individual, quality food is provided and each dog is provided with daily exercise/toys. Sue ensures time is spent with the dogs and each evening she says goodnight to each one."
Natalie Plunkett posted: "Sue looks after the dogs like they are her children. They get her individual attention."
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anna Bella</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Natalie Plunkett</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Facebook</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicole Ferrel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dogs Behind Bars</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mother's Day</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sue Lopicich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Lopicich</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Instagram</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
