<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417261940594653</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:31</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/fashion/f-fur-fashion-retailer-century-21-slammed-for-selling-real-fur-and-theyre-not-the-only-ones/news-story/ecf8804d7293519314098b7c11c99b04</url>
  <title>'F*** fur': Activists slam fashion</title>
  <content>
FASHION retailer Century 21 is the latest store being criticised for selling garments made of real fur.
And they're not the only ones.
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals has launched an online campaign urging the popular New York-based department store and online retailer to stop selling garments made of real fox, rabbit, raccoon and mink.
It described the "abuse and slaughter of animals for fur" as "appalling".
News Corp Australia found several real fur garments available on Century 21's online store as of earlier today, including a vest made of "mink and lamb", a coat advertised as "real fox fur" and a full coat made of rabbit fur, most of which were manufactured in China.
"Most of the world's fur comes from animals on fur farms, who spend their lives confined to filthy, cramped cages with barely enough room to take a few steps in any direction," said, calling for Century 21 to "drop fur".
The animal activist organisation alleged fur farmers slaughtered animals "using the cheapest and crudest methods available, including neck-breaking, suffocation, poisoning, and electrocution".
"These methods don't always kill them immediately," the organisation said, in graphic detail about the way animals were farmed for the fur trade.
"Some writhe and kick while workers tear off their skin, and some animals' hearts beat for as long as 10 minutes after they've been skinned," the statement continued.AUSTRALIAN REACTION
Ashley Fruno, PETA Australia's associate director of campaigns, said designers and retailers who still used fur were denying how "cruel this trade is to animals".
"Every fur coat, lining or bit of trim represents immense suffering for the animals," Fruno told News Corp Australia today.
In Australia, Fruno said shoppers were "increasingly concerned by the ethics of their clothes" and urged brands to "move away from using animal skins, not only for the sake of the animals, but also for their reputation(s)"."F*** FUR": DESIGNERS AND THE FUR TRADE
Several high-profile designers including Fendi, Dior, Burberry, Chloe and Louis Vuitton still use fur in their lines.
New York-based designer Michael Kors has also been heavily criticised.
Anti-fur protesters interrupted Kors' appearance at the Met in June, according to Women's Wear Daily, making "animal-like sounds" and holding signs that read "f*** fur".
Kors - who uses furs including calf hair, fox and mink in his fashion line - brushed off the protest as "never a dull moment".
In contrast, anti-animal cruelty brands including Zara, Intermix, Stella McCartney, Vivienne Westwood and Bottega Veneta have banned fur.
Top Australian designers including camilla and marc, Aje and Thurley are also fur free, according to PETA.
British designer McCartney, for example, calls her brand "vegetarian" and shuns all animal materials.
"As a vegetarian brand we do not use leather, skins, fur or feathers in any of our products, collaborations or licensed products," according to .
It even extends to the glue her label uses. "No fish glue, or any other glues derived from animal parts, are used in the production of our shoes and bags," a statement from Stella McCartney said.
News Corp Australia has contacted Century 21 for comment.
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Century 21</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>KORS</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stella McCartney</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McCartney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fendi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chloe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Zara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louis Vuitton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>China</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fruno</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-8</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Women's Wear Daily</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Kors</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>DESIGNERS AND</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thurley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-fur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ethical Treatment of Animals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>News Corp Australia</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0.67</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PETA Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>F</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ashley Fruno</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bottega Veneta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dior</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peta</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AUSTRALIAN REACTION</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York-based</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vivienne Westwood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>FUR TRADE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burberry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
