<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417309185235624</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:42</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/lifestyle/melbourne/be-your-self-is-a-strong-hardedge-contemporary-dance/news-story/ae96fdadc3efcc0ab9ee20502a237cd5</url>
  <title>Robust dance</title>
  <content>
Be Your Self
Where and when: MTC, Southbank Theatre, The Sumner, until 05 August
Reviewer: Stephanie Glickman
***1/2 Stars
Be Your Self was a seminal work for Adelaide-based Australian Dance Theatre and has had many outings since its 2010 premiere. It represents a particular "bone-crunching", hard-edge style of contemporary dance seen through the noughties in Australia, particularly in Melbourne with companies like Chunky Move.
Given all the dance product that's come since, Be Your Self may not be as much the surprising visual assault of its heyday, but its still got some robust components within its deconstruction of the body as both a purely physical object - a collection of limbs and muscles to fling around or wretch apart - and an emotional, complicated being.
Choreographer Garry Stewart sites Buddhism and neurobiology as impetuses for the work. Actor Cathy Adamek is frequently onstage verbalising a detailed narrative of every cellular, muscular and physiological requirement of the dancers' bodies, bringing out the interplay between complex anatomy and simply moving.
It's heady stuff, but you don't need to know the rectis femoris from the diaphragm to get the idea that the body is an extremely multifaceted and wondrous object, one that can be both manhandled like a lump of clay and also motivated by a deeper passion removed from anything clinical.
With its stark white aesthetics, its intermittent strobes and a stage empty except for a white raked partition that transforms into a display of disembodied limbs and heads, Be Your Self stays loyal to its conceptual dissection. Brendan Woithe's sound composition explicitly captures the literal creaks, crashes and crunches of every jarring torso twist and grotesque shift between rigidity and collapse.
The nine-strong dancers are highly committed, but its not easy to capture the particular accents and ferocity of such aggressive and whip-sharp choreography. Here it loses something in translation, although there are great moments, especially from veteran Kimball Wong and younger cohorts Thomas Fonua and Tara Jade Samaya.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MTC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Garry Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brendan Woithe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide-based Australian Dance Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cathy Adamek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southbank Theatre</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kimball Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thomas Fonua</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Glickman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sumner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Chunky Move</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tara Jade Samaya</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buddhism</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
