<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417343544974514</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/opinion/hanson-looks-on-right-track-with-rail-call/news-story/8054ca8e28ad1bd810dc3a1160e64e43</url>
  <title>Hanson on right track with rail call</title>
  <content>
EDITORIAL: Pauline Hanson may strike a nerve today with her call to stop Adani ... from owning the railway line that will connect its planned Carmichael coal mine with Bowen.
Her point, that a vital piece of nation-building infrastructure should be owned by all of us, has perhaps been lost in the white noise and emotion over the entire project.
Far too many column inches have been wasted on such hypothetical questions as whether the mine will raise global temperatures in the long term.
That is a pity because this rail line is an issue at the heart of our national interest.
It promises to connect billions of dollars worth of coal from pit to port, unlocking the Galilee Basin's job-generating mineral riches.
It will potentially link with dozens of future mines, some of them sitting on massive coal deposits that will be mined for at least a generation.
As such, this track represents a revenue stream opportunity for all Australians.
That's why Adani is so keen to build and operate it.
It stands to make billions by charging other miners to use it.
So Senator Hanson is right. We need to pause and consider the cost of handing over these rights to a private operator, let alone a foreign enterprise.
At the same time, this view should not be confused as an argument against the Adani development, full stop.
To the contrary, we are reasserting the merits of this project.
After all, it will deliver billions in royalties to our great state and thousands of jobs to North Queenslanders.
We are merely arguing for a model that maximises taxpayer benefit.
It must be said Senator Hanson is only singing from Bob Katter's song sheet - he has long declared his opposition to handing over such a vital piece of infrastructure to private interests.
We do not want to replicate the situation in Western Australia, where competing private interests choke the rail networks connecting the Pilbara mines to the port.
In a way, you could liken the proposed rail line to an easement connecting several neighbourhood properties.
All you need is a falling-out between two of the neighbours and the easement quickly becomes a weapon.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Galilee Basin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Hanson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carmichael</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bowen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Western Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>North Queenslanders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pilbara</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bob Katter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pauline Hanson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hansons</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
