<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416875393532182</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:01</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/nurofen-customers-share-35m-after-class-action/3208219/</url>
  <title>Nurofen customers to share in $3.5m after class action</title>
  <content>
AUSTRALIANS who bought a range of Nurofen products between 2011 and 2015 could be entitled to a slice of a $3.5 million settlement after it was targeted by a major class action suit.

Bannister Law reached the deal with Nurofen manufacturers Reckitt Benckiser on Wednesday.

The cash will be shared among customers who bought Nurofen's "Specific Pain Range" by an independent party.

Anyone who bought the products between January 2011 and December 2015 can then register for payment.

The company sold an estimated 5.9 million units of the products at 8500 outlets across Australia.

The deal is yet to be approved by the Federal Court.

The call for customers will also be rolled out in newspapers in coming weeks.

In a statement, Reckitt Benckiser apologised to customers "who may have been misled by the Nurofen Specific Pain Range packaging".

The company added it wanted to make sure customers were "appropriately and swiftly compensated".

The range of products -- which were advertised as targeting back pain, period pain, migraines and tension headaches -- were found to be identical to its standard and cheaper line of Nurofen.

The company was fined $6 million for misleading conduct by the Federal Court after the ACCC an earlier fine for being inadequate.

Register as an affected Nurofen customer here
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>ACCC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reckitt Benckiser</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December 2015</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nurofen Specific Pain Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Specific Pain Range</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>January 2011</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bannister Law</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Court</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
