<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417300595300921</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/south/an-organic-vineyard-in-onkaparinga-hills-has-hit-market-for-first-time-in-30-years/news-story/9aa70bf4e236ca21f8a75e257317d6a1</url>
  <title>An organic vineyard in Onkaparinga Hills has hit market for first time in 30 years - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
50 Northumberland Road, Onkaparinga Hills.

ONE of Adelaide's only organic vineyards has come on the market for the first time in almost 30 years, and is already attracting buyers form near and far.
Winner of the acclaimed 2011, Champion of the Show Shiraz, Grancari Estate Winery in  has been listed for sale with Magain Real Estate and sales agent Stuart Costelleo says the property is attracting plenty of attention.
"Since it's come to the market, we've had plenty of interest from buyers and I think we'll soon see some offers on the table," Mr Costelleo said.
"It's one of only a few organic vineyards around as it's hard to get accreditation.
"Buyer interest has predominantly been from the local wine industry but we've also had a couple of people inquire from interstate and overseas."
The property is located  and includes a spacious, split-level home with a flexible floor plan, including five bedrooms, several separate entertaining spaces, and a country-style kitchen, with plenty of storage.
The stunning open-plan family area has panoramic views and there is a great games room for all year round use. It is all topped off with heating and cooling, including a combustion fireplace.
There's also ample of parking and an adjoining annex, all set on around 18 acres.
"Having been in the family since the early 90s, the property is well established," Mr Costelleo said.
"It's a very special property and an amazing opportunity for someone to start or continue a great lifestyle."
The property is close to the Southern Expressway, good schools and shopping facilities.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Southern Expressway</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stuart Costelleo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Onkaparinga Hills</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Grancari Estate Winery</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Northumberland Road</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Costelleo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Show Shiraz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Magain Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
