<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416218263523594</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:28</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Townsville Bulletin</source>
  <url>http://www.townsvillebulletin.com.au/news/healthy-reason-to-hit-the-road/news-story/1c23a67d3f779403f44c12640a598b74</url>
  <title>Healthy reason to hit the road</title>
  <content>
STAFF from the Townsville Hospital Stroke Unit and their families have signed up to the Townsville Running Festival to raise money and awareness for healthy living.
Occupational therapist Ian Meade, Dr Sally Meade and their two children Charlotte, 13, and Oliver, 17, will compete in this weekend's event, prompted by Charlotte's involvement with a local running squad.
"We run every Saturday morning now and sometimes do a park run to prepare," Mr Meade said.
"Through that we actually got some of our colleagues at work to sign up and run with us.
"There's about 20 of us at the moment who work at the stroke unit at the Townsville Hospital who are all going to run."
They hope to not only raise money for charity but also new equipment for the hospital.
"The Stroke Foundation is a wonderful organisation that provides support for people who have suffered a stroke and their families," Mr Meade said. "We're trying to promote a healthy lifestyle, to go out and get regular exercise."
Donate to the Stroke Foundation Australia through their website strokefoundation.org.au.
The Townsville Running Festival will be held on Sunday. For more details, and to register, visit townsvillerunningfestival.com.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Hospital Stroke Unit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Hospital</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Meade</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlotte</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stroke Foundation Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stroke Foundation</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ian Meade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dr Sally Meade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Saturday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oliver, 17</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Townsville Running Festival</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
