<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417047192226761</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:41</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4830512/wright-and-fitzgibbons-advance/?cs=302</url>
  <title>Wright and Fitzgibbons advance at US Open</title>
  <content>
Tyler Wright. Photo: WSL/MORRIS

BOTH Tyler Wright, Culburra Beach, and Sally Fitzgibbons, Gerroa, have continued their hot form in the surf at the Vans US Open of Surfing - stop number six of the World Surf League (WSL) Championship Tour (CT).
The South Coast pair have both progressed to the quarter-finals, following strong performances in rounds three and four.
Reigning world champion Wright was forced to do it the hard way, after finishing second in her third round heat to Hawaiian Coco Ho.
In the four-to-five foot waves at Huntington Beach, California, Wright totalled a combined score of 10.50 round three heat two - being defeated by Ho, who managed 11.10 but edging out Hawaiian Tatiana Weston-Webb's 10.47 to progress into round four.

Wright then bounced back with a big win over French wildcard Maud Le Car in round four heat two. 

Wright threw down a commanding 7.57 to gain the heat lead. 

Le Car, with a 4.67, needed an excellent 9.07 after Wright locked in a 6.17. Le Car, who previously eliminated six-time WSL champion Stephanie Gilmore, was not able to repeat her victory yesterday and will exit with in ninth place.
"It's always a part of the plan to end up in the finals and I treat every heat pretty much the same with the same details and prep," Wright said. 

"Obviously, I have to adapt to whatever is on-hand. Clearly not enough training was done on my part as I thought paddling at J-Bay was going to be enough -- but no -- this current is super hectic. 

"The water is constantly pulling you so it's taken it out of me today, but I've kind of just been managing that and I'm managing energy in a heat."
The path to the quarter-finals was easier for current world number two Fitzgibbons, who flew through round three with a 14.33 heat total against US' Sage Erickson and Brazil's Silvana Lima. 

Sally Fitzgibbons in action
"I think a World Title is always the intention and it's just about how you get there and events like this where anything can happen," Fitzgibbons said. 

"It's shaping up to be a week where you can show up and consistently build, and get that spark in yourself -- the excitement is there for me especially this year. 

"What I love most about coming here and being in this position is putting on the jersey and the process of it all. 

"At this level, it's the tiniest thing that will send you out of the event, so it's about just being on and focused."

Sally Fitzgibbons. Photo: WSL/MORRIS
In the quarter-finals, Wright will again take on Ho, while Fitzgibbons will battle Erickson.

The other two quarter-finals will see France's Johanne Defay take on Weston-Webb and hometown hero Courtney Conlogue will battle France's Pauline Ado.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>CT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ho</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Culburra Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>California</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US' Sage Erickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brazil's Silvana Lima</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Weston-Webb</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vans US Open of Surfing</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US Open</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WSL/Morris</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gerroa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Surf League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fitzgibbon</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WSL</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Courtney Conlogue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Championship Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maud Le Car</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erickson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaiian Tatiana Weston-Webb's 10.47</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France's Johanne Defay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wright</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>12</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tyler Wright</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sally Fitzgibbons</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawaiian Coco Ho</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephanie Gilmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Le Car</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>J-Bay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>France's Pauline Ado</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World Title</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Huntington Beach</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
