<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417038602291993</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4826661/conditions-prove-challenging-for-fishos/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Reel Deal: Fishos contend with changing conditions</title>
  <content>
A beauty: Vanki Feher with her Australian salmon from a recent trip offshore. (Photos submitted for publication should be high res - at least 1MB)

Hayden from Compleat Angler Illawarra at Windang said this past week, anglers had to contend with strong westerly winds one day, two-metre seas the next and on the 3rd day, dirty green cold water that was almost devoid of anything.
Those fisho's that were able to diversify and to target several different species depending on those conditions fared reasonably well in beach, rock or estuary.
Guys that didn't mind slipping on a wetsuit and getting their head wet dined on lobster with some nice crays being caught with the clear water and calm conditions allowing those close-in nests to be checked out.
After the stir-up, snapper anglers were quick to hit the water with some nice reds coming in from both the shallow and deeper reefs with a few guys landing some solid fish over 4 kilograms with a strong report of one taken on a flutter jig that weighed in at an impressive 6.5 kilos.
Bonito were still hanging around in the warmer waters inshore with headlands like Bass Point and Kiama Blow Hole holding some nice fish that were taken on both coconut rigs and ganged pillies.
The bream fishing is kicking in around the local estuary systems including the more western side of Lake Illawarra.
Some of those winter bream has been up to a kilo and have made short work of those who were ill prepared in the skinny shallow water.
For best results while estuary fishing at this time of year, fish as lightly as possible, meaning light line strength, little or no lead and keep quiet in the boat.

A dropped sinker will echo further than you would believe.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MB</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Compleat Angler Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Vanki Feher</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Windang</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Haydens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kiama Blow Hole</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bass Point</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fishos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
