<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416140954110396</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:10</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/faith-is-fading-in-the-australian-government/3207871/</url>
  <title>Faith is fading in the Australian Government</title>
  <content>
I RECEIVED an NBN compatible wi-fi phone with the modem and needed to, but another (circa $75), the purchased phone developed heavy static and could not be used within months, now the second that came with the modem has developed the same fault, and it too will need replacing.
I received no assistance with the first phone although purchased at a Telstra Shop after a complaint with the Commutations Ombudsman Telstra credited the purchase price but the second supplied free I will replace myself.
Battling Telstra has been stressful, and I do not need any more.
Now we know that when connected to the NBN and there are any power outages you home landline fails, so one needs a mobile phone for emergencies or demand Telstra supply you with the same home service you had before the NBN and Telstra connected you to the optical fibre.
Of course, Australia consumers must still fight for their rights and demand from Telstra a home line service although I am advised that government legislation does absolve them, the NBN and Telstra, of any responsibilities on this.
So that I could have the same home phone service before NBN connections, I will now purchase a Uniden phone system that gives me four wireless phones and backup battery service for power outages.
I am doing this because I no longer have faith in my Federal Government due to the cosy deals they made enabling the NBN to get going, deals between the NBN and phone service providers.
I leave the political struggles and the maintenance of services to us, by agencies now sold off, like Telstra, to a younger generation.
After many years I will be raising my single digit salute higher to all governments and large private companies like Telstra. They all smell.
BOB BUICK
Mountain Creek
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
A NEW centre has opened on the Coast to help kids in care.
IT was heart-breaking, challenging and life-changing.
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Bras and Bikes charity motorcycle ride is now in its 16th year
EVERY mum wants to see their child live a long, happy life
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
The teen has faced charges.
Ali Oetjen appeared on the first season
Some really big bands came through Stewart's at Alexandra Headland.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBN</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alexandra Headland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra Shop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Telstra</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ali Oetjen</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Commutations Ombudsman Telstra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uniden</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BOB BUICK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federal Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stewart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mountain Creek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
