<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416265508164701</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>21:39</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4830122/men-impersonating-police-officers-pointed-gun-robbed-shellharbour-men/?cs=300</url>
  <title>Men impersonating police 'pointed gun, robbed' Shellharbour man</title>
  <content>
A firearm and a hammer were allegedly used in two separate Shellharbour robberies by men impersonating police officers, police allege.

Two men approached a man sitting in a parked car at Boonerah Point Reserve, Mount Warrigal about 11.30pm on Monday.
The men claimed they were police officers and produced what appeared to be a firearm and stole a bag from the man, police allege.
On Tuesday, three men were in a car driving along The Esplanade at Oak Flats when another vehicle approached them from behind and shined a strobe light about 11.55pm.
The men stopped their car and two men from the other vehicle got out and allegedly identified themselves as police officers. They demanded the men in the car hand over their personal property before allegedly punching and assaulting them with a hammer.
The men in the car received minor injuries before the two men left the scene.
Lake Illawarra police arrested a 32-year-old man at Albion Park Rail and a 26-year-old man from Warilla on Wednesday.

Several items allegedly linked to the robberies were seized at the Albion Park Rail house.
The 32-year-old man was charged with robbery whilst armed with dangerous weapon, impersonate police officer, robbery in company and carry cutting weapon to avoid apprehension.
The 26-year-old man was charged with robbery whilst armed with dangerous weapon, impersonate police officer, robbery whilst armed with offensive weapon, and several other unrelated offences.
Both men were refused bail to appear at Wollongong Local Court on Thursday.

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wollongong Local Court</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warilla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mount Warrigal</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albion Park Rail</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Oak Flats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boonerah Point Reserve</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Shellharbour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Esplanade</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lake Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
