<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417180336214900</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Life Hacker</source>
  <url>https://www.lifehacker.com.au/2017/08/get-fast-fighting-feet-with-this-agility-workout/</url>
  <title>Get Fast Fighting Feet With This Agility Workout</title>
  <content>
Video: Ever wonder how MMA fighters and football players get those quick feet? A big part of the secret is footwork drills like these. Practise them in short bursts, and you've got a great cardio workout.

Alex Wong demonstrates five drills in this video. Instead of an agility ladder - a standard piece of equipment for footwork drills - she just uses a line taped down the middle of the room. You can probably find a suitable line on a footpath or tiled floor near you. (For bonus points, see if you can land your feet squarely in the middle of each tile.)

To turn this into a workout, do the drills in sets of 40 seconds work, 20 seconds rest. Three rounds of each drill will keep you working for 15 minutes, or adjust to taste.

Difficulty: Easy to intermediate.

Modifications: The fifth drill is pretty tricky, so if you're not feeling up for it, just do the first four. If they're all tricky from your perspective, just work on the first one, and try to get faster with each round. It may take a few tries to get comfortable with it.

Equipment: Just a line on the floor.

Sweat Factor: Grab your . 

WATCH MORE: Healthy Living News & Ideas

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MMA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fast Fighting Feet With This Agility Workout</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>WATCH MORE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Wong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Healthy Living News</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
