<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416437306859553</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:19</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Australia Broadcasting Corp</source>
  <url>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2017-08-03/bronwyn-fieldings-family-wants-her-body-back-from-uganda/8769260</url>
  <title>Bronwyn Fielding's family wants her body back from Uganda, five weeks after her death</title>
  <content>
Bronwyn Fielding's family is desperate for her remains to be returned to Australia after the 37-year-old died in the small Ugandan city of Mbale in June.
But red tape, a lack of information and a lack of funds have left her body stranded.
Her mother, Lynn Fielding, from Morayfield in Brisbane, said it was heartbreaking.
"I know she's still in the morgue. I feel it's absolutely dreadful," she said.
"It's a shame. It's just not right.
"It's just tearing my heart to pieces."
Bronwyn Fielding was legally blind and suffered from several health conditions.
A post-mortem found she died of a pulmonary embolism, but her uncle, David Pagey, said the family had received "three different stories of how she passed away, within a couple of days" from Bronwyn's Ugandan husband, Michael Osago.
Ms Fielding married Mr Osago four years ago. She had been in Uganda for the past decade, working with orphans.
She left her own three children in the care of her family in Australia.

Mr Osago denies any foul play surrounding her death.
"They may think that maybe I'm a liar or I have done something wrong to her or anything. But I'm just requesting them, please, trust what I'm saying," he said.
"I really loved Bron. I have never done anything in my life."
Ugandan police commissioner Asan Kasingye said Mr Osaga has been interviewed.
"Police have taken a statement from him and the file has been sent to the resident state attorney for advice,"  he said.
"Then a determination is made on whether he is the one who is responsible or it was just a kind of natural death."
No charges have been laid and the Ugandan police are not expecting to take the case any further.
Ms Fielding feared she was going to be poisoned

Prior to her death on June 27, Ms Fielding had sent messages to friends and family in Australia, expressing fears that someone was trying to poison her.

In 2011, she had reported a Ugandan charity worker to police for fraud and the man was subsequently jailed.
It is unclear whether the case and her concerns about someone wanting to poison her were connected.
Mr Pagey said the family was seeking answers as to whether someone was trying to harm Ms Fielding.
"We would like tissue samples taken and blood samples taken if possible, so we can have them tested here in Australia, to check for certain she wasn't being poisoned," he said.
"So, it's been very difficult for us to obtain anything about what happened to Bronwyn and we are still none the wiser, in respect to what happened."
The family has set up a social media page to raise money for the return of her remains.
Lynn Fielding said any Australian travelling overseas must have insurance, a will and list their next of kin.
"I don't want any other family to go through what we are in trying to get a body home," she said.
"I mean, it's your family there. You want them to come home."
'None of us liked her choices', daughter says

Bronwyn Fielding's death is the latest tragedy for her family after her brother, Adam, was murdered in Wodonga in 2010.
"Nothing brings your kids back, no matter what," Lynn Fielding said.
"And then to lose Bron - that's extra, extra hard."
Bronwyn Fielding's children are coming to terms with the loss of their mother.
The eldest, 17 year-old Kierra, said the death was hard to comprehend.
"We want her home. It's the only way we are going to have peace," she said.
"It's ripping my little brother apart. He loved his mum.
"He didn't like her choices - none of us liked her choices - but we really loved her."

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mbale</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wodonga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bron</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lynn Fielding</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ugandan</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>14</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morayfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Asan Kasingye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Pagey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwyn Fielding</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Osago</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>7</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Osaga</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>David Pagey</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Uganda</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June 27</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bronwyn's Ugandan</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kierra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>June</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Fielding</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Osago</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
