<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416909753271280</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>New Daily</source>
  <url>http://thenewdaily.com.au/money/2017/08/03/icac-operation-credo-corrupt/</url>
  <title>ICAC finds Obeid, Tripodi, Kelly engaged in corrupt conduct</title>
  <content>
The Independent Commission Against Corruption (ICAC) has recommended charges be considered against former NSW Labor MPs Eddie Obeid Snr, Joe Tripodi and Tony Kelly, after finding they engaged in serious corrupt conduct.
The finding was released in Sydney this morning, and made as part of the ICAC's investigation into Australian Water Holdings (AWH), dubbed Operation Credo.
Political staffer Gilbert "Laurie" Brown was also found to have engaged in serious corrupt conduct.
ICAC recommended the Director of Public Prosecutions consider charging the four men with misconduct in public office, which is a criminal offence.
The ICAC found between late 2007 and 2010, Obeid misused his position as an MP to promote AWH's interests knowing his family stood to benefit financially should they acquire shares in the company.
Further, the ICAC found in 2010 he misused his position to advance his family's interests by working towards the submission of a minute to the Budget Committee of Cabinet recommending the NSW Government enter direct negotiations with AWH, without disclosing the potential financial benefits.
Obeid is currently serving a prison sentence for misconduct in public office arising from the commission's investigation into his family's secret business dealings at Circular Quay.
He has also been committed to stand trial alongside his son Moses Obeid for conspiracy to commit misconduct in public office following the commission's investigation into the granting of coal exploration licences in the Bylong Valley.
More to come.
- ABC
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Water Holdings</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Moses Obeid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tripodi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Laurie</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Operation Credo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Director of Public</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Obeid</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bylong Valley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Labor MPs Eddie Obeid Snr</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Independent Commission Against Corruption</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Budget Committee of Cabinet</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Gilbert</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Circular Quay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW Government</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ICAC</name>
    <count>6</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joe Tripodi</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kelly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AWH</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brown</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
