<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417167451312760</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:09</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Brisbane Times</source>
  <url>http://www.brisbanetimes.com.au/business/markets/bitcoin-cash-is-essentially-printing-money-20170802-gxo981.html</url>
  <title>Bitcoin Cash is essentially printing money</title>
  <content>
The creation of a second Bitcoin asset this week did almost nothing to dilute the original price, instead the value of the new asset rocketed skyward, generating almost $US7.5 billion out of thin air.
This week, a group of Bitcoin activists and developers , within a few hours, the value of the new unit - Bitcoin Cash - leapt to over US$600.Photo: Bloomberg
The original Bitcoin price however, remained fairly steady, still trading at around $US2700 a coin, despite an almost 1:1 duplication of itself.
"Everyone who has Bitcoin, now has Bitcoin Cash and because the market reckons this is worth $600, it's almost like free money!" crowed one Reddit user.
The "fork" - instigated by some Bitcoin miners as they ran different software to generate different sized blocks - meant Bitcoin Cash essentially inherited a similar amount of coins in circulation: around 16.5 million units.
Calculating the market capitalisation of cryptocurrencies is similar to that of a stock's: you multiply a coin's price by the total supply of coins in circulation.

But unlike when a company issues more stock and the price re-rates, Bitcoin simply cloned itself and the market instantly ascribed value to the new asset.
Investors who held on to Bitcoin - and who clearly weren't frightened off by the fork because there wasn't a selloff - are now credited with an equal amount of Bitcoin Cash.
Bitcoin's  is around $44.8 billion and as of Thursday morning, Bitcoin Cash is around $7.2 billion.
Bitcoin exchanges around the world are  and allow withdrawals, but the risk of an almost inevitable run on the exchange has many wary.
BCH deposits + withdraws may not be available for several days. We won't enable funding until we think it's safe.
Y tho?
This week's fork is a culmination of months of.
Slow transactions and soaring fees had Bitcoin miners - those that decipher algorithms and reaffirm the legitimacy of the blockchain - wanting to expand the size of each block, so transactions would flow more easily.
A compromise was reached between the Core developers of Bitcoin - those that maintain the underlying technology - and the miners, but some miners decided to branch out and run their own software, that increased the blocksize quicker.
These new miners have developed Bitcoin Cash.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>BCH</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US7.5</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$600.Photo</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bitcoin Cash</name>
    <count>7</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US$2700</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Y</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Reddit</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
