<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417253350659866</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:29</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>The Age</source>
  <url>http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/passengers-forced-off-train-to-walk-along-tracks-as-mass-of-sparks-erupts-20170803-gxoci6.html</url>
  <title>Passengers forced off train to walk along tracks as mass of sparks erupts </title>
  <content>
Train delays will continue throughout the day after a malfunctioning train sent sparks flying and caused peak-hour chaos on Thursday morning.
The malfunctioning train may not be fixed until late afternoon, Metro says, meaning services will be suspended on the Sandringham line between Elsternwick and South Yarra for much of the day.

Up Next

Anti-vaccination film screens in Melbourne

01:02

More Victoria News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Sparks fly on Melbourne train

There are train delays around the city after sparks were seen flying from a train near Flinders Street station.

Passengers were forced rushed to the back of the train after power line connectors exploded, sending sparks flying about 7.20am.
The explosion brought trains to a halt on the Sandringham line, causing up to hour-long delays for hundreds of frustrated commuters.Photo: Supplied
Two videos showed sparks shooting from the roof of the first carriage of the train.
The affected train left Flinders Street Station, but got only about 100 metres from Federation Square when all of a sudden it started to slow down.

The explosion happened above the first carriage, sending passengers scrambling to the third carriage for safety.

You will now receive updates from

AM & PM Update Newsletter

AM & PM Update Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

It cut power to the train, leaving commuters in the dark.Photo: Steve Draper
"There was a big flash, the lights went off and we just heard from the train driver that the train in front has hit the Batman bridge," one commuter told Channel 9.
Another said: "The lights went off, and the we started smelling a 'chemically' smell."Photo: Craig Platt
The train stopped between Batman Avenue and Flinders Street Station, on the Sandringham line.
All passengers on board eventually had to evacuate the train and clamber onto the tracks, before walking back to Flinders Street Station.
A Metro Trains spokeswoman said there had been an "issue" on a train between Richmond and Flinders Street.
"It was an overhead wire issue, it was electrical," the spokeswoman said.
Meanwhile, passengers were stranded on station platforms along the Sandringham line, with some unable to get onto packed trains.
Anyone travelling from Sandringham, will have to disembark at Elsternwick and catch a replacement bus to nearby Caulfield station.
From there commuters can catch a train on the Frankston/Pakenham line into the city. 
Some commuters were not pleased:

I have missed a meeting with my company CEO as a result of this. How do I receive compensation for not getting the service that I paid for?

One hour late

But at least one train driver tried to leaven the situation: 

Our  driver is telling jokes to keep us entertained while we're stuck. "What day do eggs hate the most? Friday! (Fry day)"

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Street</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Steve Draper</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Craig Platt</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Flinders Street Station</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elsternwick</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Caulfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM Update Newsletter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Richmond</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Channel 9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Friday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Federation Square</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>South Yarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sandringham</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Anti-vaccination</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Frankston/Pakenham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Metro Trains</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Batman Avenue</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CEO</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
