<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417309185235663</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:42</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/jetstar-launches-cut-price-coast-flights-accommoda/3208288/</url>
  <title>Jetstar launches cut-price Coast flights, accommodation deal</title>
  <content>
JETSTAR has just launched a massive cut-price Sunshine Coast holiday deal.

If you're booking holidays for family and friends, or expecting visitors from interstate, don't let them lock anything in just yet.

Discount holiday packages for a family of four have been released for those heading to the Sunshine Coast from Sydney, Melbourne or Adelaide.

Three nights accommodation and return airfares are included, with Novotel Twin Waters Resort and Breakfree Alexandra Beach Resort partnering with Jetstar for the deal.

For Sydneysiders looking for an escape, deals start from $376 per person for the two adults, with kids 11-and-under free.

Travel dates vary between the two resorts, starting from mid-October until early December, with additional dates in February, March and May.

Melbournites seeking some fun in the sun can secure the deal from $436 per adult (Novotel) or $517 per adult (Breakfree), while those in Adelaide can secure the vacation from $448 per person (Novotel) or $529 per person (Breakfree).

Prices and details about the deal, including conditions, are on the Jetstar website.

Travellers have a week to get their hands on a deal, with the sale ending on August 10.

A MAN has been arrested after he allegedly tried to rob a Coast bank
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
NAMBOUR residents have donated around 2000 knitted items.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
A COMEDIAN dramatises his real-life romance and Charlize kicks butt.
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
Designer waterfront house in select Noosa location
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>February</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydneysiders</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbournites</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jetstar</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sunshine Coast</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>March</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Novotel Twin Waters Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breakfree Alexandra Beach Resort</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Melbourne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>December</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Breakfree</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Novotel</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nambour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sydney</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
