<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417085846932957</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:50</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Illawarra Mercury</source>
  <url>http://www.illawarramercury.com.au/story/4814346/tackling-housing-supply-in-the-illawarra/?cs=12</url>
  <title>Property Council Illawarra welcomes Fatima Abbas, new Regional Director of Planning for south eastern NSW</title>
  <content>
Kim Rawson.

The region needs a fresh set of eyes on the housing affordability problem, the Illawarra branch of the Property Council believes. 
The Property Council Illawarra has therefore applauded the appointment of Fatima Abbas, their new Regional Director of Planning for south eastern NSW, and urged her to take on the challenge of increasing land supply in the Illawarra.
"The Illawarra needs a fresh set of eyes on the housing affordability problem which is largely caused by the acute shortage of development ready residential land," Property Council regional director Kim Rawson said. "Our members are reporting that there is scarce land available to purchase in the market right now and this is creating a spike in prices."

Ms Rawson said without a concerted effort to address the block in supply, house prices will continue to rise.
"West Dapto land has been in the rezoning pipeline for years, much of it is serviced and ready to develop, yet it is caught in bureaucratic inertia that will only worsen the housing affordability challenge in the region," she said. 
"The Department of Planning has an important role to play in clearing the blockages in the planning system and encouraging or compelling our local councils to efficiently rezone land.
"We must see action from all levels of government to demonstrate that their words of concern around land supply and housing affordability are not simply rhetoric."

Meanwhile, Property Council Illawarra will host an event at the Innovation Campus, University of Wollongong. The Sustainability Lunch & Innovation Campus Tour is on August 24. 

The event aims to be an opportunity to connect with other property industry professionals with interests in sustainability and aged care.
"Be inspired by property industry innovators as they share their projects and ideas that are improving the way our ageing population and wider community can live sustainably," Ms Rawson said. 

More details are available at the  website. 
The story  first appeared on .
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>University of Wollongong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Illawarra</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Department of Planning</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovation Campus</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Rawson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Council</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sustainability Lunch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fatima Abbas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Council Illawarra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Dapto</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Innovation Campus Tour</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>August 24</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Property Council Illawarra</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Regional Director of Planning</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kim Rawson</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
