<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417180336214885</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>The Adviser</source>
  <url>http://www.adelaidenow.com.au/real-estate/south-australia/city/million-dollar-suburbs-in-adelaides-east-double-in-two-years/news-story/f32591c2964309adf8e90a4e738de5ae</url>
  <title>Million dollar suburbs in Adelaide's east double in two years - realestate.com.au</title>
  <content>
ON THE MARKET:
is a five-bedroom home with a pool and tennis court on the market, with price tag of $2.2- $2.4 million. Hawthorn is one of several suburbs to have had a medin house price rise above $1 million.

ALMOST a third of all suburbs across Adelaide's east and inner-south now have median house prices of at least $1 million, new figures show.
The latest RP Data CoreLogic market trends report showed the number of million-dollar suburbs in Norwood Payneham & St Peters, Unley, Burnside and parts of Mitcham had doubled over the past two years, up from nine in 2015 to 18 in 2017.
The state's richest postcode, Unley Park, topped the list, boasting a median house price of $1.5 million.
On the lower end of the scale, Kings Park had a median price tag of $1 million.

ON THE MARKET:
- A circa-1900 home with five bedrooms, two bathrooms and an undercover decked alfresco area with a ceiling fan and water feature. Price guide: $1.395 - $1.445 million

Netherby, Erindale, Tusmore, Joslin, Millswood, Dulwich, Hawthorn and Kingswood were the most-recent additions to the million-dollar suburb club.
Unley Park, Toorak Gardens, College Park, Leabrook, Springfield, Rose Park, St Peters, Hyde Park and Malvern retained their seven-figure statuses from 2015.
Real estate agents put the increase down to competition between buyers and long-time blue-chip suburbs bumping up house prices in neighbouring areas.
Harris Real Estate agent and auctioneer Nick Baranikow said buyers were attracted to addresses near prestigious suburbs because they had slightly lower price tags.
He said it was a "halo effect" where the price of one area influenced the cost of another suburb.
"You get some spillage where people would love to be in an Unley Park area, but they have to go somewhere like Hawthorn or Kingswood," Mr Baranikow said.
Turner Real Estate managing director Lachlan Turner said more competition and limited supply of top-end properties had bumped up prices.
"Property for sale in very high-quality locations ... are very hotly contested," Mr Turner said.
"People are willing to pay more money for them.
"But when you strip back to the core of why they are so popular ... it is the infrastructure the (east and inner-south) offers, like schools and other services."
Ouwens Casserly Real Estate sales associate Michael Stentiford is selling a four-bedroom, three bathroom home in Erindale for $1.75 million.
The median house price in that suburb is $1.18 million, up from $883,000 in 2015.

ON THE MARKET:
- A sandstone bungalow in a tree-lined street with a character exterior and modern interior. It has four bedrooms, three bathrooms, a formal dining area, floor-to-ceiling windows, a gas fireplace and separate rumpus room. Price guide: $1.75 million

Mr Stentiford said the east and inner-south had properties with modern interiors and heritage frontages, sought after among buyers.
"The majority of people want homes with character, but have been updated tastefully," Mr Stentiford said.
Real Estate Institute SA chief executive Greg Troughton expected the number of million-dollar suburbs to increase over the next 12 months.
"I think the same amount will break through next year," Mr Troughton said.
"It will probably spread a bit further north and south-east, so it will be interesting to watch."
Erindale residents Carolyn and John Reid are selling their Lock Ave home they built 24 years ago and moving to the seaside for a "new challenge".
Mrs Reid said she was happy to have lived in the area, but looks forward to passing her home to new owners.
"It is tucked away in a quiet suburb that has very good access to the city, good
shopping, access to excellent schools ... and beautiful walking tracks," Mrs Reid said.
BY CELESTE VILLANI
-
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MALVERN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leabrook</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Baranikow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adelaide</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>John Reid</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rose Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyde Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Estate Institute SA</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CELESTE VILLANI</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Greg Troughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ouwens Casserly Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dulwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>St Peter</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Carolyn</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Springfield</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RP Data CoreLogic</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Harris Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kingswood</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lock Ave</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turner Real Estate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Burnside</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Norwood Payneham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>College Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Stentiford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kings Park</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tusmore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mrs Reid</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hawthorn</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Unley Park</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nick Baranikow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lachlan Turner</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Erindale</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Netherby</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Millswood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Troughton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MITCHAM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Toorak Gardens</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Joslin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Michael Stentiford</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
