<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417300595300948</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Cairns Post</source>
  <url>http://www.cairnspost.com.au/news/opinion/often-its-adults-who-need-to-build-up-their-resilience-to-lifes-obstacles/news-story/904435745be4a166035eb0593cd78c69</url>
  <title>Handling the truth</title>
  <content>
KIDS are resilient.
My husband and I currently house-share with one of these small humans, of the four-year-old variety. She doesn't pay any board, but we let that slide.
Because, to be fair, she never asked to live with us in the first place.
You can't choose your parents, after all.
Anyway, along with her general resilience, another attribute I admire in my daughter is her logical attitude.
You tell her something, she accepts it as fact and moves on with her life accordingly.
No muss, no fuss.
On Monday night while we were sleeping, a snake managed to slither into our guinea pig enclosure, where it proceeded to devour one of our daughter's beloved rodents, Bugsy.
We live on rainforest acreage, so snakes are just part of life there and the child understands this.
Still, after my husband had released the python back into the wild and checked on the wellbeing of the remaining pig, I didn't have the heart - or the courage - to tell my daughter about Bugsy's untimely demise. Not on a weekday morning, anyway.
She was staying at her grandparents' place the following night, so we figured if we didn't tell her immediately, at least we'd have the next 24 hours to formulate a decent game plan.
You know, with the aim of causing minimum psychological scarring and all that jazz.
Because if there is one thing I've learnt as a parent, it's that you're definitely going to mess your kids up in one way or another - nobody's a perfect parent.
The plan is simply to minimise the damage. Where possible.
As we were preparing to leave the house that morning, I was in the kitchen when I heard a little voice from the verandah: "I'm coming Mama; I'm just going to say goodbye to my guinea pigs first."
Oh no, you're bloody not, I thought to myself as I flew out the door and skidded across the verandah in a fashion not dissimilar to that of Seinfeld's Kramer making an entrance.
I slammed the cage door shut and told her she could wave goodbye from a distance because we were in a rush.
While she was away for the night, I came up with a few options.
My first - and in my mind, most ingenious - plan, was to tell her that word of Bugsy's talent had spread so far that he ended up being cast in a Hollywood movie.
Therefore, he would be staying in a massive, flashy hutch in Los Angeles for the foreseeable future. Probably next door to Kanye or something.
My husband, however, was of the opinion that we should just play it straight and tell her the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth. I conceded.
I picked her up from my mum's house on Wednesday evening and steeled myself for the death conversation that lay ahead.
Her father wanted to be the one who officially broke the news to her. He had been the one to bring the pets home as a present for her last birthday.
As we drove home, I thought I'd help out and lay the foundation for the talk. "When we get home, Daddy wants to have a little chat with you," I said, nervously.
"Yessss! Am I getting a present?" she replied.
Whoops.
When we walked through the door at home, my husband was well-prepared.
He had her remaining guinea pig in a box in the loungeroom, ready for her to pat as we delivered her this soul-shattering blow. Then, this happened.
Husband: "Mishka, I want to have a little chat with you. The other night, a snake came and got into the guinea pig cage. It ate Bugsy."
Daughter: "OK, Dad. So, where's the snake?"
Husband: "I put it back into the rainforest."
Daughter: "All right. No worries Mum and Dad! (Picks up surviving guinea pig.) Well, looks like there'll be more food for Jack now!"
I'm not sure what the moral of this story is.
But I do now wish I hadn't wasted three hours Photoshopping Bugsy's head onto a movie poster as a 'Plan B'.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>OK</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Seinfeld's Kramer</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Los Angeles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bugsy</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jack</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mishka</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Plan B</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hollywood</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Kanye</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photoshopping Bugsy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
