<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416570450848123</docid>
  <date>02/08/2017</date>
  <time>22:50</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Business Insider</source>
  <url>https://www.businessinsider.com.au/10-things-you-need-to-know-this-morning-in-australia-v3-2017-8</url>
  <title>10 things you need to know this morning in Australia</title>
  <content>
Good morning.

1. Tesla didn't lose as much money as Wall Street analysts thought it would. It burned through $US1.16 billion in cash in the second quarter, and will produce 1500 Model 3s in the next quarter. That, in Elon Musk's world, . Still, the stock price has put on 52% this year and . And the US military likes Tesla, too - here's video of , for research purposes.

2. Elon Musk's other big dream (one of them), the Hyperloop, is slowly taking shape on a test track in Nevada. While Musk only flagged the concept, several companies have rushed to develop it, and last weekend,  in a vacuum-sealed tube. The goal is 1100km/h.

3. Your immortality has arrived, almost. A team of scientists announced they cured several patients of a type of heart disease called hypertrophic cardiomyopathy that can cause sudden cardiac arrest, by altering their genes using the CRISPR-Cas9 editing technique. The big deal was the patients were human embryos. .

4. The Dow broke through 22,000 for the first time. 72% of US reporting companies have beat estimates this earnings season. And the US dollar began dipping again as the euro and pound strengthened. Interesting times. And as earnings season gets under way in Australia, ASX200 futures traders are more bullish today after  and gave most of it back to shareholders. The , as traders wait for the balance of international trade figures from the ABS at 11:30am AEST.

5. There are few cooler things on planet Earth than lightning striking an exploding volcano:

Sergio Tapiro Velasco was in Comala, Mexico, when that particular example lit up the sky, and happened to have his camera handy. It saw him named the National Geographic's Travel Photographer of the Year, and here are , including Donavon Frankenreiter surfing underwater.

6. Amazon out to crush you? Morgan Stanley has come up with five ways . Then read this brilliant commentary piece for why you should just give up now, , but frightening just the same.

7. Here are the . Here's how more than . And here are 10 ways to improve cashflow .

8. Snapchat is dead in the water. Shares of its parent company Snap fell to $US12.53 overnight and marketers are now saying  amongst their clients. Still, BAML is waiting for Snap's August 10 earnings call to see if it .

9. An Australian grandmother has found internet fame by asking Coles to tell her :

But .

10. Marriage, however, . Science has proved it. As are kitchen sponges, which sound like  every week. Which also sounds like a Big Sponge conspiracy, but it isn't. Unlike Big Cheese,  working to persuade us all to eat more cheese.

Wake up, cheese-munching sheeple.

BONUS ITEM: Meanwhile, in Finland...

How is this not on ESPN?
- Shooter McGavin (@ShooterMcGavin_)

NOW WATCH: Briefing videos

</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Sponge</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ShooterMcGavin_</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mexico</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Elon Musk</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McGavin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Geographic Travel Photographer of the Year</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wall Street</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Morgan Stanley</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snap's August 10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Model 3</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sergio Tapiro Velasco</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nevada</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BAML</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Snapchat</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Donavon Frankenreiter</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Musk</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US1.16</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ESPN</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Big Cheese</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dow</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Hyperloop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AEST</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>CRISPR/Cas9</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ASX 200</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Comala</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABS</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US12.53</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
