<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416922638173373</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:12</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sunshine Coast Daily</source>
  <url>http://www.sunshinecoastdaily.com.au/news/bullets-load-up-us-import-for-new-nbl-season/3208227/</url>
  <title>Bullets load up US import for new NBL season</title>
  <content>
BASKETBALL: The Brisbane Bullets have locked and loaded US small forward Perrin Buford for their third and final import spot ahead of the 2017-18 NBL season.
The 198cm-tall swingman played professionally in the Italian second division last year after spending two years at Middle Tennessee State University.
Buford - who hails from Decatur, Alabama - played for Boston in the recent NBA Summer League and replaces Torrey Craig in the Brisbane line-up after last year's club MVP was signed by the Denver Nuggets.
Bullets coach Andrej Lemanis said Buford ticked a lot of boxes for Brisbane.
"We took the opportunity to really analyse our team to determine what asserts we needed in whatever player we brought in,'' he said.
"Through a lot of contacts and a lot of hard work we landed on Perrin Buford and I am glad to say he's joining the family.
"The first thing that standouts when you watch Perrin play is that he is a hard worker, he's certainly puts in the effort both ends of the floor."
"He plays defence, he rebounds, he runs the ball hard. The thing I liked about him particularly when talking to him is that he understands what it takes to win in terms of you need to play as part of the team which is what we are about here at the Bullets.
"Everyone contributing their piece of the puzzle and sacrificing for the good of the group and he certainly fits that mentality"
Lemanis said Buford reminded him of Tall Blacks and New Zealand Breakers great Mika Vukona.
"Everyone appreciates the way Mika plays and I think certainly that effort is what he brings to the table and I'm looking forward to Buford playing that way for us," he said.
The Bullets start their NBL campaign against the Wildcats in Perth on October 7 before departing to the US where they will play the NBA's Phoenix Suns on October 14.
Their first home game is against Cairns on October 20.
Cr John Connolly says infrastructure upgrades on way
Coast lifeguards are real watermen
Bin day is the best day of this bubbly boy's week
NEW technology has transformed health care in one lifetime.
What do a mountain climber and a five-course dinner have in common?
A soul, funk and reggae outfit will headline Peregian Originals
Appreciate floral beauty at the Maroochydore Orchid Society show
IF YOU'RE going to see one rom com this year, make it this one.
Charlize Theron is killer but the plot is a filler.

"Honestly, Sam, you started with the gin..."
Second setback for community group struggling with Adani
Former host forced to quit campaign trail for voluntary euthanasia.
New Bob Hawke series to shed fascinating light on 80s Australia.
Immaculate Noosa hinterland home on well-maintained 2.63ha property
Live thre good life in Noosa hinterland
Superbly-located Noosa family home enjoys significant make-over
She tried calling police, but ended up getting arrested herself.
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>MVP</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Middle Tennessee State University</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Adani</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maroochydore Orchid Society</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 7</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tall Blacks</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBL</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Buford</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Torrey Craig</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perrin Buford</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mika Vukona</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perth</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Coast</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Perrin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Noosa</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sam</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrej Lemanis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Charlize Theron</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-5</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Boston</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Zealand Breakers</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA Summer League</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NBA's Phoenix Suns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peregian Originals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lemanis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New Bob Hawke</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Immaculate Noosa</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Italian</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Decatur</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>October 20</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cairns</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Brisbane Bullets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wildcats</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Denver Nuggets</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alabama</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mika</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Cr John Connolly</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
