<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651416995652618444</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>00:29</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Canberra Times</source>
  <url>http://www.canberratimes.com.au/comment/government-needs-to-act-on-our-information-security-20170731-gxmd25.html</url>
  <title>Could you be held to ransom over your information security?</title>
  <content>
Polished up your LinkedIn CV recently? If you have the odds are, surprise surprise, that you're considering the possibility of a new job. An obvious insight, perhaps, but one that's being used by San Francisco-based internet start-up HiQ Labs to predict the possible "flight-risk" of employees.
In the best American tradition this has quickly given rise to suits and counter-suits as the two companies desperately battle over who actually possesses ownership of data.

Up Next

Tesla's cash burn

02:25

More BusinessDay Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Productivity commission spruiks 'new data revolution'

Right now citizens don't have access to their own data, but the Productivity Commission has put forward a bold plan to change that. Find out how it will benefit you.

Because this is the key question - who owns information. In this case the details are factual and publicly available, it's just that a third party has worked out how to make money from putting the evidence together. Why should they be prevented from doing so?
The problem is, of course, that facts aren't neutral. The truth might be out there, but it's the way you arrange that evidence that creates value.Photo: Louie Douvis
Unfortunately, many people are unaware of the value of seemingly inconsequential pieces of data when they're processed together. Scale generates a quality all of its own and, if it's interrogated with the right questions, new relationships can suddenly become apparent.
Take, for example, the possible linkage between my library borrowing record and credit card debt. I'm not very good at getting books back on time. I do always return them in the end although regrettably this seems to be according to my timetable, rather than that of the library. This means I cop a small fine, but I'm happy to pay for the convenience. Similarly with debt. There's absolutely no excuse for this, but sometimes I don't pay off my credit card by the due date.

Things happen. I get busy and you can rest assured, dear reader, that I'd always much rather pursue a lead for you instead of troubling myself with the tiresome and boring tasks that I should be worrying about, like paying fees and clearing debt.
Now this isn't a problem in itself, but what worries me is that the bank might put two and three together and come up with something like a $5 "processing" fee, that hits the very day I go into arrears. It could work out from my library record that I'd probably just shrug my shoulders and go without a cafe latte that morning (it might check my credit card record, for example, and notice that every day I paid a library fee I hadn't handed over $4.80 at the coffee shop).Photo: Stephen Swintek
In other words, the bank would know exactly what I'd be prepared to fork out for the convenience of doing things my way. An unscrupulous bank might use that knowledge to gouge me for an extra few dollars a month. Fortunately, an Australian bank would never dream of doing anything like that.
What they will do, however, is use their knowledge of people's income to adjust the credit rate someone pays to borrow. A low-income family attempting to pay off their mortgage will be slugged at least two, more likely three percentage points more interest than someone else earning more than $200,000 and borrowing to negatively gear a rental property.
Knowledge is money. Today it's being used, quite legitimately, to exploit the most vulnerable in society through different pricing models in the name of efficiency.
Take an airfare. It's understandable that it costs more to fly in the morning or evening. These are peak times for travelling, so it's natural that airlines would seek to charge more if passengers want to travel during these periods. You'll also pay a premium, however, if you buy your ticket at the last minute and this has nothing to do with efficient rationing of services: it's all about gouging anyone who has to travel at a particular time. Brilliantly constructed algorithms can also distinguish these passengers from impulse buyers, the sort of people tempted at the last minute to buy a seat that might otherwise be empty.
The more a business knows about its customers, the more carefully it can target its services.
The use of such knowledge is only limited by imagination. Advertising has always been targeted, which no doubt explains why online readers of this particular column are being bombarded by missives for the finest, most exclusive merchandise. Nor does it take much perspicacity to realise that such people are intelligent, outwardly-looking (just like you!), and more likely to have gifted and talented children than readers of, say, some other columnists.  What's changed, however, is the incredible processing power that is now available to make sense of such information.
There is no problem when such knowledge is being used for good. But that doesn't mean that there aren't problems.
Take car insurance. Using cost to drive charges means young people have to pay more simply because they have more accidents. But what about genetic screening?
If someone in your family has had cancer, should you pay more for life insurance?
Should an individual's mental health information be accessible by potential employers? Even if someone's personal records remain private, the capacity of data mining means that it's relatively easy to build up a highly detailed picture that may reveal much more than you think.
Security of information is incredibly important. It's an issue the government needs to address - urgently.
Nicholas Stuart is a Canberra writer
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Stephen Swintek</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tesla</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Louie Douvis</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Productivity Commission</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>LinkedIn CV</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HiQ Labs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nicholas Stuart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>San Francisco-based</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
