<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417300595300926</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:40</time>
  <isTopNews>true</isTopNews>
  <source>Herald Sun</source>
  <url>http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/prime-minister-malcolm-turnbull-under-siege-from-liberal-party-colleagues-on-samesex-marriage/news-story/9a1250d3613d7e0cd07bcf3a2d527a17</url>
  <title>PM 'out by Christmas': Credlin's warning</title>
  <content>
PETA Credlin has a dire warning for Malcolm Turnbull as the Prime Minister's strategy for dealing with same-sex marriage when parliament resumes was revealed.
Tony Abbott's ex chief of staff Ms Credlin has told Sky News Mr Turbull needs to use the "safety valve" of a postal plebiscite on same-sex marriage.
However she said it won't simply be the issue of marriage equality that would bring down Mr Turnbull.
Instead it will also be the .
"I don't think that Malcolm Turnbull will be here at the end of the year, but I suspect it won't be just this issue (of same-sex marriage) that brings him down," Ms Credlin told Sky News.
"I think the response to Finkel which will be due by Christmas as well, the combination of these two matters will significantly weaken his leadership to the point that he is untenable."
Ms Credlin was asked if Mr Turnbull would have to resign or be "blasted out".
"Either, or" she replied.

"It's interesting that the postal vote matter is the one that's pushed forward very much by the conservatives: Mathias Cormann and in particular Peter Dutton, and but for those two men Malcolm Turnbull would not be Prime Minister. They very much hold him in that seat," she said.
"You can see when there's any issue it's not Julie Bishop or Scott Morrison or indeed Christopher Pyne who go out there now to defend Turnbull, it's very much the two senior conservatives, Senator Cormann and Minister Dutton who are out there defending him.
"If they were to withdraw their support, I don't think Malcolm Turnbull is prime minister."
Ms Credlin advised Mr Turnbull to push for a postal vote.
"I think if the Prime Minister was canny, he would go to cabinet on Monday with a proposal for a postal vote, he would announce that immediately as cabinet broke on the Monday night, and he would use that to push into party room on Tuesday, because the party room will happen before parliament opens again on Tuesday afternoon," she said.

Conservative senator Eric Abetz has insisted the government must hold a national vote on same-sex marriage.

Conservative Liberals push for plebiscite
"He would then be able to hold his people and say, look, whatever games Labor might play, we will have a postal vote, we'll have it before Christmas and these are the conditions."
Credlin's warming came as Sky News reported today that National Party MPs are concerned Victorian MP Andrew Broad could leave the Coalition and sit on the crossbench over same-sex marriage.
Mr Broad offered "no comment" when asked about the issue by Sky News.
Opposition Leader Bill Shorten told reporters on Thursday the Liberal Party was getting itself "tied up in a knot" over the issue.
"I actually think it's a bit weird how hard some conservative Liberals are fighting against marriage equality," he told reporters.
"Why are they so obsessed about other people's relationships?"
"Marriage equality should have a vote in parliament at the very least. We should just have a vote an get on with it."SECRET BALLOT
There are reports Mr Turnbull will use a secret ballot to canvas the opinions of his party room on marriage reform.
Mr Turnbull may use a ballot of MPs at next week's party room meeting to find out where the majority stand, and to stop infighting over the issue that threatens his leadership, reports.
According to the report, Mr Turnbull has been advised reform advocates only have 20 per cent of the Coalition partyroom with them. As a result a convincing vote for the existing policy could deter some of them crossing the floor and damaging the Coalition.
The vote could be used to deter moderates from crossing the floor of the lower house in support of same-sex marriage, with the prime minister told just one in five MPs support the reform advocates.
The Australian also revealed in 1997, as chairman of the Australian Republican Movement, Mr Turnbull wrote an article for the publication in which he was highly critical of a postal plebiscite saying the idea .
It comes as former prime minister Tony Abbott issued a stern warning that Liberal MPs crossing the floor would be engaging in a "serious attack" on Mr Turnbull's authority.
West Australian Senator Dean Smith is working on a marriage equality bill while his lower house colleagues Trevor Evans, Tim Wilson and Warren Entsch have flagged crossing the floor to support it.
With the bill to enable a plebiscite failing to pass parliament last year, some Liberals want the bill recommitted to parliament, while others say a voluntary postal ballot could achieve the same aim without the need for legislation.
Mr Abbott said the coalition should take its existing policy of a plebiscite to the next election and stand by it now.
MPs pushing for marriage equality argue they have discharged their duty to support a plebiscite and it's not their fault the Senate blocked the legislation.
But Minister Zed Seselja said that argument was nonsense, pointing to the government's persistence over workplace relations laws.
The Assistant Minister for Industry, Innovation and Science Craig Laundy claimed same-sex marriage was not a major issue for the Government.
"It is not being raised when I talk to other colleagues so I to be brutally honest think it is a media beat up," he told Sky News.MPs HAVE 'RIGHT' TO VOTE
AUSTRALIA'S deputy prime minister Barnaby Joyce says he wouldn't punish government MPs for crossing the floor of the lower house in favour of gay marriage.
Mr Joyce said Liberal and National MPs have the right to vote against party lines, and the coalition doesn't subscribe to the same "totalitarian process" as the opposition.
"I'd be the last person to criticise someone for crossing floor - in the Labor party they kick you out," the Nationals leader told ABC radio.
"We don't believe in that... if you've got a different view and you can support a potent argument, then that's your right."NSW MPS LETTER TO FEDERAL COLLEAGUES
Five NSW MPs representing the Nationals, the Liberals the ALP, the Greens and an Independent have written an open letter to the Canberra, urging their federal colleagues to move on the issue of same sex marriage.
Trevor Khan Bruce Notley-Smith, Penny Sharpe, Jenny Leong and Alex Greenwich penned the letter.
"We are concerned about proposals for any form of plebiscite," it read.
"We fear these proposals risk damaging the public's trust in Australia's federal parliament, as it sends the message that the Parliament is too weak to deal with matters that fall within its sole responsibility.
Our nation faces many great challenges and is open to many wonderful opportunities; however it is clear the passionate support for marriage equality will only continue to dominate the public and political discourse until it is resolved through a parliamentary vote. We urge you to work together towards delivering marriage equality through a vote in Parliament, a reform that will make our nation proud, and truly deliver on our shared values of fairness and equality."

Cabinet minister Simon Birmingham has warned of the consequences of crossing the floor on same-sex marriage.

Warning of 'consequences' of marriage vote
Originally published as
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW MPS LETTER TO FEDERAL COLLEAGUES</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Monday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Julie Bishop</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Simon Birmingham</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MPs</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>PM</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Ms Credlin</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News.MPs HAVE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Barnaby Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tim Wilson</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Penny Sharpe</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Joyce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Science Craig Laundy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Eric Abetz</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peter Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Labour</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Conservative Liberals</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>West Australian Senator Dean Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Turnbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Leader Bill Shorten</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Peta Credlin</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Prime Minister</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Finkel</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>SECRET BALLOT</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senate</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Abbott</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christopher Pyne</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Zed Seselja</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victorian MP Andrew Broad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australian Republican Movement</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Broad</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Senator Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Warren Entsch</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Scott Morrison</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>NSW MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alex Greenwich</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Assistant Minister</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News Mr Turbull</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mathias Cormann</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Nationals MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tony Abbott</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sky News</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Minister Dutton</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Mr Turnbull</name>
    <count>8</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>National Party MPs</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Malcolm Turnbull</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>-3</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Credlin</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Liberal Party</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Christmas</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Canberra</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Alps</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Khan Bruce Notley-Smith</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>ABC</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jenny Leong</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Trevor Evans</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>RIGHT' TO VOTE</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Tuesday</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
