<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<snippet>
  <docid>4651417270530529300</docid>
  <date>03/08/2017</date>
  <time>01:33</time>
  <isTopNews>false</isTopNews>
  <source>Sydney Morning Herald</source>
  <url>http://www.smh.com.au/business/retail/amazon-to-create-hundreds-of-jobs-in-australia-with-opening-of-fulfilment-centre-20170803-gxoakx.html</url>
  <title>Amazon to create 'hundreds of jobs' in Australia with opening of fulfilment centre</title>
  <content>
Lisa Pendry has been laid off eight times since 2008, and each time it's been even harder to find a new job.
This time, she's spent three months searching. But it's tricky to find companies in America that are hiring, she says, and even more difficult to get an in-person interview.

Up Next

Body cam shows suspected drug planting by US police

02:47

More World News Videos

Previous slide
Next slide

Hundreds queue for Amazon's job fair

With hundreds showing up for a chance to work at Amazon's fulfilment centres in the US, the e-commerce giant has made offers to some applicants on the spot.

"I've got three kids to feed," said Pendry, 44, who most recently worked as an administrative assistant for Allstate Insurance.
"It doesn't matter what it is anymore, I just need a job."Photo: AP
The possibility of an hourly position drew thousands of people to Amazon's warehouse in Baltimore on Wednesday morning, where they started lining up at 4am and waited hours in rows that snaked through the sprawling parking lot on a blistering hot day.
The on-site interviews were part of a one-day effort by Amazon to fill 50,000 jobs across the US.

The event was a vivid illustration of the ascendance of Amazon, the online retail company that has a seemingly insatiable need for human labour to fuel its explosive growth.

You will now receive updates from

Business AM Newsletter

Business AM Newsletter

Get the latest news and updates emailed straight to your inbox.

Like other tech giants, Amazon is recruiting thousands of people with engineering and business degrees for high-paying jobs.Photo: AP
But the vast majority of Amazon's hiring is for what the company calls its "fulfilment network" - the armies of people who pick and pack orders in warehouses and unload and drive delivery trucks, and who take home considerably smaller incomes.
Amazon now has more than 382,000 employees globally.Photo: AP
'Hundreds of new jobs' in Australia

On Thursday, it  South, Victoria - to .
The move would create "hundreds of new jobs", it said, adding to the almost 1000 employees already in Australia as of April. Amazon will begin recruiting immediately for a range of roles, including operations managers, pickers, packers, systems technicians, and HR specialists.
Fulfilment centre jobs are hard work - they're physically taxing, but they pay well.

"We are thrilled to be creating hundreds of new roles in Dandenong South," Amazon's director of operations for Australia, Robert Bruce, said.
"This is just the start. Over time, we will bring thousands of new jobs to Australia and millions of dollars of investment as well as opening up the opportunity for thousands of Australian businesses to sell at home and abroad through Amazon Marketplace."Photo: Bloomberg
Huge crowd

In Baltimore, Amazon planned to add 1200 people to its current line-up of 4200. The jobs, which pay more than Maryland's $US9.25 minimum wage, come with health and disability insurance, as well as a retirement savings plan and stock awards. It was enough to draw a huge crowd on a blistering hot August day, and Amazon recruiters were ready with bottled water and snow cones to cool people down.
As Amazon hires at a furious pace, many longtime retailers are scaling back by closing hundreds of stores and doing away with coveted commission-earning positions. Retail jobs - which for years have been stepping stones into the workforce - have increasingly shifted from America's shopping malls to warehouses on the outskirts of town.
"Retail employment has traditionally been face-to-face, but technology is changing that," said Jed Kolko, chief economist for the jobs site Indeed. "That has an impact on the number of jobs that are created and destroyed, but also on where those jobs are and who gets them."
Cheap land

Women hold the majority of retail jobs, he said, but a study of Census data shows that men account for 73 per cent of warehousing and storage workers. To add to that: jobs are increasingly moving from city centres and suburbs to rural areas where companies can find cheap land for massive facilities. It's too soon to tell, he said, how those changes will impact the broader economy.
Fry Dekowski says he's hopeful about the new opportunities. The 25-year-old, who makes about $US10 an hour as an electronics associate at Walmart, said he was looking for higher pay and better benefits. Driving a forklift, he said, would be an added bonus.
"I'm waiting here so I can get a better life opportunity," he said. "Working retail for the last five years has been kind of a nightmare. I need a job with benefits, the kind I can start a family with."
In many parts of the country, he said, new warehouse positions have more than made up for lost bricks-and-mortar jobs, where wages have been stagnating for years.
"I see this as a period of turmoil and upgrading," he said. "Fulfilment centre jobs are hard work - they're physically taxing, but they pay well. This could actually be a real positive for income equality."
'I'll take any job'

The promise of $US14 an hour is what drew Rebecca Dorman, 25, to the hiring fair. She has two jobs - at McDonald's and Sav A Lot - but it's still difficult, she says, to make ends meet.
"I've got a boy, he's 2, and I've got to do something better than McDonald's," she said. "I'll take any job."
A few yards away, Albert Wellons, 48, of Baltimore, agreed. "There's just no jobs out there," he said.
"Especially nowadays," added Lamont Hale, 22, who stood next to him in line wearing an Orioles cap. "Nobody is hiring."
'Good old-fashioned human labour' 

If Amazon does hire 50,000 people this month, labour economists say that could be enough to make a meaningful impact on the country's August employment numbers. The US economy has been adding 100,000 to 200,000 jobs each month.
"Fifty thousand jobs is a really big number, and it could absolutely move the needle for August," said Andrew McAfee, co-director of the MIT Initiative on the Digital Economy.
"It shows that a technology-focused company like Amazon still needs a lot of good old-fashioned human labour to get their work done."
As for Pendry, though, she left without a job offer. After five hours of waiting in the sun, it just got to be too much, she said.
"That line of thousands of people waiting around all day without food - that tells you everything you need to know about the job market.
"It's a struggle," she added. "But I'm going to keep on looking."
The Washington Post with The New York Times and BusinessDay
</content>
  <sindexList>
  <sindex>
    <name>August</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>April</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>AP</name>
    <count>3</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>HR</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australians</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>McDonald</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Bloomberg</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Jed Kolko</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Robert Bruce</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Photo</name>
    <count>4</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Digital Economy</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Allstate Insurance</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lisa Pendry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Andrew McAfee</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Australia</name>
    <count>5</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Victoria</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Americas</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>-6</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>MIT Initiative</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon</name>
    <count>16</count>
    <score>10</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Walmart</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>New York Times</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Lamont Hale, 22</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Washington Post</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Wednesday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Maryland</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Orioles</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-1</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pendry</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US9.25</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Baltimore</name>
    <count>2</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Thursday</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Amazon Marketplace</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Dandenong South</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>BusinessDay</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>World News Videos</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Sav A Lot</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Rebecca Dorman</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Albert Wellons, 48, of Baltimore</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>-4</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Fry Dekowski</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>Pendry, 44</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US14</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>2</score>
  </sindex>
  <sindex>
    <name>US10</name>
    <count>1</count>
    <score>0</score>
  </sindex>
  </sindexList>
</snippet>
